In this section, we are going to develop ordering API layer for exposing minimal Rest APIs with using
Carter following the clean architecture.
And here you can see the big picture.
We are still at the ordering microservices, but this time we will focus on API layer.
And here you can see the internal architecture of the ordering microservices.
We will develop ordering API layer.
Here you can see that we have finished domain infrastructure application layer and focus on presentation
API layer according to Clean Architecture.
So we will develop ordering API layer with exposing minimal Rest API endpoints using the cartel library
and following the clean architecture.
So we will also implement the wrap pattern, which is the request endpoint and response design pattern
for secrets and mediator request lifecycle.
And we will developing order Crud endpoints for Rest APIs in ordering API layer.
And we will develop get order endpoints for the Rest API.
And also we will perform the cross-cutting concerns for custom exception handling in ordering microservices.
And we will perform health checks for the ordering microservices with Entity Framework core and SQL
server.
And we will also test ordering API endpoints with secrets and clean architecture layers.
That means the main target of these API layer is exposing minimal Rest APIs and serving as the entry
point for the external request.
We said that in this section we will implement wrapper design pattern.
So what is the wrapper design pattern?
The wrapper pattern is a software design pattern for developing API endpoints.
Implementing a simple request endpoint response flow wrapper stands for the request endpoint response
and a pattern simplifying the development of Rest API endpoints.
The wrapper design pattern defines web API endpoints as having three components.
These are the request, endpoint, and response.
In the request phase, which is the data structure, the endpoints expected and the endpoint is the
logic the endpoint performs a given a request and response is a data structure.
The endpoint returns.
So with providing a simplified concept, which is.
Enable the development of the Rest API endpoints and enforcing the single responsibility principle for
the endpoints, and the only models that the developers need to care about the request and the response.
So we will develop authentic microservices.
Minimal Rest APIs implementing the wrapper design pattern, especially in sequence and mediated request
lifecycle.
So let's understand our SQS and mediator request lifecycle.
Here you can see an illustration of how API request flows through the system.
The request hit the presentation layer.
In our case typically a Carter minimal API endpoint exposing from the application.
And this will be received the request and initiate the process.
That means this will be sent the command in the mediator and mediator handle the process with creating
command and query and hitting the command handle class in order to interact with database and returning
the result to our response object.
And finally mediator handle process to command and return the result and the final outcome is prepared
for the client application converting the response object.
So that means we will create a request when incoming request object, and after that we will convert
these requests to the command or query.
And after processing the command or query, handle this result object again converting the response
object to sending the client application.
So according to image, we have completed the internal part of the request which is the mediator internal
command and handler classes.
And now we will focus on the exposing endpoints with request and response object using the minimal APIs
and Carter library.