In this video we are going to analyze ordering API layer in a clean architecture and application use
cases.
We can remember that we have a Crud operations, and we have also asynchronous operations for basket
checkout and order fulfillment.
So if you look at the rest API endpoints for ordering microservices, we will expose these endpoints
as a minimal Rest API using Carter following the wrapper pattern in a clean architecture.
And these are the get orders.
Get orders with order name.
Get orders by customer post orders for creating any order.
Put orders for updating an existing order and delete order with ID, so we will expose these endpoints
when developing our ordering API layer.
And if you look at the pattern and principles in ordering API layer, we will utilize the minimal APIs
for streamline the end point exposure and implement the wrapper design pattern and leverage the ASP.Net
core dependency injection and routing features.
So if you look at the folder structure, you can see that in ordering API layer we will create endpoints
folder.
And under this folder we will exposing each rest API including the create update delete order and also
get orders by customer and name.
These will be representing exposing minimal APIs as separate classes under the endpoints folder.
And also we have dependency injection which configures services and dependencies for the API layer.
And we have also global using for centralized command using directives.
And if you look at the ordering NuGet packages in API layer, we will use different NuGet packages.
These are the ASP.Net core libraries Carter for defining minimal APIs.
And we will also use building blocks comes from the application layer.
Here you can see the clean architecture getting reference application layer into our API layer that
we can use from the application layers, building blocks, libraries like mediator maps and other common
libraries.
As a result, we can say that we will expose the endpoints from the API presentation layer, and after
that we will call the application layer six command query handler classes in order to perform our actual
use cases.