In this video we are going to remembering Program.cs and Dependency Injection class in our ordering
API layer and we will install required packages.
So if you go to the ordering folder you can reach the ordering API, which is the presentation layer
of our clean Architecture and ordering API is a ASP.Net web API project that, including the program,
says if you open the program says, you can see that at this point we will add services into container.
That means we have calling different extension methods for adding services into ASP.Net dependency injection
according to clean architecture layers.
So the application is configuring services from different layers, including the application infrastructure
and API specific services.
And after that, at this point we will configure the Http request pipeline.
That means the use API services method configures the middleware specific to the API, such as the routing
and endpoint handling, and after that we are environment specific configurations.
In development environment the application initialize the database.
So these are the configurations into our ordering API.
Program.cs.
So now let's focus on the ASP.Net dependency injection.
If you come here and go to add API services right click go to definition.
You can reach the point where we are defining dependency injections.
For ordering API we can go to ordering API dependency Injection and you can reach the eight API services
and use API services extension methods that we are using in the Program.cs.
So if you look at the add API services, this method is adding the Carter and adding potentially other
API related services into the application service dependency injection.
That's why this is the extension method on the eye service collection.
And if you look at the use API services, this will configure the application to use Carter and map
Carter functionality for handling requests and mapping the endpoints.
So we should add the API related NuGet packages into our class.
And in here we need a Carter library.
For that purpose.
I'm going to right click the dependencies of the ordering API and manage NuGet packages.
In here I am going to browse for the Carter Library and install Carter Library into our ordering API
layer.
Carter Library is used to define minimal API endpoints, and it simplifies the creation and maintenance
of routing and request handling for that purpose.
After installation completed in ordering API, we can confirm that we have successfully installed Carter
into our ordering API, and if you go back to dependency Injection, we can open these command sections,
which is the Registering Carter services into ASP.Net Core Dependency Injection system.
Of course, we need to add a using statement for Carter.
And after that we can come to use API services and open these command sections, which is the app dot
map.
Carter which is configured the application to use Carter for request handling effectively mapping to
define minimal API endpoints.
We can say the dependency injection and these extension methods using in the Program.cs.
In order to activate our endpoints and exposing our Carter minimal API endpoints.