In this video, we are going to develop order endpoints for Rest APIs in ordering API layer.
So you can see the folder structure of the ordering API project.
We will be focused on developing endpoints folder.
We will implement several endpoints to manage the orders.
Following the principle of the clean architecture and utilizing the Carter for minimal API setup.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio and I'm going to start with right click the ordering API.
Create new folder.
Add new folder.
Which name is endpoints.
This folder will contain classes representing each API endpoint.
By having separate classes for each API method, we make it clear and explicit what our API is capable
of, and this approach enhances maintainability and readability.
For that purpose, I'm going to start with creating create order case under the endpoint.
Here you can see that we will create our first endpoint.
It is good to see explicitly which API method we have exposed in ordering API project by looking the
endpoints.
That's why we have given the class names accordingly.
After that, I'm going to create the second endpoint class, which is the delete order and continue
with the update order.
Get orders.
Get orders by name.
And lastly, get orders by customer.
So you can see that we will explicitly see which methods we are exposing from the ordering API by looking
at the endpoint folder.
So let me explain one by one.
The first one is create order.
Create order endpoint class provides to create new order.
So I am going to put a command for each endpoint class to understand what we are going to do and how
we can develop these classes.
So here you can see that I'm going to come here and put comments sections that will be provide our operations.
First of all I'm going to accept create order request object into Create Order endpoint class.
And after that we will make the request to a create order command.
And this command will be used mediator and send this command to corresponding handler which is the create
order command handler.
And we will return a response with a created order IDs.
So this is the process that we are going to develop in the create order endpoint class.
So if you continue with the delete order I'm going to follow the same steps to delete order and point
class provide to delete an existing order.
So we will follow the same steps that we are going to create a SQL code, which is the or actual operations.
We will accept the order ID as a parameter in the delete order endpoint class, and after that we will
create a delete order command object and we will send these command object using the mediator and trigger
the our command handler class.
And lastly, we will return a success or not found response to our delete order endpoint response.
So I'm going to follow the same steps for the update order, update order and Point provide to update
an existing order.
And in this class we will follow the same steps for the securities implementation.
Here you can see that I'm going to accept the update order request which is the incoming request.
So here you can see the steps.
So we will accept update order request and make the request to update Order command.
And we will send this command for processing update order command handler and return a success or error
response based on the outcome.
So you can remember that we are following the securities and mediator request lifecycle in here.
So we will send the request from the client application.
And we will accept into the request object.
And we will convert this request object to the command and query object.
And this object will be triggered.
The handler class using the mediator send command and handle operation.
Perform the business case and returning the result and this result convert into response object and
return back to the client application.
So all this process is the similar what we are developing in the endpoints ordering API.
So I'm going to following the next step which is the get orders endpoint get orders endpoint provide
to retrieve a list of the orders possible paginated orders.
So if you follow the same steps you can come here and see that we will accept the pagination parameters
and construct a get orders query object with these parameters and retrieve the data and return it a
paginated format.
This is the get orders endpoint.
And if you continue to get orders by name, these get orders by name and print provide to find orders
by a specific name.
And in this class we will follow the similar step which is the accepts a name of the parameter, which
is the or order name, and construct a get orders by name query, and we will retrieve and return matching
orders by sending this query to the query handler class.
So lastly we have a get orders by customer class.
Get orders by customer endpoint provide to retrieve orders for a specific customer.
So I'm going to follow the same steps and I'm going to come here.
And these are the accepting customer ID as a parameter.
And we will using get orders by customer query in order to fetch the orders and return the list of the
orders for that customer.
So as you can see that we have created a code for each endpoint class, and each endpoint can be tested
individually by setting up the appreciate request in the tools like the postman, and by developing
distinct endpoints for each Crud operation and query in the ordering API layer, we can achieve the
clear and structured API developments.