In this video we are going to develop, create, order and win class.
So we will follow the steps that we are going to write in the last video.
And we will start with creating Create Order Request Object.
For that purpose.
I'm going to go on top of this class definition.
And after that I will create public record, create order request and order DTO as a taking parameter.
So create order request capture the incoming request data and it contains an order DTO object which
represents the order detail submitted by the client.
So where this order data comes from, as you can see the using statement, it comes from the ordering
application details folder.
So if you remember our reference architecture for the clean architecture and dependencies, you can
see that we are in API layer and in API layer.
Getting reference from the application and infrastructure and details comes from the application that
you can check from the ordering application details and see that order DTO comes from in here.
So since our ordering API getting reference from the application and infrastructure layer, we can access
the order details with using statement in the Create Order request object.
So as the same way, I'm going to create a response object by following the request object.
Here you can see that we have created public record create order response and get ID as a parameter
of this response.
So that means create order response defines the shape of the response data and it contains the ID of
the newly created order.
So after created request and response object, we can start to implement our actual create order and
print class.
So the first start I'm going to start with the I Carter module implementation.
And this interface provide to make this create order as a Carter module in order to expose Http methods.
You can see the Carter comes from the our ordering API, NuGet packages that we have downloaded in the
last videos.
So now I'm going to implement these interface members which is the add routes that we can adding the
routes into our application with using and implementing this method.
So we will implement these add road methods with using the endpoint route builder.
When defining a set of routes for handling Http requests for create order, we are going to use http
post operation.
For that purpose, I'm going to remove this throw statement and write app dot map post and with writing
the map post.
Basically we will define http post endpoint at the path of the orders.
Here you can see the endpoint URL slash orders and this is the implementation of these endpoint URL
when incoming requests comes and hit this point.
And as you can see that I'm going to developing our map post operation which is the endpoint.
And this is the implementation of the asynchronous function.
So in this function we basically get a request parameters which is the create order request coming from
the request parameters.
And the second parameter which is the I sender comes from the mediator will be injected into our asynchronous
method.
So we will develop these delegate handler method with following the steps that we are writing in here.
So the first step is we are going to adapting incoming request object to the command object.
As you can see that we will map the request to create order command.
In this line of code we will use requested map method and adapt is comes from the our maps, library
and maps.
The library comes from the ordering application that is getting reference from the building blocks for
common operations and common NuGet packages, and the second operation is using the mediator in order
to send this command to the corresponding handler method.
So we are creating a create order command object.
Now we can send this command object using the mediator in order to trigger corresponding handler method.
For that purpose I'm going to use await that sender dot send method and passing this command object
as a parameter of the mediator sender object, and this will be return back a result object, which
is the create order result object that we can also continue to mapping this result object to the our
response object, which is including the created order IDs.
So after triggering the mediator, the next step is we will be again using the mapper for adopting result
object to the create order response object.
By this line of code, we will return back the response object with converting this result object to
the create order response object.
And lastly, we will return these response object to the client application with using the return results
that created method, which is basically response back to Http 201.
Created response with passing the parameters of the endpoint URL definition orders dot order id which
incoming response.id and return the whole response object as a response of the client application.
So basically with this line of codes, we will perform the mediator and secure life cycles that we have
already seen in our slide.
We will accepting the request incoming.
Take us into our request object and we will map this request object to the command object and we will
passing this command object to mediator dot send function.
This will be triggered the corresponding command handler to performing use cases and returning the result.
And we will also respawning this result object to mapping the response object and return back to the
client application.
So we will perform all these secrets lifecycle in example of the http post operation to the orders endpoint.
And after that we can configure these Carter endpoint configuration with passing the extension methods
including the with name produce with summary description, and so on.
We basically use with name for assigning a name to this endpoint for easy reference, and we will produce
use a create order response and this code will be 201 created.
And if any problem we will return 400 bad request.
And you can also configure the summary and description which provide a brief summary of the endpoint
purpose.
So this is the definition of the create order endpoint.
If you go on top of this class, you can see that we have several using statements for removing these
using statement I'm going to create a global using under the ordering API project.
And for that purpose come to ordering API and add new item which name is global using CSS.
So you can remove all things in this class, because we will be moving these using statement from the
create order and Point class.
If you open this endpoint class, you can see that these are the common using statements that we are
going to use for all endpoints.
And this is for specifically create order endpoint.
That's why I am leaving the last one and moving the rest of the using statements into our global using.
So if you go back to global using and paste in here and write the global keywords in the beginning of
this using statement.
And these will be representing the common packages that we can use the whole endpoint class definitions.
So if you go back to our create order you can see that we have one using statement.
And this is the implementation of the create order endpoint class with using the I Carter module implementation.