In this video we are going to develop update order and point class and we will follow the steps.
And here you can see that we will start with creating update Order request.
So in here I'm going to create Public Record update order request and taking parameter which is from
the order DTO and order.
So Update Order request represent the incoming data for the update operation.
And it contains an order DTO which holds the updated order details with the ID information.
So after that I'm going to also prepare update order response object.
And here you can see that we have created public record update order response and Boolean is success
as a parameter of this record type.
So basically the update order response define the structure of the response indicating whether the update
operation was successful or not.
After that, we can start to develop our actual class, which is the update order, and I am going to
implement from the equator module and implement these interface members, which is the add method.
So basically we have implemented equator module interface and defining the routes for Http request handling.
For performing the update operation, we will utilize map put method in order to define Http put endpoint
at the path of the slash orders.
For that purpose, I'm going to remove this throw statement and writing the app dot map put method and
passing the slash orders endpoint URL as a parameter of the map put.
And after that we have asynchronous delegate handler class and method.
For this method, we will accommodate the incoming requests and perform the our actual logic.
Here you can see that the first parameter is request object, which is.
The update order request comes from the incoming request object and the second parameter is I standard
sender object, which is basically injecting mediator I sender interface into our delegate handler method.
So after that I'm going to put a implementation of this method.
So as the same way we will implement this method with converting incoming request object to the update
command object.
And after converting this command object, we basically send this command object to the mediator using
the standard dot send method.
And after that we will converting these responding result object to the our response object, which
is the update or the response object, and return back this response object to the client application.
So with this line of code, we basically accept and update all the requests and adapt the request to
an update order command using the map star and using mediators sender send method.
With passing this command object in order to process the command and handle the corresponding handle
method, and also await the result from the command handler and convert the result into our update order
response and return back to that okay response to the client application.
Okay response is returning status 200 okay response.
And finally we can configure this method using the Carter extension methods, including the with name
producers.
Producers problem with summary and description.
By this way, we can complete the update order and print class.
If you go on top of this page, you can see that we don't have any special using statement.
This is for the update order command object.
And here you can see the implementation of the update order endpoint class that we are going to adhering
to implement wrapper design pattern and implementing Rest API using the Carter.