In this video we are going to develop delayed order endpoint.
As always, we will follow the steps that we have written in the last video.
And I'm going to start with creating delayed order request and response object type.
Here you can see that public record request and response object.
So in the request object as you can see that we don't require delayed order request record type, since
the only required information is the ID of the ordered to be deleted, which is obtained directly from
the request URL parameters.
That's why we don't define any request object that we get the ID information from the request parameters.
And here you can see the delayed order response object, which is the result of the delete operation
indicating success or failure.
After that, we can develop our actual class, which is a delayed order implementing Écarter module
and implement the interface members, which is the ID routes.
So in the add method, we basically uses the map delayed function in order to define a delayed endpoint
at the orders slash id and point definition.
So for that purpose I'm going to remove the throw statement and using app dot map delete.
And this is the endpoint which is the slash orders slash ID.
And here you can see the delegate handler function which is accepting two parameters.
The first one is with id id comes from the endpoint definition in here.
And the second parameter is I sender sender which is injecting mediator I sender object into our delegate
handler function.
So I'm going to implement this function.
So as you remember that we will follow the same steps.
The first step is normally we will map the incoming request object to create command object.
But this time I am passing this ID information into command object and directly using the mediator standard
dot send function and passing the new delete order command object with passing the id information comes
from the request parameters.
So with getting the result object from the delete order command handler, we will adapting the result
object to the delayed order response object.
And lastly, we will returning the results that okay function passing the response object to the client
application.
So this is the implementation of the map delete function.
We basically extract the ID information from the request URL and create a delete order command with
the ID information, and send this command to mediator for processing, handle operation and await the
results from the command handler and adapted into the delayed order response and returning the client
in a results dot okay function.
So after that we can define and configure these http delete endpoint with passing the name summary description
and produces functions.
And here you can see the implementation of the delete order.
This is the using statement that comes from the commands delete order.
And these are the delete order requests and response.
And this is the delete order actual endpoint class that we are following.
The repair design pattern and using the cutter library.