In this video we are going to develop get orders by name.
We will start by creating request and response object.
Here you can see that request object.
We will use and get name information from the request parameters.
And here you can see the record type of the get orders by name response by taking the orders as a ordered
list.
So these are the definition of the request and response.
And after that we will develop actual class which is the get orders by name and inherit from the equator
module.
And if we implement the interface members this is the address that we define our Get orders and http
get request.
So in this method we basically exposing http get method.
For that purpose I'm going to type app dot map get method and passing the endpoint definition which
is the slash orders slash order name.
And this is the delegate 100 function that we are implementing for accommodating incoming requests.
The first parameter is getting order name from the request parameters.
And the second parameter is we have injecting mediator standard interface into our method.
So I'm going to implement this method.
And we will follow the same steps that we have implemented in the previous videos.
In the first line of code we basically directly use mediator send function and passing this function
to the new get orders by name query and passing this query record type as a order name, which comes
from the request parameters, and this is available function and returning a result object that we can
converting this result object to the response object for that purpose.
After getting result from the mediator sender function, I'm going to adapting this result object to
the get orders by name response object.
And lastly, we will passing this response object to the resulted okay function and client application.
Here you can see that we will use return results okay.
And passing the response object.
And this is the implementation of the get orders by name.
And lastly we can configure these Http get method with passing the some of the extension method including
the with name produce produce problems with summary and description.
In the produce problems, you can see that it is indicate potential problems with 400 bad requests exception
and also 404 not found exception.
So this is the implementation of the get orders by name.
Here you can see that we have only one using statement indicating the queries.
Get orders by name.
And this is the request and response record type.
And this is the implementation of the get orders by name class.