In this video we are going to develop get orders by customer and we are going to follow exactly the
same steps.
What we have done in the last video.
And I'm going to create by starting Request and response objects.
Here you can see that we will create record type, but in a request object we will accepting customer
ID from the request URL parameters.
That's why I'm commenting this request part.
And here you can see the public record get orders by customer response with taking the orders order
detail list object as a parameter of this response type.
And after that we can start to implement our actual class, which should be implement Écarter module
and implement add routes method.
In this method we basically expose http get method and the URL should be the orders customer and customer
id.
Here you can see that I'm going to use app dot map get method in order to expose http get operation.
And this is the URL.
And this time you can see that our endpoint URL include slash customer and slash customer ID.
And this customer ID is a request parameters.
And we are passing this customer ID into our delegate handler function.
In the first parameter you can see that we will taking with customer ID from the request parameters.
And in the second parameter we will inject I sender mediator object.
And after that we can start implementation our delegate handler method.
And you can come here and start the implementation of this method.
In this method implementation we basically directly call the mediator standard send function with available
function and passing the get orders by customer query and passing the customer ID in this query object.
So by this way this will be trigger the query handler class and returning a result object.
And after that we will adapting this result object to the get orders by customer response.
And we are passing this response object to the client application with returning results.
Okay.
Response.
This will be returned 200 okay response.
And after that of course we should configure our Carter endpoint.
And here you can see the extension method that we are going to follow with name summary and description.
And these are the produce and produce problems that we can configure our Http get operation.
And in this class we are using one statement which comes from the orders queries from the application
layer.
And these are the request and response object definition.
And these are the get orders by query implementation with implementing wrapper design pattern and following
the Carter Library.