In this video we are going to develop get orders endpoint with pagination.
As you remember that in the last section when we are developing ordering application, we can go to
orders and you can go to queries folder.
And if you open the get orders you can see that in the Get Orders query, we will expecting the pagination
request and return back the page entity result.
And these pagination classes are developed on the building blocks in the pageant request.
It is expecting page index and page size and it is returned back to paginated result that including
page index, size, count and data.
So if you scroll down and if you look at the get orders handler, you can see that this is the incoming
query.
And in the handle method we will perform the pagination with incoming query and taking the page size
and page index and return back to get all the results inside of the page entity result and return back
to order detail list in the data of this page.
Entity result and this result also include page index, page size and total count.
So we will implement these pagination in the presentation layer, which is the ordering API when developing
or get orders and point class.
So I'm going to start with implementing Request and response object as a request.
I'm going to put a commented request object, which means that we will get the pagination request as
a request parameters of the get orders endpoint.
And here you can see the public record get orders response and taking the orders paginated result as
a type of the order DTO.
So that means if you go to page end result, the type will be the order actual data, which is the IEnumerable
data.
In our case, we will expecting IEnumerable order DTO as a data into page entity result into get orders
response record type.
So now I'm going to implement get orders actual class which is implementing Écarter model.
And if you implement this interface members, we will be developing add routes method.
In the add method we are going to expose Http get method which is a slash orders and retrieving the
whole orders with pagination.
So I'm going to develop app dot map get function and passing the slash orders as endpoint.
And here you can see the delegate handler which accodomate the incoming request.
And this endpoint is handle the Http get request with pagination details.
It facilitating the efficient data fetching from a potential large data set, and in the handler function,
which takes a paginated request object as a input.
Here you can see the first parameter is a pagination request object as input, and here you can see
as parameters attribute in the route handler.
So that ensures query parameters are correctly bound into the pagination request object.
So the pagination request object include page index and page size essential for the pagination.
So after that the second parameter is isander which is injected.
Mediator is enter into our request delegator.
So I'm going to implement this function.
So inside of this function we will follow the same steps.
What we have done in the last videos we basically perform sequence and mediator request lifecycle.
Here you can see the implementation in the first row of these hundred class.
You can see that we will use await mediator Sanderson function and passing the get orders query and
passing the request object.
So these get orders query containing the pagination information which is sent to mediator for processing
query handler functions.
Once query is executed, the result which comes from the paginated list of the ordered DTO is adapted
to get ordered response as a result object, and we will use result of adapt method with passing this
object and converting to the response object.
And finally, we can paste this response object to the result that okay function.
In order to retrieve Http 200 okay response to the client application.
And finally we can configure these Carter function with passing these extension method including name
summary and description.
And these are the produce and produce problems for returning these Http get method.
So if you go on top of this class you can see that we are using two statement which comes from the pagination
from the building blocks.
And these are the comes from the orders queries from the application layer.
And here you can see that we will create request and response record type.
And this is the actual implementation of the get orders endpoint class with following the wrapper design
pattern and using the Carter library.
So we have completed the ordering API.
I'm going to right click and build the whole clean architecture layers for ordering microservices.
And you can confirm that your application will successfully and you are ready for the test our application.