In this video we are going to test ordering microservices with secrets and clean architecture layers.
We will walk through the testing, ordering API endpoints in a clean architecture setup and ensuring
our implementation of the secrets and domain driven design patterns.
So here you can see the internal architecture of the ordering microservices that we have finished the
development of the clean architecture layers, including domain application, infrastructure and presentation.
And now we are ready to hitting or exposing Http methods and trigger our clean architecture secrets
and domain driven design implementation when interacting with SQL database and implementing business
use cases.
So for that purpose, it is good to remembering ordering microservices with clean architecture layers.
If you open the Visual Studio, you can see that we have clean architecture layers including domain,
infrastructure, application and API.
So if we explore these layers one by one in the ordering domain layer, we will contain the domain logic
and the models.
And it is crucial for the business rules and behaviors.
And if you expand the ordering infrastructure it is managed the data access and external resources providing
support for the persistence in the data folder.
And if we explore the ordering application, this will be in command sequence design pattern using the
mediator library, handling the application logic commands, queries and event handlers in the orders
feature folder.
Lastly, if we explore the ordering API presentation layer, this is the entry point for external request
and exposing endpoints to interacting with the application in the endpoint folder.
So we will follow these clean architecture layers when testing our ordering microservices, for example,
where we are initializing database and seeding data in ordering API, the application entry point is
Program.cs.
If you open the program says here, you can see that when the application start up, we will running
the initialize database async extension method.
When application startup.
And in this method we basically responsible for seeding database on application startup and Program.cs
trigger the database initialization in the development environment, which is looking for the development
environment.
And if you go to this method, you can see that this method is implemented under the Ordering infrastructure
layer under data folder under extensions.
Here you can see the database extension and initial data class that provides the seeding and database
initialization.
So we are seeding SQL server database when application start up in the program cache.
And this will be triggered ordering infrastructure.
And now the second question is how we can implement security design pattern.
In the application layer.
We are implementing the security design pattern commands, queries and event handlers in tormenting
use cases for ordering features under the orders feature folder, you can see the commands, event handlers
and queries that performing the six design pattern implementation.
And if you look at the ordering domain layer, you can see that for example, under the modules we have
a ordered aggregate that encapsulate the order creation logic and domain event raising operation.
In here you can see the create and update method that is representing our rich domain model, which
means create and update operation responsible for the order entity and when order, create or update
it will raise order created an order updated domain event that will catch these event into application
layer.
So how we can dispatch this event.
So if you go to infrastructure layer, if you go to the interceptors and go to the dispatch domain event
interceptor class, you can see that this will be intercept Entity Framework core operations in order
to dispatch domain events using the mediator.
And this dispatching domain events will catch under the ordering application layer.
If you go to orders and event handlers, you can see that the dispatching domain events are handling
under the ordering application layer.
And here you can see the order created domain event handler, which inherit from the notification handler
in order to handle domain event which is raising from the infrastructure layer.
So these are the domain events lifecycle.
And last section we have also developed the ordering API project.
Here you can see the ordering API and endpoints folder.
In this folder we basically expose Crud operations and communicates with the application layer using
the mediator.
So that means we have Crud endpoints in order to trigger application sequence command and queries using
Here you can see the Crud endpoints and this will be trigger the application layer.
And this will be performed with the mediator send operation.
If you go to the application layer orders command for example delete order command handler, you can
see that these will be trigger from the API layer.
When the request comes, this will be delayed order handler and using the AI application db context,
which is abstraction of the Entity Framework core db context object.
And perform the Crud operations on SQL server database using the Infrastructure Layer and Entity Framework
Core ORM.
So after remembering our ordering microservices clean architecture layers, it is time to perform end
to end test for ordering microservice use cases.
The first use case will be create order endpoint.
But before that, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running, and after that we should activate
the backing services for ordering microservices or backing services.
Is Microsoft SQL server database.
For that purpose, you can open the Visual Studio and go to the Docker Compose Yaml file.
If you right click and set a startup project, this will be.
Activate our backing services when running the Docker Compose profile, and this will be run all backing
services into our application.
Please set a startup project for Docker compose and run without debugging.
This will be run the docker compose up command on the behind of the scene.
In order to activate database message brokers and the rest of the backing services that are required
to run our microservices locally.
So here you can see the progress is continue.
And you can confirm from the Docker desktop when activating our backing services with running Docker
Compose.
Here you can see that our order DB now is up and running that requiring from the ordering microservices
as a backing services.