In this video we are going to test, create, order and print with Sequence and Kirin architecture.
That means we will send http post requests in the slash orders endpoint in order to create a new order,
and we will conduct end to end test for the create order endpoint.
That means we will perform queries and mediator request life cycle for incoming Http post requests.
This will be create order request and we will convert these.
Create order command and mediator will be trigger create order command handler.
In order to create a new item into database and returning result.
And this will be converting response and response back to client application.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering API endpoint and create order.
This class is academic incoming http post Cqrs in the delegate handler function.
So in here I am going to put a breakpoint which is the map post operation and this will be Accodomate
incoming create order requests and performing actual logic and after that I am going to put additional
breakpoint in the end of this function in order to understand how we can respond back to our client
application.
So in the body of this method you can see that we will basically using mediator send function with sending
this command.
And this will be trigger our application layer.
Since we are sending the create order command.
And this will be trigger the create order command handler in the application layer.
For that purpose go to Ordering application.
Go to orders commands, create order use case folder and open the create order handler.
So this will be our actual handler.
For the create order command.
You can safely remove unnecessary using statement and save this create order command under class.
So in this class you can see that we have handle method.
And in this handle method we will perform actual use case which is the interacting database and inserting
any record.
So I am going to put a breakpoint in the beginning of the handle method.
And also if you go to create new order I am going to put additional breakpoint in the create new order.
So if you look at this logic you can see that in here we are creating order entity.
And after that adding orders into Entity Framework core orders collection and save change async with
using Entity Framework Core.
So in here you can see that when we are creating a new order entity, we will use order dot create function
which is inside of the order entity order is responsible for creating its own entity.
And here you can see that we have additional breakpoint in the order create operation.
And this is happening in the ordering domain layer.
And the model under the models we have ordered aggregate and we will put breakpoint under the order
create function.
And in this function you can see that we have created domain event which is the order created domain
event and how we can dispatch this domain event.
Of course it is happening in the ordering infrastructure.
If you go to ordering infrastructure, go to interceptors and open the dispatch domain event.
You can put breakpoints when we are dispatching this domain event and when we are dispatching this domain
event, this will be handled in the ordering application layer.
If you go back to ordering application layer.
And if you go to the event handlers, if you open the order created event handler, you can see that
in this code, we will handle and catch these domain events in order to perform our use case for that
purpose, put additional breakpoint in the handle of the order created event handler in the application
layer.
So we have successfully put breakpoints for the end to end perspective of the create order use cases.
So after that, let's remember our deployment strategy.
If you open the deployment strategy we are at the first stage which is the deployment want and deploying
from the local machine.
So we have completed the development of the ordering microservices in our local environment.
And we will connect the backing services, which is the SQL server database.
And we have activating the SQL server in order to communicate from our local ordering microservices.
So that means now we will perform these deployment one and performing the testing from deployment one
and from local machine of the ordering microservices.
For that purpose, I am going to open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering API and right click the
ordering API and set a startup project.
This will be academic incoming requests from our local computer.
For that purpose, we will start from the ordering API for ordering microservices, and I am going to
hit the Https button in order to run ordering microservices in Https mode.
So when the application start up, as you remember that these applications will be migrate and seed
SQL server database.
When the application start up, it is a development environment and it is going to initialize database.
And I am going to hit F5 in order to migrate and see database.
That means we will create order db in our SQL server database.
And after that we will populate some data including customer product orders and items with asynchronous
way.
Here you can see that migrated completed and the seeding operation also completed with sending and dispatching
domain elements.
Because in this case when we are seeding order, we will create a new order and these order will be
dispatching order created domain event.
And that's why it is going to hitting the dispatch domain events from the infrastructure layer.
And when I hit the F5 this time, we can see that when the order created, this will be catching from
the replication layer.
After dispatching all of the things here, you can see that this time when we are dispatching domain
events which using the I notification from the mediator, this will be handled from the order created
domain event which is located in our ordering application layer.
And this will be implement I notification handler interface.
And in the handle method we can perform log information and return the task completed.
And I'm going to hit F5 and pacing this operation for now.
And I would like to up and running my ordering API microservices.
Here you can see the log statement is completed.
Now that means our authentic microservices is ready for Academy incoming requests.
But you can see the logs.
This will be create a new database and tables.
And after that this will be inserting any record.
In order to seeding our databases to verify SQL server database setup, you can open the SQL Server
Object Explorer in the Visual Studio, and you can refresh these SQL Server Object Explorer and connect
the localhost.
And if you go to the database, you can see that order db is created successfully.
And if you expand the tables, you can see customers orders and order items are created successfully.
If you right click the orders and view data, you can see that seeding operations also completed successfully.
And we have only two orders in our application yet.
So now I'm going to create a new order with sending http post request.
For that purpose, please open the postman.
And in the postman we have a postman collection which is the Icap microservices.
And under the ordering microservices I have created post order operation.
So please create http post request for the ordering microservices.
Here you can see the http post operation and if you look at the endpoint, you can see that we will
use ordering URL and slash orders endpoint.
If you look at the ordering URL, you can see that we will set 5053 which is indicating our localhost
environment.
If you open the environments, you can see that we have a local environment and Docker environment for
local environment.
You can see the port numbers is starting with the 50.
And if you change these localhost to Docker, you can see that the environment will be changed accordingly.
With the 60 port numbers.
Here you can see that.
So now we are going to test from our local computer and local ordering resources.
For that purpose I'm going to change the environment as a localhost.
And after that verify the ordering URL is starting with 50.
After that we are ready to send http post requests for the create order endpoint.
But before that, please check the our Json body request which is including the whole order object.
And this is an example Json body with including customer details, shipping, billing, address, payment
information and order items according to newly created order.
Here you can see that we will have two order items in this order and the order status will be two.
And these are the payment address definitions.
And the order name will be order for.
And this is the order body structure that we are going to send as a Json body when sending http post
request to this endpoint.
So after preparing this Post request, I'm going to hit the send button in order to observe the flow
of execution through the breakpoints.
So hit the send button and see that this will be triggered our ordering API and which is the create
order endpoint.
So this is the first point when Academy request and populating the incoming create order request.
If you open the request you can see that this will be include the whole order Json object and this order
including billing, customer ID, ID, order items, order name, payment, shipping address status,
and so on.
And after that this will be converting these order and requests to the command object.
And this will be sent to mediator in order to trigger our command handler.
Here you can see that this will be triggered or create order handler class which is located under the
ordering application layer.
And in this handle method this will be.
Basically create a new order, and after that save the database using the Entity Framework core.
But before that it is preparing the new order and this will be using order dot create operation and
which is hitting the order create function.
And this is locating in the our ordering domain layer.
You can verify the folder structure.
This will be hitting the order when creating any order item.
And this will be creating a new order entity and adding domain events into the ordered aggregate and
returning a new order.
And this will be also adding order items into this order and returning any order entity.
And after that, this order is ready for the saving database.
So if you continue our debugging, this will be adding orders into DB context and save change async.
When we are saving changes with using Entity Framework Core, this will be hitting the interceptor which
is the Dispatch domain event interceptor, and this will be dispatching domain events regarding trees
or aggregate, which is the order aggregate and we have one domain event and we will publish this domain
event using the mediator publish function.
And after that this will be dispatching this domain event.
And this will be catching and handling in the ordering application layer which is the order created
event handler.
And this will be implement from the identification handle.
And in this handle method we basically handle the incoming notification which is the our order created
notification event and domain event.
Here you can see the details of this domain event and the order details.
And in this place I am going to only logging the information with incoming domain event.
But in the next videos we are going to leading the integration event.
That means we will be converting this domain one to integration in and in order to notify other microservices.
But for now at least we can see that how we can handle these domain event in the ordering application
layer.
And if I continue to our debug operation, you can see that our saving operation is completed.
And if I hit F5 this will be hitting the at the end of the our create order endpoint which is our ordering
application.
That means we are end of the our request life cycle and converting these create order response from
the result object and which we are returning this response object to the our client application, which
only including newly created order ID, and this will be returning results that created.
And I am going to hit F5 and see the our postman.
And in here you can see the postman response.
This will be responding to all one created success response, and this is the newly created order ID
that we are going to verify from the database.
So now let's verify this newly created order from the Visual Studio and SQL Server Object Explorer.
As you remember that we have orders data and we have only two data when starting the application.
If I refresh this order data, you can see that this time we have newly created order comes from the
database which is created from the our http post request.
That means we will perform end to end use case for the create order endpoint in the ordering microservices.