In this video we are going to test update order endpoint with queries and clean architecture.
That means we will send http put request in the slash orders endpoint.
In order to update an existing order, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Update Order case
under the endpoint folder.
You can see that under the ordering API, under the endpoint we have update order sales, which will
be accodomate incoming http put request in the delegate handler function.
So put breakpoint in the beginning of this function and returning this function and this function will
be trigger update order command handler.
So for that purpose we will go to ordering application and go to the update order folder under the Commands
and Orders folder and open the update Order handler class and put a breakpoint in the beginning of the
handle method.
So this method will be perform actual use case, which is updating an order from the database.
And if you go to the update order with values, you can see that this will be using order update method.
From the ordering domain layer.
You can verify that under ordering domain we have ordered aggregate and under that we have ordered update
method.
That means order is responsible for update operation.
So in here also we have a order updated event list.
That means we will adding domain event into aggregate which is the order updated event.
And this domain event will dispatch with using the ordering infrastructure and dispatch domain event
handler interceptor.
And this will be trigger to handle method of the ordering application layer, which is the under the
orders event handlers and order updated event handler.
And I am going to put additional breakpoint in order to handle this domain event when updating an order.
So we have put the end to end breakpoints for the update order use cases.
You can also verify the order data in the last video.
We have added newly created order in here.
So we are going to update these order name and other details for example such as billing address and
so on.
So I'm going to copy this ID information in here and open the postman.
And if you open the postman you can see that we have additional request which is the Http put.
And these are the endpoints of these put operation.
This is similar with the http post operation.
I'm going to use 50 port numbers for sending request to our local computer and slash orders.
But this time our function is http put.
And if you look at our Json payload you can see that this is similar with the order object.
And this will be sample request payload including the whole order attributes.
And we are updating some of the fields for example order name and shipping and billing information,
payment details and so on.
So specifically I have changed the order name and shipping first name and state information, and you
can also change the billing, first name and state information and change the payment card name.
So these are the changed attributes from the our newly created order.
And this time I am going to update the order with sending the whole Json payload.
But of course, please don't forget the change ID information.
You can copy the ID from the database or in this place when we are sending the http post request from
the last video, and I am going to change the ID information with a newly created order in the last
video.
So I'm going to change with this with information and remove this note and save this payload and hit
the send button in order to trigger our breakpoints.
And now we can observe our breakpoints, the flow of the request lifecycle.
Here you can see that we have hit the update order endpoint with the request of the order details.
You can see that the order is updated with the order name is five and you can see other details.
I have changed the billing address, first name and so on.
So if I continue debugging, you can see that the first thing we are converting these requests to command
object and we will hit the mediator send button.
The command will be triggered our application layer update order handler handle method.
And in this method we will perform the actual logic.
First of all we will check this order ID exists or not in the database.
If not exist we will throw an order not found exception.
In our case we can find the order in database and after that we will update orders with the new values
in this method.
In here you can see that after preparing our value object, we are hitting the order update method which
is the located or ordered domain layer.
And in here we are going to update new order name, which is the order five and shipping address, billing
address, payment and status.
And after that we will adding domain event which name is order updated event into order aggregate.
After updating this operation and after continuing this our handle method in the application layer,
we basically update an existing order using the Entity Framework core and when saving.
Async.
Here you can see that this will be triggered our interceptor from the infrastructure layer.
And after that we will dispatching domain events.
In our case we will dispatch one domain event which is the our update order domain event.
And here you can see that this will be triggered and handled from the ordering application layer.
Order updated event handler which is implementing a notification handler.
You can confirm that this is the place where the ordering application event handlers located, and in
this case I am only logging the information which incoming domain event.
But in the next videos we can send integration event in here.
So I'm going to hit F5 and go at the end of this endpoint class and return a response to the client
application.
You can see the response is 200 okay successful.
And you can see the payload of the response which is the success is true.
So now we can verify these updated records on the database.
If you open the Visual Studio and if you open the SQL Server Object Explorer I have already opened these
orders before this video.
Here you can see that this is the last record that we have inserted in the last video.
And please check this order name.
We have updated this order name.
If I refresh this page, you can see that our order name has changed with the five and the order of
the values are changed.
If you check the the first name of the billing and shipping address and so on.
That means we have successfully updated an existing record with using the update order endpoint.