In this video we are going to test get endpoints with circles and cleaned architecture.
We will send Http get method to slash orders with sending the page index and page size in order to get
orders with pagination, and we will send Http get method to these orders and order name URL in order
to get orders by username.
And lastly, we will send http get method to slash orders, slash customer and slash customer id.
In order to get orders by customer for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Get
endpoints under the ordering API.
Here you can see the get orders with pagination.
I am going to put a breakpoint in the beginning of this delegate handler, and this will be getting
pagination request as a parameter which including the page size and page index.
And I'm going to put a breakpoint at the end of this delegate handler function in order to see when
we are returning a response to the client application, and these get orders will be triggered to get
orders.
Query handler.
If you go to ordering application and close the commands and go to orders and queries.
And if you expand these queries folder, you can see our use cases.
I'm going to focus on the get orders handle function.
And in this handle method we will perform get orders with pagination.
I'm going to put a breakpoint in the beginning of this handle method, and after that I'm going to follow
the same steps for the rest of the get methods, which is the get orders by name.
I'm going to open the endpoint and put a breakpoint in the beginning of the http get method and delegate
handler function, and put a breakpoint when leaving our delegate handler.
When the http get method of the get orders by username and this will be triggered.
Get orders by name folder under the ordering application.
If you open the handle method, you can see that this will be get orders by name using the DB context
object and put a breakpoint in the handle method of the get orders by name.
You can safely remove unnecessary using statement if you see any place and save this file.
And of course, when we change anything in our code we should restart our application.
That's why I am stopping our ordering microservices and I will restart after setting the breakpoints.
And the last use case is get orders by customer.
If you go to ordering API endpoints and get orders by customer class, you can see that this will be
a commit, which is the orders, customers, customer ID endpoint.
And you can put the banquet in the beginning of the delegate handler.
And in the end of this delegate 101 hundred function.
After that, we can put breakpoint in the implementation of these customer handle query, which is under
the ordering application.
Go to queries and go to get orders by customer and open the handle function.
And this is the get orders by customer handler class.
And you can put the breakpoint in the handle method.
This will be perform getting orders by customer with a given customer ID.
So after setting the breakpoints we can start our applications.
Wishing the ordering API in a https mode.
This will be start our application and accodomate incoming http get request.
And in here we can open the postman and if you open the postman, you can see that I have created three
http get method under the ordering microservices into our postman collection.
So now I am going to send http get methods one by one and we will start with the get orders with pagination.
Here you can see the method is http get and the URL is ordering URL orders.
And here you can see that I have added page index and page size as a request parameters.
So this will be hit our pagination.
And as an expected result I am going to expect returning the first two orders due to pagination settings,
and we will validate the pagination functionality in the query handler.
So hit the send button and see what's going happen.
This will be hitting the ordering API and hit the get orders.
And in here you can see that we have a pagination request that include our parameters which are the
page index and page size.
So when we are putting the as parameters attribute in the beginning of this request, this will be accodomate
the incoming request parameters and put into the pagination request.
And after that we will use these requests with sending the get orders query and hitting the get orders
query handler.
I'm going to continue our debugging and this will be trigger our handle method which is located our
ordering application and get orders handler.
And this will be get the page index and page size and calculate the total count of the orders.
This is the three total count of the orders on our SQL server database, and we will retrieve the orders
by pagination.
Here you can see that this will be retrieving two orders, and that means we will return back these
two orders in a page ended result, including the page index, page size, total count and orders data.
So I'm going to continue this.
Debugging and hit F5 and see that this will be returned.
A response to order list, including to two items into data of these returning the pageant result.
And if I hit F5, you can see the postman collection and this will be returned to 100.
Okay response.
And if you expand the return of the response of these Http get method, you can see that we have returned
pageant result which name is orders and in this pageant result it includes page index, page size count
and data.
In the data we will have orders list and in this case we will expect two orders according to our page
size.
This is the first order.
Which name is order one.
Here you can see the first order and if you scroll down you can see the second order located in this
place, which is the order two.
If you scroll down, you can see that we have only two order items under the data of the response of
the pageant result.
So we have successfully sent the http get request for the first two records of the pagination.
So if I change the page index from 0 to 1, we can change the page index.
That means we will get the the next of the order record with including the two rows.
But if you send the http get method, you can see that we have only three record on orders.
So that means we will retrieve only ordered last order record that we have inserted in the last videos.
So I'm going to continue the pagination.
And this time our request is including in here page index is one.
That means the second page and the page size is two.
That means we will would like to retrieve two record in the page two.
And I'm going to continue our handle method.
This will be getting the page index page size and total count.
You can see the total count is three.
That means we will expect one record in the second page of these orders.
This will be returning a orders and return back a page result including the page index size, total
count and orders.
And if I hit F5 and return the result, you can see that this time we will have a page index one and
page size two country.
And as a data of the response you can see that this will be returned last order into our order database.
And this is only one record.
That means we have only three record into our database.
In the second page we have only one order data.
With returning this pagination, we have successfully test get orders with pagination.
And I'm going to test get orders by name.
If you come to these http get method, you can see the URL ordering, URL orders and the order name.
So as expected result, we will retrieve the orders with the name of the order underscore two.
So I'm going to send http get method.
And this will be trigger ordering API and get orders by name.
And in this endpoint class you can see that we will send get orders by name query and passing the order
name as a parameter of this query.
This will be trigger or get orders by name handle in the ordering application.
And in this handle method we will perform get orders by name using the Entity Framework core.
And I am hitting F5.
And you can see that we got the exception about the order by statement.
You can see that order by is using order order name, but it is not translatable because order name
is a strongly type value object that need to set a string value.
If you go back to our Visual Studio, you can see that this is the get orders by name.
And if you look at the get orders, you can see that we will use order by order name dot volume information
in the get orders.
And also I would like to check get orders by customer.
If you look at the get orders by customer again we are using order name dot volume information when
ordering the SQL script into our Entity Framework core for that purpose.
If you go back to our actual get orders by name and stop the application, and now I'm going to change
this order name volume information in the order by of these get orders by name query.
Please make sure that you have also fixed this bug.
And after that restart our application and send again these http get method.
Okay we have fixed the exception and run the application again.
And I am going to hit the Http send button again.
Get orders by name.
And if you send this button you can see that this will trigger our get orders by name end to end.
If I hit F5 this will be handle.
Method comes in the picture.
And now I'm going to continue these orders query.
And this time we can successfully respond back to orders which is including one record.
And if I hit F5, you can see that we will return back to the client application.
And if I hit F5 again in here, this time we will get success 200 okay.
Response from the our Http endpoint.
And this is the response of the our endpoint.
Here you can see that we will return back to the URL or two details in the response of the body.
This is the order attributes including shipping address.
Billing address, payment status and order items.
So we have successful tests.
Get orders by name and if you continue our tests, we can continue to get orders by customer.
If you open these Http get endpoint, you can see the URL is a Http ordering URL orders customers and
this is the customer ID.
You can get the customer id from the http post or put request.
You can copy the customer ID from this place and paste into the our get orders by customer and hit the
Http send button.
This will be triggered get orders endpoint in the ordering API.
So if you look at the customer ID which comes from the request parameters, this is the customer ID
that we are going to retrieve via orders.
So I'm going to continue debugging.
This will be triggered get orders by customer handle in the application layer and in the handle method.
We will perform the query with using the Dbcontext object.
And this is the returns regarding the customer ID of the number of the greet, and we can return back
to the client application and this will be respond back to our Http get operation.
Here you can see the 200 okay response for related customer.
And these are the customer orders including the two orders in the response of these Http get method.
This is the first order and this is the second order related to our customer ID.
As you can see that we have successfully tested Http get methods for ordering microservices.