In this video, we are going to test the late order and paint with scratches and clean architecture.
That means we will send Http delete method in the slash order slash order id in order to delete order
with the ID for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering API and open the
Delete Order endpoint class and put the breakpoint in the beginning of the delegate handler, and put
the breakpoint at the end of the delegate handler, and this will be triggered.
Delete order command handler in the application layer.
For that purpose, go to Ordering Application Orders commands.
Delete order and open the delete order handler class and put the breakpoint in the beginning of the
handler method.
This will be interactive database and delete existing order from the SQL server database.
And now I'm going to test this delete order endpoint from the postman.
If you open the postman I have created http delete request in here.
So this is the endpoint of the ordering URL orders and this is the order ID that we are going to delete,
which is the last order id.
In the last video we have inserted new order.
So you can get this order ID from the http post or http put request in here you can see that last time
we have updated an order.
So you can copy this order ID and paste into the http delete request parameters.
And after that you can send http delete request to our application.
This will be hit the delete order end point class.
As you can see, that order id comes from the request parameters, which is the ID information.
And in here we will send the mediator delete order command.
With passing this ID this will be triggered.
Delete order 100 class in application layer and in the handle method.
First of all we will check these order exists or not.
If the order is not null, that means if the order is exist on database, we are going to remove this
order from the database.
And if I hit the F5 this will be triggered the dispatch domain events and this will be respond back
to the Or delete order response to the client application.
Here you can see the response is 200 okay.
And it is returning a success as a true response.
That means operation completed successfully.
If we open the Visual Studio and open the SQL Server Object Explorer.
If you go to orders and expand the views order, order data, you can see that we have created an order
ID in the last videos.
And if I refresh this page, you can see that the last order disappeared.
That means we have successfully delete our order with a given ID information.