In this video we are going to do cross-cutting concerns.
Especially we will develop custom exception handling in microservices.
In the last video we have tested the late order use case.
And if you look at the delayed order handler you can see that first of all, we will check that the
incoming order ID is exist or not into order DB database.
If not exist this is throwing order not found exception.
So I have tried these exception cases into our postman.
Here you can see that I have sent http delete method with non-existing ID information.
This is the response from the our API which is returning order not found exception.
But as you can see that it is not readable exception message and it is not manageable for understanding
the exception.
And it is also not formatted.
We cannot read which column is getting exception, and we cannot read in a Json format.
For that purpose, we should apply cross-cutting concerns and custom exception handling in the ordering
microservices.
So we have chosen to implement our custom exception handling in the building blocks.
As you remember that we are developing building blocks, and in the building blocks we have exception
folders and we have custom exception handler class.
In order to apply these exception handling for each microservices, if you open the custom exception
handling, you can see that this class encapsulate the logic for the handling different type of the
exceptions that the microservices might encounter.
So it is designed to catch exceptions, log them appropriately, and convert them into standardized
response format which is suitable for the API response.
So for that purpose, we will apply these custom exception in the ordering microservices.
If you go back to our delete order handler, you can see that we will throw order not found exception.
And if you go to exception details, you can see that this is inherited from the not found exception.
And these exception is located under the building blocks.
And we can see not found.
Exception is located custom exception handler.
Here you can see that we will populate the existing message name and status code will be returning.
Follow one not found.
So we will apply these custom exception handling in the ordering API.
So how we can do that?
Of course we should add the dependency injection services for the custom exception handling.
If you go to Program.cs we can add the dependency injection in here.
For the ordering API we will use add API services extension method.
If you right click and go to definition, you can see the Dependency injection class under the ordering
API layer.
In this class we can configure our application for the custom exception handling.
So first of all I'm going to start with the add API services.
At this point I am going to add services dot exception handler which is a custom exception handler and
which comes from the building blocks exception and handler namespace.
So with this line of code we will perform the adding or custom exception handling into dependency injection
container and making it available for use throughout the application.
And after that I am going to also adding use API services.
After the mapping.
Carter I am going to add that use exception handling and giving the empty options.
And with this line of code we set up the middleware for handling exceptions.
It configures the application to use the custom exception handling during the request pipeline.
So with adding these two line of code, we are activating custom exception handling for the ordering
microservices.
You can go on top of this and remove unnecessary using statement and save this file.
And now I am going to run this ordering API in https mode in order to activate custom exception handling.
After running the application, we can send http delete method with a wrong ID information and see.
This time the exception will be seem more formatted and more manageable way.
If I send again, you can see that this will be triggered or delete order endpoint.
If I hit F5, you can see that this will be comes to the if statement and enter the if statement and
throwing order not found exception.
And here you can see that this will be trigger our custom exception handling and return back as a Json
and formatted exception response to our API response.
We can see that the exception is returning 404 not found exception response to API and this is the title,
status, detail instance and trace ID is located more manageable and more readable.