In this video, we are going to develop health checks for ordering microservices with Entity Framework,
core and SQL server.
As you know that ordering microservices relying on the SQL server database.
So we should add a health check into ASP.Net core application using the Entity Framework core and SQL
server.
ASP.Net core provides middleware and libraries in order to implement health checks, and health checks
are exposed by an application as an Http.
Endpoints.
Health check endpoints can be configured for various real time monitoring scenarios.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And now we are going to implement health checks in ordering microservices.
If you open the program.cs of the ordering API layer, you can reach the point where we are adding services
into container.
For ordering API, we are using add API services and this is the dependency injection case under the
ordering API.
And here you can see that we are adding services into add API extension method.
In this method I am going to register the health check services in the application dependency container.
So in here I'm going to add a services dot add health checks method to adding health check related objects
into dependency injection.
And after that we should set up the middleware.
If you scroll down, if you go to the use API services, this is where we are configuring the Http lifecycle.
So I'm going to configure the middleware which is the app dot use health checks with exposing the health
endpoint.
In here you can see that we have added App.use health checks.
And this is the endpoint of the health.
So with these two line of code we can activate the health checks for ordering microservices.
So now we can run the ordering API in Https mode.
And after that we will hit the health endpoint and get the response from ordering microservices.
After running application you can open the postman.
And if you go to the ordering microservices postman collection, you can see that I have added get health
endpoint and this is the Http get and ordering URL and slash health that we can configure in the order
configuration dependency injection.
So I am going to hit the send button and hit the health endpoint to our ordering microservices.
And it is returning 200 okay.
And health response.
But this is only returning ordering microservice health check.
That means ASP.Net project.
But ordering microservices relying on the ordering database which is SQL server.
That's why we need to add some custom health check for SQL server.
So for that purpose, I'm going to check the SQL server database using the Entity Framework core Health
check libraries.
We can adding the custom health check.
But for SQL server there is already predefined health check libraries.
If you remember that we have mentioned a GitHub repository that includes every health checks for the
backing services.
Here you can see the name of the ASP.Net Core Diagnostic and Health checks.
If you search for the SQL server, you can go to the SQL server implementation of the health check.
And here you can see the NuGet packages for the SQL server implementation.
So that's why I'm going to copy these NuGet packages and open the R Visual Studio.
Right click the ordering API dependencies and manage NuGet packages.
Of course we should stop the application, right click manage NuGet packages and browse for the ASP.Net
Core Health checks and SQL server install these NuGet packages.
After that, we should also install UI client library in order to getting Json response.
For that purpose, I am going to browse ASP.Net Core Health Checks UI client library and install this
package.
So if you double click the ordering API, you can save the ordering API project file, and you can verify
that we have installed SQL server and UI client library from the ASP.Net Core Health checks.
So now we can configure SQL Server Health check in the dependency injection.
If you go to dependency injection of the ordering API and you can locate the services dot add health
checks method.
And I am going to modify this health check operation with adding the SQL server into the health checks.
Here you can see that we are using services dot add health checks.
And also we are using additional extension method which is the add SQL server extension method which
comes from the our newly added library.
And we are passing the connection string as a parameter of this extension method.
That means this.
Add a health check specifically for SQL server using the connection string from the configuration.
So that means we need to inject configuration as a parameter of this extension method.
For that purpose, I am going to come here and write I configuration and give the name as a configuration,
and we will use this configuration when adding SQL Server Health check into the health check codes.
Of course, we should add the configuration parameter into add API services when we are using in the
program says if you open the program says, you can see that this method is expecting configuration.
So I'm going to copy this builder config.
And facing these at API service extension method.
By this way, we can pass the configuration that we can access the configuration from the parameter
of these eight API services extension method.
And we will paste these configuration when we are adding a SQL Server health check with facing the database
connection string, and after registering Health check SQL server operations, we can configure the
health check for the UI related operations.
That means I am going to modify the use health checks condition in here.
When we are using the health checks we can configure this method.
So I'm going to come here and modify this configuration with adding the health check options.
Here you can see that I have added the new health check options and set the response writer with health
check UI response.
So this will configures the endpoint in order to return detailed health check responses in a readable
format and Json format.
So after configuring these health checks and adding health check related services into ASP.Net Dependency
Injection, we can run the application with https mode.
And now I am going to test health check with running order API application.
And after running the application we can open the our postman.
And now I am going to send http get method for the health endpoint.
And this time I have expected to return a Json format and including the SQL server.
Hit the send button and see that we have a Json response indicating that status is healthy and also
indicating the entities and SQL server is status is healthy.
So that means we have successfully configured our health checks, including ordering microservices and
SQL server databases.