In this section we are going to develop catalog API infrastructure handler and endpoint clusters for
performing Crud operations.
So we will explore and develop infrastructure related operations for performing data concerns on Catholic
API microservices.
And we will use Martinet Transactional DocumentDB for PostgreSQL database.
Martin will be at the DocumentDB on the PostgreSQL database, and we will use opening sessions, and
we will set up and run PostgreSQL database using the Docker compose files for Multi-container Docker
environment.
And we will develop products feature folders in vertical slice architecture with following the securities
design pattern and using the mediator library in the handler classes.
And after that we will develop endpoints classes with using the minimal APIs and Carter library.
And lastly we will test our product endpoints connecting to Docker environment on the PostgreSQL Docker
container.
So now let's get started.