In this video, we are going to explore the integration of database services with our microservices.
And specifically we will focus on our catalog API microservices.
And it is usage of the PostgreSQL database with using the Martin library.
Let's start by discussing the backing services in the realm of the microservices backing services for
the cloud.
Native microservices are the external resources or components that microservices, depending on their
operations they provide to support for various functionalities such as the data storage, messaging,
caching and authentication in a cloud native architecture.
Backing services like databases, messaging systems and caching services are treated as attached resources.
These backing services are located external to the microservices, and they can be swapped or replaced
without changing the microservices core logic.
In a cloud native microservice architecture, backing services are decoupled from the microservice themselves
and promoting the flexibility, scalability, and easier to maintenance.
So here you can see the illustration showing various backing services in a cloud native ecosystem.
As you can see that databases these are the NoSQL Newsql and relational databases.
Distributed caches, message brokers, event streaming systems, authentication authorization systems,
API gateways, service meshes, logging, monitoring, tracing, cross-cutting concerns, and so on.
All these services can be integrated with microservices and acting as a backing services.
They can be swapped or replaced without changing the microservice core logic during the course.
We will use these services as a backing services of issue of microservice applications.
If you look at our architecture, you can see that our catalog microservices rely on the PostgreSQL
database for database operations.
But catalog microservices is very good match for the NoSQL document databases.
So why we use PostgreSQL relational database for catalog operations and product operations even they
are more applicable with the NoSQL document database.
The answer is lies in the innovative approach.
In the PostgreSQL database, we use PostgreSQL Json object storage capabilities and transforming it
to the document database while maintaining the strong consistency so it is acting like as a naive SQL
database, providing both document database NoSQL features and strong consistency like the relational
databases.
So how we can do that?
Of course we will use Martin ORM library and we have already know what was the Martin Martin is a object
relational mapping library.
And this will use the PostgreSQL Json capabilities.
And Martin is a powerful library that transform the PostgreSQL into dotnet transactional document database.
It combines the flexibility of a document database with the reliability of the relational databases
and catalog microservices using Martin for PostgreSQL interaction as a document database.