In this video, we are going to learn opening sessions in Martin as a document database.
Martin's session is an interaction pattern for working with the documents stored in PostgreSQL database.
You can see the image on the slide.
I document store is the root of the Martin usage, but most of the Martin usage in the code will start
with one of these session types that can be created from an I document store.
So under the I document store there are different flavors of session and the root store.
So these are the query sessions that optimize for read only scenarios and document sessions that optimize
for the read and write scenarios.
So let me explain one by one.
The first one is query sessions.
These sessions is best used for querying documents without any need for the tracking or saving changes.
So under the document session for read and write operation, we can also use different type of the document
sessions.
Let me start the first one which is the identity map documentation.
Martin's I document session implement the identity map pattern that seeks to cache documents loaded
by ID.
This behavior can be very valuable, for example, in handling the web requests or service bus messages.
When many different objects or functions may need to access the same logical document.
The second type is lightweight document session.
It is suitable for small transactions with a mix of the read and write operations.
For operations that involve updates, inserts or deletes, we use a lightweight sessions.
It is still transactional but doesn't track the changes to the loaded document.
And the last one is dirty checking documentation.
This is the dirty checking document session in this case, and I document station opened with a dirty
checking enabled.
The session will try to detect the changes to any of the documents loaded by that session.
The dirty checking is done by keeping the original Json fetched from the PostgreSQL, and using the
Newtonsoft.json library that makes a node by node.
Comparison of the Json representation of the document at the time that I document session is called,
so you can find the image.
How we can create these kind of sessions from the Martin Document DB.
And here you can see that we can use a document store and dot notation to create query session.
Here you can see the query session and we can create lightweight sessions, identity sessions, dirty
tricks sessions and so on.
These provide to create sessions using the document store.
And here you can see the operations to perform read write operations or enable to identity map and dirty
checking functions.
So what is the best practice?
Best practice is understanding and choosing the right type of the session in Martin, which is crucial
for effective data handling in your applications.
Always aim to use the lightest session that meets your needs and ensure proper disposal of the sessions
in order to maintain the performance.
So we will use mostly lightweight session which is optimized for reading and writing operations.