In this video we are going to develop command handler class save to database operations with using the
Martin library.
So that means we will explore how to implement data persistence and infrastructure related operations
in our catalog microservices handler class using the Martin's documentation.
So we will use primary constructs in order to inject Martin classes into our handler class.
Martin managed the data using Trudu sessions.
You can see the image.
You can think that a session is a transactional unit of work that interacts with the database.
So that means we should use one of the session when interacting the PostgreSQL database using the Martin.
For that purpose, we will focus on the I document session performing the Crud operations.
We will directly inject these document session object to perform Crud operations.
And specifically we will use lightweight documentation.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And first of all we need to install Martin NuGet package in our project.
But before installing the new project, we should think about that.
This package is common for all microservices or not.
As you remember that when we are installing any packages, we are asking these questions ourselves.
If the package is common for all microservices, we will install this package into building Blocks class
library project.
If not, we will install the specific microservices that required the that library package.
So Martin is an ORM package that works on the PostgreSQL database.
And if we look at the our issue of microservices, you can see that only catalog and basket microservices
using the PostgreSQL database and discount and ordering microservices using different kind of microservices.
For example, ordering will be use Entity Framework core as a ORM, and SQLite can be used entity framework
code for the SQLite adapter.
So that means other microservices are not using Martin library and we should install Martin only required
microservices which are the catalog and basket microservices.
So go back to our Visual Studio and right click the Catholic API, manage NuGet packages and search
for the Martin.
Select Martin and install this package.
Okay.
If you double click the catalog API, you can verify that these Martin library is installed successfully
under our catalog API project.
So now it is time to injecting Martin AI documentation into our handler class to interact with the database
operation.
And for that reason we should go back to create product handler class.
And we will inject AI documentation directly into our command handler using the C sharp tools.
Primary constructor features.
This approach will be provide a clean way and direct way to interact with the database.
So now I'm going to injecting Martin AI documentation with adding in here open bracket and writing the
AI document session and give the parameter name as a session.
If you come here and click the add enter, we will using the Martin Library in order to inject the AI
document session.
So why we are directly injecting AI document session in here, and why we don't cover this session in
the repository folder or any data folder?
Because AI document session object is already an abstraction of the database operations.
So we don't need any additional abstractions or unnecessary code like repository patterns.
If you right click and go to definition, you can see that this is an interface.
And using an abstraction of the database operations with exposing these services.
So that means we will direct the injecting AI document session to perform database operations without
need for additional abstraction layer like repository patterns.
And also, personally, I don't like to use repository pattern if not necessary because it is very rare
to change the database or ORM system for any particular project.
So now let's perform our operation.
If you scroll down and come to this todo place, we basically using the session object and session has
store method in order to store our product information as a document database.
And after that of course we will use session dot save, change async method and passing the cancellation
token.
And of course we should paste the newly created product.
So this will be create a new product.
And in the result we will send a newly created product instead of the new grid operation.
If you right the product and go to id property, this ID will be generated from the document database.
Okay.
As you can see that we perform the handle method.
In this implementation, we basically create a product entity from the command.
And after that we will store this product into session.
And then we will perform asynchronously save operations into PostgreSQL database as a document object.
And this will be result in the product being persisted in our PostgreSQL database and returning the
ID information to the client.
So if you go on top of this implementation, you can see that we have different using statements.
And in order to organize these using statements we have already create global using.
So I'm going to adding these using statement including the Martin moving to global using statements
and passing in here.
And if we put the global on top of these statements and making it more readable.
So see that these are the packages that we are using in the catalog microservices.
If you go back to our handler class and remove all using statements, you can see that this code is
more cleaner.
And this is the are handler implementation.