In this video, we are going to register and configure Martin Document Database into Program.cs.
Because before use the Martin, it is crucial to register and configure it correctly in our ASP.Net
core applications in order to connect PostgreSQL database from our microservices.
So for that purpose, please go to Program.cs.
Locate to add services to the container part, which is adding Martin related packages into within dependency
Injection.
And we are following the same syntax which is the builder services.
And we will use add Martin extension method.
And we will configure this Martin with the options.
I'm going to write a delegate method for configuration.
And here you can see that the options is requiring for the connection string.
And in connection we will provide a connection string from the application settings Json.
For that purpose I'm passing builder dot configuration dot get connection string and give the connection
string name as a database.
So we will provide these information at the end of this video.
And let's put these configuration in here.
Because in order to connect the PostgreSQL database, Martin required a connection string for the PostgreSQL
database that we provide and configure in here.
And after that we should customize the Martin sessions with using different session operations.
You can see that if I write the use keyword, we can use dirty tracked sessions, identity sessions,
and lightweight sessions.
As we explained before, I'm going to use lightweight sessions to perform our Crud operations.
And here you can see the Our Martin configuration.
In here we use Add Martin extension method to configure the connection to our PostgreSQL database.
And we use lightweight sessions for performance.
Also, at this point I would like to show one of the Martin's features.
If you write the configuration and search for the auto create schema objects, if you right click and
go to definition, you can see that Martin using auto create operation for create or update.
So that means Martin attempt to create any missing database schema object at the runtime.
This property is create or update by default for more efficient in the development phase, but it can
be set lower values for the production usage.
Go back to our Program.cs and remove these property.
And now it is time to configure database connection string in application settings Json file.
If you come here, you can see that application settings Json file located under the catalog API.
And now I am going to add a connection string in here.
So if you come to at the beginning of the this Json file and write the connection string sections and
add the database connection string as a database name.
So this connection string representing our PostgreSQL database that we will be keeping up in the Docker
environment.
But for now let's copy and paste this database connection string and we will connect after running this
PostgreSQL container on our Docker environment.
So we have specified the connection string.
And this will be retrieving from our Program.cs when configuring the Martin as a connection string.
So we have successfully registered and configured Martin Library into our catalog microservices to interact
with the PostgreSQL database as a document database and leveraging the Martin's capabilities.