In this video, we are going to learn the deployment strategy for our e-commerce microservices, particularly
focusing on setting up the PostgreSQL database using Docker Compose.
Here you can see the recap architecture that contains different databases and different microservices.
So in here catalog microservices using the PostgreSQL database as a backing services.
And we will adding the Redis, SQLite, SQL server, RabbitMQ and so on.
So far we have built on catalog microservices into our local environment.
But now we need to connect to database and we need a database IP and port number that we can connect
from our local computer.
So we should download the PostgreSQL Docker image and run this image into our Docker compose environment.
By this way we can connect the database from our catalog microservices.
But before that we should clarify our deployment strategy of e-commerce microservices.
Here you can see the image on the slide.
Our deployment strategy has two main steps.
The first one is local development with Docker compose for backing services, and the second one is
full Docker environment and orchestration, all microservice and databases.
So let me explain one by one, in the first phase of our deployment strategy, we focus on local microservices
development.
After that, we use Docker compose in order to spin up backing services like databases which are exposed
to our local environment.
So this setup allows us to develop and test microservices locally while connecting to containerized
backing services.
In this case, catalog using PostgreSQL database as a backing services.
So we will develop microservices locally and after that activate backing services using Docker and Docker
Compose.
If we go to the second phase of the deployment strategy, which is the Docker compose, all including
microservices and backing services in the Docker environment.
So the second phase involves orchestrating all microservices, including their dependencies within a
Docker compose environment.
This is a comprehensive setup, simulates a more production like environment allowing for through end
to end testing.
So we should orchestrate all microservices with Docker compose and test inside of the full Docker environment
with end to end perspective.
And after that we can add additional deployment strategy, which include deploy all microservices to
the Kubernetes Minikube or cloud EKS, and so on.
But during the course we will focus on these two steps.
So now let's focus on the setting up the PostgreSQL database for catalog microservices using the Docker
compose.