In this video we are going to set up PostgreSQL database using the docker compose file for multi-container
Docker environment.
So now we will download and run the PostgreSQL Docker image into Docker environment.
As you can see the image, we will expose the ports into our local microservices and connect this port
from our local Catholic microservices.
So first of all, let's examine the official PostgreSQL Docker image on the crop.
If you go to the PostgreSQL Docker image from the opticom, you can reach the this page and you will
find the information on how to pull and how to run the PostgreSQL Docker image.
If you scroll down, you will see that.
There are two options that we can download and run these PostgreSQL Docker images.
The first option is directly using the Docker commands with running the docker run command, and the
second option is using the docker compose, which is our preferred method for this course.
Because docker compose allows us to define and run multi-container Docker applications, and it is ideal
for setting up the environments like ours, where the microservices interact with backing services like
databases.
So you can see an example Docker-compose.yml file for setting up the PostgreSQL that we can use this
kind of information into our Docker compose file.
You can see that this is the configuration of database providing the image restart and environment configurations.
And we will use these kind of configurations into our docker-compose.yml file.
So please open the Visual Studio and locate the.
Our project DotNet has great support for Docker and Docker Compose on Visual Studio.
So you can see the Docker file already created for our catalog API.
If you zoom into our project, you can see that Docker file is already generated when we are creating
catalog microservice web API project.
If you double click the docker file, you can see the configuration on Docker.
So that means our ASP.Net web API project, already containerized from the beginning of the project.
For now, skip the microservice point and focus on the backing services, which is the PostgreSQL database.
For that purpose, locate the catalog API project file.
Right click Add container orchestration support.
As you can see that we have two support one for the Docker support to create the Docker file, which
is already created when we are creating these web API.
And another support is container orchestration support that we are going to create the docker compose
Yaml files.
Click these Docker container orchestration support and you can see that container orchestrator is Docker
compose and click the okay button.
Target operating system should be Linux and click the okay.
And see that Docker compose files generated by the Visual Studio.
You can also create these files manually, but if we create with using the Visual Studio, we can run
the whole application on Docker environment and on Docker compose files.
You can see that in here we have a new running profile comes which is the Docker compose.
That is very powerful feature that we can debug the microservices inside of the docker compose multi-container
environment in the network.
So this is one of the powerful features of the.
Net and Visual Studio.
And now let's examine these Docker compose Yaml files.
If you expand this Docker compose operation, you can see the docker compose Yaml file and override
Yaml file.
If you double click the docker-compose.yml file, you can see that our Catholic API microservices already
stored into our Docker compose file.
And if you open the override file, you can see that catalog API overriding configurations in the listing
in here, which is including the environment variables, port numbers, and volumes.
So if you open the our PowerPoint, you can see that we can use multi Docker compose files in order
to configure different environments including the production, staging and testing environments.
So now it is time to add PostgreSQL database container into our Docker compose Yaml files.