In this video we are going to add PostgreSQL database image into docker compose file for multi-container
docker environment.
So that means we will follow the deployment one, and we will set up the PostgreSQL as a backing services
for our catalog microservices using the Docker compose.
Here you can see the image how our catalog microservices connects to PostgreSQL database within the
Docker environment and our catalog microservices requiring the PostgreSQL database.
And now I am going to show an example Docker compose yaml and override file.
If you open the GitHub and go to one of my previous microservice application repository, you can scroll
down and open the docker-compose.yml file.
We can see that there is multiple services, including databases on message brokers are defined in the
docker-compose.yml file.
And if you select the override Yaml file in here, you can see that how these microservices and backing
services configure and set the port numbers, set the environment variables and so on.
So we will follow the same steps when we are developing our application as a backing services for that
purpose, open the Visual Studio and open the Docker-compose.yml file which is located under the docker
compose root file.
So we will edit the docker compose and overwrite Yaml file when configuring PostgreSQL as a backing
services.
So according to this we will set up the backing services databases message brokers on top of these docker
compose Yaml file.
So now let's modify our docker-compose.yml file.
So we will modify this Yaml file to include PostgreSQL database services for catalog microservice says.
Here you can see that there is already existing catalog microservice API project.
But for now I'm going to remove these services because we will run these microservice from locally and
connect to our database as a backing services for that purpose.
I'm going to start with the backing services into our docker-compose.yml file.
So I'm first of all we are giving the name as a catalog DB.
And after that I'm providing only image name into this docker compose file.
So here you can see that we have added PostgreSQL database.
And the indentation and space character is very very important in here.
If you are not following the same structure for the services and image property with nested style,
this will be getting exception.
So that's why.
Please be careful about the indentation.
After defining our catalog db, we should not forget to adding the volume definition for PostgreSQL
data and volumes should be the same level with the services, and under the volumes we can give the.
Postgres catalog volume information and this will be regarding with this catalog.
DB.
Okay, now let's configure our Docker compose override HTML file.
The docker compose file is enough for this information.
We only specify the image name and we will give additional configurations in the docker compose override
yaml file.
So where this get this kind of configurations.
As.
You remember that in the official docker compose documentation, we have already seen the how to define
this database in the docker-compose.yml file.
So if we go back to our Visual Studio now we will configure the docker compose override HTML file.
Double click this file.
In this override Yaml file, we generally set up the environment variables, port mappings, and volume
mappings for our PostgreSQL services or any kind of the services that we define in the docker compose
file.
So as you can see that there is already defined for catalog API microservices.
Since we are following the deployment, one strategy, we will remove the microservices to run from
the local.
We will focus on the our backing services which will be the our catalog DB PostgreSQL database.
For that purpose I'm going to define this catalog DB configurations.
You can see that we have started with the catalog DB, and this name should be matched from the docker
compose file which the under the services catalog db.
So in the docker compose file we only specify the image name.
But in the override file we have specified additional configurations, including the container name
we will give as a container name catalog db, and after that we will define the PostgreSQL service with
environment variables for user password and database.
So you can see the user Postgres and password Postgres and db as a catalog db, and we can specify the
restart always.
This will be spin up if there is any problem in the our container.
And you can see that we have exposed the port numbers which will be the current port number for PostgreSQL,
and we will redirecting the same port number to our local environment.
And after that we have give and define volume definition and volume name should be comes from the docker-compose.yml
file which name is Postgres catalog.
So please write this configuration into your overall HTML file and save this file and make sure that
you have.
Be careful about the indentation about this configuration, because if there is a problem with the indentation,
this will not be work.
After defining the PostgreSQL override configuration, we should also configure connection string according
to these username, password and database configuration values.
So if you go to the application settings Json file, you can compare with the database connection string
with the docker compose override HTML file.
The server name should be localhost and the port number should be 5432.
This will be PostgreSQL port number that we have exposed for the host port number from the container
port number.
So after that database, as you can see that we use catalog db and you can see the database information
from the environment variables.
And after that user ID is Postgres and password is Postgres.
You can see that these are injecting as an environment variable into PostgreSQL database.
And lastly we give include error details as true for development purpose.
So that means these connection settings are prepared from our Docker compose HTML file for PostgreSQL
database.