In this video we are going to run Docker Compose running Profile on Visual Studio to set up the PostgreSQL
database on Docker.
So for that purpose, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running and you can see this green
box in here.
So after that please open the Visual Studio.
And you can see that we have developed Docker compose and overwrite files with configuring the setup
PostgreSQL database.
And here you can see that there is a new running profile which is the Docker compose that we can click
these Docker compose run profile in order to activate these PostgreSQL Docker image into Docker environment.
But this is not only one option to running the docker compose with using this button.
Actually, most of the time we can use Docker commands to activate this docker compose environment.
We can run the docker compose up command to running these containers under the docker compose file.
But since we are developing our microservices using the Visual Studio, Visual Studio has a great experience
with Docker Compose.
For that purpose, I am going to use docker compose running file, and it is also able to debug our
codes in the docker environment.
Even we are running the docker compose.
That is very great feature.
So for that purpose please click this button.
And on behind of the scenes.
As you can see that this button will be run docker compose up command for us.
And this will be retrieving container from the Docker Hub and configure our container with these configurations
and activate PostgreSQL database to our Docker environment.
So you can follow the output windows.
And you can see the logs from the containers.
And you can see that our catalog DB is activated.
And this is so fast for me because I have already pulled this image before.
And you can verify from the Docker desktop.
If you open the Docker desktop and go to containers, you can see that our Docker compose is running.
And under the docker compose root file you can see the catalog db as a PostgreSQL image is running and
activated.
And if you go to the images, you can see that Postgres image is downloaded before creating the container.
And if you go to the volumes, you can see that we have defined one volumes, which is defined under
our Docker-compose.yml file, which name is PostgreSQL catalog.
So we have verified that our container is running successfully.
Now how we can interact these PostgreSQL database.
So in order to interact with these PostgreSQL database we will use Docker commands to access the containers,
bash shell scripts and connect to the database using the SQL command line interface.
So for that purpose I'm going to open a command window.
And in this command window I'm going to run the Docker ps.
And this will be listing running containers on our machine.
Here you can see the our PostgreSQL database running as a container ID in here.
So after that we are going to run the Execute Interactive terminal with bash script.
For that purpose I'm going to run Docker.
Exec interactive terminal and I'm going to paste the container ID right.
Copy this container ID paste in here and let's start with the bash script.
Hit the enter.
So now we have connected the container bash script.
And now I'm going to connect the database PostgreSQL database.
For that purpose we are running the SQL script dash u and give the name Postgres and hit enter.
So now inside the PostgreSQL shell script we can list available databases.
So our docker compose overwrite HTML file, specifies the environment variables for our PostgreSQL database,
and we will see that the database name are catalog db.
You can verify from in here.
So now let's listing existing databases into our PostgreSQL.
For that purpose I'm going to make it backslash and L.
And here you can see the catalog DB is listing under our database.
So that means catalog DB is created by Postgres with using the docker compose overwrite file in the
environment variables.
So now our database is ready.
So if you go back with the exit.
And now I'm going to also would like to connect this database for backslash and give the database name
as a catalog DB.
And now we have connected to our database.
In order to see the tables we can write the backslash D and see that there is no tables created into
our database.
That means we see the catalog DB is created, but catalog DB not containing any table yet.
How we can configure these tables when we are running this application Martin will handle this.
Create operation of tables and schema objects based on our application models.
When the application start up.
As you know that Martin is a ORM system and will be connect to PostgreSQL database when the application
start up, you can remember that we have one configuration.
If schema is not defined, this will be create by the Martin.
So there is no need to manually create database and tables in PostgreSQL database, as Martin will automatically
generate the required database and tables based on our application need that we have already configured
in the Program.cs.
So we can say that we have successfully run our Docker container, and we see that our backing services
PostgreSQL database is up and running on our Docker environment.