In this video we are going to connect to PostgreSQL database from our local catalog microservices,
and we will send Http post requests in order to create new product in the catalog db PostgreSQL database.
So in the last video we have activated our PostgreSQL database.
And you can see the containers under the Docker desktop.
And if you scroll to the right hand side you can see the port numbers are exposed in here.
So according to our Docker compose override configuration, the catalog db PostgreSQL is exposing in
localhost 5432 ports.
So you can verify from the our docker compose or write file.
We have already expose this port number, and we can verify these port numbers from the our Docker desktop.
And according to this we will check our catalog API microservices and our catalog microservices will
connect the PostgreSQL database using the connection string in the application Settings.json file.
If you double click this Json file, you can verify that the server is localhost and port number is
this one, and this will be match our port number and exposing server name into Docker Desktop.
So we have verified the connection string.
Now we will run this catalog API microservices and integrate with the PostgreSQL database.
Before that make sure that you are putting breakpoints under the create product endpoint and after the
create product handler methods, in order to debug the whole end to end process of the create product
http post request and after verify the breakpoints, we can run this application in https mode.
That means I'm going to right click the catalog API microservice, set a startup project and change
the Https running profile and run this application.
So that means we are going to run our catalog microservices in local environment, and we are going
to connect and communicate PostgreSQL database in the environment as a backing services.
So if you go back to our Visual Studio, we can verify that our application is successfully started.
And you can open the Project console window.
And this is listening on https localhost 5050.
So now we can send http post request to create a new product.
We will use postman to send an http post request.
Please open the postman.
Set a new request I have already prepared before in the previous videos.
Make sure that you are sending http post request and the URL should be localhost 5050.
And make sure that you have added products in the Uri.
And if you go to the body raw Json file and make sure that you are sending this kind of Json in order
to create a new product onto PostgreSQL database and click the Http send button.
As you can see that this is hit the breakpoint which is.
The endpoints accommodate the incoming requests, and if you continue this process, mediator will be
sent to our command into handler class.
In the handler class we have created a new product and after that we will use Martin session in order
to store product into our PostgreSQL database.
Martin will be checking the database.
If there is no table with regarding the products, this will be create product table and schema and
this will be auto create this process with Martin.
This is powerful feature and we will use this feature when connecting to PostgreSQL database using the
Martin.
So if you continue this line of code this will be waiting and creating a new product table on the PostgreSQL.
And after that this will be saved to database and hit the F5 and see the response.
So after sending the request you can see the response coming.
In this way you should receive any product ID in return.
This indicates that our microservices has successfully communicate with the PostgreSQL database and
create a new product record.
Now let's connect the PostgreSQL container and verify the new product entry is created for that purpose.
Open the our command window.
As you remember that we have connected our container, which is the Postgres container, and open a
bash script.
And after that we run the SQL dash u PostgreSQL in order to reach the database.
And after that we will listing the our databases and see that catalog DB is including.
And you can verify again from the listing databases and see that our catalog DB is created.
And after that we can now connect to database and see the tables that are created.
And for that purpose I'm going to connect with backslash C and catalog DB.
Now I have connected the catalog DB into our PostgreSQL database.
Now we can backslash D listing the tables.
Last time we didn't see any tables, but this time you can see that empty dot product table is created
by Martin and it is automatically created when session is adding and storing new item into the database.
So this is very powerful feature from the Martin.
And now we can run the select star from this table to see is there any record on this table.
And please write this command and hit the enter.
As you can see that newly created ID and product is listing into our database.
You can verify the ID numbers is exactly the same with value, with listing from the database table
and from response to the R postman request.
As you can see that we have verified the newly created product data on PostgreSQL database and we have
successfully connect, debug and test it our local catalog, microservices and database on Docker environment.
By the way, this is very a hard way to retrieve data and running the SQL commands on the PostgreSQL
using the command window instead of that.
From now on we will install pgadmin four.
Please go to this URL and download pgadmin four according to your operating system, and we will use
pgadmin four when browsing PostgreSQL database tables and records.