In this video, we are going to continue to develop other Rest API endpoints for our catalog microservices.
And specifically we will focus on developing Get products feature in vertical slice architecture using
the Securities and Mediator library.
And we will create an endpoint and handler classes to exposing these products endpoint and accommodating
Http get method and listing all products for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And after that I'm going to create a new folder.
Which name is Get products under the are products feature folder.
If you come here and you can zoom into the solution window, you can see that we have already completed
created product feature folder.
Now I'm going to add a new feature folder.
Which name is Get Products.
So right click Add New folder.
Which name is Get products.
This will be the R feature folder for the vertical slice architecture, and under the getproducts we
will add two classes into this folder, which is one for the endpoint and another for the handler.
So I'm going to add a Getproducts endpoint class.
And this is the C sharp class that will handle for the API endpoints.
And after that I'm going to add the additional class which name is Getproducts handler class.
And this is for handling the query operations implementing SQS using the mediator.
So here you can see that every feature folder have two classes.
And now we are going to implement one by one.
If we remember the flow of the request through our system using the actors and mediator, we basically
accommodate the incoming Http get method into our endpoint classes.
And these request object will be mapping to the query object.
And after that passing to mediator sender method.
In order to trigger to query handler class.
And in the query handler class, we perform database operations and return back to a result.
And lastly, we will map these result to the response object and return the response to the client application.
So first of all we will develop with the handler class.
And in the handler class we will develop query and result record types.
For that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to Getproducts handler class.
And in here I'm going to create two record type one for the Getproducts query.
Let me write first public record Getproducts query and this should be inherit from the I query and we
should get response which name is Getproduct result.
And in the next record type we have to define our Getproduct result.
For that purpose, I'm going to write again public record Getproduct result.
And we would like to passing I enumerable I mean returning the enumerable product response.
And here you can see that we are returning the products from our result object.
These record types represent to request for fetching products and the structure of the data that we
expect to return.
So now let's develop the our actual Getproducts handler class.
This class is responsible for handling the Getproducts query and returning to the Getproduct result.
The first thing we should do is changing the class name.
Here you can see the Getproducts under.
I'm changing Getproducts query under.
So it is best practice to separate query and commands in the names of the class, and this will be Getproducts
query handler.
And we can understand what we will do in the handle method.
After that I'm going to changing the access modifier as a internal.
And first of all, let's implement from the I query handler class.
And in the query handler as a request we will explain get products query.
And as a response we will return get products result.
So here you can see that we will inherit from the equator handler.
So I'm going to implement these equate handler members.
And here you can see the handle method comes into our Getproducts query handler.
So in the handler module we will perform our actual logic.
In order to perform our actual logic we will inject some kind of classes.
So let me inject a document session.
This is comes from the Martin.
And after that I would like to also inject a logger in order to put logs into our class.
So basically you can see that we have injected two items in here.
And the first one is Martin and the second one is logger.
Now we are going to use these operations into our handle method.
In the first row I'm going to put a log and logging the information about hitting this handle method
in the query handler.
And after that we will get the products from the database.
That's why define a products variable and using the session dot query method.
And in this method I'm going to expecting the product documents.
And we can use to list async method and passing the cancellation token.
And after that we will return new get product and passing the products.
So in this handler class, we basically use AI documentation from the Martin in order to query the products
documents.
And this handle method is accepting the our get products query request.
And in here this should be as a query.
I'm going to change the name of the query in here.
So please change the incoming parameter name as a query.
Even we don't use any query object because this is the get all products and we don't any filter operation
in the query.
But the idea is that naming is important and separate the query and commands.
And after that, this method handle the asynchronous fetch all the products and return them to the get
product result.