In this video, we are going to develop Getproducts endpoint class with using minimal APIs and Carter.
So we will build Http get method endpoint for our catalog microservices to retrieve the product listing
and using the Carter library along with the mediator pattern.
So please open the Visual Studio and this time locate the Getproducts endpoint class.
So in this class we will develop our request and response object.
Since we are developing an Http get endpoint, our request doesn't require a Json input.
However, we will define a response record structure in order to return with data.
So for that purpose I'm coming in here and I'm going to put a command at request object to make it best
practices.
We should always define request and response in the endpoint and always define query or command and
result in the handler class.
So for that purpose I'm going to follow the best practice and put a command in here.
We don't required any request object but we will see in here.
And after that I'm going to define public record Getproduct response object.
And this will be including IEnumerable products that we have already defined in the result.
So this will be response object.
We have finished the request and response object.
And now we will develop the Getproducts endpoint class.
We will use Carter to create our Get endpoint.
Carter simplifies the definition and configuration of routes in ASP.Net core.
So as you remember that we have already installed Carter into our catalog microservices.
If you double click the project file, you can verify that Carter is located into our dependencies and
libraries.
And if you go to the program says, you can also verify that we have injected the Carter packages and
we have added the services into built in dependency injection.
And we have already configured Http request pipeline for Carter libraries.
That means we can use Carter into our Getproducts endpoint directly.
And I'm going to define this class inherit from the I Carter module.
So once we are inherit from the I Carter model it is indicating to implement interface member which
is the add routes.
So now in this method we will exposing Http get method and define the get endpoint using the I Carter
module.
This interface allows us to implement routes Greenway.
So now in here you can see that we will implement actual logic with using the app dot map get method.
And in here I will provide the product's Uri.
And in the delegate handle method we basically handle the async method.
And I'm going to inject Isander which comes from the mediator.
And here you can see the delegate handle method that we are going to implement when we are exposing
slash products http get method.
In this method, we basically get the result from the mediator.
I'm going to use standard dot send method and passing the new query object, which is the get Getproducts
query object.
Here you can see the object and it doesn't get any parameter because we will retrieve all products.
So after getting response from the mediator, we can convert our response type from the mediator handler
class, which will be our result object.
And we will adapt this result object to the get product response object.
Okay to use Napster in that way.
That means we can directly pass result object to do our response object.
The parameters and parameter names should be exact name.
So if you look at the Getproducts response, it is getting a parameter which name is enumerable product
and the parameter name is products.
If you go to the get products handler, the result should be the same structure and see that this is
getting exactly same parameter and parameter name is the same.
By this way, Napster can be adapted without any further configuration.
Okay, we have completed our actual operation and after getting the response, we can return these response
into results.
Dot okay, and passing the response object to the client.
After defining any Http method with Carter, we can define additional configurations including the width
name produced and produce problem summary and description.
Here you can see that we have.
Give the name as a Getproducts.
Submit and description and produce 200 okay response with sending the results.
Okay.
And if there is any problem we can return back such as 400 bad request.
So this will be complete the http get request.
So if you go on top of this page you can see that there is no any using statement because all using
stated related classes will already including our global using.
So we don't need any using statement in this class and it makes it more cleaner.
As you can see that we have defined an Http get endpoint for products URL, and we use mediator Isander
in order to send get products query and get back the results.
And adapting these results to the Get products response object which is returned to the client application.