In this video, we are going to test the Getproducts endpoint of our catalog microservices, which is
connected to a PostgreSQL database running in a Docker container.
So we are in here and we will test these http get method.
If you remember the our microservice deployment strategy, our deployment strategy is involving testing
local microservices with the containerized database on Docker.
So we will follow the first strategy when testing our Getproducts in this video.
So first of all we need to ensure our PostgreSQL database is running within the Docker.
So if we open the our Visual Studio you can remember that we will develop the Docker compose yml file.
Adding the PostgreSQL image and docker compose override file.
We will specify the configurations.
Now we will ensure that our PostgreSQL database is running within Docker.
So how we can do that.
This will be achieved by running the Docker compose from the Visual Studio.
And we will spin up catalog microservice databases.
Before we start, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running and you will see this green box.
And after that we will activate and running this catalog DB container.
For that purpose, I'm going to right click the Docker compose and set a start up project.
This means that we will run the docker compose up command using the Visual Studio two link in order
to activate our database.
So here you can see that our running profile has changed.
And please run this project in a Docker compose profile.
And this will be running the PostgreSQL container in our Docker environment.
And on behind of the scenes this will be running the docker compose up command specifying this override
and this file.
So after running this docker compose you can open the.
Look at desktop and verify that Docker compose is running.
And under this docker compose we have started the PostgreSQL database into the port number is 5432.
So we have verified that our backing services are working perfectly now and the port numbers is in here.
So if you open the application settings Json file, we can verify that our connection string is correct.
And we are going to communicate with the PostgreSQL catalog DB database in order to getting the products
from the database using the catalog API.
Microservices.
Now we can start our test which is the Catholic API microservices http get method for that purpose.
Now I am going to right click the catalog API and set a startup project.
And I'm going to run this catalog API project in an Https mode.
Before running the our microservices, make sure that you put the breakpoints in the Getproducts endpoint,
which is the starting point, incoming request and also Getproducts handle method which is the handle
method and communicate with database.
So now we are ready for the running these catalog API in a https mode.
And after that you can see that our project and microservice started in localhost 5050.
And you can verify from the project console and listening on 5050.
That means it is ready for the according request from the our postman.
So in order to send http get method, I'm going to use postman.
Last time we will use http post request.
Now I am going to change this http get method and the url is https localhost 5050 and products.
If you hit the send button, you can see that our breakpoint is comes to our get products endpoint requests.
And if we put to F10 and continue the debug operations, the first row is we are sending the get products
query.
And this mediator will be triggered to our handler class with this query object.
Here you can see that our handle method is triggered.
The first row we have logging the information and the second row is communicating this database PostgreSQL
database and listing all products into our document database which is the catalog DB.
And here you can see the products is comes and you can see the product count is one.
Because we have already created one product before when we are developing our Http post request.
And if you continue debugging, you can see that we have adapting the result object to the response
object.
And after that we will send this response to the client.
So hit the F5 and see the response in the our postman.
And you can see that our products are listed in the response of Http get method.
So by testing our catalog API with a Dockerized PostgreSQL database, we have validated the connectivity
and functionality of our microservices.