In this video we are going to create postman collections for each of microservices.
So we will create a comprehensive postman collection for interacting with and testing our microservices
or Itiel project consists of several microservices, including catalog basket, discount and ordering
microservices that we will develop during the course, and each service has its own set of use case
and exposing specific endpoints.
For example, if you look at the catalog microservices here, you can see the Http get, post, put
and delete endpoints for performing these use cases.
So if you go back to our port numbers, each microservice is representing and exposing their APIs in
different port numbers.
So that means we have assigned different port numbers for each microservices.
And these port numbers differs between the local environment and the Docker environment.
And if you look at the our deployment strategy, this will be aligned our port numbers we have divided
by two.
The first deployment strategy is local environment where microservices run locally and connect to containerized
backing services with Docker containers.
And in the deployment tool strategy, both microservices and backing services are orchestrated using
the Docker compose.
So we will simulate these environments into our postman collection and exposing our API endpoint port
numbers according to environment variables.
So for that purpose, postman has collection feature that is very great fit for this kind of implementation
and API definition.
If you open the postman, you can see that we have created an additional Http port and guest endpoints,
and we will specify the whole http uri.
And once we deploy this catalog microservice to Docker environment, we have to change this port number
manually.
And adapting into Docker environment.
Instead of that we will use postman great features which is the postman collections and environments.
So we will create collections and environments.
In order to manage our microservice requests.
We can set the port numbers as a variables and allowing us to switch between the local and Docker environment
seamlessly in here.
Now we are going to start by defining and setting up our environment in postman.
Go to the environments and if you expand these environments, you can see that we can put these plus
button in order to create new environment.
In this window, we will change the environment name as a localhost.
And we will also create a new environment which name is Docker.
So by this way we can represent and aligning with deployment strategy and select the localhost environment.
And under the localhost environments we can define variables.
So which variables we will define.
We will define microservice URL variables in here.
For example let me start with catalog URL.
And we can give the value for according to our microservice local environment endpoints and the port
numbers.
So after that we will set the Docker environments.
So for the catalog microservices in local environment we should give the 50 over 50 for that purpose.
I'm going to write localhost 5050 in here and the current value should be the same.
And if you continue with the next microservices which is the basket URL and basket URL should be the
5051 and the current value should be 5051.
And if you continue the next microservices, we will see keeping the discount microservices.
Since discount will be exposing APIs in gRPC protocol, we will set these discount gRPC endpoints with
differently.
So let's continue with the ordering microservices that exposing our local environment 5053 and 6063
for Docker.
So come here and write for the ordering URL.
And in here I'm going to give the name as a value should be localhost 5053.
And the current value should be the same.
At this stage.
Please don't forget to save this file, because without saving this file, this will not reflecting.
Save this file and remove this orange box and save this file.
Okay.
So we have successfully saved our localhost environment and variables.
And please go to the Docker environment.
And we will follow the same steps for the Docker environment.
Set the variable name as a catalog URL in the environment.
We will follow the 6060 port.
For that purpose.
I'm going to write https 66 port and the current value should be.
The same, and after that we will be basket Earl and the initial value should be 6061 and the current
value will be the same.
And ordering.
Earl.
Will be 6063 and the current value will be the same.
And make sure that you also save this file.
Okay, now we have two environments that we can use when we are dynamically change the port number by
changing the postman environments.
So you can see that environments are listing in here.
And you can select the environment and select this button.
And you can see the variables also set in here.
Now we will create a new postman collection for our microservices.
Within this collection we will add sub collections for each microservices.
So for that purpose please open the collections by clicking this button and click this plus button in
order to create new collection and give the name as a microservices.
This will be the our microservices root collection.
And under this collection we will create separate folders for each microservices.
Because if you look at the our microservices, each microservices can be exposed different Http methods
to perform their business cases.
Here you can see that catalog microservices will be exposed three Http get method.
In order to perform these use cases and some Http post, put and delete methods to perform Crud operations,
I am going to create a new sub collections with clicking this button and adding folder.
And this folder name should be the our microservices.
This will be the catalog.
And if I'm going to add a new folder, this will be the basket.
And let me add a new folder for the discount.
And I'm going to add a new folder for the ordering.
Okay.
These folders will be represent our microservices and include microservice exposing APIs.
Now we will focus on the catalog microservices.
And I am going to add a new request under this folder.
And this will be representing our Get catalog operation.
As you remember that in the Get catalog operation we will use https localhost 5050 and products.
So for now I am going to use environment variable names instead of these request URL.
For that purpose I'm going to put a double curly bracket.
And here you can see that our variables already come in here and select these catalog URL.
And if you hover this URL you can see the initial and current value will be set localhost 5050.
Because we can see that the current environment is localhost.
If we change the environment as a docker, and if you go to the catalog URL, you can see that the initial
and current value has changed as a 6060.
So by this way we can easily switch the environments and change the environment request Uri according
to our deployment strategy.
So let me set the environment as a localhost and prepare our http get method and save this method.
And this will be represent our get catalog operation.
Let's test this Http get method for that purpose.
Open the Visual Studio and run our application as a catalog API, https and run without debugging.
Because we only test our endpoint from the postman, open the postman and send the http get request.
And here you can see that we have listed the products successfully.
So our http get method is successfully prepared.
And during the whole course we will be adding new endpoints as we develop microservices one by one.
By the way, you don't have to develop postman collection like me in here.
We will also put these postman collection into our GitHub repository.
If you go to this GitHub repository, the full postman collection will be stored into our repository
and available on GitHub.
And also I will add these postman collection into downloadable resources of the Udemy lecture resources.
So once you get these postman collection, you can click the import button and drag and drop these file,
and you will reach the latest endpoints for each microservices in here.