In this video, we are going to develop Getproduct by ID feature in our catalog microservices using
this access pattern and mediator library.
So we will create a new folder as a vertical slice, which is the getproduct by ID.
And in this vertical folder we will create two classes, one for the handler and another for the endpoint
that we will define these request lifecycle using the mediator library and following this pattern,
please open the Visual Studio and go to the Products feature folder.
And you can right click and add new subfolder which will be the Our Vertical Slice architecture get
product by ID feature.
So under this folder we will create two classes one for the handler, another for the endpoint.
So let's right click and add new class which name is get product by ID handler.
And another class will be the get product by id and point.
So basically this folder will contain all necessary classes for our feature.
And we have followed the vertical slice architecture.
Let me start to develop our query and result record types.
For that purpose I'm going to define public record and get products by ID query.
And this query this time get we get a parameter which name is with id and inherit from the I query interface,
which will be the A result object returning the get product by ID result.
And if we continue with the public record, get product by ID result, this will be returned a specific
product with a given ID information.
So we have finished the development of the query and result record types.
So now we will implement Getproduct by id query handler class.
This class is responsible for handling the query object and interacting with the database and returning
the result object.
So if you open the Visual Studio and this time we will create an actual handler class.
First of all, I'm going to change the name as a Getproduct by ID query handler that we can separate
the commands and queries by the class names.
And I'm going to make this class as a internal, and this class will be inherit from the I query handler.
And as a request this will be get product by ID query.
This will be the request.
And as a result we can return getproduct by I result.
So this is the query handler.
And if I implement this interface members we can see that this will be comes with the handle method.
And this handle method gets a request parameter as a getproduct by id query.
So I'm going to change the name as a query this parameter name okay.
So we have basically created a structure of this class.
Now I'm going to inject required services.
This will be the I document session.
And the next one is the Ilogger.
Okay.
We have injected these services to perform our actual logic.
So in order to do that, I'm going to start the actual implementation here.
You can see that this will be a handle method.
At the beginning of the handle method I am adding a log information.
And after that I'm going to get the product information from sending await session load async method.
And I'm expecting a single product and passing the id information, which is the incoming query.id and
passing the cancellation token.
After that, if the product is null, we should perform some actions.
So for that purpose I'm going to check product is null.
I'm going to throw an exception which is the product not found exception that we will define in this
video.
But if the product is not null, we basically return new result object by passing the product value
that comes from the session that load async method.
In this handle method, we basically fetch a product by its id information, which comes from the query
object, and we use Martin's session.
I document session object and we use load async method in order to retrieve a specific product information
by id.
If the product is null, we basically throw a new product, not found exception, but if the product
is not null, we basically return a result which including this product information.
If you look at these, if you look where the product is null, we are throwing an exception.
But we didn't define this custom exception.
So we should create a custom exception class to handle these product.
Not found case.
For that purpose, I'm going to create an exceptions folder.
Under the catalog.
I'm going to right click and create a new folder and for the name is a exceptions.
And after that I'm going to create a product Notfoundexception.
Under this folder.
And in this folder we will define a new class which is the product not found exception.
And this exception will be inherited from the exception class.
And in constructor we can basically perform operation inheriting from the base class.
And in the base class we can paste the our product not found error message in here.
So this is typical a custom exception class that we use into our handle method.
And in this handle method we basically returning product not found exception under the get product by
id handle class.
In here you can see that we need to using statement API exceptions.
And I'm going to move these using statement into our global handle global using class.
And here you can see that I'm going to add a global using statement in here.
As you can see that we have completed the get product by ID query handle class with following six pattern
and handle method.