In this video we are going to develop get product by ID and point class with using the minimal APIs
and cutter library.
So we will start with defining request and response record types.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Get product by ID and point classes.
And we will start with the request and response object.
We don't have any request object because we will get the ID information from the request parameters.
But to be following the best practices I am putting in here commented request object.
And after that we will continue with the response object as a record type, and this will be the get
product by ID response.
And in the response we are expecting a single product.
And make sure that your parameter name also product P is uppercase.
And this will be same as your handle class because we will use master in order to map correctly.
The parameter and parameter name should be exactly same.
Okay, now we can develop our implementation which is the get product by id and point class, and we
will inherit from the equator module and implement the interface member, which is the ID Ross.
And we will start with the app dot map get operation.
And we basically define products slash and curly bracket.
We will getting the ID information from the request parameters.
And in the delegate handler we implement an asynchronous function with expecting with ID information
which comes from the these request parameters.
And also we will inject Isander which is the mediator sender object.
So now we will accodomate the incoming requests and paste the mediator.
For that purpose I'm going to define a result variable and sending with the mediator with using the
sender dot send method.
And we are passing naive get product by ID query information.
And that means we will passing the query object.
And in the query object we passing the id information which comes from the our request parameters.
So by this way we will pass these query object to the mediator.
And mediator will be trigger corresponding query handler class and perform its logic and return back
as a result.
And after that we can define a response object with mapping the result object result dot adapt and passing
our get product by id response.
And lastly, we will return to the client with this response object.
So for that purpose I'm going to write return results that okay.
And passing this response object.
And always we will configure these Http get endpoint with using the extension methods we will define
the API name summary description and produce the Http results according to these implementation.
So basically in this endpoint definition we are mapping the Get request with this product slash ID information
which takes a product id as a parameter.
And the endpoint is using the mediator.
In order to send get product by id query object, then mediator will be trigger the corresponding query
handler, and after that with getting the result object mapping this result object to the or get product
by id response object and return to the client as a result that okay 200 response.