In this video, we are going to test Getproduct by id and point with connecting to the PostgreSQL container.
So before we testing, make sure that your Docker environment is up and running, and you also started
your Docker compose and make sure that your PostgreSQL database is running and exposing the ports in
this way.
So if your Docker compose is not working, you can come to Visual Studio.
Right click Set Startup to Docker Compose and running the Docker compose profile.
And after that we can start with catalog API.
Microservice test.
We have confirmed that our database is up and ready.
So now we can start with the catalog API microservice test.
For that purpose, right click the catalog API and set a start up project.
And before running this application, make sure that you put the breakpoints under the getproduct by
ID.
And if you double click the endpoint, you can put the breakpoint in the beginning of the Http get request.
And if you go to handler method, you can put the breakpoint in the handle method.
So now we are ready to run this application.
For that purpose I'm going to run this application in https mode.
And after running this application we can go to the postman.
As you remember that we have developed Getproduct endpoint, I have changed the name from Get Catalog
to Getproduct, and I'm going to right click and duplicate this endpoint and creating Getproduct by
ID request under the catalog folder.
So first of all let's try to hit get products and get all products from our application.
So we have already additional breakpoints for get products.
And you can see that our product list is coming in here as a response.
And we can see we have only one product and which ID information in here.
I'm going to copy this ID information and go to the newly created Http get method.
And using this URL information and passing this ID in the request parameters.
So this will be the our get product by ID information.
If you save this request and click the Http send button, you can see that our debug point comes to
the newly developed get product ID endpoint class.
And this will be triggered handle method.
And in the handle method we are passing the ID information and get a specific product.
You can see that product is loaded successfully in debug mode.
And if the product is not null, we basically return a result and this will be converted to response
and return back to the client application in a Json format.
Here you can see that postman receive a request response object for a single product, and this confirms
that our endpoint is correctly fetching data from the PostgreSQL database and working perfectly.
So we can also verify from the console logs.
If you open the console logs, you can see that we have information logs that we have added when the
method starting points and we can see the log information also located in here.