In this video we are going to start to develop get product by category feature.
So as you can see that under the products we have develop create products, get product by ID and Get
products features.
So now we are going to focus on the developing Get products by category feature.
For that purpose right click with the products and add a new subfolder.
Which name is Get Product by category.
So under the Get Product by category we will create 100 and endpoint classes.
For that purpose I'm going to create a new class which name is Get Product by category under class under
this folder.
And also I'm going to create an additional class which name is endpoint class.
So as always we have start with the handle method.
So in this handle method this will be responsible for handling the query for fetching products by category.
Let me start with developing query and result object.
So we will start with public record.
And the name of the query is get product by category query.
And as a parameter we will get a string category information in order to filter by category and inherit
from the I query.
And this time we will return a result object which name is get product by category result.
Okay, after this definition, we will again public record and get product by category result and as
a result we expecting I innumerable.
Product that means product list.
So we will give the name as a products okay.
We have defined the our query and result object.
Now we will focus on the actual operation.
First of all, we will change the name as a query handler to indicate that this is the query handler
class and make it internal.
And after that we will inherit from the AI query handler, which passing the query and result object
into the interface.
And if we implement this interface you can see the handle method in here.
So in the handle method we basically interact with the database.
For that reason I am going to inject two items which are the AI documentation and AI logger to our handler
class.
So let's implement this handle method with using these injecting objects.
First of all I'm going to logging the incoming handle object with passing the query.
As you can see that we should change the name as a query in the parameters of the handle method, and
this will be log incoming request and query operation.
So after the logging operation we basically perform actual logic which is the getting the products from
the database with filtering session dot query method and we expecting product.
And in here we will filter by using the where statement.
And inside of the where statement I'm going to define p dot category.
Dot contains and pacing the incoming query category information.
And after that we can return to to list async.
So after getting filtered products we will return new result object with pacing this products.
In this handle method we use I documentation from the Martin in order to query this product document
table by category.
So this method handle the asynchronously fetch all matching products with given category information
and returns them as a part of the our result object in a I enumerable product object.