In this video we are going to develop get product by category and point class with using minimal APIs
and Carter.
So we will start with defining request and response object.
And we don't have any request object because we will get the category information from the request parameter.
But I am putting a request object as commented to following the best practices.
And after that we will create a response object which will be the including I enumerable product object.
So this will be the our request and response object.
Now we can implement actual endpoint class and this will be implement I Carter model.
And this class will define our Get endpoint for fetching products by a specific category.
So let me inherit from the I Carter model and implement the members.
So now I am going to exposing map get method.
And this time the URL should be different.
We can give products and slash category slash curly breaker category.
We have to put additional category in here because we have already using the id request parameter under
the products.
So in order to get category information we have to define additional layer in here.
That's why we have added products category and category name getting from the request parameter.
To implement these handler method we can use asynchronous function.
And I'm going to get the category name from the request parameters.
And after that I will use Isander method which is the mediator sender.
And after that we will implement actual implementation.
So here you can see that asynchronous function.
And we will implement asynchronous function in order to accommodate these requests.
So first of all I'm going to get the result object from the mediator.
For that purpose we are passing the.
Query object to the standard dot send method.
So now we will use naive get products by category query object.
And we will passing the category name where this category name comes.
This comes from the request parameters.
And this mediator will be returned a result object.
And after that we basically adapting result object to our response object.
And we will return results dot okay.
And passing the this response object.
And of course, as always, we have configured the API endpoint definition with using Carter extension
method.
So here you can see the definition of name summary description and produces Http endpoints.
In this endpoint definition we basically map Http get method with these URL products category and category
name.
And this endpoint uses mediator to send the get products by category query.
And then this will be trigger the handler method and then adapts to our response object that will be
returned to the client.