In this video we are going to test Getproduct by category endpoint with connecting to Docker PostgreSQL
container.
So that means our first step is make sure that PostgreSQL database is set up and running inside of the
Docker.
Open the Docker desktop and make sure that your Docker compose is running and PostgreSQL container is
exposing to ports.
If you didn't start yet, you can come here and right click the Docker compose, set a startup project
and run the Docker compose profile.
And after that we will continue to our catalog microservices.
We will test the catalog API microservice.
You can right click and set a startup project.
But before that make sure that you should put the breakpoints in the beginning of the endpoint class.
And after that, if you go to the handle method, put a breakpoint handle method.
So after setting up the breakpoints, you can run the https mode and we will send http get method for
get products by category information.
Okay.
If you open the R postman, I'm going to duplicate the get product by ID and create a new http get method.
And this time you can see that the endpoint URL including the products category and category information
in here.
So basically I'm going to send a C5 as a category five and click the send button.
And this will be hit the R endpoint class.
And this will be redirect to mediator trigger to handle method.
And in the handle method we basically query inside of the product document table and see the products
regarding to C5.
So as you can see that there is no product because C5 category is not existing.
If you go to the get product by ID response, you can see that we have two categories C1 and C2.
So I'm going to change as a C2.
Save this request and send again http get request and hit the F5 and EF5.
This time you can see that we have get successful response including products filter by categories which
name is C2.
And that confirms that our endpoint is correctly querying data from the PostgreSQL database.