In this video we are going to develop update product handler class with SQS and mediator implementation.
So we are in here and we will handle the update a product use case with creating update product feature
folder following the vertical slice architecture.
So please open the Visual Studio.
And under the products we are going to create a new sub folder which name is Update Product.
And this will be our command use case that we can perform Sex and mediator.
So in the update product folder we will create two classes, one for the handler class which is the
update product handler, and another for the endpoint class which will be the update product endpoint
class.
And as always we will start with the handler class.
This class will be responsible for processing the update command for products.
So now let me start with developing our record types which will be the common ID and result.
This time we will develop a command record type.
If you look at our mediator request lifecycle, in order to perform security implementation for Crud
operation, we will use command object and in the command object will be trigger command handler and
return a result.
For that purpose.
Let's follow the this structure and create our record type which is the update product command public
record update product command.
And inside of this command we will get all members in the product model.
So I am going to add a with ID string, name category and other properties.
Under the models product.
You can see that we will require all these parameters in order to update the whole single product.
So please locate the update product command handler.
And we have defined the command record type.
And as a result we will define the update product result.
But before that let me inherit this command object from the I command interface that we can separate
the commands and the queries.
So to response of the this command we will use update product result.
For that purpose I'm going to define additional record type which will be the update product result.
And this will be get only one parameter which is the will is success okay.
We have defined the our command and result object.
Now it is time to implement actual update product command handler class.
First of all, we should update the name as a command handler.
As you can see that we make it command handler to identify and distinguish query and command handlers.
And after that I'm going to change the modifier as a internal.
And now we are going to inherit from the.
This time I command handler.
And this command handler gets a update command.
And return back to the update product result.
And if we implement these interface members this will be create an handle method.
And in the handle method we have one parameter which is the update product command and change the these
parameter name as a command.
Okay, now we are ready to implement our handle method.
In order to implement and interact with the our database, we have to inject a document session.
For that purpose, I'm going to use Primary Constructor and add a I document session and Ilogger okay.
Now we will start with the handle method with adding a logger dot log information and we will notify
that update product handler handle method is called with this command.
And after that we will perform the actual logic.
Basically we will get the products from the database first and we will use session dot load async method.
And we expecting a product information.
And in here we can pass the command.id information and paste the cancellation token.
This will retrieve the single product.
But if the product is null we will throw an exception because we cannot be update null product.
So for that purpose I'm going to throw new product not found exception that we have created in the previous
lectures.
So if the product is not null, we basically update all the members including name, category, description,
image, file and price that can be updated with incoming command object.
So after updating these variables and members, we can use session dot update method and passing the
updated product entity which will be document entity for us.
And in order to perform the update operation we use session dot save change async method.
And.
Async the cancellation token.
And lastly, we can return new update product result object with passing the tour information.
That means this is successfully complete.
Update operation.
In this handle method, we basically use Martin's documentation in order to load the product by ID and
apply the updates.
If the product doesn't exist, it throws and product not found.
Exception.
After updating the product details, it saves the changes to the database.