In this video, we are going to develop update product and pointclass with using minimal APIs and Carter
to automate Http put request in this URL.
So as you can see that we have already implemented actual handle class.
And now we are going to implement endpoint class.
First of all we will develop request and response record type.
And after that we will handle the incoming requests and redirect to the mediator sender.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio and locate the update product and point class.
First of all we will create Request and response record type.
For that purpose.
I'm going to write Public record and this time we will require a request object which is the update
product request.
And we should passing all the items into product model as a parameter.
You can see that I'm going to pass ID name category description.
And so on.
By the way, these parameter names should be exactly name with the command object in the update product
handler.
Because these maps will be mapped these objects looking for the parameter type and the parameter name.
So make sure that you have created update product request correctly.
And this will be comes from the Http body into http put request.
And after defining the request object we will also response object.
Again we will write the public record and this type I'm going to write update product response object
with getting the boolean is success property.
So these are the requests and response object when we accommodating http post request.
And now we can implement actual endpoint class with inherit from the equator model.
And if you implement this interface you can see that we will define what's inside of the add method.
So in here basically I'm going to use app dot map put because this is the http put operation.
We should map the put operation inside of the map put method.
And in here we are going to use products endpoint again.
And when we are implementing this Http put operation I have two parameters.
The first one is update product request.
And we will get this request from the Http put body information as a Json format.
And after that the second parameter is I sender interface, which is the mediator interface that we
are going to inject with using the delegate handler function.
And in this function we are going to implement accommodating request with getting the command value
from the request object.
The first row.
We are going to adapting incoming requests and converting these requests to the update product command.
Because the mediator is requiring command and query.
That's why we should define a command object in here with mapping from the incoming request object.
And the second thing we will perform getting result information from the mediator with sending using
the sender dot send method.
And this time, as you can see that we are passing the command object okay.
After sending the command object, mediator will be trigger command handler and return back to the result
object.
And after that again we are going to use map star to converting result object to the response object.
So I'm going to use adapt method and passing this update product response object.
And this will be perform convert operation.
At last point we can use return results.
That okay to respond back to client with passing these response object?
As always, we will configure with using the extension method.
And here you can see that extension methods about update product providing the name description summary.
And we can return back to the 200 okay.
And if there is any problem we can return 400 bad request or 404 not found exception.
In this endpoint class we basically define a put request for slash products endpoint and the endpoint
receive an update product request object, and it adapts it to do an update product command using the
master.
And we basically send this command through the mediator.
And mediator will be triggered the command handler and respond back the result object.
Again.
We will adapt the result object to the response object and send back to the client.