In this video, we are going to test update product and point connecting to Docker PostgreSQL container.
So the first step is ensure that your PostgreSQL database is up and running on your Docker environment.
Open the desktop and make sure that your Docker compose is running and PostgreSQL up and running on
that port.
And the second thing is we will put the breakpoints under the update product endpoint in the beginning
of the put method delegate handler.
And if you go to the handler method, you can put breakpoint in the handle method of the update product
command handler.
And after that right click set as Startup project for Catholic API and run https mode.
So after running the application, we will use postman to send http put requests in order to update
product details.
So for that purpose please open the postman and please create an Http put request in postman.
You can see in here I have created http post and put request and in the post request you can see that
I have specified these kind of Json body requests and an http put request.
We will additionally add ID information into the updated product details.
So where can I find this ID information?
If you go to the Get product and get product id http get request, you can copy and paste the ID information
from in here.
The response of this kind of Http get response and put the ID into this ID information and update the
rest of the attributes like we have updated the name information, new product, a updated and new category
is added.
Description and image file has changed.
So now we are going to test these http put request and see how the system affected.
Click the Http send button and you will see that these will be trigger or update product endpoint class.
And these will be get the first line of the our delegate handler.
In the first line of delegate handler, we will basically get the request object and convert these request
object as a command object, because this command will be sent to mediator.
And mediator will be send this command corresponding command handler class.
If you put F10, you can see that our handle class is triggered.
And the first line we will log the information.
And the second line we will retrieve the product which is select product in the database.
And you can see that if the product is null, we should throw an exception.
But we have already comes product from the database.
And after that we will update all the attributes in the product and we will update product intersection,
which is the ID documentation from the Martins library.
And with saving change these updated product, we will reflect the update and return back the command
response result to do our endpoint class, and these result object will be converted to response object
and return back to the client.
You can see that our response is comes from the postman.
And this response is is success is true.
And this is indicating that success of this operation and this confirms that our endpoint is correctly
processing this update.
We can verify this update operation.
So in order to ensure the product was updated, we can send an http get request to retrieve the product
by ID and observe the updated details.
If you click the get product by ID and if you retrieve again the same ID information, this will be
also hit the our breakpoints and I'm passing this breakpoint with F5.
And here you can see that these attributes are coming with the updated values that we have confirmed
and verified the update operation into our database.