In this video we are going to do developing delayed product handler class with secrets and mediator.
So we are at this point and we will perform remove a product use cases for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and under the products feature folder you can see that we will create
our vertical slice use cases.
And this time I'm going to create a new folder which name is Delete product.
So right click Products Add new folder and this will be delete product.
And inside of the delete product folder we will create two classes one for the handler class which is
the delete product handler, and another for the delete product endpoint class.
And we will perform our actual logic.
In order to delete product with following the vertical slice architecture, we will start to developing
delete product handler class.
This will be responsible for processing the command to delete a product.
So please open the delete product handler and we will start our developing.
First of all, as you remember that we always start with developing command and result record types.
And after that we will develop actual logic in the command handler class.
So let's get started I'm going to write the public record and delete product command object and passing
the gid id information because we will delete the product by ID.
So after that I have to implement this interface which is the I command, and passing the our result
object which is the delete product result object.
And just after that I'm going to define delete product result.
And as a result we only store is success.
Property.
As you can see that we have defined the command and result object.
Now we can start to developing actual command handler class.
The first thing we should do that change the class name as a delete product command handler to identify
command and query handlers.
So after that I'm going to change the modifier as a internal.
And after that we will inherit this command handler from the I command handler interface.
And passing the delete product command and result object in the interface members.
So after that we will implement this interface and see that the handle method is created, comes from
the interface.
And we will change the first parameter name which will be the command.
Now we can start to implement our actual logic.
But how we can interact with database.
Of course we should inject required services into the R class with using the primary constructor.
I'm going to inject documentation and ilogger to perform actual logic.
After injecting these services with using the primary constructor, we can implement our handle method.
In the first line of code, we will logging the information about the incoming command object, and
after that we will perform our actual logic.
We will delete the product with incoming command id.
So I'm going to use session dot delete method and passing the product as a document table.
And we are passing commanded information to delete these ID product.
So after delete operation we always need to call save changes async method and passed the cancellation
token.
After that we are returning the new delete product result and I'm going to pass it.
Success is true.
In this handler class, we basically use Martin's I documentation in order to delete the product by
its id.
After performing the delete command, we save the changes to the database and ensuring the product is
removed.