In this video, we are going to develop delete product and point with using minimal APIs.
And Carter.
That means we will expose Http delete method and performing this delete method in this URL.
And we will remove a product from the database.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio.
This time we will developing the delete product endpoint class.
Double click this class and go to this class.
As always, we will start with the defining record types.
In the endpoint class, we have defined request and response record types, and after that we will perform
an exposing Http delete operation with using Carter.
So please open the Visual Studio.
And I'm going to create a request and response object.
For request object.
We basically require a gid id information that we can get from the request parameters.
For that purpose, I'm putting a commented request object to following the best practices in here,
and after that we are developing the response object, which name is delete product response and it
is getting the bool is success property, and this should be same as the r result object into the handler
class in order to convert each other easily using the master.
So we are creating request and response object.
Now it is time to develop our actual delete product and point class.
In this class we will implement I Carter model interface in order to define our delete end point and
remove the products for that purpose, I'm implement I Carter module and implement these interface members,
which is the add routes in the Addross methods.
We can exposing the Http methods with calling the map methods.
This time we will using the map delete to exposing Http delete operation as a request URL.
We will use products slash ID information that we can get the ID from the request parameters, and after
that we will implement this operation with writing the delegate handler.
First of all, we need a gid id value from the request parameters, and after that we can inject I sender
which is the our mediator.
And in here we can perform the our actual operation in the delegate handler method.
So I'm going to open this method and writing the result variable.
We will get the result variable from the mediator.
I'm going to using the standard dot send to passing our delete product command to the mediator.
So in the product command I'm going to paste the ID information that comes from the request parameters.
And mediator will be trigger the delete product command handler class and return back the result.
And after that we can convert these result as a response object that we can use the result dot adapt
method and pacing the delete product.
Response object.
Lastly, we will return results.
Okay response to the client.
As always, we can configure this endpoint with using the extension methods.
Here you can see that we have defined the name summary description and produce Http responses.
In this endpoint definition we define Http delete requests for slash products slash id endpoint.
And the endpoint uses mediator in order to send a delete product command with the specified product
ID, and then adapts the result to the delete product response and return back to the client.