In this video we are going to test delete product end to end connecting to Docker PostgreSQL container.
So the first thing we should do that open the Docker desktop and activate and set up the PostgreSQL
database.
If you can see that I have opened the Docker desktop is running, but there is no running containers
for PostgreSQL database.
For that purpose.
I'm going to open the Visual Studio and right click the Docker compose, set a startup project and run
without debugging this docker compose.
This will be running this docker compose on behind of the scenes.
And if you open the Docker desktop, you will see that our Docker compose is running and catalog db
is activated and see that ports are exposing in this URL.
So basically we are ready to run our catalog API.
If you go back to our testing operation this was the delete product.
That's why we will put two breakpoints under the endpoint class and inside of the map delete operation.
And if you go to the handler class you can put the breakpoint in the handle method.
So now after that we are going to right click the catalog API and set a startup project.
This will be running microservices on our local computer that we will connect to Docker container environment
as a backing services PostgreSQL database.
And we have already arranged application settings before we proceeding this video and we are ready for
the test.
Our actual operation, which is the delete product endpoint, run this application as an Https mode,
and after that we will send http delete requests to our application.
Okay, application is running correctly and if I open the postman you can see that first of all let's
get products inside of the our database.
And after that we will delete this product.
I'm going to send http get method.
This is also get breakpoints.
And now I would like to get a response of the products.
See that we have one product in here.
Which id is this ID number.
Copy this ID number.
And I have created Http delete operation under our catalog microservices from our issue of microservices
route postman collection.
And please create any Http delete endpoint in here and copy and paste these ID information into this
URL which is the products slash ID.
And as you remember that catalog URL comes from the our environment which is localhost 5050.
And now I can send Http delete method with clicking this send button and see that the breakpoint is
hitting our delete product endpoint class.
If you continue to debugging, step over the this line of code and this will be mediator center.
Delete product command with ID information.
Here you can see the ID comes from the request parameter.
And just after that this will be trigger our handle method in the handle method we will log the information.
After that we will delete these commands with incoming ID information and save the changes from the
database and return the delete product response result as a true.
And after that this result object converting to response and we will return to client this response
object hit the F5.
So you can see that postman is received a response indicating the success of the operation is true.
This response confirms that our and been correctly processed product delete operations.
So in order to ensure the product was indeed deleted, we can send an http get request again to retrieve
all products in here.
So we have one product and we should delete this product.
And if we send again this http get method and hit the F5 facing these breakpoints, you can see that
there is no products is listing from our PostgreSQL database.
So we have verified these operation.
We don't have any products in here.
Also we can use the get product by ID to retrieving the product which deleted IDs.
You can see that this ID comes from the deleted ID.
And this time I'm going to use get product by ID.
Hit the enter and see that what will happen.
This will be also triggered our breakpoint and hit the F5 and hit F5 again.
And see that this time it is returning a response, but this is very unreadable and not manageable response.
It is returning is a product not found exception.
But we see a lot of class names and this will be not acceptable as a response to see from the client.
So that means we should enhance our API to handle the product, not found exception scenarios more gracefully,
and we should provide a clear and informative response to the client.