In this section, we are going to develop ordering infrastructure layer with using Entity Framework,
Core Code, first approach and SQL server.
Here you can see the big picture that we are going to develop one by one.
We are still in the ordering microservices.
And if you look at the ordering microservices internal architecture, this time we are going to develop
the infrastructure layer.
We have developed domain layer in the previous lecture.
And now we are going to develop ordering infrastructure in order to communicate with SQL server and
implement the external communications.
So what we will include these infrastructure layer.
First of all we will use Entity Framework core eight features code first Approach migrations and SQL
server Connection.
We will develop Entity Framework core Dbcontext object for storing entities in ordering infrastructure.
And we will mapping the domain driven design objects to the Entity Framework core entities.
And we will develop order entities configurations with using the model builder and complex types in
the ordering infrastructure.
And also we will perform auto migrate and seed operations with Entity Framework core entities to the
SQL server database when the application start up with coding.
And lastly, we will raise and dispatch domain events with using Entity Framework, Core and Mediator.
So we can say that the main target of the ordering infrastructure layer is the mapping the domain objects,
including the aggregate entity value objects to the Entity Framework core entities, and migrate the
tables into SQL server database.
For example, value objects can be defined as a complex type in the Entity Framework core eight and
Entity Framework Core Aggregate root entities.
So we will use complex types as a value objects into the Entity Framework core.
And here you can find the folder structure of ordering infrastructure layer that we are going to develop
in this section.
So basically we will have a data folder under the infrastructure.
Under the data folder we have a configuration sub folder.
This will be include customer order, order item and product configurations.
In order to configure our entities for Entity Framework Core.
And after that we have extensions folder.
These including database extensions and initial data for seeding the data and performing migration operations.
And you can see interceptors listing in here This will be performing auditable entity and dispatched
domain events using the interceptors.
And here you can see the migrations folder.
This will be provide to migrations on the Entity Framework core.
And lastly we have a application DB context.
This is the main DB context object for Entity Framework Core.
And we will use global using and dependency injection case with following the other layers.
So now let's start to develop ordering infrastructure layer.