In this video we are going to learn Entity Framework Core eight features Code First Approach, migrations
and SQL Server Connection.
So let me start with the what is Entity Framework core.
Entity Framework Core is a lightweight, extensible, open source and cross-platform data access technology.
Entity Framework Core can serve as an object relational mapper, which is a ORM tool which enables.
Net developers to work with the database using the.
Net objects, and it eliminates the need for the most of the data access code that typically needs to
be written, and Entity Framework Core supports many database engines.
We can see the database providers for details, and here you can see Entity Framework core NuGet packages
for all DB providers.
Entity framework Core support different database systems through the use of the database providers,
and each system has its own database provider, which is shipped as a NuGet.
Packages An applications should install one or more of these provider packages.
You can see the common database providers are listed on the slide.
So these are the SQL server and SQL Azure.
We will use the NuGet package of the Microsoft Entity Framework core SQL server.
And here you can see different databases and different database providers from the Entity Framework
core, including SQLite, cosmos, PostgreSQL, MySQL and in-memory databases.
And these are the popular high quality open source providers developed and shipped by the community
and the Microsoft itself.
So now I am going to explain how we can interact this database using the Entity Framework core tooling.
So we can use of tooling for Entity Framework core migrations and reverse engineering scaffolding from
an existing database that require installation of the appropriate tooling package.
So we have two ways to use Entity Framework core tooling.
The first way is using dotnet core CLI In this case we can use dotnet EF and Microsoft Entity Framework.
Core design NuGet packages for cross platform command line tooling that you can see the commands in
here.
And the second way is Package Manager Console in Visual Studio.
So in this case we will use Microsoft Entity Framework core tools, NuGet packages for PowerShell tooling
that works in the Visual Studio Package Manager console.
And you can see the package that we are going to use for the Package Manager console.
And please note that tooling packages are different from these two way.
The first one is the.
Net CLI using the design packages, and the second one is using the Microsoft Entity Framework core
tools NuGet packages.
You can also see the installation packages.
The first one is installing the design package, and the second one is installing the tools package.
During the course I am going to use these second option, which is the Visual Studio, and using the
Package Manager console.
That's why we will download and install tools packages for Entity Framework Core operations.