In this video, we are going to learn the key steps of developing ordering infrastructure layer using
the Entity Framework core.
The first key step is install Entity Framework core NuGet packages.
We should install the necessary packages for SQL Server and Entity Framework core tools.
So these are the packages including the Microsoft Entity Framework, core SQL server and the tools NuGet
packages.
So I'm going to use Visual Studio and Package Manager Console.
That's why I have installing the tools NuGet packages.
But if you use the.
Net CLI, you can install the design packages instead of the tools to perform an interact Entity Framework
core tooling operations.
And the second key step is developing Dbcontext object.
We will be adding entity objects into the Entity Framework core Dbcontext object.
And that's why we will define a Dbcontext class in the infrastructure layer, which name is application
Dbcontext.
So in this context class we will define entities as a DB set, including the customer product order
and order item in order to interact.
Entity framework core and SQL server database using the entities under the Dbcontext class.
And after that we will configure the domain entities to Entity Framework Core entities for SQL server.
That means we will mapping domain driven design objects to the Entity Framework core entities.
We are going to use Entity Framework Core Module Builder for mapping domain driven design entities to
Entity Framework core entities.
That means we will map the domain entities to database tables and configure their relationships.
You can see all the configurations and this is inherited from the I entity type configurations.
In order to configure all the entity members, including the ID and other members inside of these configure
methods.
And the next key step is ASP.Net core setup and configurations, including the application settings
JSON file.
That means we should configure the database connection string in application settings JSON file.
You can see the connection string database and this is representing SQL server database connections
And after that we should register Entity Framework Core Dbcontext to ASP.Net Dependency Injection,
and we can register the services like application Dbcontext in the Program.cs.
In order to add these Dbcontext into ASP.Net Devtool.
Here you can see that we have going to adding Dbcontext, which is our application Dbcontext.
With configuring the interceptors and using the SQL server with a given connection string indicating
the application settings JSON file.
And the next key step is create migrations and create database with commands.
We will use Entity Framework Core tools in order to create migrations and update the database.
So that means in Visual Studio.
First of all we will install the tools packages.
And after that we will run these two command which is the add migration initial create and update database.
The add migration command scaffolds the migration table and migration folder.
In order to create the initial set of the tables for the model and update database command creates the
database and applies to new migrations to the database itself, which is the SQL server that we can
check the SQL server database from the Visual Studio Management console.
And after that, the next key step is create database with migrate method.
And after creating manually we will also migrate these operations with coding.
And we will update the Program.cs in order to automatically apply migrations at startup.
You can see in here we will use context database migrate async method in order to perform all the migrations
from the folder automatically when the application start up, and after that the next key step is seeding
the database.
We will populate the database with initial data using a seeding method or class, and in this section
we will add a code that populates the database with the test data with including the data db initializer
class.
We will create this class in order seeding database.
We will check the orders in the application startup.
If there is no orders, we will adding the predefined orders from our initial data class, and the next
step is to dispatch the domain events with Entity Framework core interceptors.
We will implement a Savechanges interceptor in order to dispatch domain events before saving the changes
to database.
You can see an example of the Dispatch Domain events interceptor we have defined.
Domain events in the ordering domain layer.
In this layer, we will dispatch these domain events using the Savechanges interceptor.
And this is one of the powerful features combining Entity Framework core Savechanges interceptor with
a mediator mediator library in order to dispatching to domain events in the infrastructure layer.
And the last key step is test all from the local with containerized SQL server in Docker.
So we will set up a docker compose file in order to run SQL server in Docker container, and we will
test the application locally with the containerized SQL server.
And after that we will test the whole application in Docker compose environment.
So now let's follow these steps in order to develop ordering infrastructure layer one by one.