In this video, we are going to start with the first step.
That means we will install the necessary Entity Framework core packages for the ordering infrastructure
layer.
For that purpose, we will install Entity Framework, core SQL server and the tools packages.
SQL Server Package is the Entity Framework core database provider for the Microsoft SQL server, and
we will use SQL server as a ordering database for that purpose.
We will install these database provider NuGet packages in order to interact with SQL server using the
Entity Framework core, and after that we will install Entity Framework Core Tools packages.
These are the tools for the Entity Framework core that integrate with the Visual Studio Package Manager
console.
They provide commands for managing migrations and updating the database schema.
And I will use Package Manager Console and Visual Studio.
That's why we will install the tools packages.
If you use the.
Net CLI, you can install the design package and follow the commands for the net f commands.
So now please open the Visual Studio and go to the Ordering Infrastructure layer and right click dependencies
and manage NuGet packages.
So the first package I am going to install is a.
Microsoft Entity Framework core and SQL server.
So select this package and install under the Ordering infrastructure layer.
Okay, except.
Okay, the first package are installed and the second package is Microsoft Entity Framework Core Tools.
Select this package and install for the Ordering Infrastructure class library and click the I accept.
And if you double click the Ordering Infrastructure class library, you can confirm these installations
in the item groups.
We have successfully installed SQL Server and Tools NuGet packages into our class library, and under
the tools you can see private and include assets in here.
That means that are available for development purpose, but that are not included in the projects output
when they published.
So with these packages now we can start to developing database context, entities, configurations and
other data access components using the Entity Framework core in the Ordering infrastructure layer.