In this video we are going to do a second step, which is the Develop Entity Framework core DB context
object for storing entities in ordering infrastructure layer.
And we will create application db context.
So for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to Ordering Infrastructure and create a new
folder.
I'm going to right click Add New Folder which name is Data Folder.
And inside of this data folder I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is application db context dot cs.
So this class will extend the Dbcontext class from the Entity Framework core and act as a primary class
that coordinates Entity Framework Core functionality for the data model.
So please remove the unnecessary using statement and inherit from the Dbcontext object.
And this object comes from the Entity Framework core packages, and we will implement the actual Dbcontext
operation inside of this class and make this class as a public.
And now I'm going to develop the constructor and a Dbset values.
First of all, I'm going to develop the constructor of these Dbcontext object.
Here you can see the constructor and these will be inherited and called from the base options method.
So we will call the base constructor.
So in the Dbcontext constructor we basically accept Dbcontext options as application db context and
passes these options to the base Dbcontext constructor.
So these will be transformed options when configuring to our application db context.
And after that we can create our DB sets with including the entities.
For example, we will create a DB set which is the customer entity as a customer and give the set customer.
This will be provide a customer entity under the application DB context.
And I'm going to follow the same steps for the other entities, including the product orders and order
items.
And these will be represent each entity into the our application.
And each of these DB set properties on the context object.
Represent a database table in the database.
So that means we will create customer product orders and order item tables on the SQL server using DB
context and Entity Framework core.
So after that we will overwrite the on model creating and apply configurations from the assembly.
That means if I come here and write the override, you can see that there is lots of overridable methods
under the DB context.
And we are going to override all model creating.
What is mean that?
That means we can configure Entity Framework core entities on model creating method.
And in here you can see that it is calling the base on model creating method.
But before that we can configure our entities in the beginning of this method with overriding.
If you look at the on model creating Overrideable method, you can see that there is a parameter which
name is model builder.
So this is important parameter that we can use these model builder in order to configure our entities.
Before that I'm going to change the name and make it more concise as a builder.
And I'm going to use builder to configure one of the entities by using the dot notation.
So we can use builder dot entity and give the entity name.
For example I'm going to configure the entity and even we can give the property in the entity.
After getting the entity we can check the property.
And if you go to the customer property for example, customer has a name property and we can configure
the customer table and the name property.
And we can set these as required or using different methods in here in a fluent API way using the Entity
Framework Core Model Builder.
For example, in here, as you can see that we are configured to our customer name property which is
required and max length is 100.
So this is one of the basic configurations in the on model creating and using the Entity Framework,
core Model Builder and Fluent APIs.
But this is the long configuration, right?
If you think about that.
Lots of tables and lots of columns need to configure in this model.
Creating these method should be lots of line of code, and we cannot manage and refactor and readable
this method.
So instead of that we can grouping these configurations in a separate class.
So how we can grouping these configurations.
So the idea is that in order to reduce the size of the on model creating method with all configurations
for entity type that can be extracted to the separate class implementing the I entity type configuration.
Here you can see that Entity Framework core also provides some of the powerful interface, which is
the I entity type configurations, that we can inherit all the configurations from these interface.
And these will be reduced to configurations in this model creating method.
So by this way we can apply these configurations from the assembly.
So I'm going to remove these configuration model configuration.
And now we are going to use apply all these configurations from the assembly.
For that purpose I'm going to use as a builder object again.
And if you look at the builder object you can see that.
There is a method which name is applied.
Configurations from the assembly and this method require assembly information as a parameter.
And I am passing the assembly dot.
Get executing assembly with this line of code.
The apply configuration from assembly method scans the assembly for all classes that implement I entity
type configuration and apply state configurations, and this method is called within the all model creating.
So as you can see that we have completed the application db context and we have successfully set up
the application DB context in the ordering infrastructure layer.
And this setup is organized our database context and entity configurations.