In this video we are going to do step three which is configure domain entities to Entity Framework core
entities.
That means we will develop Entity Framework core entity configurations in the ordering infrastructure.
Please open the Visual Studio.
As you can see that in the last video we have used apply configurations from assembly method in order
to configure all these entities in a separate folder and in a separate class.
For that purpose, I'm going to right click the data folder and create a new subfolder, which name
is configurations.
So in this folder we will configure entities.
And I would like to start with the customer configurations.
And I'm going to add a new class which name is Customer Configuration.
Under this configuration folder create new class which name is Customer configurations x.
So we will configure customer entity in this configuration class.
First of all I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make it public.
And the important thing is I'm going to inherit from the I entity.
Type configuration and placing the customer entity as a generic.
As you can see that we have implementing I entitytype configuration under the customer configuration.
And if you implement these interface members, you can see that the configure method comes in here.
By this way we can configure specifically customer entity in this customer configuration class.
So before configure the customer entity we can go to the customer entity and see the members.
Here you can see the name and email property including customer entity and customer entity using customer
ID as a primary key.
And if you go to the entity definition, the ID property comes from the entity base class.
So if you go back to our customer configuration, we can start by configuring the primary key.
And in here you can see that the builder object comes from the parameter of the configure method I'm
going to use builder dot has key method in order to identify the key information of this customer table
on database.
And we are going to use ID as a key of this customer table.
But if you look at the ID value, you can come here and see that the ID is customer ID that means it
is a value object and this is the customer ID.
But when we configure any entity, we would like to specify how we can store these columns into the
database.
So that means SQL server database should know the customer ID and how can store the customer ID into
For that purpose we are going to use custom conversions.
Here you can see that I'm going to use his conversion method.
In order to custom conversion the customer id to id value.
You can see that we can configure the customer ID with a custom conversion between the customer ID value
object and it is database representation.
So that means we will use customer ID dot value when we are storing these information in the database.
And when we are reading this value from database, we will be using customer ID of method.
In order to reach the customer ID into our application.
So this is very powerful feature when configuring the Entity Framework core entities.
And after that we can continue to configure the other properties which is for example the name column.
In here we have defined maximum length and required constraint for the name property.
And I'm going to follow the same steps for the email column in here we have defined the maximum length
for the email column.
And also I would like to use his index method for the email property and column.
And using the is unique method.
With this line of code, we will ensure uniqueness of the email field using an index for the customer
table.
So this is the configuration for the customer entity, and we will follow the same steps for the product
configurations.
For that purpose, I'm going to create a new configuration under the configuration folder create a new
file.
Which name is product configuration dot cs.
And we will follow the same steps.
And the first thing we should do that we will inherit from the I entity type configuration and passing
to our product.
Entity and implement this interface and make sure that the class should be the public access modifier.
And now we can start to configure these product entity is the same way.
We will start configuring with defining the primary key and defining the ID column.
So in here you can see that we will use hash key method in order to identify the ID column of the product
table.
And after that we will use custom conversion in order to convert the product id value object to the
database weight value.
And at the same way we will read this value from database, converting the product ID of method to reaching
the product id value.
So after that, we can configure the name of the product table.
If you go to product, you can see that we only have name and price.
So I'm going to put a configuration for the name with defining the maximum length 100 and is required
attribute to the name column into the product table.
And this is enough for the product configuration.
And we have completed the product and customer configuration.
Now it is time to configure order and order item configuration that are more complicated.
So I'm going to start with creating order configuration under the configurations folder create new class
which name is Order Configuration Case and follow the same steps I'm going to inherit from the I entity
type configuration and passing the order entity inside of this interface, and implement these interface
members and make it public to this configuration class.
So this is the order configuration.
For now, I am skipping the implementation of the order configuration and contain the create a new configuration
file, which is the order item configuration.
Create new class, which name is order item configuration and follow the same steps.
Inherit from the I entity type configuration and pass order item as a entity of this configuration class
and implement members.
Make this class public and we are ready to implement Order and order item configurations in this class.
Before start the Configuring Order and Order item.
In this configuration classes, we should review the Order and Order item entity in the entity classes.
If you go to Order Configuration and select the order, right click go to definition.
You can reach the Order aggregate and you can see the order has complex types including the address,
shipping and billing address payment.
These are the value objects that we should define when configuring the own Entity Framework core entities.
And also you can see that order has one to end relationship with the order item.
So how can we configure these custom relationships and also value objects into the Entity Framework
core.
How can we mapping these domain driven design order object to do Entity Framework core entity.
So we can see these details in the next video to understanding and configuring Entity Framework, core
Relations and Value objects.