In this video we are going to learn Entity Framework, Core Relations and Domain driven Design value
object mappings with complex type and complex property method.
Let me start with the Entity Framework core relations with using the has and with patterns.
In domain driven design, entities often have relationships with other entities.
These relationships are typically 1 to 1, one to many, or many to many.
Entity Framework Core handles these relationships using the has and with pattern relationships can be
configured using the has many with one methods for one to many relationships, and has one with many
methods for many to one relationships.
And here you can see one to many relationship.
Example.
In our authentic microservices, order and order items have one to many relationship.
That means an order can have multiple order items and this can be configured using the Entity Framework
Core Fluent API.
As you can see in the picture, we can configure with the builder entity order entity, and we will
use has many methods and identify the many items which is the order items.
And we can continue with the Whitman, which is the one to many relationships and specify the foreign
key as order ID.
And this configuration sets up the relationship where each order item references an order through a
foreign key.
Which name is order id?
Now we can explore domain driven design value object mapping with complex type and complex property.
So in Entity Framework core eight complex types are introduced to better support value objects in domain
driven design.
A complex type is an object that doesn't have a primary key, and it is used to represent a set of properties
in an entity.
As an example of the complex type of objects in our ordering.
Microservices address can be a complex type representing the shipping and billing address for an order.
Here you can see that address value objects is indicating as a complex type with attribute, and we
can also configure address as a complex type on model.
Creating method.
When configuring the order entity, you can see that in order entity, we will use complex property
method in order to identify billing and shipping address as a value object.
So this configuration in our model creating method tells Entity Framework Core that billing and shipping
address are complex types, and it will then map these types to the same table as the order entity,
treating them as a part of the order entity rather than a separate entity.