In this video, we are going to develop order and order item entity configurations with using hazard
pattern to identify the relationships.
And we will also use complex types for the value objects.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the Order Item configuration.
We will start with the order item Entity Configuration and this class configure the order item entity.
If you go to Order Item Entity, you can see that there is one primary key which is the order item ID
and also there is two foreign key.
These are the indicating order id and product ID.
So these are the one to many relationships that we can define in the order item configuration.
If you go back to order item configuration I'm going to develop these configurations under the configure
method.
So basically we will start with the primary key configuration.
Here you can see that I'm going to use builder dot hash key to identify the primary key.
This set up the id property of order item as a primary key.
But if you look at the ID property, you can see that this is the order item ID, which is a strongly
type ID that we need to conversion using the has conversion method.
When saving this data into Entity Framework core and SQL server.
For that purpose, we have additional configuration including the hash conversion method, and this
configures the ID property to use the order item id value object and converting it to from a guide for
the database operation.
That means when we are saving this ID to database, we will use value as a guide information into SQL
server column.
And when we are reading these value from the database, we will convert them order item id with off
method and converting the strongly type IDs.
And after defining configurations about the primary key, we can go to foreign key configurations including
the product and order.
So for the order part I'm going to move this order configuration in the order configuration class.
And for order item configuration I'm going to put a configuration only the product ID foreign key relationship.
For that purpose I'm going to come here and using the with many and has foreign key methods in order
to identify product ID as a foreign key.
So this is the foreign key as product.
And with using this code this will be a subject a relationship with the product entity.
And each order item relates to one product.
There is a one to many relationship with product and order item.
We can define these configuration with builder that has one and specify the one item, which is the
product entity, and we can use with many method.
That means one product has many order items, and after that we will specify the foreign key column
which is the order item dot product id.
So after that we can configure the quantity and price which is required keywords.
Here you can see that we will define quantity and price is required.
And these codes make sure that the quantity and price fields are always populated in the database.
So we have configured the order item and you can see the codes in here.
We didn't configure order item with the order relationship in the order item configuration.
Because I'm going to move this configuration in the order configuration.
We should not duplicate these communication into configuration in order to avoid duplicate column on
the database.
So you can write the order item configuration with this configuration.
And I'm going to move order configuration.
And the order entity is more complex and include the relationship value objects and enums.
You can right click order and go to definition the Order entity.
You can see the different relationships including the one to many order items.
And we have customer ID relationship and we will have value objects including the shipping billing address
and payment.
And we will have enums for the order status.
So we will configure all these columns into our order configuration.
This is one of the most complex entity type for mapping Entity to Entity Framework course entities.
Please open the order configuration and go to the configure method and start to configure our operations.
Of course I'm going to start the configuring the primary key as the same way we have defined with the
hash key method in order to identify the primary key.
And after that I'm going to use his conversion method in order to convert these value object to the
database.
Guid value is the same way.
We will read these gid value as a order id of method, and we will return back the order id strongly
type ID to our application.
After that, we can continue with the relationships from the order entity and the first relationship
is customer ID.
In order to configure customer ID for N.k, we can use has one with many pattern.
You can see that we will use has one method including the customer entity and after that.
We will use with many method specify.
One customer has many orders and we will specify the has foreign key which is a customer ID and this
is the required column into database.
So this will be configured our relationship customer and order with one to many relationship.
And after that we have also one to many relationships order and order items.
In order to configure these relationship we can follow the same steps.
So in here you can see that I'm going to use has many Whitman pattern.
In the has many method.
We will specify the main items from the order which is the order items, and we will specify order should
be with one.
And this is the foreign key which is the order item dot order id that will be held one to many relationships
between order and order item, and after completed the relationship configurations, we can continue
to implement configurations for the value objects.
So as you can see in the order entity, we have lots of value objects including the order name, address,
payment and so on.
So I'm going to start with the configuring the order name we can configure with using the builder Dot
complex property.
Entity Framework Core eight introduces the new complex property method which we use to map domain driven
design value objects like address payment directly into our Order Entities columns.
So in here you can see that we will use complex property method when defining order name value object.
And you can specify the column value and column name as max length and is required property in the name
builder complex property method operations.
So I'm going to follow the same steps when defining our shipping and billing address.
So after defining these order name as a value object I'm going to come here and continue with the shipping
address.
Here you can see the complex property.
For the shipping address.
We will specify the complex property and passing the shipping address.
And here you can see the address builder.
And in the address builder we will specify every column under this value object which including the
first name, last name, email address, address, line, country, state and zip code.
And for each column for the value object, we can specify the max length and is required keywords for
each of these value object items.
So this is the definition of the shipping address for mapping Entity Framework core entities from the
Domain driven Design Value object.
And I'm going to follow the same operation for the billing address as you remember that for order entity
we have shipping and billing address.
That's why we have using two complex property for the address value object.
This time you can see that we will use billing address and the address builder part is the same.
The previous code we have configured all members under the address value object.
So after these definitions we can go to the next value object which is the payment.
So here you can see that we will use complex property method in order to configure payment value object
inside of the order entity.
And the payment builder is following the same steps.
We will define each property in the value object as a column of the SQL server database with specifying
max length is required, and so on.
So after defining these payment information, we have one more operation left, which is the enumeration.
As you remember, that order has order status enumeration.
And we should also configure these enumeration into these method.
And here you can see that we have defined order status column as a property.
And this will be definition of the enum.
And we can give the has default value as a order status draft.
And we can use has conversion method.
In order to convert these enumeration to the database table and column, you can see that we will convert
these as a string method.
After that we have convert back the string to the enum value with parsing the enum dot parse method.
Lastly, we can configure the total price column in the database.
Here you can see that I'm going to only indicate as a property method, which is a total price.
In order to create a column into SQL server database and store the total price in that database.
So as you can see that we have finished the configurations for the order entity, including the enumerations,
value objects, relationships, and so on.
So.