In this video we are going to do step four, which is Entity Framework core SQL server connection string
in the Application settings Json file.
In ordering microservices, we will use SQL server database as a backing services, and we will also
add SQL server into our Docker compose file.
But now let's focus on the development part of the Entity Framework core.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Application Settings.
In ordering API, we will have application settings in the web project.
If you open the ordering API project, you can go to the Application Settings Json file.
And I'm going to define connection settings in here.
As you know that application settings is typically in ASP.Net core project and storing application settings
like database connection strings.
And I'm going to put connection strings in this file.
And if you look at this connection string you can see that we have connection string database.
And as a server I am giving a localhost which is specifies the database server.
Localhost means the database is running on the same machine as the web application.
When we are containerize this application, we will change the server name as a Docker container name,
and after that you can see the database name as a order db.
This is the name of the database to connect to SQL server.
In this case we will give order db.
And here you can see the user id sa.
And this is the username for SQL server login SA stands for the System administrator.
For password I'm giving a complex password.
This is for the SQL server login.
And if you continue the connection string you can see the encrypt as a false.
This indicates whether the connection should be encrypted or not for development environments.
Mostly it is using as a false because we don't need the encryption in development environment, and
after that we have trusted server certificate configuration as a true.
This is often used in development environment where the SSL TLS certificate might not be certificate
or SQL server.
So that's why.
Please give true for the trust server certificate.
And this is the connection settings for communicating SQL server from our ordering API project.