In this video we are going to do step five which is registering Entity Framework core DB context object
into ASP.Net core Dependency Injection container tool for SQL Server Connection.
For that purpose, we should go to the Visual Studio.
And now where we should register Entity Framework core DB context into Clean Architecture.
Of course we should start with the ordering API Program.cs, where we are registering all objects into
ASP.Net core.
So you can see that we will register services into Program.cs with using the different layers.
For each layer we have separate register operation.
That means every layer register its own dependencies.
Since we are developing infrastructure layer, we should register Entity Framework core classes into
infrastructure layer add infrastructure method.
So I'm going to right click and go to definition.
You can see that this is located under the ordering the infrastructure layer.
And there is a dependency injection class that we can register all infrastructure related objects in
this extension method.
So this class provides to configure and register services specific to infrastructure layer such as the
Entity Framework code DB context object.
So in this class we can see add infrastructure services.
And this is an extension method for Iservice collection which is used to configure and add services
to the ASP.Net core dependency injection container.
And here you can see that this method is getting a parameter for I configuration.
And the parameter allows to access the applications configuration settings such as connection string.
So in our case in the beginning of this extension method under the ordering infrastructure we will retrieve
the connection string.
And this line fetches the connection string which named database from the application Settings.json
file.
And you can go to Application Settings file.
And you can see the database connection settings comes from this place into the order dependency injection
of the ordering infrastructure.
So after getting the connection settings we can easily register Dbcontext object for that purpose.
I'm going to uncomment this section of the code.
You can come here and see that we basically use services at Dbcontext and adding the application DB
context.
If you come here and you can using the ordering infrastructure data namespace.
And after that we can come here and options use SQL server and we will using Microsoft Entity Framework
Core.
So after adding these namespaces you can see that we will register application DB context with the dependency
injection container and configures it to use SQL server with the specified connection string.
So at DB context is an extension method for adding database context services to Entity Framework core.
You can see that we have lots of using statements for that purpose.
I'm going to create a new class under the ordering infrastructure which name is global using.
And I am going to moving these mostly using packages namespaces in the global using statement which
is the ordering infrastructure data.
And also I would like to move in here which is the Microsoft Entity Framework core.
So come here and move these two using statement into the global using save this file.
If you go back to dependency injection I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement including data
and infrastructure.
So these are the extension namespaces is regarding only these dependency injection class that are not
using commonly for each operation in the ordering infrastructure.
So as you can see that we have successfully registered application DB context into dependency injection
class.
And we have encapsulated all infrastructure related services into one place.