In this video we are going to do step six which is create Entity Framework core migrations for application
DB context in ordering infrastructure.
But before that, let's understand what is Entity Framework core migrations.
Entity framework core migrations are a powerful feature for managing database schema changes in an application's
life cycle.
They enable a developer to evolve a database schema in a controlled and consistent way, in line with
the domain model.
Changes in real world projects.
Data models change.
As features get implemented, new entities or properties are added and removed, and database schemas
need to be changed accordingly to be kept in sync with the application.
Migrations provide a way to incrementally update the database schema so that it stays in synchronous
with the application's data model.
It is especially useful in team environment and continuous deployment scenarios, where database schema
changes are frequent and need to be applied systematically.
So how Entity Framework core migration works when a data model change occurs, developers use Entity
Framework core Tools in order to create a corresponding migration folder that describes the necessary
database updates.
Entity Framework Core compares the current model against a snapshot of the previous model in order to
find differences and generate migration source files.
Once any migration has been generated, it can be applied to a database in various ways.
Entity framework Core records all applied migrations in a special history table, allowing it to know
which migrations has been applied and which haven't.
So we will use Entity Framework core code first approach in our application.
We have already followed the Entity Framework Core Code first approach with creating Dbcontext class,
developing entity class and configure Entity Framework core entities in the configuration files.
Now it is time to perform migrations.
In this approach, database creation and schema updates are driven by the entity class and the Dbcontext
configurations in the application.
That means, first of all, we should complete the development of the entity class configurations and
Dbcontext classes.
After that, we can run the Entity Framework core migration commands.
So we are at this stage of the running Entity Framework core migration commands.
So how we can run these Entity Framework core migration commands.
In order to create database we have two ways to perform this command.
The first one is using the dotnet core CLI.
We can follow the dotnet f and Microsoft Entity Framework core design packages for cross platform command
line tooling, including the dotnet command.
First of all, we will install the dotnet f global tool, and after that we will add the package which
name is design.
And after that we can run the migrations to create migration folder with running dotnet f migrations.
Add an initial create which is the name of the the first initial migration folder, and after that we
can perform these migrations to the database with running dotnet f database update.
But the second way is using the Package Manager console.
In Visual Studio we can use Microsoft Entity Framework core tools, NuGet packages for PowerShell tooling
that works in the Visual Studio Package Manager console.
So in this case we will install the package which name is tools NuGet package, and after that we can
run the Add migrations initial Create and update database command.
In the Package Manager console in order to create migration folder and update the database.
So we will use and follow the second way when we are developing our application, I'm using Visual Studio
and Package Manager Console.
That's why we have installed these tools NuGet packages.
Now it is time to run these commands under the Package Manager console.
And before that I'm going to show Entity Framework Core migrations.
Add migration command parameters that we can define when running our commands.
You can see that we can give the name of the migrations, which is the name of the migration.
And here you can see output tier which is the directory where migration files will be created.
And here you can see the namespace.
This is the namespace for generated classes.
And we can specify the context.
This is the context class that we can use.
And also we can specify the project.
This is the project containing the context.
And we can also specify the startup project.
This is the project with the configurations and settings.
At this stage we have a special consideration for different assemblies.
Since we are applying the clean architecture or infrastructure layer and Dbcontext class starting on
the ordering infrastructure.
But our API layer is different layer, which is the presentation layer that we need to consider the
different assemblies when generating the migrations and running the migration commands.
If the Dbcontext class is in different assembly than the startup project, you need to specify both
target and startup project, either in the Package Manager console tools or the dotnet core CLI tools.
So we will use the startup project, and the startup project will be the ordering API.
And we will use the target project, which is the Dbcontext object for the ordering infrastructure layer.