In this video we are going to create Entity Framework core migrations for application DB context in
ordering infrastructure.
So that means after setting up the Entity Framework Core Context object and configure these entities
into our configuration classes, the next step is generate and apply migrations in order to create or
update the database schema on our SQL server.
So to perform the migrations, there are several steps to generate and apply these migrations.
Please follow me carefully, because this is the crucial step that we are going to create migrations
and run these migrations.
So the first step is we should ensure the correct startup project.
So if you look at the our ordering microservices, we will follow the clean architecture.
And you should set a startup project for ordering API.
I'm going to right click and set a startup project.
And make sure that ordering API is set as startup project.
This is necessary because Entity Framework core tools will look for the database related configurations
like connection string in the startup project.
That's why the application settings storing the database connection string and these API project should
be set as startup project.
And the second step is we should specify the target and startup project in the command.
So when running the migration command, we should explicitly specify both the target and the startup
project.
This is important if your DB context object is in different project, in our case our db context object
storing under the ordering infrastructure and application db context.
So we should explicitly specify the target and startup project in the Package Manager console tool or
the dotnet core CLI tool.
Since I'm going to use Visual Studio, I'm going to use Package Manager Console for that purpose, you
can go to Visual Studio Vive, and in the Vive window you can go to the other windows.
And if you come here you can see the Package Manager console.
Click this Package Manager console and open your Package Manager console.
And as you can see, that Package Manager console, including the package source and the default project
in this window, I'm going to change the default project name from ordering API to ordering infrastructure,
because we will run the migration command where the application DB context is stored, which is the
ordering infrastructure.
After changing the default project, we can run the add migration command, which is including the add
migration initial create, which is the name of the migration, and we can specify the properties like
output tier which is the data migration folder.
And I'm going to specify the project which is the default project ordering infrastructure.
And we have to specify the startup project which is the ordering API.
This is important to running this add migration command with giving these properties, specifying the
target and startup project explicitly.
If you are using the.
Net CLI, you can run dotnet f migrations command with passing these parameters dash or dash p and dash
s commands in here.
So I'm going to follow the Visual Studio and Package Manager console.
And after writing this command I'm hitting the enter and see what's going on.
So this will be start to build our application.
And after that we can see that we got exception.
Which name is your startup project?
Ordering?
API doesn't reference Microsoft Entity Framework Core Design package, and this package required for
the Entity Framework core tools to work.
So we should ensure our startup project is correct.
Install the package and we will try again.
That means the startup project, which is the ordering API requiring to install design packages in order
to understand the whole application and reach the connection strings of our application, which is including
the application setting.
So as a solution, I am going to go to the ordering API and right click the dependencies and manage
NuGet packages.
In here.
I'm going to install Microsoft Entity Framework Core Design package into ordering API in order to access
application settings, connection settings, and so on.
So this is required for the clean architecture setup because in a clean architecture setup, it is a
common goal to encapsulate all data related concerns, including Entity Framework core dependencies
within the infrastructure layer.
However, the Entity Framework core tools, particularly for migrations, often need some more information
from the start up project, which is in our case, ordering API.
That's why the Entity Framework core tools are looking for the design packages in the startup project
that we have to install design package into ordering API.
So select the design package and install into ordering API.
And installation is completed.
You can verify from the ordering API project file.
The design package is located in here.
So if you go back to our package manager console and running the same command with setting the default
project ordering infrastructure, and you can hit the enter this time, this will be create our migration
folder under the Our Infrastructure project.
You can see that the migration completed successfully.
And here you can see the details as a log.
So if you go back to our infrastructure project you can see the data configurations.
And now we have created migration folder.
And under migration code folder we have two classes which is indicating our initial create the first
migration.
If you go to the our initial create class you can examine our up and down method.
You can see that we have two methods for up and down.
Up for the creating a migrations in the database and down for the rollback the changes from the database.
So in the up method you can see that we basically create a table which name is customers products orders
with a given and specifying configurations that we have defined the value object as a complex type in
here you can see that comes in here billing address and address line country and so on.
And these are the value object definitions and relationships and enumerations are configuring according
to our configuration classes.
That is generating the migration folder that is going to create our update the database table on SQL
server.
In the down method this will be dropped two tables.
And because this is the first migration that we are going to apply for the initial create of the ordering
tables, for example, we can also check the relationships.
If you scroll down and go to the Order and Order item table.
For example, in order Item table, you can see that we have two foreign key, one for the order ID
and another for the product ID these columns will be generated with using these migration folder.
So after generating these migration class we should run additional command which is the update database.
I'm going to open the Package manager console and run the second command, which is the update database
command.
In order to reflect these class to do our SQL server database, this command is going to apply these
migrations to the SQL server.
And I'm going to hit the enter and see what's going on.
This will be try to connect SQL server with ordering API application settings in order to affect these
changes to the database.
But we didn't create a SQL server database as a backing services in docker compose file yet, so we
have expecting a network related or instance specific error occurred when connecting communicating to
SQL server.
Yes, you can see that the exception comes as a network related and instance specific error when connecting
to SQL server.
Because we didn't create a SQL server image in our Docker environment, yet that means we should set
up the SQL server database using the docker compose file for multi-container Docker environment.