In this video, we are going to set up a SQL server database using docker compose file for multi-container
Docker environment.
Here you can see that our ordering microservices using SQL server database as a backing services.
So we should download SQL server Docker image and run this image into our Docker compose environment.
If we look at our deployment strategy, we are at the deployment.
One stage we are going to develop ordering microservices with clean architecture.
But now we will focus on activating SQL server database as a backing services in Docker compose files.
So how to set up the SQL server database in the environment?
I'm going to follow an article from the Microsoft documentation, which is the run SQL Server Linux
container image with Docker.
If you scroll down, you can see that we will use Microsoft SQL server Docker image with running docker
pull command.
And here you can see the environment variables and the port numbers that we are going to follow when
defining these image into our Docker compose file.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio.
And I'm going to use docker compose file in order to activate SQL server.
If you close these folders and go to the Docker compose files, you can see that we have docker-compose.yml
file and docker compose overwrite yaml file.
So that means we will update these files in order to include SQL server docker image.
And also we will set the environment variables and ports under the docker compose or write file to configure
SQL server database with necessary environment variables and so on.
So let me start with the docker-compose.yml file.
As you can see that it is starting with the backing services and continue with to microservices and
come here after the distributed cache as a backing services I'm going to add a new service which is
the order DB, and make sure that you have correct indentation.
This is important to activate these services correctly.
We are providing order db.
And as an image I'm going to copy from the Microsoft SQL server.
The image from the Docker Hub.
So this is the definition of the Docker-compose.yml file that you can save this file.
And in order to configure these SQL server database, I'm going to open the Docker compose overwrite
file and go to the same location which is the after distributed cache.
And before starting to microservices, we can specify the configurations about the SQL server.
SQL server has a environment and port numbers that we should define according to our article.
If you come here and put these order db, we can give a container name as a order db.
And here you can see the environment variables are crucial when implementing the SQL server docker image.
The except error should be y and C.
Password should be the complex password that we can connect for the SQL server.
Login with the same username and password.
In here we can confirm the password from the application settings file that we defined as a and password.
In the Application settings connection string, we can follow the same configurations in the docker
compose or write file for order db, SQL server, docker image and we will give the port numbers.
Also crucial.
This is the port number.
Default port number, which is the one four, three three is exposed and mapped to the host for database
connectivity.
As you can see that we have defined Docker compose, overwrite HTML file and docker compose Yaml file
in order to activate SQL server database as a backing service of authentic microservices.