In this video, we are going to run Docker Compose on Visual Studio in order to activate SQL server
database on the environment.
For that purpose, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running on your computer.
And after that we will run the Docker compose using the Visual Studio.
So please open the Visual Studio and we are going to come here as a Docker compose.
Right click Docker Compose and set a startup project.
By this way we can run the docker compose Yaml file to activate our backing services.
So after setting the startup project we can run without debugging.
So come here and click this button in order to execute Docker compose project without debugging.
And if you click this button this will start building and running the containers defined in our Docker-compose.yml
and overwrite Yaml files without debugging profile.
And these will be run docker compose up command, and you can verify the SQL server container from the
Docker desktop.
If you open the Docker desktop, there is nothing happened yet because this is going to pulling the
latest Docker image in here.
After waiting a certain time, we can reach the SQL Server Docker image on Docker desktop.
If you open the desktop, you can see that our Docker compose is up and running and Oldroyd-b comes
in the picture.
And if you click the order db container, you can see the logs.
That means we have successfully activated SQL server database on our Docker environment.
So now in order to connect these SQL server I'm going to use SQL Server Object Explorer into the Visual
Studio.
Here you can see that I'm going to close these windows.
If you come to view and open the SQL Server Object Explorer, you can reach the SQL Server Object Explorer
window located in here.
So I'm going to open these SQL servers and I'm going to connect to localhost.
For that purpose we can add a new server into our databases.
If you click this button add SQL server we can define the server name or server name is localhost and
authentication should be SQL server authentication, username should be SA and the password should be
the 1 to 8 that we have defined.
Complex password under the our application settings Json file and give the password.
And after that we can continue to encrypt property.
This should be false.
And the trust server certificate should be true.
This is for development purpose that we can connect our SQL server database in Docker environment.
Click the connect button and this will be.
Communicate to our SQL server Docker image under this localhost server.
If you expand this server and refresh this page databases, you can see that there is no databases because
we didn't create any database into our SQL server database server yet.
So if you open the ordering infrastructure and go to data migrations.
In the last video, we have generated the migration folders with using the Package Manager console.
But when we run the update database command, we got the exception about the network related exceptions
when connecting the SQL server.
But now we have activated the SQL server using the Docker compose that we can run this command in order
to create our database and tables into our SQL server database.