In this video, we are going to apply Entity Framework Core migrations to SQL server database with using
update database command.
So in the previous videos we will apply the migrations and create the migration folder.
And remember that before you can run the update database command, you must first generate the migrations
using the Add Migration command.
If you open the Visual Studio, come to Package Manager Console.
Before running the update database, you have to run add migration, initial, create and give these
specifications and properties.
When creating these migration folder.
If you open the migration folder, you can see that we have successfully create initial create an op
method.
This will be create all tables into our SQL server database.
So that means if you change anything on your DB context and the properties of the entities.
For example, if you change or add new property into product entity, you can delete the whole migration
folder and rerun these apply command in the Package Manager console.
Add migration in order to create new migrations and generate the latest codes into the SQL server database.
For that purpose, we have already generated the migrations and we have already up command, which is
the up to date.
I'm going to open the Package Manager console and run the update database command and make sure that
your default project is ordering infrastructure.
And before running this command, also make sure that your ordering API should be set as startup project.
Right click Set Startup Project for ordering API and open the Package Manager console the default project
ordering infrastructure and hit the update database command.
This command will be run all migration codes and create database and tables that we have applied these
migrations to the SQL server database.
So you can see the logs in here.
This is running SQL commands onto our database including the create table commands.
For example this is creating order table including these columns.
And after that execute DB command which is the create table for order items.
And here you can see that we will create the indexes foreign keys and so on.
So we have successfully running the update database command.
And this will be run these commands generating from the our migrations folder.
And now I am going to verify migrations execution onto the these SQL Server Object Explorer Object Explorer.
You can see that there is no databases under our local SQL server database.
If I refresh this page, you can open and open a database.
This time you can see that our order DB is generating and created successfully.
And if you expand this order db and expand the tables, we can see that our customers ordered order
items and product table is comes into our order DB database.
That means we have successfully applied Entity Framework core migrations to SQL server database, creating
the necessary schema for the ordering microservices.