In this video we are going to do step seven which is Auto Migrate Entity Framework core entities to
SQL server database when application start up with coding.
So that means we will apply Entity Framework core migrations to the SQL server database using the coding
instead of the running update database command.
So if you remember the previous videos, if you go to the step six, you can see that we have running
two commands when we apply Entity Framework core code.
First approach to the SQL server database.
These are the add migration command and update database command.
In the first command which is created migrations folders and classes, and the second command is.
Apply these classes on database by connecting the SQL server with application settings Json file connection
string.
But when we deploy all microservices using Docker Compose, we can't run update database command for
every deploy operation.
Instead of that, one of the good practice is migrate Entity Framework core classes.
When the application start up using the ASP.Net Core Middleware extensions.
So now we can start to development of these auto migrate operation.
As you can see the example code, we will use application DB context.
And we will use context database and migrate async command in order to run update database command.
So for that purpose please open the Visual Studio and go to the Program.cs.
In ordering API, we have program says that we can add the services into ASP.Net container, and we
can also configure the Http request pipelines.
So in here we will add logic in the Program.cs in order to execute database migrations on the startup
of this application.
And this can be achieved by adding a custom extension method that applies the migration.
If you look at the program says, you can see that we have already developed an extension.
Methods.
When registering different layers, including the add application infrastructure and API services.
And if you go to the add API services, which is located under the dependency injection of the ordering
API, you can see that we will add required services into the service collection and for API services.
We have also one more method which is the use API services in order to configure the Http request lifecycle.
And this will be adding extension method on the web application object.
So I'm going to use these API services in the program says because we will use these app dot use API
services after the following videos.
And after these using API services, we can configure our application in order to automate and see the
operation.
So when configuring the ASP.Net Http request pipeline, it is a good place to database initialization
creation and seeding operation.
And we will perform these operation with extension method.
But of course this kind of operation should fall only do development environments for that purpose.
I'm going to put a if statement app dot environment dot is development environment and after confirm
that it is a development environment we can run awaits app dot are custom extension method which will
be the initialize database async method that we are going to develop in this video.
So please also develop these if statement under the these configured Http request pipelines.
And we will put a if statement for its development.
And after that we will develop our custom extension method to perform auto migrate and sync operations.
So now it is time to create an extension method for database initialization.
And I'm going to put this extension method under the ordering infrastructure.
For that purpose please go to the Ordering Infrastructure project.
And under the data folder I'm going to create a new folder.
Which name is extensions.
If you right click and add new subfolder which name is extensions.
We can create all data related extensions under this folder.
And I'm going to add a new class which name is Database extensions dot CSS.
So we will implement these initialized database async method in this place.
And this method will handle the logic to apply Entity Framework core migrations.
So for that purpose please remove the unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And now start for the extension development.
First of all, this class should be a static class in order to create an extension method.
And after that we can define our method body which is the public static async, and this will be return
a task.
And the name of the custom extension method is initialize database async.
And as a parameter we can give these web application and app.
So we will put these extension method.
On the web application object.
So after that we can create a scope which will be getting a service scope for us.
And after getting this scope operation we can get required services which is our application DB context.
And in here you can see that we get the application db context using the scope dot service provider
dot get required services and we have required application db context in order to run my get async command.
And with using this context object, we can run context database and migrate async command.
And this will be perform update command operation.
And I'm going to use my get async method.
And after that I would like to use get Awaiter and get result method.
So these will be provided to wait until my get operation complete.
And this will be return task operation when the whole migration is completed.
So basically this calls make update database command operations.
That means running the SQL scripts on the SQL server database.
After developing these extension method, it is time to modify the Program.cs to call these initialized
database async method during the application startup in development environment.
For that purpose, please open the ordering API and Program.cs and come to the displays after the configured
Http request pipeline.
And here you can see that this is getting exception.
In order to do that, I'm going to put a alt enter and adding using statement which is the ordering
infrastructure data and extensions.
And after that you can save these Program.cs and these will be provided to our operation in the if statement.
Basically these initialize database async method is invoked only if the environment is development,
and this ensures that the database is updated with the latest migrations upon the application startup.