In this video we are going to do step eight, which is seeding a SQL server order DB using the Entity
Framework core when application startup with coding.
So this process involves populating the database with initial data, which is particularly useful for
development and testing environments.
So please open the Visual Studio.
In the last video we have created an extension method and called this extension method in the Program.cs.
When application start up here, you can see that we call initialize database async extension method.
So in this method we migrate and created Entity Framework core entities into SQL server database tables.
Just after that, it is good to see the database tables so we can create code structure for seeding
database into this extension method.
If you right click and go to definition, you can see that this method is located under the Ordering
Infrastructure extensions and Database extensions.
Yes.
And right after the migrate async operation and performing these migrate operation, we can seeding
our tables and databases in this extension method.
For that purpose, let's plan our codes after these migrate operations.
So first of all we will implement these settings in this line of codes.
That means I'm going to modify this method to include seeding operations just after the applying the
migrations here you can see that I'm going to add a new function which name is seed async.
And passing this context object as a parameter of this method.
And after that we can implement these seeding methods with creating methods for seeding each table.
For example, in our model you can see that we have customer order, order item and product entities
that we are going to seed each table in this method.
For that purpose, I'm going to develop and implement this method as a private static async method.
Just after the developing our extension method in here, you can see that we call seed async method.
This is the private static async task method and accepting the application db context as a parameter.
So in this method we basically seeding tables one by one.
So I'm going to implement these seeding table operations.
Here you can see that seeding customer product order and order item async functions located under the
seed async method.
And after that I'm going to create a new method.
For each seed operation we will develop seed customer async method just after the seed async method.
So in this method we are also taking the application db context as a parameter.
But this time we will check that if there is any customer inside of the database table or not.
If not any table including any row about the customers, we can use context customer at range async
method which passing the customers from the initial data class.
And after that we can save changes async method.
So basically this is one of the customer seeding method that provide that.
This method checks that if the table are empty and if so, populate them with the predefined data which
comes from the initial data that customers.
So we can follow the same steps for the other entities.
But before that, you can see that in order to adding the seeding data, we are using the initial data
dot customer.
That means we will create additional class which name is initial data initial data class, including
static properties, in order to provide the initial set of the data for seeding.
For that purpose, I'm going to create a new class under the extensions folder.
So I'm going to add a new class which name is initial data and this will be internal class initial data
removing unnecessary using statement.
And in this class I'm going to create some of the properties which is a static properties.
Returning the list of the initial data, including our entities.
For example, in here I'm creating public static IEnumerable customer customers property and it is returning
new list of the customers.
And I'm going to use customer dot create method, which is the a rich domain model.
And we are going to create the new with customer ID using the strongly type IDs.
And after that these are the predefined values that we are going to use when seeding our customer entity
table when the application start up.
So initial data provide a set of predefined data for our entities.
Here you can see the two customers seeding into our table.
And this method will be using one or seed operations happened in the database extensions.
You can come here and see that when seeding customer async method we use add range async.
That accepting an array of the customer records into the customer saving operation.
So if you go back to our initial data, you can see that we are using two statements, which is the
come from the ordering domain layer.
I'm going to move these using statements to our global using into ordering infrastructure.
If you go here and copy paste these using statements for the ordering domain layer, you can move that
global using.
And if you come back to initial data this will be activated.
Or customer create operation and customerid the operation from the domain layer.
So as you can see that the seeding process is part of the or I initial database async method.
And just after the migrate operation we perform the seed operations.
And first of all we will seeding the customer data using the I initial data that customers.