In this video, we are going to continue seed operations with product and order tables in SQL server
database.
Previously we have developed initialized database async method and after migrate operation we will perform
seed async method.
And in this method you can see that we will implement only seed customer async method to performing
adding range of the customer array into customer's table.
But now in this video we will focus on seeding product and order and order items.
So I'm going to open these command codes and comes here.
You can see that seed async functions including three functions.
Now this will be seeding customer product order and order items.
If you scroll down you can see that we will continue our static async methods for each entity.
And this was the customer entity.
And I'm going to follow the same steps for product and order and order items.
So come here.
And just after this method you can create any private static async method which name is seed product
async.
And this will be also executing context object which is our application db context.
And in here we will follow the same steps.
First of all we have checked if there is any product into database exists or not.
If not exist we will apply the add range async method with passing the product array into the products
entity.
And after that we will save changes async to reflect these new records into the database.
And after seeding the products, we will follow the same steps for seed order and items async method.
So after this method I'm going to create a new method which name is seed orders with items async method.
And this is also private static async method and accepting the application db context.
And we have followed the same steps.
First of all, we will check if there is any orders in the database.
If not, we will use ad range async method in order to add orders array into the orders entity of the
SQL server.
So these are the seed product and orders method.
As you can see that these methods are expecting initial data properties, which are the static properties
in the initial data class to provide initial data for product and orders.
For that purpose, I am going to open the initial database and after defining the customers property,
we will follow the same steps for the products and orders.
And here you can see the products static property which is the public static IEnumerable product, which
name is products property.
And here you can see that we are returning a new list product and this will be including for new product
using the product dot create method.
And inside of this method we will passing the product id using the product id of strongly type IDs to
generating these with id and following that, you can see that I'm going to add new for product with
different prices.
So you can confirm these product create operation in your initial data class operation.
And just after that I'm going to create orders with items for that purpose.
I'm going to create an additional static and IEnumerable order property.
And here you can see that this is long property, which is the public static IEnumerable order order
with items.
And in the getter of these property, you can see that we have defined two new address and two new payment
in order to prepare for creating orders.
So these are the address and payment value objects that we defined predefined values.
And after that we have create a new order using the order create method and passing the order ID, customer
ID, order name, shipping and billing address and payment information.
And after created a order one we can adding new products which are the ID information comes from the
above of this property and passing the quantity and price.
And just after that we have create order to including a different order ID, customer ID, order name,
shipping and billing address and payment to the value object.
And we have added different two products into this order.
And we are going to return these order one and order two as a generated predefined seating order tables.
So make sure that and note that we have using the different grid IDs and passing the same IDs when creating
order.
So this is crucial when making consistency between table rows, including the customer product order
with items.
So you can copy this code and initial data from the GitHub of our repository in order to seeding our
operations in the database extensions.
And by this way, we will execute these codes automatically when the application start up into our initial
database async method.
So here you can see that we got an exception which is the seed order and items async method.
If you scroll down you can see that the method name is different.
You can see that we will use order in here.
We can use orders in here.
I'm going to copy this method and make this method seed orders with items in this method.
So after that you can come here and right click.
And building the ordering API make sure that your codes are building successfully.
This setup provides that SQL server ordered DB database populated with essential data for customers,
products and orders when application startup.