In this video, we are going to run ordering microservices to automatically migrate and see the order
DB in SQL server using the Entity Framework core.
When the application start up for that purpose, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running.
And after that, if you open the Visual Studio and go to Docker Desktop, you can right click and set
a startup project, and you can click run button without debugging in order to activate SQL server database
image up and running.
So after running this docker compose up command with using Visual Studio, you can confirm from the
Docker compose into Docker Desktop.
Here you can see that our order db image is up and running now, so that means we can verify the SQL
server communication from the Visual Studio.
If you open the SQL Server Object Explorer and connect to localhost under the SQL server, you can connect
to localhost and under the localhost you can browse the databases.
If you expanding the databases, you can see that we don't have any database under our localhost connection.
So if there is order db please remove it because we will create with coding one application startup
with following the migration folder.
But at least we can verify that we have communicated to SQL server database successfully.
And we don't have any databases.
So now I'm going to start ordering API application.
And please come here and right click Set Startup Project for ordering API.
And after that before starting this application go to program.cs and put a breakpoint under this if
statement.
And this will be running when the application start up.
And after that this extension method will be hit the debugger.
Put a breakpoint at the beginning of this initialize database async method.
This will be performed.
Migrate operation and see the operation at the same method.
And you can also put breakpoint in here, which is the seed async method.
So after that we can right click set startup project ordering API.
And we are going to run ordering API in https mode.
If you hit the https button this will be start ordering API and this will be trigger our Program.cs.
When the application start up, we are going to check if the environment is development or not.
We are at development environment and in here we are going to start the initialize database async extension
method.
And in this method we will create scope.
And after that we will get the application db context from this scope.
And using this context object in order to run migrate commands which are the running the migration folder
and create database and create columns for each tables.
And this will be provide the update command operation with coding.
And here you can see that these operations take some time in order to create database and tables and
columns and so on.
After the schema is created successfully, we will we will continue to our seed operation.
In here you can see that the migration is completed successfully.
And after that it is continuing the seeding operation.
As a seeding operation.
We will see the customers product and orders.
You can go to details and see that if there is no customer, this will be adding range from the our
initial data class and save change async.
And if you continue with the products, if there is no products, you can see that new product is adding
from the initial data.
We will add four products and save change async.
That means save the tables on database and we will follow all the same steps for order and order items
from the database operation.
Here you can see that we got exception, which is the argument out of range exception.
So that means we are at the order name record type.
And when we are trying to saving order name with a default length, default length is five.
But we are trying to insert new order name which value length is seven.
So I'm going to continue this exception and throwing and accepting exiting these operation.
So if you go to the initial data you can see that when we are saving the orders as a order name, we
are using the order one and order two.
But in the order name value object, you can see that we have a business exception about that.
The length should not be greater than five.
For that purpose, I'm going to calculate these names and change the names according to maximum character
should be five.
For that purpose.
Please change these order names as the order code.
For example order one which is including only five character.
And in here you can come here or the underscore two.
This will be also five character.
And save these initial data and run these application from the scratch.
And this will be restart again the ordering API operations and restart for migrate and seeding operation.
I'm going to follow the same steps.
And in here you can see that we will perform the migrate operation.
And after that continue the seeding operation.
And.
And this time I'm going to continue and go to the seed orders with items.
If there is no order items, we are going to save this order item into database and this time we will
perform the saving operation successfully.
Hit F5 and complete the starting operation.
That means complete the migrate and seeding operation.
We can verify database create and seeding operation from the SQL Server Object Explorer.
If you come here and connect to localhost and refresh this databases, and this time you can see that
we have ordered the DB database.
And if we expand this database and expand the tables, you can see that our tables entity tables are
created successfully.
If you right click the orders and view data, we can verify the seeding operations performed successfully
in the orders table.
And also you can right click products and View data.
You can see the new orders and products also created successfully.
So as you can see that when we are starting the ordering microservices, the SQL server database order
db is automatically created and the necessary tables are created and seeded with initial data on the
application startup.
You can also confirm all these processes in the logs of the ordering microservices.
Here you can see that when the application start up, first of all, we will perform the migrate operations
with running the create database command.
And after that we will performing the seeding operations with running the insert into commands.