In this video we are going to learn Entity Framework Core Interceptors, which is save Change interceptor
for auditing entities.
Interceptors in Entity Framework Core enable the interception, modification or suppression of Entity
Framework core operations.
These include low level database operations such as executing a command, as well as higher level operations
such as the cost to save changes.
So let me explain.
Save changes interceptions the save changes and save changes.
Async interceptions points are used to execute custom logic when saving changes to the database.
These interceptions points are defined by the I save change interceptor interfaces.
Entity Framework Core provides a save change interceptor base class with no operation methods as a convenience.
So let's see one of the use case when saving changes.
Interception for auditing.
Interception of save changes can be used to create an independent audit record of the change.
This is useful for maintaining a history of who changed an entity and when changed this entity.
Before saving changes to the database, you can iterate through the changed entities in the DB context
and lock or store the audit information like timestamps or user identifiers.
Now we can learn how to register interceptors so how we can register interceptors.
Interceptors are registered using the add interceptors.
When configuring a Dbcontext instance, a common approach is usually done in the on configuring method
of the Dbcontext.
As an example, you can see how to register a save change interceptor into the DB context object.
Here you can see that we have a example db context.
And when configuring these db context, we can add interceptors with using the add Interceptors method
into these on configuring method.
And here you can see that we have added text query command interceptors.
Now I am going to explain how we can implement a custom save change interceptor into our codes.
We can use custom interceptor.
We will implement a custom interceptor by extending save change interceptor or implementing I save change
Interceptor interface.
So this will be done with typical overriding methods.
We can override methods like saving changes and save changes to execute custom logic.
And here you can see an example of the save change interceptor implementation for auditing.
You can see that this will be inherited from the save change interceptor.
And this is our class for interceptor.
And we will override saving changes in order to perform auditable entities with setting the created
at and created by columns in the Saving Change Interceptor.
So we will follow the same steps when implementing our entities and using Entity Framework.
Core interceptors for auditing is a powerful technique to inject custom behavior during the lifecycle
of the Dbcontext operations.