In this video we are going to develop save Change Interceptor in order to auditing entities for order
entity.
So this interceptor will automatically set the auditing fields such as the created at, created by,
last modified and last modified by columns whenever entities are added or modified.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the Ordering infrastructure and under data folder we are
going to create a new subfolder which is the interceptors.
Right click data and add new subfolder which is the interceptors.
So in the interceptors folder I'm going to create a new class which name is Auditable Entity Interceptor.
So come here and create a new class auditable entity interceptor dot CSS.
And we will implement this interceptor into the this class.
Before start implementing remove unnecessary using statements and make this class as a public.
The first thing we should implement the base class which is the save change interceptor.
Come here and implement Save Change interceptor which comes from the Entity Framework Core Diagnostic.
And we are going to inherit from this class in order to override saving changes method.
After that, we should define the methods to override.
We override the saving changes and saving change.
Async method not saved changes.
If you type to override in the beginning of this class, you can see that there are lots of methods
that we can override into our custom interceptor, and specifically we are looking for the saving changes.
But here you can see that there are saved changes methods that we can override.
But please make sure that you have selecting the saving changes because if you select the saved change,
the entity status will be disappeared and performing after the saving changes.
But specifically we are writing these custom interceptor for auditing entities when saving the changes.
So please select this overwrite method.
The first one is saving changes and the second one is saving changes.
All right saving changes.
Async I'm sorry.
The second method is saving changes async method.
So here you can see that we have implemented two Overrideable method into our custom interceptor.
Now we can implement our actual logic for auditing entities.
In these methods we can audit the entities.
But before that I'm going to show you a base abstract entity class into the auditing domain.
If you go to ordering domain you can see the modules are creating in here.
For example I'm going to open an example customer model entity.
And here you can see that this is inherit from the entity base class.
If you go to definition of these entity base class.
And this is the abstract class that you can see, the members are including auditable members which
including created at created by last modified and last modified by.
That means every entity class has these audit columns that we need to set during the Entity Framework
Core saving change operation.
So we will set and load these values for every saving operation into Entity Framework Core.
For that purpose, go back to Interceptors and Auditable Entity Interceptor, and we are going to update
the entities before saving the changes.
Come here and I'm going to create a new method which name is update entities method that checks the
entity state and update the audit fields accordingly.
But before that you can see the method signature.
As you can see that these saving changes method is accepting the Dbcontext event data that we can access
the context object inside of these event data.
And the second parameter is result.
And the third parameter is Cancellationtoken for asynchronous Overridable function.
So we are going to use event data in order to reach context object.
You can come here and see that context object is reachable which is a db context into our application.
So I'm going to use a new method which is the update entities and passing context object as a parameter
of this method, and copy this method and paste into beginning of the hour saving change async operation.
By this way, we can perform the update entities before saving change and saving change async method
into these custom interceptor.
But of course I'm going to create our update entities method after this class definition.
And in this method we basically get the db context object as a parameter.
And if the context is null, I'm going to return back to the method.
If not null, we can iterate the entities and check the entity state according to the entity state.
We can set the auditable columns here.
You can see the for each statement and we will basically.
The context change tracker entries, which is inherited from the I entity.
And with looking these entries, I'm going to check the entry state.
If the entry state is added, which means this is the new record, we can set the created add and created
by columns, but if the entry state is added or modified, we can set the modified auditable columns
which including the last modified and last modified by.
Here you can see the if statement.
In this if statement we have checked entity state is added or modified.
And also we have some custom extension method which is the has changed owned entities.
So I'm going to create and develop these custom extension method in order to understand these entity
changed owned entities.
So you can come here and close the for each statement.
And after these update entities and go to the class definitions.
At the end of this class definition we can create a new class which name is extension static class.
And I'm going to develop has changed owned entities on the entity entity extension method.
And this method basically identify the owned entities has changed or not.
It is looking for the target entity state.
And if the target entity state is added or modified, this will be indicating the changed owned entity.
And we will populate the last modified by and last modified columns into the actual update entities
method.
So after developing these interceptor, it is time to register the interceptor into our Program.cs.
But before that I'm going to arrange our global using statement.
Here you can see that this is required for the abstractions folder from the domain.
And also we have created a new namespace under Data Interceptors.
So I'm going to add these using statements under the global using.
Come here and make global using for the ordering domain abstractions.
Also I'm going to add a new global using for data column data folder.
Under data folder we have created an interceptors that we are going to use in the Program.cs when registering
this interceptor.
So now it is time to register these custom interceptor.
For that purpose I'm going to open the program CSS.
If you open the program CSS of the ordering API, you can see that we have registered our services according
to clean architecture layers.
So for Entity Framework Core interceptors we should register into the infrastructure services.
If you right click and go to definition of this extension method, you can see the dependency injection
class under the ordering infrastructure layer.
So when we are registering our DB context object, we can set up our interceptor and register in this
place.
For that purpose I'm going to locate the add db context operation.
And when setting the options I'm going to extend these options as a curly breaker and setting these
options as a use SQL server as expected.
And before that, I'm going to also set the options that add interceptors method and setting the newly
created auditable entity.
Inside of this add interceptor method, I'm going to use Neve Auditable Entity Interceptor, and this
will be provided to interceptors added to DB context object.
Enable automatic auditing whenever entities are saving and creating or updating.
So this is the registration step of the our custom entity interceptors.
By implementing the Auditable Entity Interceptor, we have automated the process of setting audit information
for all entities within our auditing microservices.