In this video, we are going to run and test our ordering microservices for testing auditable Entity
interceptor into our application.
Before we start, we should start the Docker desktop and make sure that your SQL server Docker image,
which is the order DB up and running.
If not, you can come here and right click the Docker compose, set a startup project and run without
debugging in order to activate backing services.
After activating the order DB, you can connect with using the SQL Server Object Explorer.
If you expand the localhost.
If you go to database, you will reach the order DB in here.
If you have order db, you can delete this database and after that we will recreate this database with
running the application and one application start up.
As you remember that we have auto migrate and seeding database with coding.
So we will follow the same steps.
If you have ordered DB please delete these order db.
And for this video we will test our custom interceptor.
Maybe you remember when we are seeding our database, you can see that our tables are populated with
data but auditable columns which including the last modified by or created at this kind of columns is
not populated when we are seeding database, but this time when we are seeding database.
This will be also populate the auditable columns with using the custom interceptor, which is the auditable
entity interceptor.
For that purpose, please put a breakpoint in the beginning of the saving change and saving Change async
method, and after that put a breakpoint into update entities.
So now after that, we can set a startup project ordering API and hit the https and run this application.
This will be start our application and when the application start up, we will auto migrate and seeding
our tables.
And we will use interceptors to populating the auditable columns.
Here you can see the Program.cs and hitting the initialize database async method.
And this will be basically migrate our tables and create database create tables.
After perform the migration we can start the seeding operation.
Here you can see that we will seed customers products and orders.
When we are seeding any entity, we can see that this will be performed.
Context dot save changes async method.
And whenever we are hitting these sales sales async method in the context method, this will be automatically
triggered.
Our interceptor which is the auditable entity interceptor and it is hitting the saving changes async
method which is the Overrideable method and interceptor interceptor save operations.
And comes to this point.
And at this point we will perform the update entities with using DB context object and with looking
to db context object, we are iterating the entities that we are going to perform and setting the auditable
columns.
Here you can see that these entity state is added, which means this is going to creating any record
in the customer entity.
That's why we are setting the entity created by and created at columns in here.
And after that, we can also set the last modified and last modified by columns, because this is also
including the edit entities into that place.
And after setting these columns we will continue to the next entity operations.
In this case we have adding two customer into customer entity.
That's why we are following the same steps for each row into entity.
And after updating entities, it is going to saving changes to the database.
And if I hit F5, this is going to follow the same steps for each entity when we are saving our tables
into the database.
So after completing this process, you can come here and check the Project console window.
And here you can see that the migration and also seeding operation completed.
We can follow with using the SQL statement.
In here you can see that we have completed the create database, create index foreign key and so on.
And in here you can see the insert into command to performing the seeding operations.
So to verify from this database you can come here and open the SQL Server Object Explorer.
And if you connect to localhost and SQL server database and refresh the databases this time you can
see that order db is created successfully.
And if we expand the tables we can see that our tables are created in here.
For example, I am going to right click customers and read data.
In this case this seeding operation performed successfully.
And also you can see that these auditable columns also populated in this application with using the
custom interceptor.