In this video, we are going to learn how to dispatch domain events using the Entity Framework core.
Save changes interceptor.
It is a crucial step when implementing domain driven design in e-commerce application like ordering
microservices.
But before that, let's remember what is domain events in domain driven design?
Domain events represent something that happened in the past and the other parts of the same service
boundary.
Same domain need to react to these changes.
A domain event is a business event that occurs within the domain model, and achieve consistency between
aggregates in the same domain, and when any order placed the order placed event might be triggered,
it triggered the side effects or notify other parts of the system about changes within the domain.
And also we can see how to use domain events in domain driven design.
It is basically encapsulate the event details and dispatch them to the interested parties and communicate
changes within the domain to external handlers, which may be perform actions based on these events.
And here you can see each sub domain.
Events in ordering microservices.
When a customer place an order a domain event, which name is order created, domain event is raised
that will trigger.
Several things need to happen like updating inventory, notifying the shipping department, and sending
an email for confirmation to the customer.
So all these actions can be triggered by throwing an order created domain event from the order aggregate.
So how we can dispatch these domain events.
How we can raise and dispatching domain events into our application.
So when we talk about the raising the event within the order aggregate, when order new order placed
and it adding an order created domain event to the collection of the domain event in the order aggregate.
So the question is how to dispatching these domain events.
So in order to dispatching this event, this will be typically done in the infrastructure layer and
often in the repository or unit of work.
That means after saving to do changes into database, the domain events are dispatched to their respective
handlers.
You can see that we have started with the entity.
In our case, this will be the order aggregate that include domain events list.
So whenever any order created this will be triggered order created, domain event and adding this domain
event into list of the domain events into the aggregate.
And after that there is a separate event dispatcher.
In our case this will be using Entity Framework code save change interceptor in order to dispatch these
domain events to the event consumers.
So why we use Entity Framework Core Save Change Interceptor for this action?
Because it is a best practice to use these Entity Framework core Save change interceptor for dispatching
domain events, because it allows you to hook into the lifecycle of database operations, particularly
after changes have been successfully committed.
So after deciding to using these save chains in Susceptor, we can go to the steps when implementing
dispatching domain events.
The first step is create a save change interceptor class.
We will implement a class that inherits from the save change interceptor and override methods like saving
changes or saving change async.
And the second step is identify and dispatch domain events.
In the override methods, we can check the Dbcontext for entities that have unprocessed domain events,
and after that we will dispatch these events using a mechanism like mediator.
That means we will use mediator library when dispatching these domain events.
And after that you can see we will use Domain Event Dispatcher interceptor class to perform these operations
and inherit from the save change interceptor.
And lastly we will register the interceptor.
In this step we will register the interceptor in the Dependency Injection class of our infrastructure
layer.
So dispatching domain events using the Entity Framework core Save Change Interceptor is a powerful approach
to handling business operations that are triggered by the changes in the domain.