In this video we are going to develop Dispatch Domain Events interceptor class in order to trigger domain
event handlers with using mediator library in the ordering microservices.
So for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and navigate to interceptors folder.
Under the data folder go to interceptors.
And in here we are going to create a new interceptor which name is Dispatch Domain Events Interceptor.
So add a new class which name is Dispatch Domain Events Interceptor and start developing our new interceptor.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this as a public class.
And we will start with inheriting from the save changes interceptor which comes from the our Entity
Framework core.
This is the important step when we are starting any interceptor.
It should be inherit from the save changes interceptor.
After that, the next important thing is overriding method.
If you come here and write the overwrite and you can see that there are lots of methods that we can
override when implementing our interceptor, and in here, make sure that we are going to use saving
changes, not saved changes.
This is important decision when you are implementing your interceptor for dispatching domain events,
we are going to use saving changes and saving changes async method.
For that purpose.
Please overwrite these methods one by one and prepare your method operations for saving change async
and saving changes under the dispatch domain Event Interceptor.
Now we can start our actual logic which is dispatching domain events.
But before that, let's understand what is domain event in our codes.
If you go to the ordering domain and go to abstractions, you can see that we have interface which name
is domain event.
And this interface implements I notification from the mediator.
So that means we are looking for the I domain interface when dispatching our domain events.
So if you look at the abstractions you can see that we have also I aggregate dot CSS and in this interface
is implementing I entity and I aggregate interface also including two members which are the domain event
list and the clear domain event method.
We can also see aggregate abstract class which is implementation of the I aggregate interface.
And in this base class we can see that we have domain event list.
And we will add and clear domain events into these aggregate class.
So now we can go back to our dispatch domain event interceptor.
And we will implement the logic in order to extract domain events from the aggregates and dispatch them.
So in here before saving change operations we are going to dispatching this event.
For that purpose I am going to create a new method which name is dispatch domain events and this method
require for the event Datacontext.
That means our DB context object and for saving changes, I'm going to use get Awaiter and Getresult
method to perform this operation completely.
And after that I'm going to copy this method and use in here with available function and using the dispatch
domain events method.
So that means we are going to develop dispatch domain events methods with async and available.
And as you can see that since we are making this function async, the return should be also available.
And now it is ready to implement our actual method which is the dispatch domain events.
After these methods, we can start developing for the dispatch domain events.
Here you can see that we have created public async task dispatch domain events method, which is parameters
of the DB context object.
And in the beginning of the method I'm going to check context is null or empty.
If the context is null, we can return empty response to dispatch domain event methods and after that
we can retrieve from the aggregates from the db context object.
Here you can see that we are looking for the DB context entities which implemented the I aggregate interface,
and that entities is including domain event list.
That means we are looking aggregates that including any domain events, and we are adding these aggregates
into this variable.
After that we can retrieve the domain events from this aggregate.
And if you come here and write the aggregates, select many with including domain events and convert
them to lists in order to get domain events from our aggregate entities.
And once we get the domain events, we can dispatch these events with using the mediator.
But before that, I am going to iterate the aggregate domain events and clear all domain events into
each entities and aggregates, because we will dispatching domain events and we would like to avoiding
duplicate dispatch.
That's why I'm going to clear domain events before dispatching these events.
So after clearing these domain events into aggregates, we can use domain event list in order to dispatch
these events and using the mediator publish method.
Here you can see that we have iterated domain event list.
And for each domain event we will use mediator dot publish method in order to dispatch these domain
event in the consumer side.
So as you can see that we need mediator package and mediator variable in order to publish these domain
event.
So how we can inject these mediator into our dispatcher.
And if you go on top of this page you can come here and inject AI mediator in the beginning of the class
with primary constructor.
So I am going to open a bracket and using I mediator interface in order to inject mediator into my class.
And in here, as you can see that we have injected AI mediator into our dispatch domain event interceptor.
And this mediator is using when we are dispatching domain events into method of the our main method
in the.
For each statement, we are using mediator that injected our interceptor.
So as you can see that we have completed our dispatch domain event interceptor class.
Now it is time to register these newly created interceptor into our Dependency Injection.
For that purpose you can go to the ordering Infrastructure and Dependency Injection CS.
In this class we will basically register interceptors when we are registering the Dbcontext object.
Here you can see that when we are adding Dbcontext object, we have adding the interceptor for naive
auditable entity interceptor in the previous videos.
Now I am going to add a new interceptor, which is the dispatch domain for that purpose.
I come here and using the Naive Dispatch Domain Events interceptor.
If we look at the interceptors in here, you can see that we have two interceptor.
But if we come here for dispatch domain events, you can see exception.
It is accepting mediator in the parameters of the interceptor.
Because we inject mediator in order to dispatch domain events in this class.
But to create our dispatch interceptor class it is required to pass mediator.
But we will register mediator in the application layer.
And it should be resolved by the ASP.Net Dependency Injection tool.
That means we cannot register by this way.
Instead of that, we will register an adding interceptor with using the Isafe changed interceptor interface,
and we will add scoped services in the beginning of this dependency injection.
And after that we will register and adding interceptors by this way.
So let me develop.
And after that I'm going to explain that.
So basically when we are adding services in the container I'm going to add scoped services for auditable
entity and dispatch domain events interceptors.
And this will be comes from the I save changes interceptor because for each interceptor you can see
that we have inherited from the save changed interceptor that is comes from the I save change interceptor
interface.
That's why before registering any services, we add scoped for each interceptor.
And after that we can add these interceptors in to do our add interceptor extension method when configuring
the Dbcontext object.
But this time we need service provider in order to get services from the I save changes async interfaces.
So come here and get the service provider with the options when configuring our Dbcontext.
And in here I'm going to remove new statements.
And we are going to use service Provider for getting services.
And getting services from the.
I saved Chang's Interceptor with using this way.
So please make sure that you can add these interceptors using the service provider and getting services
from the.
I saved Chang's Interceptor interface that we have added scoped in this line of codes.
So by this way, these dispatched Domain event interceptor can access to mediator and register the mediator
when creating these interceptor from these primary constructor injection.
But how we can get these I mediator and how we can register mediator into our application.
So if you go back to program.cs of the ordering API, you can see that we are accumulating all these
registrations according to clean architecture layers.
So that means before adding infrastructure services and registering interceptors we should register
the mediator into application service layers.
So I'm going to ensure that mediator is registered before registering the infrastructure services,
especially interceptors that require mediator interface for that purpose.
Right click this method and go to definition which is coming the ordering application dependency injection
case.
And in this service registration I am going to adding the mediator into our application.
You can see that we will use services dot add mediator method in order to register our I mediator operations
for the whole executing assembly.
And it is requiring for the assembly using statement which comes from the system reflection.
And make sure that you have added mediator into your application layer.
By this way ASP.Net resolve the mediator and inject our dispatch domain event interceptors when configuring
our infrastructure layer.
So now we can build our application from the ordering API.
Right click and build.
You can see that build completed successfully.
So with using the Mediator and Entity Framework core interceptors we achieve a clean and efficient way
to handle domain events.