In this video, we are going to run and test all the microservices for dispatching domain events using
the Entity Framework Core Interceptor, which is the dispatch domain event interceptor.
So before we start, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running and ensure that order DB is
up and running.
So you can also verify these order db to connecting from Visual Studio if you open the SQL Server Object
Explorer, if you connect to localhost, you can see that order db is created in the previous videos.
I'm going to delete this database in order to recreate these migrations into our application.
When the application start up, please delete order db and after that we can restart our application
and this will be run migrations.
But before that please make sure that put a break points before saving the changes into our interceptor
and see how we can trigger our interceptors when saving the orders.
Because if you look at the ordering domain models we have ordered aggregate only order has aggregate,
and this aggregate is adding and removing domain events when creating orders.
As you can see that in the create method we basically create new order.
Just after that we will add domain event which is the order created event.
So we can use add domain event method which comes from the aggregate in the order entity.
And here you can see the domain event.
If you go to domain event, you can see that this domain event is inherited from the I domain event.
And I domain event inherit from the I notification comes from the mediator.
By this way, our dispatch domain event handler and interceptor method can easily publish the domain
events with mediator, which is expecting a notification interface when publishing any operation.
So this is the I notification and I domain event, and the order entity is representing adding domain
events into our list.
You can put breakpoint in here.
When creating any order you can check the reference which is inside of the initial data when seeding
our operation after created the database.
So now I'm going to right click the ordering API and set a startup project.
And now you can run Https mode and see how we can trigger our application and our newly created interceptors.
This is coming from the Program.cs and continue to initialize database async.
And in here we are going to migrate our database to create database and tables.
After waiting a certain of time we can come to see the async method.
And in here I'm going to focus on the seeding orders because only order has our operation which is the
aggregate.
Before that you can see that the auditable entity interceptors trigger for customer and the product
entity.
And I'm going to continue these operations for dispatching domain events.
And in here you can see that we are triggering the dispatched domain events.
Interceptor comes from the seeding operation.
But if you look at the code stack these interceptors triggers from the.
When seeding the customers customer is an entity, not aggregate.
That means customer has no end domain events.
So if you go to the call stack and go to the last point in the interceptor, if you continue to this
method, you can see that there is no aggregates according to our customer entity and there is no domain
events exist regarding to our customer entity for that purpose.
This will not be published any operation and continue to our operation.
If I hit F5, you can come here and see the product async information and I'm going to continue for
the product.
Also, product also has no domain events and hit F5 and see orders seeding operation.
At this time we can see order create method.
And in this method we basically add domain event which is the order created domain event.
And after that we will perform the other seeding operation.
If I hit F5 this will be triggered again order create operation and after that when saving changes async
operation completing in the dispatch domain events.
It is triggering our custom interceptor.
And in this interceptor we will basically get the aggregates from the context object.
And after that we will get the domain events inside of these aggregates.
Here you can see that we have two domain events listed for the order created event.
Because of the we are adding two order into our operation.
So in here first of all we will clear the domain events for each aggregate.
And after that we will iterate the domain events and using the mediator publish operation in order to
dispatch domain event to the consumer operations.
So here you can see that we have dispatch these two events with using the mediator publish operations.
Since we don't have any subscriber.
We didn't trigger any subscriber class, and I'm hitting F5 and complete this operation.
So as you can see that we have dispatched the domain events into our custom interceptor, and we observe
how domain events are dispatched using the mediators Send method.
Because mediator send method is expecting a notification interface from the domain event, and we have
already implementing this interface using the I domain Service interface.
So we will handle these domain events in the application layer soon.
Now we can verify from the database operations from the SQL Server Object Explorer.
If you refresh this database go to localhost and open database.
You can see the order db is created successfully.
If you expand the tables, we can check the order and order items with right click and view data.
And here you can see that the seeding operations also completed.
That will also dispatching the order created domain event.
When creating these entities into our application.