In this section, we are going to develop our very first microservices, which is Catholic API with
vertical slice architecture and six.
So now let's check our big picture and see what we are going to build one by one.
As you can see, the image we are in here and start to developing catalog API microservices and catalog
API microservices will be used PostgreSQL database.
And here you can see the NuGet package that we are going to use when developing our catalog microservices.
So we can say that in catalog microservices we will use minimal APIs and latest features of dotnet eight
and C 12.
And we will implement vertical slice architecture.
And we will implement six design pattern.
And we will use Martin Library for dotnet transactional DocumentDB.
So now let's see what we will develop for catalog microservices internal architecture.
So for internal architecture you can see that we will start at this point.
And we will create an ASP.Net core web API project.
And we will use minimal APIs for building fast Http APIs, fully functioning Rest endpoints and top
level program.cs.
So if you look at the database part, the catalog database will be PostgreSQL, but we will use Martin
Library.
You can see in here Martin NuGet package for dotnet transactional DocumentDB on PostgreSQL.
So that means Martin will be convert this PostgreSQL as a dotnet transactional DocumentDB.
So our product microservices database will be PostgreSQL, but acting as a DocumentDB using the Martin
library.
If we look at the internal architecture you can see the internal of the our microservices.
We will use vertical slice architecture implementation with the features folders and single C-sharp
file including different classes in one file.
So we will implement vertical slice in the catalog microservices.
And also we will implement six design pattern with using the mediator library and also we will use Carter
for implementing minimal API endpoint definition into our catalog microservices.
And also we will use master when it possible for mapping DTO classes.
And also we will use fluent validation in order to validate inputs and add the mediator validation pipeline.
And we will also implement login and exception handling mechanism with mediator pipeline behaviors for
implementing cross-cutting concerns.
And lastly, we will implement a Docker file and Docker compose Yaml file for running the product.
Microservices and PostgreSQL database in Multi-container.
Docker environment for containerization and orchestration.
So let's remember our course development flow.
Here you can see the course development flow.
Our journey begins with the development of the microservices and starting with the catalog API microservices.
Here we will embrace the vertical slice architecture and implement the secure design pattern.
This is the foundational step we will stage for the rest of the R microservices.
So if we remember our way of learning methodology throughout the each section, we will follow this
way of learning methodology which consists of the four key steps.
These are the analyze, learn, develop and test and deploy.
So we will start with the domain and technical analysis.
After that we will delve into pattern and principles.
And after that we will develop our microservice codes and test these microservice project in our local
computer.
And lastly we will containerize and orchestrate these microservices using the databases.
For example, catalog microservices with PostgreSQL database using the Docker compose, and debugging
the Docker compose on Visual Studio for particular microservices.
So that means we will follow these learning methodology when developing our catalog API microservices,
including the ASP.Net core, minimal APIs for building fast Http APIs and fully functioning Rest endpoint.
And we will use top level Program.cs and we will implement vertical slice architecture with the feature
folders and single C-sharp file, including the different classes in one file.
And we will implement six design pattern using the mediator library.
And we will use Martin Library for dotnet transactional DocumentDB on PostgreSQL.
And we will use Carter for minimal API endpoint definition.
We will use Mapserver for mapping operation.
And we will use fluent validation to validate inputs and add a mediator validation pipeline behavior.
And lastly we will implement Docker file and docker compose file for running the catalog microservices
and PostgreSQL database in Docker environment.