In this video, we are going to create a naive GitHub repository for our microservices project.
This is not a mandatory step, but I would like to see your progress of developing microservices and
if you encounter any problem, it is very easy to check your GitHub repository.
So let's take an action.
First of all, you should ensure that you have a GitHub account and login your GitHub account.
And after that navigate to repository section.
Click the repositories and after that you can click the new button in order to create any repository.
So as a repository name we will give each of microservices.
And if you scroll down you can select the public repository and add a Readme file.
We should add a git ignore as a Visual Studio, since we will use Visual Studio either for our development,
the git ignore should be Visual Studio, and you can choose any license for your repository, and after
that you can create repository by clicking this button.
Yes, our repository is created.
Once we create the repository, you can see the link is generated from the GitHub.
By this way we can follow your progress on this repository and I can easily check your repositories
when you stuck at some point of this course, you can share the repository address and I will check
your problem on that location.