In this video, we are going to clone these newly created GitHub repository on our local environment
and set up a new solution in Visual Studio for our microservice development.
So now let's take an action.
So we will start cloning this repository.
First we are going to open a Visual Studio 2022.
In the welcome page you can see Get Started options.
And this time we will clone a repository.
So if you click this clone a repository section, you can see that it is expecting that repository location.
So we can enter a git repository URL in here.
So where we can get this URL.
So if you go back to our GitHub you can come here and click the code button.
And here you can see the clone section that we can copy from the https option.
And we can copy this URL.
And if you go back to our repository section you can paste these cloning repository for your newly created
each of microservices.
And also verify that your path is correct under your repositories and click the clone button.
So this will be clone or repository.
Okay.
The clone operation completes successfully.
After cloning the repository in our local environment, we should start to create our project.
So for that purpose on Visual Studio we are going to file new project.
So if you come here under the this folder view you can select the file New project.
And we are going to create a new project.
But this time we will create a new project for blank solution.
You can search for the blank solution and select the blank solution.
That means we will create a root file for our microservice project.
For that purpose, you should select the blank solution and click the next button.
And after that we will give the name as a solution name.
In here I'm going to give as a name SCP dash microservices.
And the location is very important.
You should select the location that we have created and cloning our repository.
So please select this browse window and you can go to the SCP microservices that we have created and
cloning from the GitHub.
So under these folder path location we will create a solution name.
Which name is SCP microservices I'm going to zoom into this solution.
You can give the solution name and location is important and we will create a new solution at the last
configuration.
So now I'm going to click the create button.
And this will be create a blank solution under this folder and open this solution.
After created in that location we can verify the folder location of these blank solution.
You can right click the solution.
And after that open folder in the File Explorer.
And you can see that these blank solution is located under the escape microservices that we have cloned
from the GitHub.
And under these folder it is created a new folder, which name is SCP microservices.
And under this folder you can see the are blank solution that we are going to develop the whole microservices
under these root blank solution.
So if you go back to our SCP microservices repository, you can see that these repository cloned from
the GitHub.
And after that it is creating an additional the same name folder which is the SCP microservices.
And it could be make the confusions.
And in order to avoid this kind of conflict, I would like to rename this solution folder as a source
folder.
So I'm going to right click and rename and give the name as a source, because I would like to encapsulate
all source codes under the source folder.
And these blank solution will be represent our.
Net application including the R microservices.
So these folder will be the root folder and including the source codes.
And after that we can add a deployment files like Kubernetes Yaml files and so on.
In order to separate these things it is good to create a new folder which name is source folder.
So now we are organizing our folder structure.
And after that we can come to our Visual Studio.
And if you go to the git change you can see that we have added new blank solution under the source folder
into our microservices repository.
We can commit these changes with writing the initial command.
And you can commit and sync this change with the GitHub repository.
So if you go back to our GitHub repository and refresh this page, you can see that our building solution
comes under the source folder on GitHub.
So that means we have successfully cloned the repository and set up our solution and push our project
into the GitHub.
And now we are ready for the develop our very first microservices.