In this video we are going to create our first microservices, which is the catalog API, ASP.Net web
API project.
But before that we will setting up the project folder structure.
Here you can see the folder structure that we are going to build one by one.
So first of all we are going to start with Creating Services folder which will be including for each
microservices under the services.
So we will be create a service folder in our solution.
And after that under the service folder we will be create additional sub folders for each microservices.
Since we are developing catalog we will be creating a catalog sub folder under the services folder.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio environment and we are going to open our blank solution.
And after that you can right click this solution add Naive solution folder.
So in this solution folder we will give the name as a services.
And after that I'm going to create an additional sub folder which name is catalog.
Again we are going to create a new solution folder and give the name as a catalog.
So here you can see the our latest solution folder structure.
We have a services folder.
And under that we have a catalog folder.
So now we can create ASP.Net web API project for catalog microservices.
For that purpose select the catalog sub folder.
Right click Add New Project.
In this window we can select the ASP.Net templates.
We will choose ASP.Net Core Empty Project template because when we are selecting with the web API and
empty web API has lots of boilerplate code, and we have to remove that code.
Instead of that, we will choose empty project template for all microservices and arrange our code very
fast.
So for that purpose, you can search for the empty solution in here and select the ASP.Net core project
and you can also pin these project in here in order to use frequently.
So I'm going to select in this recent project templates.
And I have pinned this kind of project and select the ASP.Net Core Empty and click the next button.
So we will give the name as a catalog API.
Since we will develop our catalog microservices, the project name should be catalog API.
And the location is very, very important because we will create this project under the source folder.
But we have an additional folders created in here which is the services catalog.
These are the solution folders that will not create a physical folder.
In order to create physical folder as the same as our project, we should add the these folder path.
In here I'm going to add a slash and services and add again slash and give the name catalog.
So that means we will create a catalog API project under the Source Services and Catalog folder.
So you should verify the location name is correct on your computer.
And after that we will continue to create our very first microservices with clicking the next button.
Here you can see the configurations for ASP.Net empty Project template.
The framework of course should be the.
Net eight and we are leaving as it is for all configurations including the configure https, enable
Docker and Docker operating system is Linux and we will use top level statement.
That's why this is not selected.
So please create this project with clicking this create button.
And here you can see the very first microservices is created successfully.
You can examine the folder structure.
It is located the services catalog.
And you can right click and open the folder structure and verify from that.
This is creating in the correct folder.
If you open in File Explorer, you can see the folder structure is correct under the source folder we
have services and services has catalog.
And under the catalog we have catalog API microservices that will be include our actual microservice
codes.
So if you come back to our Visual Studio we can go to the Catholic API, ASP.Net project and open the
Program.cs.
So we are going to simplify the boilerplate code.
Once we have created, let's simplify the default code in the Program.cs for the clean start.
So I am going to put a comment in here and also providing our program.cs structure.
As you remember that we have two main division in this file.
The first one is before building the application.
The second one is after building the application.
So now I am going to remove these Mapkit operation.
Since we will develop our catalog related operation we don't need any map get operation now.
So basically before the building the application what we will do we will.
Add the services into ASP.Net builtin dependency injection container.
So that's why it is good to put a command in here.
So after building the application we will configure the Http request pipeline to mapping the incoming
requests.
So this is the structure of every Program.cs for all microservices.
In ASP.Net core we typically follow two main steps.
The first one is before building the web application in here we use various service methods for built
in dependency injection.
These are the registration operations and the second one is the.
After building the web application, we will apply use function or map function methods in order to
configure the Http request lifecycle.
So you can save this file.
And now we are ready to develop our Catholic API.
With these steps we have set up the foundation for the Catholic API microservices.
As we progress, we will delve into deeper developing the Catholic API functionality using the vertical
slice architecture.