In this video we are going to do domain analysis of catalog microservices.
But before that let's remember the way of learning methodology of the course.
According to the way of learning methodology we have four key steps.
These are the analyze, learn, develop and test and deploy.
So we will start the analyze phase.
That means we will perform domain and technical analysis of the particular microservices.
So let's start with the domain analysis of catalog microservices.
When we are performing domain analysis we will also explore in four key areas.
These are the domain model analysis, application use cases, Rest API endpoints and underlying data
structures.
So let's start with the first key area which is the domain model and entity analysis of catalog microservices.
Here you can see the domain models of catalog microservices are primary domain is product which is associated
with the category.
So a product has attributes like id, name, category, description, image, file and price.
And also product has a relation 1 to 1 relation with the category.
Here you can see the domain model analyze picture in here.
So basically product has attributes including in this class.
And product has one to many relation with the category.
So we will also consider a domain event for price change and leading to integration events in the upcoming
videos.
In the next step we will analyze use cases of the catalog microservices.
So we should define our catalog use case analysis.
Our main use case is listing products and categories and able to search products.
And also we will perform Crud operations on product entity.
So that means our main use case are listing product and categories.
Get product with product ID, get products with category, create new product, update product and delete
product.
And along with this, we should design our APIs according to Rest perspective.
So in the third step, we will analyze Rest API endpoints of the catalog microservices.
That means we will develop a set of RESTful APIs for catalog microservices.
Here you can see the table about the RESTful APIs that will expose from the catalog microservices.
According to this table, you can see the Http get methods, post, put and delete methods, and in
the first row we will get all products that mean list all products with these request Uri which is the
slash products, and this is the http get method.
In the second row you can see the.
We can add a specific product with getting ID information from the request query parameters.
So in the third row it is again http get.
But this time we will get products by category.
Again category name will be retrieved from the query parameters.
And in here you can see the post method.
This will be create any product.
Again it is slash products endpoint and Http put will be update specific product which is the ID getting
from the request parameters.
And here you can see that we can remove the A product which id comes from the request parameter.
So these are the rest endpoints.
And the last domain analyze item is underlying data structures of catalog microservices.
So underlying data structure of the catalog microservices will be document database in order to store
catalog Json data catalog data will be available for the Json.
And it is very good to store in the document database.
So after we have decided to be a document database for data storage, we have two main options.
These are the use MongoDB as a NoSQL database.
Or we can use PostgreSQL database Json column feature with using Martin library that provide the.
Net transactional DocumentDB.
So each offers a robust way to store our catalog in a Json format as a document database.
But for our catalog microservices, we will utilize PostgreSQL with using the Martin library.
So what is Martin Library?
Martin is a powerful library that transforms PostgreSQL into a dotnet transactional DocumentDB.
It leverages the PostgreSQL Json column features and allowing us to store and query our data as a Json
documents, like a document table.
So this approach combines the flexibility of document database with the reliability and robustness of
the relational PostgreSQL database.
We can query an index Json data efficiently, making it a great fit for modern agile microservices that
require quick iteration and flexible data models.
So we can say that catalog API microservices will be the simple Crud implementation on product data
and document database.
You can see the external and internal architecture.
We will apply internal architecture design patterns and we will use different kind of libraries.
So as you can see that we have finished the domain analysis of the catalog microservices.
Now it is time to do technical analysis.