In this video we are going to do technical analysis of the catalog microservices.
So we will explore the technical analysis in four key areas.
These are the application architecture, style, pattern and principles libraries, NuGet packages and
project folder structure.
So we will explore the architecture, pattern, libraries and folder structure in the technical analysis
of the catalog microservices.
Let's start with the first one which is the application architecture style.
As the application architecture style of catalog microservices, we will use vertical slice architecture.
So we are implementing a vertical slice architecture.
This approach organizes our code into feature folders, with each feature encapsulated in a single C
sharp file and containing all necessary classes.
So you can see the traditional layered architecture.
In vertical slice architecture, we can encapsulate the features with including different layer perspectives.
So in the second analyze is pattern and principles that we will use catalog microservices.
Let me shortly explain these pattern principles that we used in our catalog microservices.
The first one is six design pattern command query responsibility segregation divides the operation into
commands and queries.
Or we can say write and read operations promoting the flexibility and scalability.
And the second pattern is mediator pattern.
It facilitates object interaction through the mediator, reducing the direct dependencies and simplifying
communications, especially in complex workloads.
And we will also use dependency injection in ASP.Net core.
Dependency injection is a core feature allowing to inject dependencies rather than hard coding them.
This will increase the maintainability and testability, and another pattern is minimal.
APIs and routing in ASP.Net eight.
So ASP.Net eight minimal APIs simplify endpoint definition, providing lightweight syntax for routing
and handling Http requests.
And lastly, we can say that all patterns, which is the object relational mapping patterns object relational
mapping abstracts the database interactions, enabling to work with the database object using the high
level programming constructs and simplifying the data manipulations.
So we will use also object relational mapping patterns.
And in the third step we will examine the libraries and NuGet packages that we are going to use in the
catalog microservices.
So now let's explore the key libraries and NuGet packages that power our microservices.
The first one is mediator four six.
So Mediator Library simplifies the implementation of the six design pattern by acting as an in-process
messaging mechanism, helping to send commands and queries to their respective handlers.
Another library is Carter Carter for API endpoints.
Carter offers a lightweight library for routing and handling Http requests, making it easier to define
API endpoints with clean and concise code.
Another library is Martin for PostgreSQL interactions.
Martin Library provides a way to use PostgreSQL as a document database.
It leverages the PostgreSQL Json capabilities for storing, querying and managing documents, and another
library is mobster mobster for object mapping.
Mobster is a fast, configurable object mapper that simplifies the task of the mapping operations from
one type to another, and it is also streamlining the data transformation process.
And another library is fluent validation for input validations.
Fluent validation is a popular library for building strongly typed validation rules, ensuring our inputs
are correct before they are processed by the application.
So in the fourth step, we can examine the project folder structure so you can see the project folder
structure for the Catholic API on the slide.
So the project is organized into modal features data and abstraction folders.
So feature folders like create product and Get product have dedicated handler and endpoint definitions.
Feature folder will be the products and data folder and context objects managed database interactions.
So you can see the picture on the slide.
These are the data folder model folder products as a feature folder and under the products feature folder
you can see the use cases.
These are the vertical slices, create product, delete product and get products.
These implementing Crud operations and under the one of the use case folder which is the create product,
you can see the handle and endpoint to see classes.
So lastly we can examine the deployment of the catalog microservices.
Finally, we will containerize our microservice with Docker and ensuring the seamless deployment and
integration with the PostgreSQL database.
So we will implement Docker file and docker compose file for running the catalog microservices and the
PostgreSQL database in Docker environment.
As you can see that we have finished the domain and technical analysis for our catalog microservices.