In this video we are going to learn vertical slice architecture.
Vertical slice architecture introduced by Jaime Bogaerts.
And it offers this architecture against two traditional layered onion clean architecture approaches.
Vertical Slice Architecture aims to organize code around specific features or use cases, rather than
the technical concerns in a vertical slice architecture.
A feature is implemented across all layers of the software, from the user interface to the database.
This approach is often used in the development of complex, feature rich applications, particularly
those that are delivered over the web.
Vertical slice architecture is dividing an application into distinct features or functionalities, and
each of them cuts through all of the layers of the application.
This approach is in contrast to the traditional n-tier or layered architectures, where the application
is divided horizontally.
So that means, unlike the traditional n-tier or layered architectures where the application is divided
horizontally.
As you can see, the image, presentation, application and data layers, the vertical slice architectures
divide an application vertically based on the features or functionalities.
So let's see the characteristics of the vertical slice architecture.
Of course, the first characteristic is.
The application is divided into feature based slices.
So the application is divided into slices based on the features or use cases.
Each slice represents a complete vertical pathway through the application stack, including the user
interface, business logic, and data access layers, and each slice is self-contained and independent.
That means each vertical slice is intended to be self-contained and independent from other slices.
This means that a single feature can be developed, tested, and deployed without impacting other parts
of the application.
There are reduced dependencies between different parts of the application by focusing on the vertical
slices, dependencies between different areas of the application are minimized.
Each slice can be seen as a mini application with its own distinct functionality and dependencies.
It promotes the use of the cross-functional teams.
Development teams working with the vertical slice architecture are often cross functional, containing
all the skills necessary to develop a feature from start to finish, which promotes a more holistic
view of the development and the architecture supports scalability and maintainability.
This architecture allows for better scalability and maintainability.
As the application grows, new features can be added as a Neve slices without significantly impacting
the existing code, and also it allows for improved testing and deployment process.
Vertical slices can be individually tested and deployed, which simplifies the testing process, and
it can lead to more reliable and faster deployments.
Vertical slice is an internal application architecture pattern that every microservices can follow.
This architecture in their internal code.
Organizations in the microservices.
Every microservice handle a specific piece of the functionality and communicate with other services
through well defined interfaces.
So let's see the advantages of the vertical slice architecture.
Vertical slice architecture offers several benefits.
It allows for focused development where the teams can concentrate on one feature at a time.
It simplifies refactoring and upgrades, since changes in one slice usually don't affect others.
It aligns well with the agile and DevOps practices, supporting incremental development and continuous
delivery.
However, there are also challenges with using the vertical slice.
You might encounter duplication of code across slices, particularly for common functionalities.
There is a learning curve involved, especially for teams opposed to the traditional architectures.
The design of the each slice requires careful consideration in order to ensure independence and maintainability.
So vertical slice architecture is a powerful approach for developing complex applications where modularity
and rapid development are crucial.
So we will also use vertical slice architecture into our catalog and basket microservices.