In this video we are going to compare vertical slice architecture versus clean architecture.
Vertical slice architecture emphasizes organizing software development around the features, cutting
through all layers in a vertical manner.
Each feature or slice is developed and deployed independently.
On the other hand, clean architecture focuses on separation of concerns and dependency rules.
It organizes the code into layers with the most stable and business agnostic layers at the center of
the entities, and use cases and external concerns like UI and data access layers on the outer layers.
With vertical slice architecture.
Development teams concentrate on delivering complete features, each potentially touching all layers
of the stack.
It is closely aligned with the agile methodologies where delivering working, testable features rapidly
is a key, but the clean architecture advocates for a more structured approach, ensuring that business
logic is decoupled from the external concerns.
This approach is beneficial for long terme maintainability and scalability.
Vertical slice architecture shines in scenarios where the rapid development and delivery of the independent
features are critical.
It is well suited for agile teams working on complex applications with numerous features that may change
or evolve independently.
Clean architecture is ideal for large scale applications where long Tum maintenance and scalability
and the ability to adapt to changing business requirements or technologies are paramount.
It ensures that core business logic remains unaffected by changes in the external layers.
So once you choose vertical slice over the clean architecture, the first reason is rapid development
and deployment.
When the priority is to develop and deploy features rapidly and independently, vertical slice is more
appropriate.
The second reason is agile and scrum teams.
For teams practicing the agile or scrum that need to deliver complete features in short cycles.
Vertical Slice aligns well with these methodologies.
And another reason is microservices.
In a microservice architecture, where each service is often responsible for a distinct feature or business
capability.
Vertical slice can be particularly effective.
So let's see our issue of microservices and compare with the catalog versus organic microservices catalog
microservices using the vertical slice architecture.
So in our issue of microservices, the catalog microservices manage the products categories and inventory.
And it is using the vertical slice architecture.
Each feature, like adding any product or updating inventory or managing categories, is developed as
a separate slice.
Each slice would include its own API endpoint, business logic and data access code, allowing for the
rapid development and updates to individual aspects of the product catalog without affecting the others.
Mặt khác, ordering microservices sử dụng clean architecture.
Vậy ordering microservices xử lý logic xử lý đơn hàng, bao gồm quản lý giỏ hàng, đặt hàng
và xử lý thanh toán.
Với clean architecture, các quy tắc kinh doanh cốt lõi và các trường hợp sử dụng của xử lý đơn hàng là trung tâm và
được cách ly khỏi các mối quan tâm bên ngoài như các hoạt động cơ sở dữ liệu hoặc UI.
Sự tách biệt này đảm bảo rằng các quy tắc kinh doanh quan trọng vẫn ổn định và không bị ảnh hưởng bởi các thay đổi trong các hệ thống bên ngoài,
như cổng thanh toán hoặc schema cơ sở dữ liệu.
Vậy lựa chọn giữa vertical slice architecture và clean architecture phụ thuộc vào các yêu cầu cụ thể
của dự án.
Vertical slice tập trung hơn vào tính năng và nhanh nhẹn, và nó lý tưởng cho phát triển tính năng nhanh chóng và
triển khai.
Clean architecture phù hợp hơn cho các ứng dụng quy mô lớn, tồn tại lâu dài, nơi các quy tắc kinh doanh
phải được cách ly khỏi các thay đổi bên ngoài.
Chúng ta sẽ sử dụng cả hai kiến trúc trong các microservices khác nhau có thể tận dụng các điểm mạnh của chúng theo
yêu cầu của từng microservice.