In this video we are going to learn six design pattern which is the command query responsibility segregation
pattern.
Six is one of the important pattern when querying between microservices.
We can use six design pattern in order to avoid complex queries to get rid of the inefficient joins.
Seacrest stands for the Command and Query Responsibility segregation pattern.
Basically, this pattern separates read and write operations with separating databases.
The main idea is that we can divide the application operation into two separate categories.
The first one is commands.
These commands are changing the state of data into application.
And the second one is the queries.
These queries are handling complex join operations are returning a result, and don't change the state
of the data into the application.
In large scale microservice architectures, it needs to manage high volume data requirements for this
kind of use cases.
Monolithic approaches like single database for services can cause bottlenecks for complex and large
scale microservice architectures.
We can use both SQS and event sourcing patterns to improve application performance.
SQS offers two separate read and write data that provide to maximize query performance and scalability.
Let's think about the monolithic applications.
Most of the time we have one databases, and this database should respond to both query and update operations.
That means a single database is both working for complex join operations and also perform Crud operations.
But if the application goes more complex, this query and Crud operations will be also going to be unmanageable
situation.
In example of reading database, if your application required some query that needs to join more than
one table, this will lock the database due to latency of query computation.
Also, if you give example of writing database when performing the Crud operations, we would need to
make complex validations and process long business logics.
So this will cause the lock database operations.
So reading and writing database has different approaches that we can define different strategies to
handle that operation.
In order to that, SQL is offered to use separation of concerns, principles and separate reading database
and writing database with two databases.
By this way, we can even use different database for reading and writing database types, like using
NoSQL database for reading and using relational database for Crud operations.
Mostly read database uses NoSQL databases with Denormalized data, which generates from the right databases,
and the right database uses relational databases with fully normalized and supports strong data consistency.