In this video, we are going to learn logical and physical implementation of the secrets.
Secrets can be implemented in two main ways.
These are the logical and physical implementation.
Let me start with the logical implementation of secrets.
We will splitting to operations, not databases.
In a logical implementation of secrets, the key idea is separate read and write operations at the code
level, but not necessarily at the database level.
So that means we will separate the query and command operations at the code level and not separate in
the database level.
Both types of the operations still interact with the same underlying database.
So we said that it is the same database but different paths, even though the same database is used.
The path for reading and writing data are distinct.
This means that you might have different models or methods for querying and updating data.
For instance, read operations could utilize the simple data transfer object optimized for performance,
while write operations might interact with a more complex domain model to ensure business rules and
validations are enforced.
So the second type of the implementation is physical implementation of the queries.
A physical implementation of the securities involves splitting the read and write operations, not just
at the code level, but also physically using the separate databases.
This is often seen in a more complex systems, particularly when scaling is a concern.
So there is a synchronization challenge happen when we are separate databases.
While a physical implementation can offer performance advantages and better scaling capabilities, it
also introduces complexity in terms of maintaining data consistency and synchronization between the
read and write operations.
So you can see that if we separate the write and read databases, we have to concern about the synchronization
challenges.
That's why logical security is often the first step in adopting this security pattern, especially for
applications where the overhead of managing separate databases is not justified.
It offers many of the benefits of the six, such as the clearer separation of concerns and potentially
more optimized read operations, without adding additional complexity of the managing separate databases.
For that reason, during the course, we will implement the logical sequence with ASP.Net Core and Mediator.