In this video we are going to learn six design pattern with Mediator library.
That means we will be logical sequence implementation using the mediator library.
Mediator is a popular.
Net library used to implement the mediator pattern, which is great fit for the sequence design pattern.
It allows to send commands and queries to the appropriate handlers without coupling the sender to the
receiver.
In mediator.
We have a I request interface.
So both commands and queries are modeled as a message.
The I request interface is used to define a request which can be either a command or query.
The return type of the request can be specified as a generic parameter.
After the I request interface definition, we should define the handlers for each command and query.
We define a handler that inherits from the I request handler, t request, and t response, where the
t request is the type of the command or query, and t response is return type.
So we can define custom I command and I query abstraction.
So in order to make the distinction between the commands and the queries clearer, we can define two
custom interfaces.
These are the I command and I query.
Both interfaces can inherit from the mediators I request object.
So in ASP.Net core application, using the mediator controllers or minimal APIs act as a entry point
for handling Http requests.
You can see in here Http request comes from the client and the mediator acts as an entry point.
So instead of the implementing the business logic directly within the API action, these actions delegate
the responsibility to mediator, and after that mediator sending the command and queries.
When a controller or minimal API receives a request, it creates a command or query object and send
it to the mediator.
Mediator then dispatch this object to the appropriate handler.
So if you look at the mediator pattern and pipeline behaviors, the mediator pattern is implemented
by.
The mediator library is particularly useful in a complex or enterprise level applications, where request
processing often involves more than just business logic.
In this kind of applications, handling a request might require additional steps like logging, validation,
auditing, and applying the security checks.
These are known as a cross-cutting concerns.
Mediator provides a mediator pipeline where these cross-cutting concerns can be inserted transparently.
These pipeline coordinates the request handling, ensuring that all the necessary steps are executed
in the right order.
So in mediator, we have a pipeline behavior and pipeline behaviors are used to implement cross-cutting
concerns.
You can see the image on the slide.
They wrap around the request handling allowing you to execute the logic before and after actual handler
is called.
So this is the mediator pipeline process before handle the actual operation mediator allowing to preprocessor
behavior or post-processor behaviors that you can use these behavior as a implementing cross-cutting
concerns.
Here you can see the issue of microservices.
It is also used for the implementing various cross-cutting concerns.
The first one is log behavior.
A behavior that logs details about the handling request.
And the second one is the validation behavior.
This is the behavior that validates incoming requests before they reach the handler.
So we will use these two behaviors when implementing our issue of microservices.
And these behaviors ensures every request processed by the mediator in the application is logged and
validated consistently, and it demonstrates how the cross-cutting concerns can be efficiently managed
using the mediator pattern and mediator library pipeline behaviors.
So we can say that using mediator in ASP.Net applications provides a structured and clean way to handle
complex request processing.