In this video, we are going to start to develop catalog API microservices with creating domain entities
in modules folder.
So we are in here developing catalog microservices and we will focus on the domain entities.
We will create domain entities under the modules folder.
So far we have finished the domain and technical analyze and understand the pattern and principles that
we use during the course.
So now it is time to develop our catalog microservices and we will focus on creating product entity
for our catalog microservices.
Here you can see the our catalog microservices domain model.
We will create product entity and this will be one to end relation with category.
So let's take an action.
Please open the Visual Studio 2022.
And we are going to start by adding modules folder into our project folder structure.
So if you come to catalog API and right click Add New folder which name is modules.
And after that I'm going to add a new class under the modules folder.
Right click Add New Item.
And we are going to create a product C-sharp class.
Here you can see that we will create a models folder under the Catholic API, and under the models we
will add a product key domain entity class.
Now we are going to implement this product entity class product domain.
Entity class will include ID name category description and so on.
So we will start to implement this kind of properties.
The ID property should be guided.
And after that we will set the name and I'm going to give the default value.
And after that we will define list string category.
This will be one to end relationships.
Here you can see the category.
And we will create a new category list when the product is initializing.
And after that I'm going to add a description.
Again I'm going to provide a default value after description property I'm going to define image file
property.
Again it will be string and the name of the property will be image file.
So we can again give the default value of the image file property.
And lastly we will define.
Decimal property, which will be the price.
This will be the product price.
Okay.
As you can see that we have finished the implementation of product domain.
Entity class and product class includes properties like ID, name, category and others.
Product and category has one to many relationships and this class will be our document table on the
document database.
These ID property will act as a our document ID identified in the document database.
That means this ID will be document ID that we will manage by database.
And remember that we will use PostgreSQL with Martin Library for this catalog.
Microservices.
So in the PostgreSQL database we should be transform this PostgreSQL database as a document database
that will provide by the Martin converting this PostgreSQL database to the dotnet transactional document
DB.
So PostgreSQL has Json column features that allowing us to store and query our data as a Json document.
So it combines the flexibility of document database with the reliability of the relational PostgreSQL
database.
So this setup is ideal for handling complex data structures like our product entity, which includes
a list of the categories and other varied data types into document entity object.
As you can see that we have finished the development of product document entity for our catalog microservices.