In this video, we are going to developing vertical slice feature folders with circles and mediator.
So we said that in vertical slice architecture we structure our application around the features or functionalities
rather than layers.
So in Catholic microservices we will follow the vertical slice architecture.
And each vertical slice cut through all architectural layers such as the UI, business logic and data
access.
And the project organized with the models, features, data and abstractions that you can see the folder
structure as a feature.
Folders.
We will give the name as a products, which will be the our domain entity name, and under the products
feature folder we will add the use case features which is the create product, delete product, get
product and so on.
So now let's get started to implement this kind of folder structure into our application, open the
Visual Studio and go to the catalog API project folder.
And you can right click Add New Folder.
The folder name will be the products.
This will be the our feature folder and under the products folder we will create each use case or feature
as a sub folder in here.
So for example we will create a create product feature and we will create corresponding sub folders
under the products feature folder.
Let me right click Add New Sub folder and give the name as a great product.
This helps in organizing our code based functionalities and keeps related components together.
So we have created a sub folder which name is Create product.
Under the Create Product sub folder, we can create one class in order to include all codes in a vertical
fashion.
But since we have already created a separate folder for the vertical slice feature folder, I would
like to separate by two, which are the handles and the endpoints.
So that means within the create product folder, we will divide our code into two main classes.
The first class is create product handler.
If you right click Add New item, I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is Create product handler class.
And also I would like to create an additional class under the create product.
Right click Add New Item and give the name as a create product endpoint.
So if I zoom into this folder structure, you can see that we have created a products main feature folder.
And under the products we have created application use case folder name.
This will be the our vertical slice folder.
And under these vertical slice I have divided by two which is the handler and endpoint.
So that means handler will be our application logic layer endpoints will be represent our presentation
API layer.
So why I have created two classes inside of the feature folder.
A common approach in vertical slice architecture is to encapsulate all aspects of a feature in one class.
However, this makes the code hard to read, hard to maintain, and hard to locate for actual business
logic.
Instead of that, even we have.
Following the vertical slice architecture.
Inside the feature folder, I have separated application logic and presentation endpoints into two different
classes in order to make it more readable and manageable and easy.
Maintenance.
This separation makes it easier to locate specific parts of the code and manage them effectively.
Especially, we will encapsulate business logics under the handle class, and we will see API related
operations in endpoint class.
And we already applied the vertical slice architecture in the folder level.
We will apply the same structure approach to other Crud operations like get product, update product
and Delete product.
As you can see in here, each feature will have its own dedicated folder with the handle and endpoint
classes.
Now let's focus on the develop these create product handle class.