In this video we are going to develop feature handler class with six and mediator.
So we are in here create product feature folder and we will be develop create product handler class
using the six and mediator.
According to our main architecture we will follow the vertical slice architecture.
But when implementing the handler class we will use six and mediator library in six.
The handler is responsible for executing the command logic with using the mediator library, the handler
receives a command and process it, encapsulating the business logic for specific operations under the
handler class.
So in this video we will delve into implementing create product feature using the securities and mediator
in ASP.Net core Web application.
So now before that, let's start understanding the life cycle of a request in a system that use mediator
and six design pattern.
And here you can see the illustration of the six and mediator request life cycle.
This is request comes from the client.
And this will be process or catalog web API application and respond back.
So you can see the illustration how API request flows through our application.
The request first of all hits the our presentation layer.
This is typically Carter library Carter endpoint which is the minimal API endpoint in our case.
And after that it sends a command to the mediator.
And mediator redirect this command to the corresponding handler class.
And this class will process this command and perform business logic with using the DB operations, and
after that return the result.
And this will be responding to the client application.
So according to this flow, the mediator will be triggered by command or query object that will inherit
from the mediator I request interface.
And this is the first point to trigger the mediator.
So according to this command or query request object mediator will be redirect to corresponding command
handler class which should be inherit from the I request handler.
And in the command handler, we can perform business logic and return back the result.
So that means to trigger our handler class we need command query and result objects.
And after that we will define command.
Under this command query should be inherited from the I request and this command handler should be inherited
from the I request handler.
So let's get started.
If you open the Visual Studio, our first step is to define the command and result class for the create
product feature.
So for that purpose open the Create Product feature and go to handler class.
So in the handler class we are going to create our command and result classes inside of the command
Csharp file.
So we are going to create two type inside of the handler class.
These are the create product command and create product result and we will create two record type inside
of the handler.
Let me create first record type which is the public record create product command and we will specify
the.
Parameters which are the members from the product entity.
Here you can see that I have added the name, category, description, image, file and price.
This comes from the AR product model and you can see these parameters are passing into the AR create
product command record object.
And as a result we will need an additional record type which is the public record.
And this will be the create product result record type.
And as a return type we will return only ID information.
Okay.
Here you can see the two type in this code.
The create product command represents the data that we need to create a new product.
And these create the product result representing the response object return object, which in this case
we just return the product id.
So we have completed the command and result object.
And if you go back to our architecture you can see that we have developed this command and result object.
Now it is time to develop command handler object.
Now let's create our handler class.
This class will contain the business logic to handle create product command.
So in here I'm going to change the public as a internal because I would like to be in internal class
and the class name will be changed.
Create product command handler.
So I'm going to emphasize that this is the command handler.
And we will expecting a command okay.
Now we have finished the our command handler.
And we will implement the business logic inside of this class.
But before that let's understand how to trigger this handler class with this command object.
So if you go back to our architecture you can see that in order to trigger our command handler we need
a mediator.
So mediator provides to trigger command and queries and abstractions with the mediator pattern.
In order to trigger handler class, we should derive a command or query classes with the I request result
interface.
This comes from the mediator library, and after that the handler class will implement the I request
handler command and result interface.
So that means before we start, we need to install mediator NuGet package to benefit from mediator pattern.
So if you go back to our Visual Studio, if you can right click and manage NuGet packages, you can
go to the NuGet package window.
And if you browse and write the mediator package, you can see that we will download the mediator library
into our catalog microservices.
And if you double click the project file, you can see that we have successfully installed Mediator
Library into our catalog microservices.
Now it is time to implementing these mediator into our great product handler class.
If you go back the handler class, the first thing we should do that we will inherit our command object
from the request.
So if you come here and write the request, you can see that our request comes from the mediator library.
So we can provide the request.
And you can give the response as a generic.
In our case our response is create product result.
And now we are ready to using this command object for mediator trigger operations.
We are indicating that this product command inherited from the request which is the mediator and one
mediator.
See this request comes from the API request.
This will be triggered or create product command handler.
So in order to trigger this product command handler this is also required to inherit from the request
handler object.
And in here we will provide request and response.
That means we can provide the create product command as a command.
This will be the our command object.
And after that I'm going to provide create product result this object okay.
Now we have defined that we are a request handler interface.
And this will be accepting command and returning the command result object.
If you click the alt enter you can see that we will implement these interface members which is the handle
method.
So in this handle method we basically perform the business logic to create a product.
So you can put a command.
We will put our business logic in order to create a new product.
But for now let's throw an exception before we implementation we should understand how this trigger.
So basically with this setup we can use mediator send method in order to trigger this command.
And this command will be redirecting to.
Command handle class.
This will be work very well with using the mediator package.
But before proceeding the implementation, I would like to emphasize that we should separate the command
and queries in sequence because according to security design pattern, the commands and queries should
be separated.
But if you look at the mediator library, mediator will use both these operations as a I request interface.
In order to implement security design pattern, we should separate the command and query object.
That means in a true queries implementation, we will separate the command and queries at the request
level.
This means we will create distinct abstractions over the mediators.
I request interface object in order to differentiate commands, which is the rights and queries which
will read operations.