In this video, we are going to create abstraction on mediator for securities design pattern.
We will create a clear separation between commands and queries using the mediator, enhancing the clarity
and maintainability of our code.
In order to implement securities design pattern effectively, we will create specialized interfaces
for commands and queries.
So you can see the picture on the slide.
We will create the specific interfaces for query and command operation and we will inherit from the
mediator I request.
You can see in this picture we will create a query interface which inherited I request and again inherited
from I request.
And this time we will create a command interface.
And at the same way we will create request handler classes for I query handler and I command handler.
So these are the generic and normal methods with inherited from I request mediator.
By this way we can separate the responsibilities and apply the cross-cutting concerns with different
ways into commands and queries.
For example, you can think that we will implement a validation only run for the command objects and
we don't want to run validations query objects.
With separating these interfaces, we will apply validations only our command.
But before that there is very important thing before abstractions on the mediator and queries.
Here you can see the Icap microservices using the building blocks libraries.
These are the microservices that we are going to develop during the course.
And all these microservices are using building blocks class library.
So that means building blocks encapsulate our common operation for each microservices.
For example, we will use these six design pattern abstractions and mediator library almost for all
microservices.
So why we should develop each microservices to implement these six implementation and mediator library.
For that purpose I am going to create Building Blocks class library that can use every microservices
with referencing this class library and perform these common operations.
Also, we will install all common NuGet packages and codes into Building blocks class library that you
can see list of the NuGet packages, and these are the common NuGet packages that can be used for each
microservices.
We will encapsulate in the Building Blocks class library.
That means in order to ensure reusability and maintainability across for each microservices, we will
create a Building Blocks class library.
This library will contain our secrets, abstractions and these interfaces, and can be referenced by
any microservices in our system that can implement the secrets design pattern and using the mediator.
So let's start with the setting up the Building Blocks project.
For that purpose, open the Visual Studio and we are going to create Building Blocks project.
But before that let's create a folder which is a solution folder which is same as the services folder
structure directory.
We can right click the solution and add a new solution folder.
Which name is building blocks.
Because this is the existing from the microservices.
That could be different folder location.
And we are adding the building blocks at the top of the our solution perspective.
So under the building blocks I'm going to create a new class library.
And this class library will be include our common operations.
For that purpose right click the Building Blocks solution folder add new project and this time we will
use Class library.
I have already pinned the class library before in my recent project templates, and select the class
library and click the next button.
So project name will be the building blocks you can see in here.
The project name will be the building blocks.
And the location is very important because we should add the location name according to our building
blocks.
So as you can see the Our solution window we will have a building blocks folder.
And under the these building blocks folder we will create a class library which name is building blocks
which is the same name.
For that purpose I'm going to add additional slash and building blocks in here in order to create our
building blocks project under the source folder.
So under the source folder we should have a building blocks folder physical folder.
And under these physical folder we will create Building Blocks class library.
So make sure that your location and the project name is correct.
And after setting up these location you can see that project will be created under this source building
block.
Slash again the second building blocks and click.
Next button.
And of course framework will be.
Net eight and click the create button.
Yes, this will be great building blocks under our solution and the correct folder path.
You can verify from the solution window and make sure that you have created the correct building blocks
class library.
And the first thing we should do is delete the class one.
We will create our own class for common operations.
So that's why I'm going to remove these class one.
And after that you can save the solution.
And now we are ready for the perform our common operations.
If you look at the slide the common operations is implementing the six abstractions and mediator library.
So let's start with the installing the mediator library.
Mediator is essential for implementing the mediator pattern and which is also central of our six implementation.
Actually we will also install all common NuGet packages for each microservices into building blocks.
By this way, whenever a new microservice comes into the picture, we will just reference to the building
blocks and start writing the code with all common NuGet packages.
This also provide version management of NuGet packages make easier in one class library.
Instead of installing the mediator for different microservices, we will only install in one place and
it will be easy to managing versions.
So please open the Visual Studio and right click the building blocks and manage NuGet packages.
So again in here you can browse for the mediator and install the mediator NuGet package under the Building
Blocks class library.
We can double click the class library and verify from in here and save these building blocks.
So inside of our building blocks library.
Now we are ready to create our six abstractions.
For that purpose, I'm going to create a new folder under this class library, which will be the Our
Abstractions add new folder and give the name as a six.
So under the six we will define our interfaces that we have designed in the block blocks in here.
So we will create these interfaces to abstract our six operations in six folder.
Let's start with defining a command interface.
And this command interface will be inherited from the mediator I request interface.
So please go back to Visual Studio and open the our folder and add new class under the six folder.
Which name is L command.
In here I'm going to create an interface which will be the public and this will be inherit from the
I request object which comes from the mediator.
So we can remove unnecessary using statement.
And first of all I would like to implement for the generic one.
For that purpose we will also make generic our I command, which will be the returning response.
That means this command will be returning this response type that we can pass these I request generics.
So this is the first abstraction.
And the second abstraction we can define our regular interface which will be again public interface
I command.
But this time we don't have any generics.
So we can inherit from the I command in here.
And as a generic we can give the unit.
Unit is a representing weight type for the mediator.
So that's why we can define an empty or no generic type of the I command.
So this is also an empty interface.
We don't have any additional members.
So here we can implement it.
The I command part in this code I command defines a contract for all command types.
And the generic version allows for commands that produce a response.
So this is producing a response.
This is an empty I command that doesn't return any response.
So now at the same way.
Similarly we can define I query interface for our queries.
For that purpose.
In the queries location we can add new item which is the I query interface.
So this is the interface that we are going to abstract.
So again this will be the follow the same steps I query will be returned as a response again.
And we are going to inherit from the I request which comes from the mediator.
And I'm going to give the response in here okay.
We will make this interface as a public due to using from the other microservices.
And also we can add a generic filter which response could not be null.
We can add a not null filter in here okay.
The query also completed the I query interface inherit from the I request and it is designed to return
a result.
This is used for the read operations.
By creating these abstractions, we can separate the responsibilities and manage the cross-cutting concerns
like validations more effectively.
Commands can have their own validations and distinct from the queries.
And also you can see in here these six abstraction will be used across for each microservices by referencing
the Building Blocks class library, by adding all common stuff in the Building Blocks class library,
we ensure consistency and reduce the code duplication across other microservices.