In this video, we are going to continue to create abstractions on mediator for sequence.
So we will continue building upon our sequence abstractions with the mediator framework.
As you can see that we have created a query and a command.
Now it is time to create a query handler and a command handler.
Firstly, let's define the command handler interface.
This interface will extend the mediators.
I request handler interface, but will be specific for the handling command request.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the Building Blocks and C queries folder.
You can right click and create new interface.
Which name is a command handler.
Okay, now we can develop our AI command handler interface.
First of all, I would like to create this command handler with getting the generic responses.
This will be the command and response I'm going to passing the int command and t response.
This will be represented by command handler.
And this is the command.
And this will be the command response.
So we will inherit from the I request handler.
This comes from the mediator.
And this makes this interface as a handler interface for command operations.
So you can continue the passing generic types.
Here you can see that we have defined our command handler.
Of course this should be public.
And after defining this command handler you can see that there is an exception.
If you hover this exception, you can see that these three command type cannot be used as a T request
that means these t commands comes from the request object.
That's why we should put some of the parameters in var keyword.
So the t command should be a command and returning the t response.
If you go to the I command, you can see the I command comes from the I request t response.
When we have defined this filter, the exception is gone.
Okay, now we have completed the command handler for the first interface.
We will also create one more interface as the same name.
But this time the response will not be coming.
So we will prepare additional interface as the same name.
But this time if there is no any response, we will only accommodate the command object.
So I'm going to make it a command handler inherit from the below interface and as you can see that it
is expecting command and response as a command.
We will passing the T command.
And as a response we can define the unit.
As you remember that unit is a void type as mediator.
So that's why we have defined additional interface in order to accommodate.
If there is no response from the command object, we will use this kind of interfaces.
So again I'm going to put a var keyword which is the filtering.
The command should be a command.
And as you remember that we have also a command passing the unit object.
So in here we have defined two interfaces one for the command handler and do not return any response.
We can see the unit type and one for the I command handler getting the response object.
And this response object should not be null.
By this way, we can use a command handler according to our type.
If we return any response, we will use this command handler.
If we don't any return response, we will use these interface which is the I command handler.
After defining the I command handler now we should define the I query handler.
It is similar to I command handler and it specialized mediator.
I request handler for handling the query request.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the secrets folder under the building blocks.
And you can right click and add new interface.
Which name is AI query handler.
So this should be public interface.
And again I'm going to get a query object and returning the response type.
These are the generics.
And we will inherit from the I request sender.
From the mediator and desist accepting the decree and returning to teh response.
And also we should define the word keywords in here in order to specify the query should be the I query
object and returning the t response.
And again we should additional where filter for the response should not be null.
Okay.
As you can see that we have defined our query handler in one interface.
This interface will handle our query request and providing that each query is matched with a corresponding
response type.
By this way, we can separate the query and commands.
You can see in here the query should be inherited from the query object.
But if you go to the command handler, this command should be comes from the I command.
So that means we have separate query and command handler according to our abstraction.
Now it is time to get in reference to our microservices.
If you go back to our main architecture, you can see that all microservices are referencing building
blocks.
So now let's referencing these interfaces into our catalog microservices.
First we need to remove the direct installation of the mediator package from the catalog API, because
it will now come through our building blocks library.
As you remember that when we are developing the catalog microservices, we install Mediator library.
Now we should remove this library.
And this library comes from the building blocks because we will install all common packages under the
building blocks for each microservices.
Let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio Code and go to the catalog microservices.
If you double click the catalog API project file, you can see that we have installed the mediator library.
In order to remove these package from our catalog API microservices.
You can remove these line of code or you can remove from the NuGet package window I am going to remove
from in here.
And you can see that there is no mediator package in the item group in the project C-sharp file.
So we removed the mediator package from our catalog API in order to avoid conflicts and ensure that
all mediator related packages comes from the building blocks.
Next, we will add a project reference to our Building Blocks library.
In our catalog project.
So let me right click dependencies.
Here you can see the dependencies add project reference.
This time we will add a project reference.
And here you can see that there is only one project listed which is the building blocks.
Check this checkbox and click the okay button.
So once we add a project reference, you can double click the catalog API and you can see new item Group
edit which is the project reference and indicating the are building blocks.
C-sharp project which is the class library.
Save this file and you can now right click and build the catalog API.
So after adding the reference, we build the project in order to verify that everything is correctly
set up.
And there is no any compilation error.
Yes, there is no any compilation error and we will complete it successfully.
Now we can go to the our actual business logic which is a feature folder products and go to the create
product feature.
And if you go to the create product handler, now we can implement the actual logic which is the business
logic, to create a product using the mediator libraries.
Since we are getting reference from the building blocks now, we can use these abstractions into our
handle class.
Now we will refactor our existing handler in the catalog microservices and we will replace mediators
eraqus with our I command and Iquery interfaces.