In this video we are going to developing http post endpoint with using the Carter with implementing
the I Carter module for building minimal APIs.
So let's begin by implementing I Carter module interface into our code.
Open the Visual Studio and go to Create Product Endpoint and locate the Create Product Endpoint class.
And now I'm going to inherit from the I Carter module.
So this should come from the building blocks Carter Library.
And we can adding the using statement.
So once we adding the I Carter module and implementing to our endpoint class, it is required to implement
some of the methods.
These are the add route methods.
So as you remember that in the add methods we can define exposing APIs from our minimal API.
So that means these create product endpoint class will be responsible for setting up our post endpoint.
We will exposing post endpoint in here using the minimal API and Carter.
But before that let's understand our requirement.
We should passing the objects to the create product request to do command handler.
The idea is that in here we will use the mediator library and trigger the mediator command under class.
So that means we should pass the values from the request object to the handler command object.
In order to pass values from request to command object, we need a mapping object and mapping library.
So if you open the our request lifecycle, you can see that once we get the request object, we should
convert this request object as a command object in order to trigger command handler.
So how we can convert request to command object.
Of course we need a mapping library.
Here you can see the a mapping library which name is master.
Master is a high performance object mapper.
And it is very straightforward and flexible and perfect for mapping objects.
In ASP.Net core applications.
We will use master in order to convert our request module to the mediator command object and vice versa.
So if you go to the GitHub project, you can see the details on the Readme file.
You can see the master writing mapping methods is a machine job and do not waste your time and let master
do it.
This is very typical installation.
We will install Mapsto nuget package and if you scroll down you can see the basic usage.
We can just using the adapt method in order to convert target and destination object.
And you can see additional configuration in order to activate master into an ASP.Net core application.
So now let's install the master NuGet package into our application.
So where should we install Master library in catalog microservices or building blocks.
If you open the R class library project diagram, as you know that we have created the Building Blocks
class library in order to storing all common operations and all common NuGet packages for any microservice
development.
In our issue of microservice solution.
For that purpose, it is best practice to move master class library into building blocks class library
in order to manage common libraries into one place for each microservices, and it could be also easy
for the version management of these kind of NuGet packages.
Whenever any microservices added into our picture, it will very easy to start development with referencing
the Building Blocks class library.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the Building blocks.
Right click and manage NuGet packages.
So in here we are going to install Master Search for the master library and select and install this
library.
And if you double click the building blocks you can see that this time master comes into our command
class library.
And you can see that we have three common library for each microservices.
Please save these building blocks.
Now we are ready for the development or actual endpoint definitions.