In this video, we are going to implement an http post request with slash products endpoint for creating
product in our catalog.
Microservices using Carter and Napster for object mapping.
So please open the Visual Studio and locate the Create Product Endpoint class and locate the Add Routes
function.
So in this function we will define our Http post endpoint using Carter and Napster.
And after that we will map the our request to a command object.
And after that we will send it through the mediator and then map the result back to the response model.
So let's get started.
For that purpose I'm going to start with the app dot map operation mapping the http post request.
For that purpose, we are using the map post method, and in the configuration of this method we should
define the request Uri or request Uri should be products, and in the second parameter, we will implement
the actual handler method of this request.
For that purpose, I'm going to start an async anonymous function and I'm going to get a great product
request parameter.
From the request body and I will inject Isander object from the mediator.
We can use mediator in here and using the sender object in order to send.
Our function.
Okay.
Here you can see the our method.
This will be the.
Anonymous method.
Let me come here.
And it is more clear now.
So we will define handle method of the these request object.
First of all I'm going to get a command object from the request.
How we can create request object to command.
Of course we will use Napster.
And Napster has adapt method.
And as a generic we can give the command object which is the create product command object.
And now we will convert using the Napster from request to command object.
Why we need a command object?
Because our mediator is requiring command object in order to trigger our command handler.
So for that purpose I'm going to trigger the mediator with using the sender object.
Sanderson method will be trigger our handler.
If we send this command to object which is the or create product command object okay.
This command will be.
Start the mediator and trigger the handler class.
And after getting the result, we can again convert the response type from the result.
Using the maps to operation and Napster.
Using the adapt method and in the adapt method, we can convert back to our create product response
object and we can return results that created.
This comes from the ASP.Net, and we can return the newly created product ID with using the results
class.
Here you can see the class is in here.
Result set created.
Returning to our 202 created response to Http method and we can redirect to product by id method.
After that, we will develop this method soon and we will return the response object that including
the get newly created id okay, now we can configure these http post method.
If you come here and put the dot method, you can see that there's lots of extension method provided
by the Carter library to configure our Http method with specifying the with name, description, summary
and so on.
So we will use these kind of extensions.
Let me remove this throw method.
And now I am going to copy paste these configurations that you can also copy paste from our GitHub project.
So here as you can see that we will specify the name of the http post method which is the create product
and it will be produced create product response.
And the status code should be 201 created that we are returning in this line of code.
And if there is a problem we can return 400 bad request.
And these are the summary and descriptions of these http post method.
So basically in this implementation we map the incoming request to the create product command object
and send it using the mediator and mediator will be trigger our handler class.
And after that we will get back the response and adapt the result back to the create product response
and return these response to the client application.
Okay.
Here you can see the our endpoint class.
But in order to simplify our code we will move the command using statement to global using C sharp file.
Here you can see that it is increasing the using statement.
And these libraries are using mostly all of the classes for that purpose.
It is best practice to creating global using C sharp class under the catalog API.
I'm going to right click Add New file.
Or we can add control shift add button and adding new class which name is global using.
And in here I'm going to adding global using statement which includes the Carter Master and Mediator.
Please save these global using C sharp class.
And if you go back to endpoint class you can see that these will be obsolete if you remove unnecessary
using statement.
You can see that now our class is more cleaner.
Now we can right click and build catalog microservices.
After setting up our endpoint and refactoring using statement, we build the project and ensure that
the build complete successfully.
Okay, now can we send the request to our microservices?
We have already developed our microservices in here.
You can see that this time we will send Http request and we will develop our endpoint class and also
handle class.
No.
Because even though we built our endpoint and handler class, we can test it yet because we have to
register Carter mediator and master libraries in ASP.Net Core Dependency Injection container and configure
them in the startup process, which is the program.