In this video, we are going to register Mediator and Carter libraries into ASP.Net Dependency Injection
Service and Request pipeline.
Let's start by examining the program.
Exe file.
If you open the program CS for Catalog Micro Services you can see the these empty structure.
As you remember that the structure is divided by two.
Before building the web application, we will add the services into dependency injection container.
And after building the web application we will configure the Http request pipeline.
So we will follow these steps when registering Carter and Mediator.
Our first step is Register Carter Library which will handle our minimal API endpoints.
Carter provide a structured way to define our routes using the Carter model.
For that purpose, we will register the Carter in here.
First of all, we will start with the adding Carter classes into dependency injection using the builder
object Builder services.
And we can use Add Carter method.
So this method comes from the Carter Library.
And this will be registered Carter classes into ASP.Net Dependency Injection container.
And after that we will configure Http request pipeline with Carter in order to exposing the Http get
and post methods.
For that purpose, we will use Http method after building the web application and we can use map method
map Carter.
If you look at the ad carton method, this is adding the necessary services for Carter into ASP.Net
code dependency injection.
If you look at the map carton method map, Carter maps the routes defined in the I Carter module implementation.
So if you look at the our endpoint class here, you can see the I Carter module implementation class
which is the create product endpoint class with adding the map Carter operation into Program.cs.
This will be Carter will be secondary I Carter module interface implementation and expose the minimal
APIs looking for the map methods.
So that means this will be secondary.
All code and looking for the I Carter module implementation and map the required Http methods.
So the next step is we will register the mediator library which will manage our command and query handlers.
I'm writing as a builder services and this time we will add mediator.
But this time I'm going to configure the mediator.
That's why we can define the config method in here.
And in the config method I'm going to specify the required configuration.
In here we can say that config dot register services from assembly.
So that means we are going to register all services into this project into the mediator class library.
For that purpose I'm going to give the type of program.cs that means this class and give the assembly
name when registering services into mediator.
So this is the adding required services into mediator.
So that means add mediator method, register the mediator services and register services from assembly
method tells the mediator where to find our command and query handler classes.
So with these Mediator and Carter registered our application is now ready to handle requests.
Carter will manage the API endpoints and mediator will handle the business logic through our command
and handlers.
And we are ready for the sending request to our application.