In this video we are going to test catalog API with sending to create product http post request.
So that means we will send an http post request to our API endpoint.
And Carter will handle the routing and redirecting to mediator.
And mediator send operation will process the request through the appropriate handler and the handler
operation, perform the actual logic and returning the response.
So we will test and debug the create product endpoint in our catalog.
Microservices.
In order to understand these request lifecycle in ASP.Net core with using the Carter and Mediator.
So our first step is running the catalog microservices.
If you open the Visual Studio and select the catalog API, right click Set Startup Project.
And if you open the properties and check the line settings, we will already change the these application
URL and port numbers in here, which is the 5050 50 for Https.
And we will run these microservices in the Https running profile.
For that purpose.
Please come here and select the Https and run this application with clicking this button.
As you can see, that application started successfully.
We can see the localhost 5050 for https.
And also you can check the project console window and verify from this here application are listening
on https 5050 port.
So now it is ready for the Sendrequest.
But before testing, let's set our breakpoints in our code.
If you open the Visual Studio, we should place one breakpoint on the minimal API endpoint, which is
the create product endpoint and put the breakpoint in here to understand and catch the incoming request.
And after that, we should put another breakpoint in the create product handle method, which will be
provide actual business logic in mediator handler operation.
So this will allow us to observe the flow of the request through the application.
So we put our debuggers and now we will send the http post request.
In order to send http post request we will use postman.
If you open the postman and create any Http method, the Http method should be post and the URL should
be the our application, which is the.
Localhost 5050.
You can copy from here.
And now we should also add product suffix in here.
Because if you look at the R code you can see that we are exposing our microservice application as a
Http post slash products endpoint.
So that's why we should add this endpoint at the end of the localhost 5050.
And after that we should define our body operation which will be the our row body and Json file.
And this will be the our request object.
I'm going to copy paste our body operation which including the name, category, description, image,
file and price.
These are the members of the product entity.
And we will send these Http request.
And this will be also members our record type of the our request object.
If you go to the Our Visual Studio and open the create product endpoint at the first point, this will
be expecting a body information as a great product request.
And in this request object you can see the members are name, category, description and so on.
So we will send these Json format in the body operations with sending http post request with this URL.
Let's click the Http send button and observe how the execution happens for this request and see that
it responds.
404 Not found exception.
So what is mean 404 not found response.
That means there is no endpoint on this http url, which is the localhost 5050 products endpoint.
But how it can be happen.
We already expose http post endpoint using the Carter.
If you open the Visual Studio and go to the create product endpoint, you can see that this class is
inherited from the Eye Carter model.
And we already mapping the post operation with using the Eye Carter model.
And if you look at the program says we have already registered the Carter into our catalog API.
So how it can be happen.
We set that Carter will second the Eye Carter module interface implementation and expose the minimal
APIs.
So if Carter will scan our project this will be found.
Create product endpoint that inherits from the Eye Carter model.
So why Carter is not scan or catalog API assembly?
After investigating the issue, I found that when we have installed our Carter into building blocks,
you can see the picture on the slide.
We have installed the Carter in the Building Blocks class library so it is sickening.
Eye Carter module interfaces in the building blocks class library due to installation happened in this
assembly, but we define endpoints in the catalog microservices.
That's why the Carter cannot be scanned or catalog API.
Microservice and cannot be find eye catalog interface modules.
So after that I go back to our program.cs and check the Carter configuration.
You can see that mediator has also in the same station, mediator installed in the building blocks and
using in the catalog API.
But we have configured the mediator with using the register services from the assembly and passing Program.cs
assembly for catalog microservices.
So is it possible for the Carter?
For that reason, please open the Our Carter GitHub repository.
And if you scroll down you can see the configurations and the current configurations.
We don't have any configuration for setting or giving assembly from outside.
The only configurations are these.
We can only specify the modules and passing the modules.
That means the class endpoint names, but we cannot pass the assembly name.
If you go back to Program.cs and try to configure these, Carter, you can see the config operations
and see the methods.
There is no SMD definition.
We only define the module configuration.
That means we can specify the direct class name, but we would like to passing the assembly that is
not available for now.
When you are watching this, if the Carter developed this kind of assembly config method, please use
it like similar with the mediator.
But for now we should remove the Carter from the building blocks and install for catalog microservices.
For that purpose, please go to Building Blocks.
Double click the C-sharp project and remove the Carter from the building blocks and save this file and
go back to catalog API.
Right click and manage NuGet packages.
Of course we should stop the project, and after that right click and manage NuGet packages and search
for the Carter and install Carter into catalog.
Microservices.
For that purpose, I'm going to right click and manage NuGet packages and search again for the Carter.
And install Carter into catalog microservices.
If you double check, you can see the Carter is located under Catholic API and removed from the building
blocks.
So now if we review our codes, look at the endpoint class we have already using the Eye Carter module.
And since we are using the global using statement, this will be correct itself inside of the Catholic
API.
And now when the program is running and adding the Carter, this will be scanning the current assembly
which is the Catholic API, and this will be find Catholic API endpoint which is the create product
endpoint.
So if we run the application in Https mode again, and this time we will see that our endpoints will
be hit the breakpoint and we will debug the whole request lifecycle.
See that the application is start successfully.
If you open the our postman and send the same Json payload to the http post request here.
This time you can see that our map post method is triggered and we can debug our incoming request.
We can see the request details in here.
If you expand the request, you can see the request values comes in here that we send as a Json payload.
So in this line of code we convert these request object to the command object.
And after that mediator will send the command to the internal handler class.
And here you can see that our internal handle class is triggered.
And in this code we perform business logic with creating new product and passing and skipping the database
operation.
For now.
And we are returning the result object which including newly created our.
Product object that comes from the mediator handler.
You can see the result and see the id is newly created product.
And in this line of code, we will use master to adapting the result object to the create product response,
and we will return the response to the Http client.
If you click the F5, you will see the response is coming in here and you can see the Http status is
201.
That means it is created successfully.
As you can see that we have successfully seen ASP.Net request lifecycle using with Carter minimal APIs
and mediator command and command handlers.