In this section, we are going to consume discount gRPC service from the basket.
Microservices.
When adding cart item into shopping cart in order to calculate the final price.
So we will focus on integrating the discount gRPC service into the basket microservices.
Let's check our big picture and see what we are going to build one by one.
As you can see that we are at this point and we will consume discount gRPC service from the basket microservices
when adding cart item into shopping cart.
So in the last section we have developed a discount gRPC microservices.
And we have exposed the gRPC methods to the basket API.
So in this section, when the client add item into shopping cart basket, microservices will consume
discount gRPC service methods in order to calculate and get latest discount and calculate the discount
for the particular product item.
In this picture you can see that basket API microservices will be our gRPC client and call the gRPC
method to the discount gRPC server, and this will be triggered by the client add item into basket use
cases.
So let me explain the main steps of the our application.
So the first step is integration of gRPC client.
The basket microservices will act as a gRPC client to consume services exposed by the discount gRPC
service.
And this involves registering discount gRPC operations into basket microservices.
That means the next step is service registration.
Modify the Program.cs in the basket microservices to include the discount gRPC client, and we will
configure the client with the necessary endpoint details of the discount gRPC services.
And after that we will consume discount services in the relevant part of the basket.
Microservices.
That means when adding items into cart, we call the discount gRPC services in order to fetch applicable
discounts, and we will update the logic to apply these discounts to the cart items and calculate the
final price accordingly.
And lastly, we will perform re containerization.
That means we will update the Docker compose setup to ensure the basket microservices can communicate
within the discount gRPC services in the orchestrated environments.