In this video we are going to consume discount gRPC service from the basket microservices.
So we are going to establishment to connection between basket and discount gRPC microservices.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And the first point is we should identify the trigger point from the basket API microservices.
For that purpose, please open the basket API and go to Basket Vertical Slice folder and go to the store
Basket use case.
And if you open the store basket end point, you can see that this is the end point.
When triggering add or remove item into shopping cart.
And in the shopping cart is a Json object that we can store the whole Json as an object into this shopping
cart.
You can see the shopping cart model in here, and we will send and receive shopping cart Json request
and response with using this slash basket http post endpoint in order to store baskets and this class
trigger mediator store basket command and execute the handler method.
In this line of code.
This will be.
Send this command to the our handled class.
And if you open the store basket handle class in here, you can see that this is the handle method that
we will trigger when we are add or remove item into shopping cart.
So this is the point where we are communicate and integrate with the discount gRPC and call gRPC methods
from the basket microservices.
For that purpose, I am going to put a command in the beginning of the handle method, and this is the
communicate with discount gRPC and calculate latest prices of products into basket.
And this is the 2D statement that we are going to perform in the beginning of the handle method.
And after that I am going to refactor this handle method.
For example, this cart variable is not using anywhere.
So I'm going to remove this statement.
And after that I'm going to combine these statements which is basically we have already performed this
todo statements.
And I'm going to put a command about what we have done in the previous videos.
We basically store basket in database using Martin and Redis cache.
Now we can focus on our todo statement which is communicate and integrate discount gRPC from the basket
microservices.
So how we can do that?
The first thing we should do that we will set up the gRPC client.
That means in order to consume our discount gRPC microservices, we should set up the basket API as
a gRPC client in the basket API project.
So how we can do basket API to the gRPC client?
We should use the Connected Services feature in Visual Studio for this purpose.
So I'm going to open the Visual Studio.
If you go to the basket API project you can see that under the basket API we have connected services.
So we will use connected services for creating client for the discount gRPC into basket API.
For that purpose I'm going to right click and manage Connected Services.
And in this window you can see that there is a service reference that we can define OpenAPI, gRPC,
VRF and so on.
So at this point I'm going to click this button.
And after that I'm going to add a service reference for gRPC to consume these web services.
And click the next button.
And this will required a file definition which will be the R protobuf files.
In the file definition we should provide the discount gRPC proto file which is the discount proto.
So I'm going to browse this file and go back to services and go to Discount discount gRPC protocol folder
and select the Discount Proto file.
And after that we should select the type of the generated class as a client object.
Because basket microservices will be client of the discount gRPC and call the gRPC methods.
So make sure that you have selected the type of the class as a client and click the finish button.
And this will automatically perform client requirements for us.
This will add required NuGet packages and create reference to proto file.
In the client application, you can see that our service is added successfully.
We can close this window.
So in order to verify this operation you can double click the basket API.
And we will check the basket API project for the correct configuration under the item group.
If you scroll down, you can see the packages added in here.
In here you can see that the gRPC dot ASP.Net core package is added successfully when adding the connected
services.
And if you scroll down, you can see that there is new item group added in here.
According to this item group, we will define a protobuf file including the address of the discount
proto file, which is the discount gRPC address, and we will link this discount proto file into the
basket API project.
You can see that naively proto folder created under our project.
If you open this folder and come to discount proto, if you right click this discount proto file and
see the properties, you can see that this is the gRPC stub classes client only.
That means basket API microservices will be our gRPC client and this will be protobuf compiler.
And this will be create a client class in order to communicate with the discount gRPC.
For that purpose, I am going to build the basket API project.
If you right click and build the basket API, this project will be build and ensure the gRPC client
code is generated correctly and we will confirm this.
Create operation of the Discount Proto Service client class in the object folder.
Here you can see that Will is completed successfully.
If you select the basket API and show all files, you can see that the hidden object folder is comes
in the picture.
And if you open the object and if you open the debug net eight.
And if you scroll down a bit, you can see that the discount and discount gRPC client object is generated
from the Visual Studio as a client of the RPC services.
So we will use these classes when communicating between discount gRPC and call the gRPC methods.