In this video we are going to modify the store basket handle class in the basket API to dynamically
calculate final price of the products.
For that purpose, please go to store Basket Command handler and go to the handle method.
And we are going to perform this todo statement before start implementing these todo statements.
We should inject discount portal service client object into our constructor.
This is the first point that we should do in here.
Come to store basket handler class.
And after the repository object I'm going to inject discount proto service.
And this time we have created the client object and give the name as a discount proto.
So this is our client object that is generated from the Visual Studio when we link application and connected
services.
So we are going to use this discount proto object to performing these two statements.
For that purpose go to this handle method and perform the todo statement.
Basically, we will iterate for each item into the cart cart coming from the parameters of the command.
So I'm going to perform for each statement in here.
So we will iterate the shopping cart items.
And we will perform and call the gRPC services for each item.
For that purpose I'm going to communicate with the discount gRPC proto file.
We basically use discount proto object that we have injected in the class, and we will use get discount
async method in order to get discount operations from the discount microservices.
And I am going to pass as a parameter Ngif discount request object.
And in this request object we will perform the product name with incoming item operation item product
name, and after that passing the cancellation token of this method.
So this is the synchronous gRPC call communication handle with this line of code.
And we will return back a coupon object.
And after getting the coupon object we basically calculate the latest prices with deducting coupon amount
information from the actual price of the item.
So this is the for each statement that we are going to perform.
For each shopping cart items, call the discount gRPC services using the Get discount async method,
and after that adjust the items price based on the discount amount received.
So this is the implementation of this Todo statement.
And after that I am performing some of the refactoring in this method.
So basically we should extract the logic of the discount calculation into separate method.
Which name is deduct discount for better readability and maintainability.
For that purpose, I'm going to extract this method and make clear our handle method for that purpose.
Come here and I have creating a new method which name is deduct discount.
And this is the method that we have extracting this Todo statement and operation.
Here you can see that we are getting shopping cart as a parameter of this deduct discount method and
performing for each operation for calling discount gRPC.
So after developing this deduct discount method, you can copy paste this for each statement and to
do statement.
And after that you can remove this code.
And now we can safely call await deduct discount operation with passing the command dot cart object
and cancellation token.
By this way, we can use two operations.
The first one is deduct discount and the second one is store basket.
And after that return back to the store basket.
Result.
So this is the implementation of the communication with discount gRPC and calculate latest price of
the products into shopping cart.