In this video, we are going to register discount gRPC client object into the ASP.Net Dependency Injection
container.
Here you can see that we have injected discount proto service client object and we use this object when
performing deduct discount actual operation.
So we inject this operation into the our store basket command handler class.
So when we inject any services we should not forget to register ASP.Net dependency injection container.
So let's take an action for that purpose please go to basket API and Program.cs.
In here we are going to register all services into the edge services to container part.
But before that I'm going to organize Program.cs by configuring various type of services application
data, gRPC and cross coding services.
These will be increased the readability and maintainability of the program says.
So.
Let me start with the application services in here.
The first line of codes are application services.
So these are the application services including Carter and Mediator Library.
And after that we will inject the data services.
These are the Martin.
So here you can see that I have put a command for the data services that is representing repository
objects and Martin objects.
And also we can add in here as a Redis cache operation.
So these are the data related services that adding to ASP.Net built in dependency injection container.
And after that I am going to add a gRPC services.
For now I am putting a command in here.
We will add gRPC related services in this line of code.
So after that we can see that the rest of the codes are registering crosscutting services.
These are the exception handling health checks and so on.
So these are the grouping the main methodology of the our services application data gRPC and crosscutting
for the basket API.
Now we can focus on the gRPC services and registration.
In here we can start to register gRPC client.
So I'm going to write builder services add gRPC client extension method.
And inside of this method we will pass discount proto service dot discount proto service client.
So I'm going to using discount gRPC namespace.
And in here we can register discount Proto service client object.
And of course we should provide the options in here as options I am going to provide discount gRPC endpoint.
As you can see that we will specify the options at this way.
In the options you can see that.
Let me check the options.
We can specify the address information that we can give the new Uri.
So I'm going to provide the new Uri which is the gRPC discount URL.
And I am passing this line of code here.
You can see that we will paste the Uri with incoming configuration from the application settings under
the gRPC settings discount URL.
So we will provide these configuration application settings very soon.
But before that make sure that you have registered discount proto service client with a giving configuration
including the address information.
For client connection, we should define discount URL configuration into application settings Json file.
For that purpose, please go to application Settings.json for the basket API.
And after that under the connection string, we can define the gRPC settings as we are using in the
Program.cs.
Here you can see that I have added gRPC settings and specifying the discount URL and indicating the
localhost 5052.
As you suggested, this port number is indicating discount gRPC microservices that we can connect in
order to call gRPC methods.
So with adding these configuration into application settings, Json file and also adding registration
operation in the program says we have completed the basket API configurations as a gRPC client.