In this video, we are going to test end to end use case for discount and basket microservices.
So we are start with the basket microservices.
When adding item into basket.
This will be integrated with the discount over the gRPC protocol and get discount values and calculate
the latest price of the products into the basket.
So when we are sending these payload, we will send the price 500 and we have discount 150 and 100.
So this will be deduct our product prices.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And first of all we should make sure that our Docker desktop is running.
And after that we should start baking services like PostgreSQL, Redis, cache and so on.
For that purpose, I'm going to right click the Docker compose and set a startup project.
And this time I'm going to run without debugging because the idea is that activate and up and running
for the backing services, because we will test these basket and discount integration into our local
computer.
Please click this button, start without debugging and make sure that your backing services is up and
running.
That our local microservices can connect to database and cache services.
So this will be running the docker compose up command on behind of the scenes.
And after that you can open the Docker desktop and verify that your backing services are up and running.
Catalog basket and distributed cache.
So after that we will perform and test our discount operation into our local computer.
For that purpose, we can put breakpoint under the store basket command handler class and put breakpoint
into deduct discount method.
And at the same way we can put a breakpoint under the discount.
And if you go to the services discount services and we will put a breakpoint under the get discount
method.
So now it is time to run multiple startup project in our local environment.
For that purpose I am going to right click the solution file.
Come here, right click the solution file and select the properties.
And we can select the multiple startup project.
And these are the basket API.
We can set a start and after that discount gRPC.
Because these will be integrated when performing add item in the shopping cart and apply and okay.
So now we are ready to test our basket and discount gRPC in our local computer.
In here you can see the newly start button comes in here and click this run button and start basket
and discount gRPC into our local computer.
You can verify the microservices from the Project Console windows.
So here you can see that basket microservices is up and running on my local computer and listening to
5051 port.
And also you can see the discount gRPC services is running on local computer and listening to 5052.
So if you look at our basket microservices, if you go to application settings, these will be getting
5052 port for the discount URL.
So that means it is ready for the accepting requests to our services.
Please open the postman.
And first of all, I would like to verify that our gRPC services is working fine for that purpose.
Open the discount servers and select the method as a get discount and change the port number localhost
5052.
And after that I will paste product name as a request parameters and invoke gRPC call.
This will be trigger or get discount method of the gRPC microservices and this will be return us a id
one product name and amount as 150 discount information from the coupon table.
So our discount service is running successfully in our local computer.
That means we can go to end to end test.
For that purpose, I'm going to open each of microservices postman collection, go to basket folder
and go to Post Store Basket operation.
And if you open this store basket operation you can see that we have already prepared our endpoint http
post request and the payload.
In the payload you can see that items has two items and the item price is 500.
So we have two discount for iPhone X and Samsung ten.
And this will be price deducting from the coupon amount information.
And we will calculate the total price in different and deducted way.
So you can check the basket URL in here in basket URL.
Now looking for the Docker environment.
But we are testing in the local environment.
That's why I change the environment as a localhost and verify the basket.
URL comes as a 5051 and send http post request to perform store basket operation.
Here you can see that our breakpoint is triggering in the store basket endpoint.
If you continue to debug operation, you can see that it comes to our store basket command handler handle
method.
In this method we basically perform two main operations.
These are the deduct discount and store basket.
So if you continue the debugging we will basically paste the shopping cart into deduct discount method.
And in this method we basically iterate for each item in the shopping cart.
And after that for each item we will call the discount gRPC services get discount async method.
Here you can see that we suddenly trigger get discount operation under Discount services.
In order to get the coupon information from the discount gRPC database and return back to the client
for this operation, we can put breakpoint after the item price point in here.
And if I hit the F5, you can see the coupon amount comes 150 and item price is 500.
And we will calculate the latest price and set the latest price is at 350.
And for the next item we can call again the discount gRPC get discount async method.
At the same way we will retrieve the coupon information and after that calculate the amount.
Deducting from the 500 to 100 and latest price is calculated to 400.
So this is the deduct discount operation.
And the rest of the operation is similar that we have done before.
Connected and communicating PostgreSQL database and Redis cache.
I'm going to hit the F5 and complete the operation.
And you can see that the client response comes in here as a username as the boolean.
That means this will be complete this operation successfully 201 created operations.
You can see the payload of the store basket.
We will send 500 price for each item in the shopping cart for the username as Julian.
If we get basket by username and send http get method and I'm hitting F5 to skipping these debugging
operations and focus on the response, you can see that each item deducted from the coupon amount discounted.
The first item is 350, and the second item comes 400 and the total price comes accordingly for the
deducting prices into our shopping cart.
And as you can see that we have successfully called discount gRPC service from the basket microservices
when adding and removing item into shopping cart.