In this video we are going to do the last step, which is the re containerization.
We will adding gRPC discount URL configuration in the basket API container configurations on docker
compose file.
This is important to provide correct configuration into basket API microservices in order to connect
to discount gRPC microservices.
So let's take an action.
First of all, please open the Visual Studio and let's open the basket API project.
If you double click the project file, we can review the changes in the project file.
If you scroll down, you can see the item group and protobuf definition that is gRPC client configuration
in basket API project indicating the discount gRPC profile and this will be performed the client operations
in the basket API.
And after that we have changed Program.cs adding gRPC related services in the dependency injection container
and change the code into store basket handle.
So for all these changes, we should re containerize basket API and recreate the Docker image for basket
API to incorporate these recent code changes.
And this ensure that the Docker container runs the latest version of the basket API.
With communicating the discount gRPC.
For that purpose, please go to basket API project file.
Right click Add Docker Support and select the Linux as the operating system and click the okay button.
So we have regenerated docker file, but there is no code change.
But basket API image should be recreate from the scratch to adding new codes into our container.
And if you look at the application settings, you can see that we should add an environment variables
for gRPC settings, discount URL and these URL should be changed according to our Docker port and server
name.
That means we should update the docker compose override Yaml file to configure these gRPC settings.
Discount URL as an environment variable.
For that purpose, please open the docker compose.
Overwrite Yaml file and locate the basket API configurations.
If you scroll down, you can reach the basket API configurations.
So at this point, the first thing we should do that we should add an environment variable for gRPC
settings and discount URL at the same way with the other connection string and other operations.
Here you can see that I have added gRPC settings, double underscore discount URL and give the URL https
discount, gRPC and 8081.
So we configure the URL for the discount gRPC service and using the discount gRPC 881 directs to basket
API to communicate over the Https protocol, with the discount gRPC services running on port 8081 in
the Docker network.
Because in Docker network, the discount microservice server name is a discount gRPC.
If you scroll down, you can see the discount gRPC microservice configuration, and the container name
as a discount gRPC.
And inside of the discount gRPC you can see the port numbers.
These are the Docker port numbers, which is the internal port numbers that we can access inside of
the Docker.
That's why we will use 8081 to using Https protocol for discount gRPC microservices from the basket
microservices in Docker environment.
So this is important because we explicitly give the network URL and the port number for correct gRPC
communication inside of the docker.
So if you don't set the correct URL for this configuration, you will end up the socket exception and
you will get connection refused exception from the gRPC communication.
Please don't forget to adding 8081.
If you want to use Http protocol, you can even use 8080 in here.
So this is the important configuration to communicate basket and discount microservices in Docker network.
And after that we can also set the dependencies option under the Dependson.
I'm going to add a new Dependson which name is discount gRPC because depends on provider to ensure that
basket API starts after the discount gRPC service is up and running and establishing dependency order
in the Docker environment.
So as you can see that we have successfully added gRPC discount URL settings and adding depends on into
our basket API and configure our basket API in the docker compose environment.
Next video we are going to test all in docker compose environment.