In this video, we are going to test the communication between basket API and the discount gRPC microservices
within the Docker environment using the Docker compose files.
And we will also addressing the SSL certificate exception when we are integrating basket API to discount
gRPC for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and we will recreate the basket API container
in order to reflect new changes in our code.
For that purpose, I'm going to right click the Docker compose and set a startup project.
Normally, you can remove all existing containers and recreate from scratch in your Docker desktop.
We should delete the basket API and recreate from the scratch.
But when we use Visual Studio docker compose running profile, it will detect the changes on specific
container, which configurations are changed and recreate the container for us.
For example, in our case we have changed the basket API microservice configuration and the docker compose
overwrite file.
So it should only recreate basket container.
And we will see this when running docker compose on Visual Studio.
Set a startup project.
And this time I'm going to start without debugging to observe the containers being created or updated
in the Docker desktop, click this button to start without debugging, and you can check the container
logs for basket and discount microservices to ensure they are ready to accept requests.
But here you can see that the basket microservices is removed and recreate from scratch using the Docker
compose up commands by Visual Studio and the basket API recreate with the newly adding codes and configurations,
and we can confirm the basket API and discount gRPC from the logs.
If you open the basket API here, you can see the basket API created successfully and discount gRPC
also created successfully.
Now we can send the request using the postman.
Please open the postman and let me start with testing discount gRPC microservices.
Select the discount service and select the Get discount method.
Make sure that you have called the Docker IP and port number.
This is localhost 6062 and get discount method and the method body should be product name iPhone x.
Click the invoke button in order to run gRPC and get a success response from the discount microservices,
which is the environment.
So we have confirmed that the discount service is up and running.
Now we should go to end to end test for the basket API.
Microservices.
Under a microservices postman collection, you can go to the post store basket request.
And in here we should change the environment localhost to the docker and make sure that the basket URL
is 6061.
And you can see the payload in here we are going to send http post request in order to communicate with
the discount gRPC fully Docker environment using the docker compose.
And I'm going to send http post request.
And this time you can see that we got 500 internal server error.
And the exception is error.
Starting gRPC call.
And this is the SSL connection could not be establishment.
That means we don't have the remote certification.
And this is the invalid according to the validation procedure.
This error happens due to ASP.Net core Https development certificate not being trusted by the client.
In our case, client is basket API.
When making call to the gRPC server discount gRPC, the asp.net https development certificate is required.
So how we can solve this problem?
We can solve this problem to configure gRPC client in basket API to bypassing SSL certificate validations.
And this is done by modifying the configure primary Http message handler method.
For that purpose, I'm going to open Visual Studio and go to the basket API programs case.
If you open the Program.cs and go to the configuration of the gRPC services here, you can see that
we would like to bypass the SSL certificate validation for that purpose.
There is very good method extension for the configuration.
I'm going to edit this configuration after these builder services at gRPC client.
In here I'm going to add this line of code which is the configure primary Http message handler method,
and specifying the Http client handler, and say that you can bypass the server certificate, custom
validation callback and accept any server certificate validators in our gRPC settings.
But this setup is typically used for the development purpose and you should not be used in production
environment due to security risks.
So with this configuration we have fixed the SSL certification exception and we will continue our test.