In this video, we are going to continue our integration tests on Docker environment.
In the last video, we have fixed the SSL certificate exception with newly configuring gRPC services.
For that reason we need to re containerize basket API.
To do that, please set a startup project for Docker Compose and after that run without debugging.
This will be run Docker commands on behind of the scenes and the containerized basket API, and after
completed these operations, the basket API will be configured with SSL certificate avoiding these certificate
problem.
So if you open the Docker desktop, you can see that our basket API is created successfully and the
other microservices and backing services are up and running.
So now we can continue our entire test in Docker network.
So please open the postman.
Last time we have left in the http post, request to the basket API with a given username and the card
details, and we got exception about SSL connection and certification is invalid.
I'm going to send again http post request to the docker environment 6061 port number.
Click the send button and this time we will see that this will be returned to all one created success
response and return a username.
So that means we have successfully communicate this gRPC and calculate and deduct the price for each
items on the shopping cart.
To verify that I am going to get the shopping cart.
But before that you see that prices are 500 and if you go back to Http get method and if you send the
http get request to our username, you can see that the prices are deducted with the discount information
from the coupon table and total price is reflected successfully.
As you can see that we have successfully testing and debugging in the Docker environment.
The basket API microservices correctly communicate with discount gRPC services.