In this section we are going to develop ordering microservices, implementing domain driven design cycles
and clean architecture patterns using the ASP.Net core, Entity Framework core and SQL server database.
Let's check our big picture and see what we are going to build one by one.
As you can see that we are in here and start to developing ordering microservices with SQL server databases.
And here you can find the internal architecture of the ordering microservices.
Ordering microservices will follow the ASP.Net core, minimal APIs and latest features of dotnet eight
and C 12, and applying the domain driven design cycles and clean architecture patterns and best practices,
and also implementing design principles including solid keys, uni separation of concerns or dependency
inversion principles.
And also we will use Entity Framework Core and communicate with the SQL server databases.
So we will develop clean architecture layer in the internal architecture of the ordering microservices.
And these layers are domain application infrastructure and API layer.
And we will also follow the unimplemented secrets with mediator library to implement command and command
handler classes.
And here you can see the NuGet packages that we are going to use when building ordering microservices.
So now let me explain the clean architecture layers for ordering microservices.
Let me start with the ordering domain layer.
In this layer we basically implement tactical domain driven design pattern entities, value objects,
aggregates and also implement strongly typed IDs in domain driven design, implement anemic domain model
versus rich domain model entities.
And lastly we will see domain events and integration events.
And the second layer is ordering infrastructure layer.
In this layer we will use Entity Framework core eight code first Approach and migrations and SQL Server
Connection.
We will use Entity Framework, core eight relations and Domain driven Design value objects mapping with
the complex type and complex property.
And we will follow the Auto Migrate Entity Framework core entities to SQL server database.
That means we will migrate and see the order DB in SQL server, and we will use Entity Framework Core
Interceptors, which is the save change interceptor for auditing entities.
And we will dispatching the domain events in Entity Framework Core interceptors.
And the next layer is ordering Application layer.
In this layer we will follow the secrets with Mediator Library in order to implement the command and
command handler classes.
And we will use mediator pipeline behaviors like validation and logging behavior.
And we will use domain event handlers with mediator in notification handler class.
And we will also use fluent validation to validate inputs and add mediator validation pipeline.
And the last layer is ordering API layer.
In this layer we will use Carter for minimal API endpoint definition and we will perform cross-cutting
concerns, custom exception handling and health checks and so on.
And finally, after all these implementation we will perform deployments.
So in deployments we will use SQL server database containerization and orchestration for each microservices
in the Docker compose.
And we will use Docker file and Docker compose file for running ordering microservices and SQL server
database in Docker environment.