In this video we are going to create ASP.Net project for ordering API microservices.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the services folder that include all microservice folder inside
of this services folder.
And we are going to create a new subfolder.
Right click Add New solution folder.
Which name is ordering.
In this folder we are going to create ASP.Net web API project for ordering API project and we will use
empty project template.
I'm going to right click Add New Project.
And in here we will select the ASP.Net Core Empty project and click the next button and give the project
name as a ordering dot API.
And after that the location is very important.
Please make sure that you have located the same directory.
If you open this directory and go to the source services.
And now I'm going to create a new folder.
Which name is ordering.
And under the ordering folder we will create ordering API project.
Make sure that you have following the same structure in your project.
After that we can click the next button and configure ASP.Net Core Empty project.
The framework should be dotnet eight and we will configure for Https.
Enable Docker and operating system will be Linux and we will use top level statement.
So leave as it is for the configuration and click the create button.
This will be create ASP.Net web API for ordering API project.
And here you can see that this is located under ordering.
If we right click and open in the File Explorer, we can verify that this folder is located under the
src services Ordering and Ordering API.
So now we will start to examine our project.
So the first thing we should do that we should go to the Program.cs.
And this is the default code from the ASP.Net empty template.
So we will refactor these Program.cs according to our requirements.
First of all, I am put a command before the building application which is the add services to the container.
This is representing ASP.Net built in dependency injection container.
And after that we can remove the current map, get operation and put a command again which is configure
the Http request pipeline in here.
And lastly we will run the application.
So this is the minimum code for the program for each microservices.
When we start to developing typically we use two main steps before and after building the web application.
Before building the application we use add services methods for dependency injection.
And after building the application we use use or map function methods for configuring Http request lifecycle.
So now we can build the application and continue with our port numbers.
If you go back to our slide you can see that for ordering microservices we will use 5003 and 5053 port
numbers for Http and Https in our local environment.
So we will follow these port number settings.
In order to do that, please open the Visual Studio.
If you go to the properties and if you expand this properties folder, you can see the Launch settings
Json file.
So we will set the Http and https running profile and the port numbers for http.
I'm going to change 5003.
Here you can see the http url.
And for https we can provide http and https endpoint.
Again for http I'm using 5003.
For https we should change 5053.
So please make these changes and save these launch settings Json file.
This will reflect our port numbers in our local environment.
So in order to set up these configuration we can right click the ordering API, set a startup project
and we can run the Https profile.
And we can verify that these application will start up and listening on localhost 5053.
So I'm opening the project console window.
You can see that application is starting localhost 5053.
And also we should remove this browser open property from the launch settings.
If you come here and if you see this property we can set the launch browser as a false.
And also I'm going to set launch browser false for Http and Https learning profiles.
As you can see that we have successfully created ordering API project and perform the initial setup
for developing ordering microservices.