In this video we are going to do domain analysis of ordering microservices, including domain model,
analyzing application use cases, Rest, API endpoints, and underlying data structures.
So let me check for the domain model.
Analyzing for ordering microservices.
Primary domain models are ordered and ordered item, and these models capture the core business entities
for ordering microservices.
So we said that we have two domain model.
You can see domain model analyze diagram in here.
This is the order and order item.
And we can also add customer and product which are the representing different domain analyzing.
So we will focus on the orders according to our domain.
Analyzing.
The main primary domain model is order.
An order is an aggregate root with the properties such as the customer ID, order name, shipping address,
billing address, payment status, and the list of the order items.
So the next domain entity is order item.
Order item is an entity associated with the order and containing fields like the product ID, quantity
and price.
So the order and order item entities has one to many relationships.
You can also see the class including the order aggregate.
See that order entity is inherited from the aggregate and including the order items, customer ID,
order name, shipping address, billing address and so on.
So also we can consider integration events for order created action.
Here you can see that we can throw an order created event from the order domain model.
The next step is application use case analyzing for ordering microservices.
And we can say that these are the starting with the Crud operations on ordering microservices including
get order with order items, create, update, delete, order, add and remove order item from the order.
So these will be handling the entire lifecycle of an order, including the order items, and these operations
will handle with the Entity Framework core over the SQL server database.
And the second application use cases are asynchronous cases.
And we have two asynchronous cases.
The first one is basket checkout.
We can consume the basket checkout event from RabbitMQ using the Masstransit library performing the
asynchronous communication.
And also we have order fulfillment asynchronous case.
This will be perform order fulfillment operations like billing shipment notification with raising the
order created domain event that leads to integration event.
So we will perform these asynchronous case in the next sections.
And after that we can analyzing the presentation layer which is Rest API endpoints of ordering microservices.
Here you can see the table including the Http get, post, put and delete methods.
We will basically perform these use cases, which is the slash orders, get order with pagination and
slash orders.
Slash order name.
We will get orders by order name filter by the order name, and after that we can filter by the customer
ID including the orders slash customer slash customer ID end point.
And after that we will perform http post, put and delete operation in order to perform Crud operations
on the database.
And lastly, we can say that we have Amqp protocol, which is basically consume basket checkout event
from RabbitMQ using the Masstransit library.
And the last analyzing is infrastructure data underlying data structure of the ordering microservices.
So we can say that ordering microservice has one data store which is the SQL server relational databases.
So that means we basically use relational database SQL server used for the storing orders and order
items.
And we will use Entity Framework Core, which is chosen as a ODM tool.
Applying the code first approach and the domain models are mapped to the Entity Framework core entities.
Considering the domain driven design concepts like aggregates and value objects.