In this video we are going to do technical analysis of ordering microservices.
These are the application architecture, style, pattern and principles libraries, NuGet packages and
project folder structure.
Let me start with the application architecture style.
As an application architecture style, we will follow domain driven design secure and clean architecture.
These are the fundamental architecture styles guiding the development of the ordering microservices.
Clean architecture implementation with creating four layers including the class library project that
reference according to the clean architecture.
We will explain all in the next videos, but for now, let me skip the second technical analysis, which
is the pattern and principles.
When developing ordering microservices, we will see and implement lots of pattern and principles,
and we are grouping these patterns and principles according to clean architecture layers.
But before that, let me start the common principles that we are going to follow.
These are the solid keys Jagni SoC, the IP principles and dependency injection principles.
These are the foundational principles.
And after that we can follow the patterns according to clean architecture layer.
So for the domain layer we will see and implement these patterns.
These are the designing domain driven design oriented microservices and applying the technical patterns.
And we will follow domain entity pattern and entity based classes for seed work operations.
And we will use anemic domain model versus rich domain model.
And we will use value object pattern aggregate pattern aggregate root and root entity pattern, strongly
typed IDs pattern domain events and integration events.
And if you follow the other layers, these are the infrastructure data layers.
In this layer we will follow repository pattern, entity framework, core ORM code first approach migration
and seeding the database value object complex types and entity framework core aggregate root entities
and entity configurations with model builder domain driven design to Entity Core Entity objects.
And lastly, we will raise and dispatch domain events with Entity Framework Core and using Mediator
Library.
And the next layer is Application Use Case layer.
And in this layer we will use these patterns including Singkreis and Kqs pattern command and command
handler pattern, mediator pattern and mediator pipeline behaviors, fluent validation and logging,
cross-cutting concerns.
And lastly there is a presentation layer in the clean architecture.
And we will use minimal APIs and ASP.Net die routing with the latest ASP.Net eight features.
And all these pattern principles that we will follow as a section flow.
In section flow, we will explain all these pattern and principles when developing clean architecture
layers in a separate lecture.
So our sections should be ordered like that.
That means we will create domain infrastructure application and presentation section for each layer
representing the clean architecture.
So during this section we will learn all these pattern and principles.
If you go to the libraries and NuGet packages, we will also explain explicitly in each layer.
But I am going to pacing very fast as a domain layer.
We don't have any library infrastructure data layer.
We will use Entity Framework core application layer.
We will use mediator fluent Validation and Mapserver as a presentation layer.
We will use Cutter library for defining API endpoints.
And lastly we will check project folder structure.
And we said that we will follow the clean architecture.
That means we will create three class library and one ASP.Net web API.
And we will use ordering domain for defining domain models and value objects and so on.
We will use ordering application layer for implementing skills command and handler classes, and organizing
by features.
And we will use ordering infrastructure for implementing database context configurations, migrations
and so on.
And lastly we will implement ordering API to exposing API contracts and endpoint definitions.
You can find the folder structure on the slide picture that we are going to explain in the next videos.
And finally we can say that we will containerize our ordering microservices with Docker.
That means we will implement Docker file and docker compose file for running ordering microservices
and SQL server database in docker environment.