In this video, we are going to start to explain common pattern and principles that we will use when
developing organic market services.
We will start with the solid principles that include five different principles Single responsibility,
open closed, Liskov substitution, interface segregation, and dependency inversion.
So the first one is single responsibility principle.
Each of our components or modules should responsible only one functionality.
And the second one is open.
Closed principle.
When we design the system, it should be able to extend without changing existing architecture.
That means it should be open for extensions, closed for the modifications.
And the next one is Liskov substitution principle system can be substituted each other easily.
In our case we can use plugin services that we can shift them easily.
And the other one is interface segregation principle.
It states that no code should be forced to depend on method it doesn't use.
And the last one is dependency inversion principle.
It states that high level modules should not depend on low level modules, but should depend on the
abstractions.
So now let me expand these dependency inversion principle.
Basically, in dependency inversion principle we provide to block dependency of classes by inverting
dependencies and inject the dependent classes via constructor.
That means we can say that upper level class and lower level class must not be dependent on the modules.
Lower level modules must be dependent on the higher level modules with using the interface or abstractions.
Here you can find the illustration of the dependency inversion and without dependency inversion according
to without dependency inversion, you can see that our business layer directly access to our data access
layer and using the SQL database classes.
In the business logic, this is not acceptable and not following the dependency inversion principle.
Instead of these coupling, we can use dependency inversion.
That means lower level class, which is a data access, can be dependent to higher level modules using
the interface and abstraction.
In our case, we will use AI repository in the business logic to perform data access operations into
the SQL database.
We have already used this kind of abstractions and injecting dependencies into our ASP.Net microservices.
So the next thing we should check the design principles of the separation of concerns according to separation
of concerns, which is the one of the core software design principle, we can separate the computer
program into distinct sections.
That means we can isolate the software application into separate sections, manage complexities by partitioning
the software system.
It distinguish between the concepts of the layer and tiers with certain responsibilities, and basically
IT elements of the software should be unique and limit to allocate responsibilities and low coupling
and high cohesion.
You can see an example of the separation concerns in here we can separate our web application, writing
the HTML, CSS and JavaScript file in different layers.
And here you can see the separation of concerns about the HTML elements.