In this video, we are going to see how to apply domain driven design skills and clean architecture
patterns in ordering microservices.
So here you can see the architecture diagram for internal architecture of the ordering microservices
that we are going to develop during this section.
So we said that we will start with the domain driven design.
And it is focusing on the modeling business domain encapsulating the business logic in domain entities
value objects and aggregates.
And after that we will implement six design pattern.
It basically separates the handling of the data modifications from the data retrieving operations.
That means commands and queries and enhancing the scalability and maintainability.
And lastly, we will apply clean architecture.
It ensures separation of concerns by dividing the system into the layers and each layer with a specific
responsibility.
So we will apply these three main patterns into internal architecture of the ordering.
Microservices.
And if you follow the clean architecture in the domain layer, this will be contain the business logic
and the domain models like order and order item.
And these will be incorporated with the aggregates entities, value objects and so on.
This layer is the heart of the microservices dictating the business rules and the behaviors.
And after that we can go to the application use case layer.
In this layer we will basically implement securities using the mediator for handling command and queries.
And these commands might include create order, command, update order command and so on.
And queries could be the get order by ID query or get orders by customer query objects into the use
cases.
After that we can go to the infrastructure layer you can see in here.
So it will basically integrates with the databases external systems and implement the repository pattern
and interfaces defined in the domain layer and handles the data persistence, network communications
and external integration and contains Entity Framework, core context, migrations and data configurations.
And lastly, we can say that presentation UI layer.
It basically defines RESTful endpoints using the minimal APIs and possibly with Carter for routing the
definitions.
So basically, the combination of these domain driven design secrets and clean architecture provide
a powerful structure of the microservices.
So in the next videos we will explain detailed for these architecture styles.