In this video we are going to learn domain driven design.
So what is domain driven design?
Domain driven design has been around since Eric Evans published his book about the subject in 2003.
Domain driven design is not an improved technology or specific method.
Domain driven design is.
Solving a complex problem is to break the problem into smaller parts and focus on the smaller problems
that are relatively easy.
A complex domain may contain subdomains, and some of the sub domains can combine and grouping with
each other for common rules and responsibilities.
So domain driven design has two types.
These are the strategic and tactical domain driven design.
Strategic domain driven design is about understanding and modeling the business domain.
It involves identifying the different domains, their sub domains, and how they interact with each
other.
In tactical domain driven design is more about the implementation details and provide design patterns
including the patterns like entities, value objects, aggregates, and so on.
For this video, we will focus on the strategic domain driven design and its key concepts.
In order to understand domain driven design, some basic concepts need to be mastered and these are
the domain subdomain, ubiquitous language, bounded context and context mapping.
So let me start with the domain.
The domain is the sphere of the knowledge and activity around which the application logic revolves.
It represents the problem space and the array of the expertise or business need that the software addresses.
An example of the domain in e-commerce application domain might include ordering, inventory management
and customer support, and so on.
The second concept is sub domain.
A sub domain is a part of the domain and represents a specific area of the expertise within the overall
domain.
Each sub domain has its unique logic and rules, and another concept is ubiquitous language, which
is a common language used by the developers and the domain experts in order to ensure clarity and consistency.
It is crucial for this language to be used in both discussions and in the code base.
It helps to avoid misunderstanding and ensures that all stakeholders have a common understanding of
the domain concepts.
And another important concept is bounded context.
Bounded context is the grouping of the closely related scopes that we can say logical boundaries.
Bounded context is a logical boundary that represents the smaller problem particles of the complex domain
that are self-consistent and as dependent as possible.
It is a central pattern in domain driven design, and help to manage complexity by dividing these domain
into manageable parts.
Each bounded context can have its database schema.
It is called modules and it is team working on it.
And another domain driven concept is context mapping pattern.
In DDT, we can use context mapping pattern for identification of bounded contexts.
With context mapping pattern, we can identify the whole bounded context in the application and with
their logical boundaries.
And the context map is a way to define logical boundaries between the domains.