In this video we are going to learn clean architecture.
Clean architecture introduced by Robert C Martin, also known as uncle Bob.
It is a software architecture design that aims to separate concerns and create systems that are independent
of the frameworks, UI and databases.
This approach leads to systems that are more maintainable, flexible and adaptable to changes.
So let's check the key principles of the clean architecture.
The first key principle is independence of frameworks.
The system is not tight coupled with a specific framework, which makes it adaptable to changes in frameworks
and tools.
And the second principle is testable.
The business rules can be tested without the UI, database, web server or any external element.
And another key principle is UI agnostic UI independence.
The UI can change easily without changing the rest of the system.
The architecture can be unplugged from the user interface.
And another key principle is database agnostic, which means database independence.
The business rules are not bound to the database.
The architecture is decoupled from the underlying data store.
And another key principle is external system agnostic external agency independence.
Business rules do not know anything about the outside of the world.
The business rules of the architecture are isolated and know nothing about the outside of the world.
And now let's check the clean architecture layers.
The first layer is entities layer.
Or we can say domain layer.
Domain layer represents the business objects of the application.
It is the core of the system and includes enterprise wide logic and business rules.
It contains enterprise wide business rules and entities encapsulate the most general and high level
rules.
As an example, we can give ordering microservices.
Entities might be ordered and order item, and the second layer is use case layer, which we can say
application layer.
It contains application specific business rules, and it encapsulates and implements all of the use
cases of the system.
As an example of the application layer use cases, we can say that create order, cancel order and update
order status use case for ordering microservices.
And another layer is interface adapter layers, which is the infrastructure layer.
It basically converts data from the format most convenient for the use cases and entities to the format
most convenient for external systems.
As an example, we can give mapping data from database models to the domain entities.
And the last layer we can say that frameworks and drivers.
That means infrastructure external concerns the outermost layer consisting of the frameworks and tools
such as the database, the web framework, and so on.
So generally includes the UI database and external interfaces and so on.
As an example, we can say that Rest controllers and database repositories.
So as a conclusion, we can say that clean architecture in microservices lead to system that are more
modular, adaptable, testable and maintainable.
We say modular because changes in one module or service don't heavily impact others, and we say adaptable
because it is easier to update or replace technologies and databases.
And we say testable because core logic can be tested in isolation.
And lastly, we say maintainable because clear separation of concerns makes the system easier to understand
and maintain.