In this video, we are going to learn how to use clean architecture with domain driven design.
Clean architecture focuses on separating concerns into layers, ensuring that dependencies are directed
outwards from the core business logic.
On the other hand, domain driven design is centered around the domain model, which represents the
business and its rules.
It emphasizes understanding the business domain, creating a ubiquitous language, and aligning the
software design closely with the domain.
You can find the architecture images on the slide.
We have different clean architecture images.
In here we have concentric circles and each representing different layers of the application.
And also you can see clean architecture layers in rectangles with specifying the dependencies.
And here you can find the domain driven design layers and dependencies.
And it is very similar with the clean architecture.
And this will be an implementation of the domain driven design layers.
If we look at the dependency of this architecture, you can see that the dependencies are explaining
with these arrows for each architecture style.
And the main principle of these dependencies is dependency rule.
As we already seen in the dependency inversion principle, there is a dependency rule, and this rule
says that source code dependencies can only point inwards.
Here you can see that source code dependencies can only point the inwards, and the inner circle can
know anything at all about something.
In outer circle only implementation, those of abstractions will become external outer layers.
So this is the dependency rule that we can see different implementation and illustration of dependencies.
And these will be pointing inwards always because domain layers implement the business logic with the
abstractions.
So now let's see how we can integrate domain driven design in clean architecture layers.
As you can see the image we have different illustration of the clean architecture again in a circle
phase.
And you can see the rectangle phase.
But this time as you can see in the image there is separating two main concepts.
These are the core layers and peripheral layers.
And core modules include domain and application layers and peripheral layers.
These are.
The peripheral modules include all external outer layer which are the persistence infrastructure and
presentation layers.
Of course, all of these layers.
Using the Dependency Inversion principle inside core layers, we should have pure logic and abstractions
and never have any knowledge about the outside of these layers.
Implementations and inside layers work with the abstractions that are defined within those layers,
and the actual implementation logic exists in the outside of the layers.
So dependency inversion principle provide to work with abstractions and implement them outside layers,
but in a concept manner we can distinction between what is essential, which is mean the core layer
and what is the details, which is the peripheral layers.
So let's talk about the core layers.
In the core layers we can say that domain and application layer in different illustration.
You can see in here we put two core layers including the domain and application class library.
And these will be communicate with the peripheral layers to implement actual logic to implementation
of these presentation and infrastructure operations in under the peripheral layers.
So this is the main two divisions of the clean architecture.
But inside of these core and Fairfield layers we have domain and application layer.
So in the domain layer which is development of the domain logic with abstractions, it includes interfaces
and interfaces drives business requirement with the light implementation.
The core layer project is a center of the clean architecture design, and all other project dependencies
should point inwards to it.
So that means dependencies comes from the outside layer, the inverse layer and this layer build out
using the domain driven principles, and nothing in it has any knowledge of anything outside of it.
For the most part, dependency injection is not using in here.
So let's check the application layer in application layer for development of the domain logic and implementation.
So these application layer declares interfaces and other abstractions which stands for the infrastructure
persistence and presentation components.
The actual implementation of these components are not declared in this layer, but they are provided
an application.
Components via dependency injection interfaces drives business requirements and implementation in this
layer.
So that means application layer basically implements our business logics and use case operations.
And here you can see the application layer using the.
Presentation and infrastructure layers as an abstraction with interfaces in the application layer and
performing business logic.
So now we can go ahead to peripheral layer.
And in here you can see that peripheral layer including presentation persistence and infrastructure.
So let me start with the infrastructure layer.
This is the implementation of the core interfaces in this project with the Entity Framework core and
other dependencies.
The infrastructure layer contains implementation for the infrastructure interfaces declared in the application
layer.
And most of our applications, dependence on external resources should be implemented in classes defined
in the infrastructure project.
That means this class must implement the interfaces defined in the core layer.
Here you can see another illustration infrastructure project must implement the interfaces defined in
the core layer.
And this will be actual implementation code for database connection and external system integration
and so on.
And if you have very large number of the project with many dependencies, it makes sense to have more
than one infrastructure project, for example, infrastructure, that data or infrastructure that extension
or external systems and so on.
But in most projects, one infrastructure project that contains folder work very well.
And this could be include, for example, email provider, file access, web API client and so on.
And lastly, we can explain the presentation layer under the Fairfield layer in the presentation layer,
which is the API layer that brings together all the application layer components and injects them with
a proper implementation.
So this is the development of UI logic with the implementation in here also interfaces drives business
requirement and implementation of this layer.
And here you can see different illustration presentation layer under the peripheral layer.
As you can see that all the arrows is go to presentation layer which is implemented of the UI operations
with using the infrastructure application and core layers.
And here you can find different illustration of the clean architecture.
According to these architecture we can see domain model layer is sitting in the middle of the architecture,
including the domain entities, domain services and other domain driven design objects.
And see that domain model layer has no dependency but application and infrastructure layer depending
on the domain layers.
If you look at these architecture, we can call domain and application layer as a core layers.
Here you can see that we can call these layers as a core layer.
And in the application layer we will use application services and use cases implementing with abstractions
of the these peripheral layers.
So you can see abstractions.
And depending for dependency rule.
And in the infrastructure layer you can see implementation of the repositories and actual persistence
implementation with communicating with the database and external services.
And this is the infrastructure layer.
And these layers will be using all in the presentation layer with getting reference for each layers
in order to implement user interface operations, performing the use cases, implementing the infrastructure
objects, all in the presentation layer that we call Presentation and Infrastructure layer as a peripheral
layer.