In this video, we are going to learn code structure on domain driven design and clean architecture
when developing organic microservices, ordering microservices using ASP.Net Core Web API, and using
Entity Framework Core to communicate with SQL server.
If you look at the internal architecture, we can see that organic microservices implements clean architecture
with including the core application infrastructure and presentation layers, and domain driven design,
which is the entities, repositories, domain and application services and so on.
And also it is implements and provide good infrastructure and best practices such as dependency injection,
logging, validation, exception handling and so on.
But we will focus on the code structure during this video.
If you look at this architecture, you can see that the code structure of the ordering microservices.
We will create four different class library.
These are the ordering domain ordering application ordering infrastructure and ordering API layer ordering
domain and application layer representing the core layers and ordering infrastructure and API layer
will be representing the peripheral layers, so these will be referencing each other according to clean
architecture.
So how we can implement these layers into our ordering microservices to make it simple and easy to understandable.
I'm going to start with the ordering domain.
And after that I'm going to develop ordering infrastructure and continue with the ordering application
and ordering API layers.
If you look at the folder structure, you can see that we will create three class library and one web
API project.
So I'm going to start with ordering domain including the domain models, domain events, value objects
and so on.
After that I'm going to develop ordering infrastructure including the data related operations, Entity
framework, core seeding, migration and so on.
And after that I'm going to implement ordering application class library including the order use case
implementation with abstractions in here.
And lastly, we will develop ordering API in order to expose endpoints for performing the ordering use
cases.