In this video we are going to create clean architecture layers for ordering microservices.
These are the domain application infrastructure and API layer.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering folder.
And under this folder I'm going to right click and Add New Project.
This time we will create a class library and click the next button.
So Project Name will be ordering dot domain.
And make sure that location could be same as the ordering API if you open this location and go to services.
Ordering folder.
Here you can see that these will be creating ordering domain class library under the ordering folder
and click the next button.
And the only configuration is framework and leave as it is selecting.
Net eight and click the create button.
Here you can see that the ordering domain class library created successfully, and this layer will include
domain models, value objects, and domain services that encapsulate the business logic and rules of
the ordering microservices.
You can double click the this class library project and verify that our target framework is.
Net eight.
After that, we are going to continue with the ordering application class library.
I'm going to right click the ordering folder, Add New Project and select Class Library.
Click the next button and change the project name as the ordering application and set the location as
the same way Source Services ordering and select this folder.
And we are going to create Ordering Application class library.
Under the ordering folder, click the next button and click the create button.
So this layer is responsible for application logic.
And it will typically include classes for command and query handling dtos and interface for application
services.
So we can call these ordering domain and ordering application layers with together as a core layer.
Because these layers will cover line of business requirement without any infrastructure dependency.
After that we will create ordering infrastructure.
For that purpose I am going to right click the ordering folder, Add New Project and select Class Library
and change the name as a ordering infrastructure and change the Location Source Services ordering folder.
This will be create Ordering Infrastructure class library.
Under the ordering folder, click the next button and click the create button.
So this layer will contain implementation of interfaces defined in the domain layer and application
layer, such as repository implementation classes, along with any other code that interacts with external
concerns.
Example of the database access file system, email sending and web services.
As you can see that we have successfully created clean architecture layers.
These are the three class library and one API project.