In this video we are going to add project reference between clean architecture layers.
It is crucial step to establish the correct dependencies between different layers of the application.
Let's understand layer dependencies.
As we said before, our domain and application layer responsible for business requirement without any
external dependencies.
So we can think domain and application layer as a core layers and only application layer get referenced
from the domain layer and domain should not get any reference.
And after that we have infrastructure layer which includes all external concerns and infrastructure
layer should encapsulate these external dependencies like databases, edge systems, integrations and
so on.
So these infrastructure layer could be replaced when needed.
And infrastructure layer should have application layer get referenced.
That means we need to reference from the core layers into infrastructure layer in order to perform infrastructure
works properly.
And lastly, we have API layer as a presentation layer and this will need it both application and infrastructure
layers.
As a result, we can say that domain layer, which is the ordering domain, has no dependency on other
And application layer, which is the ordinary application depends on the domain layer and infrastructure
layer, which is the ordering infrastructure depends on the application layer for implementing interfaces
and API layer, which is the ordering API depends on both application and infrastructure layer.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to Ordering Application layer.
In ordering application layer we are going to add project reference from the ordering domain.
Also, we will add a reference from the building blocks of the project in order to leverage skills,
abstractions and other shared functionalities into ordering microservices.
For that purpose, I am going to come to ordering application, right click dependencies, Add Project
Reference and in here I am going to select Building Blocks and also ordering domain.
And click the okay button.
And you can confirm in the Ordering application project file and save this file.
See that these item group added.
And two project is adding reference into ordering application.
After that we can go to the ordering infrastructure.
In Ordering infrastructure layer, we will add a project reference from the ordering application and
implement its interface and use its services inside of the infrastructure.
For that purpose, I am going to right click dependencies, Add Project Reference and select the ordering
application and click the okay button.
You can see that we have successfully added ordering application project getting reference in the ordering
infrastructure.
Lastly, we will go to the ordering API project.
In ordering API we will add a project reference both ordering infrastructure and ordering application.
If you right click the dependencies Add Project reference, I'm going to select Ordering Application
and Ordering Infrastructure and click the okay button.
If you double click the ordering API, you can see the item group comes in here from the ordering application
infrastructure reference to ordering API.
This allows the API layer to use application services and infrastructure implementations inside of the
endpoint.
Definitions.
After adding all necessary references, we can build the solution and ensure everything is correctly
set up and there is no missing dependencies.
If you right click the ordering API and build the API project, you can see that will is succeeded completed.
That means we have successfully added project references into our clean architecture layers.