In this video we are going to add dependency injections for each clean architecture layers.
Adding dependency injections in a clean architecture setup provide to organize the dependency injection
registrations for each layer that maintains a clear separation of concerns.
Let's take an action.
Please open the Visual Studio and let's understand Dependency Injection in ASP.Net core.
As you know that ASP.Net core provides built in support for dependency injection and clean architecture.
Layers should register their dependencies in a structured manner, and every layer has its own dependencies,
and only the domain layer typically has no dependencies.
Before going to the ordering API, I would like to show the basket API.
If you open the basket API and go to Program.cs, you can see that when adding the services into die,
we basically separating by the application services, data services and gRPC services, crosscutting
services and so on.
So this is the separation inside of the Program.cs.
But it is hard to readable and hard to maintain.
Instead of that in the ordering API, we are going to organize our dependencies into the here.
And we basically perform these separation using the extension methods.
In here I'm going to add a commented section, and as you can see that we basically separate the infrastructure
application and API layer dependencies with using the extension methods.
The main idea is instead of manually adding all dependencies into program.cs, it is best practice to
separate dependencies for each layer and inject them into the program series with layered dependency
injection extension methods.
These are the Add Application services, Add Infrastructure Services and Add Web Services.
So as you can see that this is very clear to see which dependencies you are going to inject.
So in order to separate dependencies explicitly, we should create dependency injection class for each
layer except the domain layer.
This layer has no dependency for that purpose.
I'm going to start with the application and remove the class one and add a new class in here, which
name is a dependency injection?
Abk's.
And follow the same steps for the infrastructure.
Delete the class one and add a new class.
Which name is dependency injection case and for domain we don't have any dependency.
That's why I have only remove this class one.
And if you go to the API layer, I'm going to add a new class and which name is dependency injection.
So as you can see that we have added the dependency injection for each layer except the domain layer.
And we are ready to inject our dependencies for each clean architecture layer.
So why we use Dependency injection class for each layer?
The first reason is separation of concerns.
By this way, each layer has its specific responsibilities.
And the second reason is maintainability.
When dependency is for each layer are managed in a dedicated file, it becomes easier to update, modify,
or refactor a specific layer without affecting the other layers.
Now it is time to implementing extension methods.
For each layer.
We will define extension methods in the dependency injection files for each layer to register its dependencies.
So that means we will develop extension methods for that purpose.
I'm going to start with ordering application.
Please go to Ordering Application and go to Dependency Injection class.
And now I'm going to create an extension method to register application related dependencies make it
public.
And this class should be static because extension methods should be required static classes.
And inside of that we will create a static method public static and this should be returned Iservice
collection to register dependencies to ASP.Net dependency injection container tool.
And after that I'm going to give the name as a add application services.
And now as a parameter I'm going to use this keyword.
And we would like to write extension method on the Iservice collection and give the name of the parameter
as a services.
Okay.
Now we can start with the extension method.
Basically in application layer we will inject for example mediator related services.
I'm going to put here as a commanded way.
And after that we will return services after registration is complete for the application layer and
remove unnecessary codes.
So in this class we typically register services related to application layer such as the mediator validators
or domain event handler and so on.
So the important thing is how can we access Microsoft's extensions dependency injection namespace in
this class.
Because this is the ordering application and we don't any install NuGet packages.
The answer is comes from the fluent validation that ASP.Net core NuGet package.
Because if you go to ordering application, you can see that we have getting reference from the building
blocks.
And if you go to the building blocks, you can see that we have adding different validation that ASP.Net
core that include I service collection and other ASP.Net related classes that we can access into our
ordering application layer.
Now we can follow the same steps for ordering infrastructure layer.
Go to Ordering Infrastructure Dependency injection.
Remove unnecessary using statements.
Make this class public and static.
And after that, in the method of this class, I'm going to create public static Iservice collection.
And the method name is Add Infrastructure Services.
And as a parameter, we will use this keyword in order to make this extension method for I service collection.
And I'm going to put as a services for I service collection.
And in this method we also would like to access I configuration in order to reach the connection strings.
For that permission I'm going to write I configuration and write the configuration as a parameter.
So you can see that the parameters are these I service collection services, which makes these methods
as a extension method.
And we also expect I configuration and configuration object in order to access application settings
file from the ASP.Net core application.
So now let's show me how we can get connection string in here I'm going to create connection string
variable and use configuration dot get connection string method.
In order to access the database connection strings from the ASP.Net core application, in our case from
the ordering API.
And after that we can use this connection string when registering Entity Framework core with SQL server.
I'm going to put a committed value in here, because we will use these committed values when implementing
our Entity Framework core and this application DB context object.
And after that I'm going to return services.
As you can see that we have also completed dependency injection for ordering infrastructure in this
class.
The focus is on registering services like database context repositories and any external APIs or services
the application depends on.
So now we can go ahead to ordering API for that purpose, go to ordering API and open the dependency
injection and we will register API specific services like Carterhatch x and so on.
So I'm going to make this class again static.
And we can create a static method public static.
And this will be again I service collection.
And the name of the method is add API services.
And we will use this keyword to make this service collection extension method.
And in this method we basically perform some operations like adding services for Carter and this kind
of NuGet packages and return services.
But for these ordering API project I am going to add additional extension methods in the.
Here I'm going to write public static, and I'm going to create a extension on the web application.
And the name of this method will be use API services.
And I'm going to make this project web application and app.
So that means we are going to create extension method on the web application.
And in here we are going to use this kind of operations like app dot map Carter.
So as you remember that we are using two operations before building the application and after the building
application for that purpose.
Before building the application, we will add Carter into dependency injection.
And after building the application we will configure Http lifecycle for using the Carter with map Carter
operation for that purpose.
For API project we have two services add API services and use API services.
Finally, we can register all dependencies in the Program.cs.
So in the program.cs of the ordering API project you can go to Program.cs of the ordering API.
We can change the extension methods to register all necessary services.
I'm going to remove all these commented code and come here.
We can write builder services in order to register our services.
And in here you can come to that point and add application services.
And this is the extension methods comes from the ordering application.
If you can't reach these application services please build these applications one by one.
And after that you can see that these extension method will be activated.
And after that I'm going to add infrastructure services which passing to our builder configuration.
In here you can see that it is expecting I configuration.
I am passing the builder configuration to reach the connection string.
And lastly I'm going to add API services.
And this will be Register all Clean architecture layer into program.cs of the ordering API and make
sure that you are adding the using statement for each clean architecture layer.