In this section we are going to develop microservices asynchronous communication with RabbitMQ and Masstransit.
This is for checkout or the use case between basket and ordering microservices.
Here you can see the big picture that we are going to build one by one.
So we will build asynchronous communication between basket and ordering microservices using the message
broker.
If you look at the our course flow, as you can see that we have finished the development of the microservices
and now we are in here and start to developing microservices asynchronous communication.
So this is the microservices asynchronous communication using the RabbitMQ and Masstransit.
And we are going to cover asynchronous microservice communication using the RabbitMQ message broker
service and using the RabbitMQ publish subscribe topic exchange model.
And we will use Masstransit for abstraction over the RabbitMQ message broker system.
And we will publishing the basket checkout event queue from the basket microservices and subscribing
these events from the ordering microservices.
And we will create RabbitMQ building blocks messaging library and adding reference this library into
microservices.
And lastly we will containerize RabbitMQ message queue system with the basket and ordering microservices
using the Docker compose.
So we will implement publish subscribe design pattern in this microservice.
Asynchronous communication using the RabbitMQ and Masstransit.
That means we will create RabbitMQ connection on the basket and ordering microservices when producing
and consuming events.
Basket microservices which include publish basket checkout queue with Masstransit and RabbitMQ queue
and ordering microservices consuming the RabbitMQ basket checkout event queue with using the mass transit
and RabbitMQ configuration.
So here you can see our publish subscriber of the Basket Checkout event.
This is the end to end use case for the basket checkout event.
So in the first step Basket Checkout API hitting from the client application and these requests comes
from the client and hitting the basket.
Microservices and basket microservices perform their operations like removing the basket in the Redis
database.
Because this is going to be an order, this will be removing the database and also removing the cache.
And after that basket microservices publish basket checkout integration event to the RabbitMQ using
the Masstransit.
And this queue typically implement with the topic messaging technology.
So the subscriber microservices in our case it will be ordering.
Microservices will consume this event and create an order in their SQL server database.
So by the end of the section we will have a library which provides the communication along basket and
ordering microservices with creating a class library.
The event bus implementation with RabbitMQ that microservices publish the event and receive the events
with using this library.
Before we start the development, we should understand the microservice communication basics and the
RabbitMQ.