So what is asynchronous communication?
Basically, in asynchronous communication the client sends a request, but it doesn't wait for a response
from the server.
So the key point is here that the client should not have blocked their thread until waiting a response.
The most popular protocol for this asynchronous communication is Amqp.
That means advanced message queuing protocol.
So with using Amqp protocol, the client sent the message with using message broker systems like Kafka
and RabbitMQ.
The message producer usually doesn't wait for a response.
This message consumed from the subscriber systems in asynchronous way and no one waiting for a response
suddenly.
If we have a few interaction with querying microservices, then we should use Http request response
with resource APIs.
But when it comes to busy interactions in communications across multiple microservices, then we should
use asynchronous messaging platforms like message broker systems.
We said that asynchronous protocols, which is the Amqp protocol for performing async message transmissions.
In this amqp protocol.
The producer sent a message and doesn't wait a response.
It only sends a message and expects that it will consume by subscriber services via to message broker
systems.
So Amqp protocol mostly using in message broker that responsible for handling the message sent by the
producer service in asynchronous messaging based communication.
After the message is received by the broker, now it is passed the message to the target service that
you can see in the image.
The order microservice send message to message broker and this will be consumed by the subscriber.
Microservices.
If the consumer microservice is down at the moment, the broker might be configured to retry as long
as necessary for successful delivery.
These messages can be persisted if required or stored only in memory.
In the latter case, they will be lost when the broker is restarted and they aren't yet sent to consumer.
Since the message broker is responsible for delivering the message.
It is no longer necessary for both microservices to be up and running for successful communication.
Therefore, asynchronous messaging mitigates the biggest problem of synchronous communication, which
is the coupling, and it is provided to loosely coupling services with providing asynchronous communication.
Let's see.
The image you can see in the synchronous communication is becoming a chain of requests and highly coupled
dependent between microservices.
So this is the pain point of architecture.
And we can say this is a anti-pattern and need to redesign your system.
With asynchronous communication, this problem can be solved.
Microservices communicate with each other over the message broker system in asynchronous way.
Mostly it is good to use publish subscribe pattern with message broker systems that we will see in the
upcoming videos.