In this video we are going to learn benefits of asynchronous communication.
The first benefit is adding new subscriber services.
So adding new subscriber services is very simple.
We can easily subscribe to a message that we want to receive.
The producer doesn't need to be know about subscribers.
We can remove and add subscribers without affecting producer service.
And another benefit is scalability.
When services communicate with direct sync communications, if the servers get high volume requests,
these communication parties should be scaled together and at the same time, so it is hard to maintain
high volume peak requests.
With asynchronous communication, we can easier to manage scalability issues.
We can scale producer, consumer and message broker system independently, so we can also scale services
according to incoming messages into event based system.
The message broker can distribute the received message to more than one target services.
If incoming message are increased into message broker system, we can scale consumer services and receive
messages faster in microservices.
Kubernetes has autoscaler that we can define maximum port number according to CPU and Ram usage into
current instance.
But also there is another good product which is the Keda, which is a Kubernetes event driven application
that we can auto scale pods according to message broker system loads.
For example, if our microservice architecture uses Kafka, and if Kafka has more messages that we expected
with using the Keda, we can auto scale consumer microservices automatically.
So asynchronous communication is allowed to be more flexible in terms of the scalability issues.
And another benefit is event driven microservices.
With asynchronous communication, we can provide event driven architectures, which is the best way
to communicate between microservices services, communicates with each other by creating events and
send events to message broker, event bus system and subscribe events from the microservices.