In this video we are going to learn challenges of asynchronous communication.
The first challenges is single point of failure message brokers.
The message broker becomes a single point of failure if we don't configure the message broker properly.
It can become a problem for our architecture.
We shouldn't rely on all communication with a single node of the message brokers.
Instead, we should scale it and use hybrid communication with synchronous and asynchronous in our cases.
And second challenges is debugging.
It is often difficult to debug issues with asynchronous communication, because it can be hard to trace
the flow of the single operation across service boundaries.
Since there is no clear data flow now and messages get processed when they arrive to consumer systems,
debugging of the flow and the payload of the events takes so many times and hard to debug at the same
time.
So this is why it is usually a good idea to generate a unique ID when the message is received, so that
you can track with the unique ID into the logs.
Also, we can call this correlation ID.
And another challenges is at least once delivery and not guarantee an order of messages.
Message broker systems are a very good fit for event driven microservice communication, but mostly
they use at least once delivery and not guarantee order of messages.
So we should embrace these message delivery mechanism with applying idempotency consumers and not designing
Fifo requires cases.