In this video we are going to learn event driven architecture in microservices.
In an event driven microservice architecture, services communicate with each other by publishing and
subscribing to events.
When a service needs to communicate with another service, it publishes an event to the message broker
or event bus.
Other services can then subscribe to that event and take appropriate action when the event is received.
This can have several benefits.
For example.
Asynchronous communication.
One key feature of event driven microservice architecture is that it allows services to communicate
asynchronously rather than synchronously.
This means that a service can publish an event and continue processing without waiting for a response
from the other service.
Another benefit is decoupled communication.
And another key feature of event driven microservice architecture is that it decouples the publisher
and subscriber that allowing them evolve independently without affecting each other.
This can make it easier to make changes to individual servers without affecting the rest of the system.
And another benefit could be the real time processing.
Event driven architectures can support real time processing as events are published and consumed as
soon as they occur.
This can be useful in such a scenario where you need to react to events in real time.
For example, in systems that use change data capture to track changes to a database.
Another benefit is high volume events.
Event driven architectures are well suited to handling high volume events, as they can scale horizontally
by adding more events consumers as needed.
This can be particularly useful in Microsoft's architectures, where individual services can be scaled
independently in order to handle increased load.