In this video we are going to learn what is RabbitMQ?
RabbitMQ is a message broker software that implements the Advanced Messaging Queue protocol, which
is the Amqp protocol.
It allows applications to communicate with each other by sending and receiving messages through the
queues.
So RabbitMQ is a message queuing system.
Similar ones can be listed as a Apache Kafka, Msmq, Microsoft Azure, Service Bus, kestrel, Activemq
and so on.
It is proposed to transmit a message received from any source to another source as soon as it is their
turn.
In other words, all transactions can be listed in a queue until the source to be transmitted gets up.
It also allowed to send and receive messages asynchronously.
This decouples the sender and receiver, allowing each to continue processing without waiting for other
to respond.
This can improve the overall performance and scalability of the system.
RabbitMQ supports for multiple operating systems and open source code in one of the most preferred reasons.
The main components of RabbitMQ are producer queue, consumer message exchange, binding and Fifo.
So I will explain all these components on the RabbitMQ architecture that you can see on the picture.
So let me start with the producer.
I will continue with the producer queue and consumer.
And after that I will explain the exchange and bindings.
So what is producer?
Producer is the source of the message for the application.
So after that what is Q?
Q is where the messages are stored.
The sent messages are put in queue before they are received.
All incoming messages are stored in the queue.
That is the memory.
And after that we have consumer.
It is a server.
That means the send message.
It is the application that will receive and process the message on the queue.
And also we have a message.
Message is the data that we send on the queue.
So now I can explain exchange and bindings.
So what is the exchange.
It is a structure that decides which queue to send the messages.
It makes the decision according to routing case.
And also we have bindings.
Bindings are the link between the exchange and the queues.
And also we can explain the Fifo.
What is the Fifo?
Fifo is the order of processing of outgoing messages in RabbitMQ.
In.
First in.
First out.