In this video we are going to learn RabbitMQ exchange types.
Here you can see the exchange sitting between producer and queues.
Exchange control the routing of the messages to queues.
Each exchange type defines a specific routing algorithm, which the server uses to determine that bound
queues a published message should be routed to.
So RabbitMQ provides four types of the exchange.
These are the direct fan out topic and headers.
So let me start with the direct exchange.
Indirect exchange uses of a single queue is being addressed.
A routing key is determined according to the things to be done, and accordingly the most appropriate
queue is reached with the relevant direct exchange, and the next exchange type is a topic exchange.
In topic exchange, messages are sent to different queues according to their subject.
The incoming message is classified and sent to the related queue, and a route is used to send the message
to one or more queues.
It is a variation of the publish subscriber pattern.
If the problem concerns several consumers, topic exchange should be used to determine what kind of
message they want to receive.
So the next exchange type is Fanout exchange.
It is used in situations where the message should be sent to more than one queue.
It is especially applied in broadcasting systems.
It is mainly used for the games for global announcements, and the last exchange type is header exchange.
In headers exchange, you guided by the features added to the header of the message routing key used
in other modules is not used.
Transmits to the correct queue with a few features and descriptions in a message.
Headers.
The attributes of the header and the attributes on the queue must match each other's values.