In this video, we are going to do domain analysis of asynchronous communication between basket and
ordering microservices.
This will include event model, analyzing application use cases, Rest API endpoints and underlying
data structures.
So let's get started and we will start with the event models of the basket checkout event.
That means we have only one event model which is the basket checkout.
This is the primary event model used for the asynchronous communication between basket and ordering
microservices.
In the Building Blocks shared project, we should add a new class under the events folder, and this
should be used from the basket and ordering microservices.
But also we can create a new class library which is a building blocks messaging.
And this will include this kind of common event classes which will be the basket checkout.
If you look at the basket checkout class, this will be including user details which is the username,
total price and billing address, address, line, country, state and also payment details will be
including the card name, card number and so on.
This is the event class structure for the basket checkout, and we will also consider the domain events
for the basket checkout and leading to integration event.
But Basket Checkout event will be our integration event from throwing our basket microservices.
So if you look at the application use cases we should define our application use case analyzing for
asynchronous communication.
And we can say that our asynchronous use case is basket checkout operation.
This is the checkout basket with all information and publish event to the RabbitMQ.
And if you look at the asynchronous use case for ordering microservices we can say that again basket
checkout.
But this time ordering microservices.
Consume the basket checkout event from the RabbitMQ using the Masstransit, and after that this will
be start order fulfillment process that perform order fulfillment operation that is notifying billing,
shipment and notification of the other microservices and this can be raised order created domain event
that leads to integration event.
So now I'm going to check presentation layer and the Rest APIs.
Here you can see that we have a one post http API.
And we will expose http post method from the basket microservices with this endpoint which is the slash
basket and slash checkout in order to check out the basket.
And this will be asynchronous.
To check out the basket and receive the basket, checkout data in a Json body of the web API.
And after that you can see that ordering microservices will be using Amqp protocol in order to consume
basket checkout event from the RabbitMQ using the Masstransit.
So we have two protocols one protocol Http and exposing Http post from the basket microservices.
And another protocol is Amqp protocol consuming ordering microservices from the RabbitMQ message broker.
And if you look at the underlying data structure of the asynchronous communication, we can say that
for asynchronous communication between microservices we have one backing services, which is the RabbitMQ
distributed message broker.
And as a distributed message broker we will use RabbitMQ and we will see it in the implementation phase.
RabbitMQ allows for the robust, efficient and scalable asynchronous communication, and it facilitates
pub sub messaging between basket and ordering microservices.
And here you can see the our main architecture for the microservices asynchronous communication.
Basically basket microservices publish event to the RabbitMQ message broker for asynchronous communication
and ordering.
Microservices consume these event from the RabbitMQ in order to perform asynchronous communication.