In this video we are going to do technical analysis of the asynchronous communication.
This will include application architecture, style pattern and principles libraries, NuGet packages
that we are going to use and project folder structure.
So let me start with the application architecture style.
As an application architecture style we will use event driven microservice architecture.
This architecture style focuses on events as a primary source of the communication between different
microservices.
The benefits are enhanced decoupling, scalability and responsiveness for implementation.
In our case, we will basket an authentic microservices communicate asynchronous through the events.
So if you look at the pattern and principles, we can say that we will follow the publish subscribe
design pattern, which is a core pattern enabling event driven architectures.
One service which is a publisher, send message or events without knowing the receivers which are the
subscribers.
So subscribers listen and react to these events and basket service basically publish event which is
ordering services.
Subscribe to this event and process accordingly.
Now we can also check the class library architecture analyzing.
So if you look at the class libraries we can say that first of all we have a building blocks.
Building blocks is a shared class library catalog basket and ordering microservices already getting
referenced building blocks, shared class library for common operations and abstractions like securities,
cross-cutting concerns and so on.
Also, we will create a new class library which name is Building Blocks Messaging.
So this class library will be dedicated for common asynchronous communication operations and for each
microservices that need to asynchronous communication over RabbitMQ and communicate via integration
events will be used.
These building blocks messaging class library.
So please look at the image on the slide.
Here you can see the microservices that using building blocks for common operations.
So we have developed building blocks class library which is a shared class library that contains common
class and logic shared across microservices.
That is using from the catalog basket and ordering reference these building blocks for common sequence
abstractions and cross-cutting concerns.
But this time we will also create Building Blocks messaging Class library, which is a dedicated class
library for asynchronous communication over the RabbitMQ and will containing common integration events
and mass transit configurations.
So by this way, only asynchronous communication required.
Microservices will be getting reference.
These building blocks class library in our case basket and ordering microservices will be getting reference
from the building blocks messaging class library for common event classes.
That means we will implement common event objects into these building blocks messaging class library,
and these will be getting reference from the basket and ordering in order to perform asynchronous communication.
So if you continue our analyzing here, you can see the libraries and NuGet packages that we are going
to use.
We will use Mass Transit NuGet packages, Mass Transit, and abstraction over the message broker for.
Net and simplifying the implementation of the asynchronous messaging.
And we will also use Mass transit RabbitMQ which is specific integration for the RabbitMQ with mass
transit.
It enables the basket microservice to publish the events and the ordering microservices to subscribe
them, using the RabbitMQ as a message broker.
So we will use RabbitMQ Message Broker and Mass Transit NuGet package and library for implementing publish,
subscribe, design pattern and asynchronous communication.
So lastly we will check project folder structure according to folder structure.
First of all, we will develop a new class library which name is Building Blocks Messaging.
This is newly created shared class library for asynchronous communication.
And this will be include events folder which is the common events between basket and ordering microservices.
And also this will be include Masstransit extensions and configurations inside of these messaging class
library.
So we have explained that this class library getting reference from the microservices that required
for the asynchronous communication.
And after that we will develop basket API checkout basket feature folder.
So that means we will add a new feature folder, which name is checkout basket and adding handler and
endpoint classes in order to handle checkout process.
And after that we will consume these event from the ordering microservices.
That means in the ordering application layer we are going to create a new event handler which is integration
event handler.
Which name is basket checkout event handler.
So this will be contain these event handling from the integration event handling to consume these event
from the RabbitMQ and handle the events from the basket microservices.
Lastly, we will analyze the deployment part of the asynchronous communication.
So basically we will add RabbitMQ image container into.
Or multi-container docker compose file, and after that we will implement Docker file and docker compose
files for running basket and organic microservices with RabbitMQ message broker in a Docker environment.