In this video, we are going to define the development steps of the asynchronous communication.
And the first step is creating building blocks messaging shared class library.
And we will create a shared class library for common asynchronous communication functionalities.
And we will develop basket checkout event class in order to represent the data structure of the event.
And also we will develop mass transit extension methods in order to facilitate the registration and
configuration of the mass transit with RabbitMQ in the microservices.
And the second step is developing basket API to publish basket checkout event in order to enable basket
microservices to publish Basket Checkout event to RabbitMQ, we will expose Http post endpoint and develop
a post API endpoint for the basket checkout operation.
So that means we will develop a new feature folder, which name is checkout basket under the basket
microservices and this will be include endpoint and handler class.
In the endpoint class we will expose http post API to client.
And in the handler class we basically use mass transit in order to publish basket checkout event to
the RabbitMQ.
And the third step, we will develop authentic microservices to subscribe and consume basket checkout
event.
So that means we will set up the authentic microservices, listen and process the basket checkout event.
From the RabbitMQ.
We will create integration event handler folder under the event handlers and under the Creating integration
folder we will develop Basket Checkout Event handler class in order to implement event processing logic
in the event handler to create orders based on the received basket checkout event.
And the last step is we will add RabbitMQ image in a multi-container environment.
That means we will add RabbitMQ service configuration in the docker compose file.
We will execute the docker compose setup in Visual Studio to bring up the RabbitMQ container connected
with our microservices.