In this video we are going to do step one which is creating boolean blocks messaging shared class library
for common asynchronous communication responsibilities.
So for that purpose I am going to open our class library image which including microservices and building
blocks class library.
So here you can see that Building blocks messaging class library will be getting referenced by the microservices
that requiring asynchronous communication specifically basket and ordering microservices in our case
other microservices like catalog microservices which may not require asynchronous communication, will
only getting reference from the main building blocks class library.
So that means in our e-commerce application catalog only getting reference building blocks, class library
basket and ordering, getting reference both building blocks and also building blocks messaging class
library.
The idea is that every microservices need to getting reference from the building blocks, but only asynchronous
communication required services need to getting reference building blocks.
Messaging class library.
It is a best practice to separate and grouping these shared class libraries according to microservice
requirement and responsibilities.
So now let's develop the building blocks messaging shared class library.
Please open the Visual Studio.
We can go to the Building Blocks folder under our solution which is the building blocks.
If you expand this folder, you can see that we have only one building blocks class library.
I'm going to create a new class library under the Building Blocks folder.
Right click Add New Project which will be the class library.
And here you can see the class library and give the project name as a building blocks dot messaging.
So in here the location is important.
If you click this button, you can go to the microservices source and select the Building Blocks folder.
Under this folder we are going to create a second class library.
I'm going to select this folder.
And here you can see the the project directory that we are going to create.
These are the microservices source building blocks main folder and building blocks messaging class library.
And make sure that you have selected the correct location and click the next button.
So select the framework as a.
Net eight and click the create button.
So in here you can see that we have created Building Blocks Messaging class library which is dedicated
to messaging and asynchronous communication.
You can right click and open folder in the File Explorer.
And you can verify that we have created building blocks under the Building blocks folder, including
two class library under this source building blocks folder.