In this video we are going to develop events folder under the Building Blocks messaging class library.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Building Blocks class library.
Right click and create new folder.
A new folder.
Which name is events?
So within the Building Blocks messaging project we will create events folder.
And this folder will include all integration event classes.
And we will start developing by adding a base class for our integration event.
Which name is Integration event.
And this will be base class that provide common properties that all integration events will inherit.
For that purpose, I am going to add a new class under the events folder, which name is Integration
Events.
So in this folder I'm going to create a new record type.
First of all, remove unnecessary using statement and remove this class definition and create any record
type.
Which name is integration event including members of the ID occurred on an event type.
So that means this will be the our base class, which is the integration event including the property
of the ID.
Each event gets a unique identifier from the get Nuguid.
And also there is a occurred on property.
That means each event also have a timestamp of the occurred on.
We will pass the date time now.
And lastly we will have a event type member under the integration event that is ensuring the event type
from the SMD qualified name.
By this way, we can ensure the standard structure for all events.
After that we can create our actual business event which is the basket checkout event.
So which will be inherit from this integration event?
For that purpose, I am going to create a new class under the events and which name is Basket Checkout
Event.
So this class will represent the data structure for the basket checkout process.
And it is a key part of the our asynchronous communication setup.
Remove unnecessary using statement and make this as a public.
And also I would like to use record type and basket checkout event.
So this will be inherit from the integration event.
As you can see that we have created our basket checkout event inherited from the our integration event
and both these event types as a record type.
Because record type is very good match for the event.
Deserialize and serialize operations.
After that we can develop basket checkout event members.
Here you can see that this will be include username, customer ID, total price, shipping and billing
address information and payment data.
So these are the comes from the our checkout data and which is basket checkout event.
And these basket checkout event contains all necessary information for processing a basket checkout
including user address and payment details.
And notice that we only use primitive data types in order to ensure easy serialization and deserialization
across different microservices.
So see that event object types are primitive types that is available for Json conversion for different
services.