In this video we are going to develop mass transit folder.
We are at this point and develop mass transit extension method in order to register RabbitMQ connection
into dependency injection of the basket and ordering microservices.
For that purpose we should install Masstransit NuGet packages.
Masstransit is an open source message broker middleware that abstract the Message Bus APIs and provide
simple, extensive framework for creating distributed applications.
So where we should install these Masstransit NuGet packages into our application.
If you look at the class library architecture, we can see that both basket and generic microservices
need to install Masstransit RabbitMQ NuGet packages.
But instead of installing these packages one by one for each microservices, we should install these
RabbitMQ NuGet packages into the Building Blocks messaging class library.
By this way, we can put the asynchronous communication related packages into this class library that
can be getting reference for any microservices that need to be asynchronous.
Communication and Masstransit NuGet packages provide to work RabbitMQ as a message broker.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Bullying Blocks messaging class library and go to dependencies.
Right click manage NuGet packages and browse for the Masstransit RabbitMQ and select this package.
And please install this package into our class library.
Click the this link and install the packages I accept.
Okay installation completed.
You can verify from the class library.
If you double click the project, you can see that we have successfully install Masstransit RabbitMQ
NuGet packages and this package enable Masstransit to work with RabbitMQ as a message broker.
So now we can start the developing for Masstransit configurations.
Please go to Building Blocks Messaging and remove these class one.
And I'm going to create a new folder.
Right click Add new folder.
Which name is master Asset.
And under this folder I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is extensions.
Thanks.
This class will contain extension methods for setting up the Masstransit with RabbitMQ.
Please remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And also we need to set the keyword in order to create extension methods.
And inside of this class I'm going to create a new extension method, which name is Add Message Broker.
Here you can see that we develop public static Iservice collection add message broker.
And this will be an extension method on the I service collection.
That's why we are using this keyword in the first parameter of this method.
And you can also see the assembly information as an optional parameter of this extension method.
So this is extension method over the I service collection.
In order to register these message broker related configurations when the application start up in the
Program.cs.
So in this method we basically configure Masstransit with RabbitMQ settings.
But for now I'm going to put a comment to this statement and we will come here after defining the RabbitMQ
configurations.
That means before developing Masstransit extension method, we should define RabbitMQ configurations.
And it is good to get RabbitMQ settings from the application settings Json file.
So in the application settings file we can see the basket and ordering microservices.
If I open the basket API, we can go to Application settings Json file for both basket and ordering
microservices.
We should add a RabbitMQ settings, and these settings should contain the host username and password
for connecting to RabbitMQ.
So I'm going to open the basket microservices application settings Json file.
And I'm going to add a message broker part after the gRPC settings.
Here you can see that I have added the Message broker section including the host username and password
host address including amqp, slash, slash, localhost and the port number, which is the default port
number for the RabbitMQ connection and username and password is a guest.
We will follow the same steps for the ordering microservices.
If you go to ordering API and go to the Application settings Json file, you can go to the Connection
settings part and paste in here Message Broker section, including the host username and password.
And these settings are crucial for establishing a connection to the RabbitMQ server, and we assume
that RabbitMQ is running locally on the port of the default port, which is the 5672, and with default
guest configurations.
And this configurations will be used in our extension method that we are developing on the Building
Blocks messaging class library.
To set up the connection to the RabbitMQ using the Masstransit library.