In this video we are going to continue developing our extension method.
So here you can see the add message broker.
And this is getting the parameter as a Iservice collection services and send information with optional
parameter.
So now we are going to implement RabbitMQ Masstransit configuration in this place.
So I'm going to copy this configurations.
And we can step by step explain these configurations.
But before that you can see that we are using configuration variable in order to retrieve message broker
host username and password from the application settings.
So that means we need configuration value when calling this extension method.
That means we have to inject I configuration into our method.
So I'm going to add a I configuration parameter in the add message broker extension method.
Here you can see the first parameter is I configuration.
We are going to paste this configuration from the program.cs of the basket and ordering microservices.
So after getting this configuration variable we can paste this value and get the value when configuring
our RabbitMQ.
So let me start explaining from the scratch.
This is using services dot add mass transit function.
And this add mass transit function is used to set up mass transit in the dotnet service collection.
It allows configuration of the message bus consumers, sagas, and so on.
So after that we are opening a configuration for the mass transit and in the first configuration is
set kebab case endpoint name formatter.
So this line sets the naming convention for the endpoints.
Kebab case is a common naming convention used in the URLs, which is preferred by the readability.
So after that you can see that we are adding some consumers in here we are checking the assembly information.
If not null, we are adding the consumers because this method can using from the boat basket and ordering
microservices.
When we are using for the ordering microservices, this will be as a consumers that we can trigger for
the consumer operation.
So if the assembly parameter is provided, this line will scan the assembly and automatically register
and discovered consumers.
This is crucial for the microservices acting as a subscriber or consumer of the messages.
For our cases this will be the ordering microservices and after that we can reach the RabbitMQ host
configurations.
So we are using the using RabbitMQ configure method, which is configures the bus to use RabbitMQ as
a transport.
And inside of this method you can see that we specify the host settings for RabbitMQ.
The host method takes the RabbitMQ server URL.
From the configuration you can see that we will passing the configuration message broker host, and
we will also configure the host with passing the username and password configurations from the application
settings Json file.
The username and password also configured from the application settings Json file.
And after that, at the end of the line, you can see that we will configure endpoint with passing the
context object.
This ensures that Masstransit automatically configures the endpoints for the consumers.
And lastly, we can return these services into our service collection with configuring the Masstransit
and RabbitMQ.
And this is the our extension method that we are going to using from basket and ordering microservices.
When we are using from the basket microservices, which is the publisher system, we are sending the
assembly as null because it doesn't require for the publisher system.
But when we are using this method into ordering microservices, we will pass the assembly information
in order to adding consumers into our configurations and hitting the our consumer side.