In this video we are going to do step two which is publish basket checkout event from the basket microservices.
In order to start asynchronous event driven communication using the mass transit and RabbitMQ.
So that means we will apply publish subscribe pattern and we are in the publisher side.
Basket will publish the Basket Checkout integration event to the RabbitMQ.
In order to store this event and send this event to the subscriber system.
In our case it will be ordering microservices.
So if you look at the sub steps of publishing event from the basket microservices, we can say that
we have four steps.
So now let me explain the sub steps of the publishing event from the basket microservices.
And the first step is project reference to building blocks messaging in the basket API project in order
to access shared events and mass transit extensions.
That means in the last videos, we have developed a common shared responsibilities for the asynchronous
communication in the Building Blocks messaging class library.
So now we will use this class library in order to publish event to the RabbitMQ into the basket microservices.
So this is the first step.
Getting reference from the building blocks messaging into our basket API project.
And the second step is registering Masstransit RabbitMQ packages into basket API, dependency injection
into the program CSV file.
And in the third step we will expose http post method for basket checkout operation in the basket API
project.
And the fourth step we will develop basket checkout handler method in order to publish event to the
RabbitMQ using the Masstransit library.
So we will implement these four steps.
Let me start with the first one which is the getting project reference into basket API.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the basket API project.
The basket API project must getting reference from the Building Blocks messaging project to access the
shared events and mass transit.
And I'm going to right click the dependencies and add a project reference.
In our case, we will add a Building Blocks messaging class library.
As you can see that we have already including building Blocks class library for the shared common operations
including the sequence and so on.
So now we are going to adding messaging class library in order to access Masstransit libraries and extensions.
So click the okay button and you can double click the basket API and see that we have including the
project reference building blocks messaging.
In this line of code you can say the basket API project file.
By this way we can provide that basket.
Microservices can access and use basket checkout event folder inside of the building blocks messaging
that we are defined in the shared library.
So if you go back to our steps, the second step is we are basically need to register Masstransit RabbitMQ
packages into basket API, dependency injection and Program.cs.
So for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to basket API and go to the program sales.
But before that, we need to ensure the message worker configurations is correctly set in the application
settings Json file to define RabbitMQ connection details.
For that purpose, I am going to go to basket API and Application Settings Json file and make sure that
you have added message broker section including the hostname, username and password in order to connect
and communicate with RabbitMQ from the basket microservices.
After that we can go back to Program.cs and now we can register required mass transit RabbitMQ classes
into our dependency injection tool.
So in Program.cs we can use the extension method which is the add message broker method from the Building
Blocks messaging class library.
So I'm going to scroll down and continue the this register operation.
Here you can see the application services data services gRPC services added into dependency injection.
And before cross-cutting concerns I am going to come here and add a new tag which is the asynchronous
communication services.
And I'm going to use Builder Services Add message broker passing the configuration from the builder
object.
So this will be provide and required message broker configurations into basket microservices dependency
injection.
You can see that add message broker extension method not introduced in the basket API.
For that purpose I am going to go to using statement and add a using statement manually, which is using
building blocks, messaging and mass transit namespace.
So by this way this extension method will be available for the program case of the basket API.
Here you can see our configuration.
So basically we will call the add message broker which is sets up the mass transit with the RabbitMQ
and preparing the basket microservices to publish messages to the message broker.
And we are not providing any parameter, any assembly parameter in here, because we are in the publisher
side and we don't need to passing any assembly for consumer side.
So this is the adding registering operations for the basket microservices.
And we can now right click and build the basket API.
And this will be completed our.
First two steps of the public checkout operations from the basket.
Microservices.