In this video we are going to develop Basket Checkout feature folder to expose post and point and publish
event to RabbitMQ.
So that means we are at the third and fourth step.
And we will start with the third step for exposing Http post method.
For that purpose, we will create a new feature folder.
If you open the Visual Studio and go to basket API and go to Basket Folder.
If you expand this folder, you can see the feature folders including delete Gate and Store basket.
Basket.
Microservices is designed with a vertical slice architecture that use slices.
Include both end point and implementation class into handle classes.
If you open the one of the use case, you can see that these are including end point and handle classes.
So now we are going to create a new feature folder.
Which name is Checkout Basket in the basket API project.
So I'm going to right click Add new subfolder.
Which name is checkout basket.
And this align with the vertical slice architecture where each use case includes both end points and
implementation in the handle classes.
So that means we will develop two main class under this folder, which is the checkout basket end point
and the checkout basket handle classes.
So now I'm going to add a new two classes.
The first one is for the checkout basket and point six.
And the second class will be the checkout basket handle class.
So these two classes will be aligned with the vertical slice architecture and exposing endpoints in
the endpoint class and implementing actual logic in the handle class.
So now we are going to develop checkout basket and point class.
And this class is responsible for exposing APIs from the basket microservices.
So that means we will implement http post method at the end point of the basket slash checkout.
So now we are going to start with the developing request and response object.
So I'm going to come here and create a two record type for the request and response object.
Here you can see that I have created request and response object.
This is for the request which is the public record checkout basket request.
And as a parameter it is taking basket checkout DTO and the name of the basket checkout DTO.
That means this will be accepting basket checkout DTO object in a Json payload of these http post operation
and as a response this will be returned public record checkout basket response and parameter should
be boolean is success that indicating the operation is successfully complete or not.
So after that we will define our actual checkout basket.
Endpoint classes.
This class should implement Ikatan module in order to expose http post method in a minimal API way.
So that's why I'm going to implement this interface, which is the Ikatan module.
And when we are implementing interface members, this will be adding routes into this method.
So we will use Endpoint Route Builder when exposing APIs with using the Carter.
But before developing this method, it is good to define our DTO object, which is the basket checkout
DTO.
So I'm going to right click the basket API and create new folder, which name is DTO.
And in this details folder I'm going to create basket checkout DTO.
In order to accept these Json object into from the client application, please add a new class.
Which name is basket checkout DTO under the DTO folder.
So after that we can start the implementation of the basket checkout DTO class.
This is typical basket checkout event class.
I'm going to copy these members from the Basket Checkout event and paste in here including the username,
customer ID, total price, billing and shipping address and payment information so you can get these
properties from the Basket Checkout event under the Building Blocks messaging.
Copy from this side and paste into the D2 object.
The idea is that we can getting these DTO variables from the client application as a Json format and
passing these informations to the event object.
So please develop these DTO objects, including these members.
And after that we can go back to our Checkout Basket endpoint class and start to implement our add method
in order to expose these Http post method.
But before that, of course we should add a using statement into our basket API DTO into our checkout
endpoint class.
By the way, we can move these using statement to the our global Usings.
I'm going to cut in here and go to global Usings into basket API and adhere with adding the global keyword.
By this way, we can develop checkout basket end point class without adding the using statement.
So go back to our checkout basket endpoint.
And now it is time to exposing http post request.
So we are going to use app dot map post operation in order to exposing our checkout basket.
So let me develop.
And after that I will explain one by one I'm going to using app dot map post operation.
And after that we will exposing basket checkout end point.
And this will be representing our minimal API definition using the.
Or Carter Library.
So these are the extension methods that we can configure these endpoint.
So here you can see the implementation of the expose checkout operation.
So we are going to start with the app dot map post method to define Http post endpoint for the basket
checkout.
And it is adopting incoming requests in to do our checkout basket request that we have defined in this
class.
And this will be accodomate the incoming requests in this object.
And after that you can see that we will inject Isander center object, which is the mediator Isander
object, into our asynchronous delegate handler class.
When we are calling the http post request for this endpoint.
So this will be delegate handler using the sender method in order to send this command to the mediator.
Here you can see that in the first row of code, we will basically adopting incoming requests to the
checkout basket command object that we will develop in the next video.
And after that we will passing this command object to the mediator.
This will be trigger handler class and returning a result.
And lastly we will converting this result object to our response which is the checkout basket response.
And this will be returned back to the client.
This response object which is using the results method.
And after that we will configure this method with using different extension method from the Carter,
including the with name, summary and description and producers methods.
So this is our typical implementation for the secrets and mediator.
And using the Carter library which is for accepting map post operation with the URL of the slash basket
and slash checkout and implementation using the mediator and secrets lifecycle.
So in the next video we are going to develop actual command and command handler class with using the
mediator.