In this video we are going to do last step for the basket microservices which is develop basket checkout
100 method in order to publish basket checkout event to the RabbitMQ using the Masstransit library.
And in the last video we have developing an exposing http post request for the slash basket slash checkout
end point and we will create request and response object in order to perform our secrets and mediator
request life cycle.
So we will use Carter Library when exposing these endpoint.
And now we are going to use mediator and create command and command handler class in order to perform
actual business logic and return a result object.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and this time please go to the checkout Basket handler.
So I'm going to create firstly command and result object.
And after that we will develop our actual handler class.
So I'm going to start with creating command and result object as a record type.
In here you can see that I have created two record type.
The first one is public record checkout basket command.
And as a parameter it is getting basket checkout DTO and the name of the basket checkout DTO.
And this command object will be implement I command interface which is the I command.
And as a generic it is accepting checkout basket result.
That means we will run this command and return a result which is name is checkout basket result.
So we will indicate this is the I command operation that we are going to hitting the command handler
object with using this command result record type.
And after that here you can see the second record type which is the public record checkout basket result.
And as a parameter it is taking Boolean is success property that is indicating the operation is completed
successfully or not.
So after defining this command and result object, we can define our validator.
But before that we are developing command object.
If you open the checkout basket end point, you can see that the checkout basket command is coming in
here and there is no exception from the our end point class.
So if you continue our implementation handler class, you can see that I'm going to develop our validator
class which is the public class checkout basket command validator.
And this will be inherit from the abstract validator which comes from the fluent validation and taking
generic parameter which is a checkout basket command.
That means we will validate this command object and DTO object inside of this constructor using the
rule for methods and we will check basket checkout.
DTO is not null and the username is not empty with a given messages.
After develop this validator class, we can start to implement actual handler class.
Which name is checkout basket handler?
I'm going to make it command handler checkout basket command handler in order to identify this command
or query handler class.
And after that we are going to implement an interface which is the I command under this interface,
taking two generic arguments as an input and output.
The first one is checkout basket command which is indicating incoming command object to handle class,
and the second one is checkout basket result, which is indicating the response object from the handle
object.
So I am going to implement these interface.
And you can see that this will be create a handle method which basically implement.
The handler is responsible for the processing the checkout requests.
And in this handle method you can see that the first parameter is command object which is the checkout
basket command.
And I am going to change the parameter name request command.
And the second parameter is cancellation token.
So now we are going to implement this handle method.
I'm going to make this method as an asynchronous method.
And we will perform the handle operations in the middle of this method.
Basically, this method should perform a series of steps including retrieving the basket, publishing
the basket checkout event, and after that deleting the basket.
So let's plan this checkout handle method.
I'm going to write a command to do list, which is including the steps that we are going to handle in
the handle method.
So now these are the get existing basket with the total price.
And after that we will set the total price on Basket Checkout event message.
And we will send the Basket Checkout event to the RabbitMQ using the Masstransit library.
And lastly we will delete the basket.
So now we are going to follow these steps in the handle method.
But before that we should inject the required services to perform these actions.
As you can see that we need to interact with the database and RabbitMQ.
For that reason, we need two services to inject our class in order to perform these actions.
For that purpose, I am going to come here and create a primary constructor and I'm going to edit two
services.
The first one is AI basket Repository and repository object in order to perform database operation.
And the second object is AI publish endpoint class which is interface comes from the mass transit library
in order to publish an.
RabbitMQ.
So we will inject these two services to perform these tasks.
So after that we can start the first task which is the get existing basket with a given username.
So I am going to remove this throw statement and perform the first task which is the getting the basket
information using the repository object.
As you can see that we will use a basket repository and we will use get basket method.
In order to get existing basket with a passing the parameter incoming command object, which is the
command at basket checkout dot username.
And we will pass the cancellation token and we will get back to basket information.
And if the basket is null, we will return checkout basket result as a false.
That means we cannot perform this checkout operation successfully.
And after that we can go to the second step, which is to set the total price on basket checkout event
message.
That means we will create an event message and prepare and calculate the total price.
For that purpose, I am going to create a event message in a variable of the event message, and this
will be basically adopting the incoming basket.
Checkout DTO to the Basket Checkout event.
So this will be preparing the event message when we are sending to publishing to RabbitMQ.
And here you can see that we will calculating and passing the total price from the checkout DTO to checkout
event.
So now we are going to come to the point where we are publishing the event message to the RabbitMQ.
So here you can see that I am going to using the publish endpoint interface object that we are going
to use publish method from the mass transit and passing the event message as a parameter and cancellation
token.
So this will be basically perform the publishing the event to RabbitMQ using the message transits.
I publish endpoint interface and after that we will come to the point where we are delete the basket
because after publishing the event to the RabbitMQ, we should delete the existing basket into the basket
database for that purpose.
Again I am going to use repository object and this time we will use await repository dot delete basket
method and passing the username from the incoming command basket.
Checkout DTO username parameter.
With passing the cancellation token.
With this line of code, we basically delete the existing basket which is coming from the incoming command
object.
And lastly, we will return a result.
And in our case I'm going to return checkout basket result.
And this will be taking true.
Which means we will perform the checkout operation successfully as a result of the handle method.
So this is the basket checkout implementation of the basket microservices.
This will be start asynchronous communication with publishing event message to the RabbitMQ that will
consume from the ordering microservices.
So basically we will create a checkout basket vertical slice feature folder.
And we will create an endpoint class exposing the slash basket slash checkout http post method.
And we will accepting the request object with passing the DTO object.
And after that handle these operations in the handle method of the checkout basket command handle class.
And we will get existing basket with incoming username.
And after that we will create an event message that we are going to publish these event message to the
RabbitMQ.
And lastly we will delete the basket with incoming username.
And after that we will return a result as a true parameter.
So this is the implementation of the handle method.
I'm going to right click the basket API and build the basket microservices that we are going to finish
our publisher site.
But I'm going to explain some of the considerations when we are implementing this handle method.
In here you can see that we basically publish basket checkout event to RabbitMQ.
And just after that we will delete the basket into our basket database.
So that means we will interacting to different external systems in the handle method.
And this will be leading dolerite problem.
And these dolerite problem can be solved by using the outbox pattern.
So in the next video we are going to learn dolerite problem and the outbox pattern.