In this video we are going to learn dual write problem.
Dual write problem occurs when application needs to change data in two different systems, for example
a database and a message queue.
If one of the write fails, it can result in inconsistent state.
This is the typical case when you use a local transactions with each of the external systems operations.
For example, when an application needs to persist data in the database and send a message to the Kafka
for notifying other systems.
If one of two these two operations fails, the data will be inconsistent data and these two systems
become inconsistent.
Here you can see the problems.
This can lead to problems such as data loss or corruption, and can be difficult to resolve without
proper error handling and recovery mechanism in place.
So that means dual right can be hard to detect and fix.
Here you can see an example of dual write problem.
In this example we will illustrate create order use case in microservices.
That means when create an order request comes, we want to change data in order database with creating
a new record and also send an order created event to the event bus.
Like Apache Kafka, both operation is handled with two different local transaction that causes dual
write problems.
As you can see the image we have a order microservices client application send the request which is
the create order and in the order microservices we have two main operations.
The first one is write order table which is the create any order item in the order table into the database,
and after that order microservice is going to publish event to the create order event in order to start
order fulfillment process to notify other microservices which subscribing to event from the create order
event into the event path, which could be the inventory shipment and so on.
So this is the dual write problem.
So how to avoid dual write problem in microservices transactional outbox pattern.
What is the transactional outbox pattern.
The outbox pattern provides to publish events reliably.
The idea of this approach is to have an outbox table.
In the microservices databases, we solve dual write problem at the last video.
That happens when application need to change data in two different systems.
So we transactional outbox pattern.
Instead of sending the data to separate locations, we send a single transaction that will store two
separate copies of the data on the database.
One copy is stored in the relevant database table, and the other copy is stored in an outbox table
that will update the other microservices over the event path.
For example, we might connect the outbox table from the Kafka or other messaging queue systems.
That means when your API publishes event messages, it doesn't directly send them.
Instead, the messages are persisted in a database table.
After that, a job publish events to the message broker systems in the predefined time intervals.
So with the outbox pattern, domain events aren't written directly to the event bus.
Instead of that, it is written to a table in the artworks role of the service that stores the events
in its own databases.
However, the critical point is here that the transaction performed before the event and the event written
to Outbox Table are part of the same transactions.
For example, when an Eve order is added to the system, the process of the adding order and writing
the order created event to the outbox table is done in the same transaction, in order to ensure that
the event is saved to the database.
If one of the process is failed, this will rollback the whole operation with following the Acid principles.
The second step is to receive these events written to the outbox table by an independent service, and
write them into the event bus.
We can see the image on the slide.
This is an example of creating an order, creating new order record into the order table, and creating
a new order created event into the outbox table.
And these are the in the same transaction.
And these same operations perform in the same transaction.
If one of the process is fails, this will be rollback the whole transaction with following the Acid
principles.
After that, another service.
Listen and post the outbox table records and publish to the into separate process.
Publish the events into the event post.