In this video, we are going to continue steps of developing a synchronous communication.
And we are at the third step, which is ordering microservices to subscribe and consume basket checkout
event from the RabbitMQ.
In order to perform asynchronous event driven communication.
So this time we will add the consumer side.
That means subscriber side basket will publish the basket checkout event and RabbitMQ store this event
and after that ordering microservices.
Subscribe and consume basket checkout event from the RabbitMQ using the Masstransit to perform asynchronous
event driven communication.
So now let's check the sub steps of the ordering.
Subscribe consume operation for the basket checkout event.
And the first step is getting project reference to building blocks messaging class library in ordering
application project in order to access shared events and masstransit extensions.
That means in ordering application we will add a reference to building blocks, messaging class library.
This inclusion allows to access shared events and masstransit extensions required for the Consuming
the Basket checkout event, and the second step is register Masstransit.
RabbitMQ packages into ordering application dependency injection in the dependency injection file.
So in this step we will modify the dependency injection file into ordering application layer in order
to register Masstransit and RabbitMQ packages, and this setup will configure the necessary services
for handling the basket checkout event.
And the third step is we will develop basket checkout event consumer integration event handler class
to perform checkout and order create operations.
So in this step we will implement an integration event handler class within the ordering application
layer.
This class will handle the basket checkout event, creating an order and executing relevant business
logic.
And the last step is we will have a bonus step which is the publish order created integration event.
Optionally in the domain event handler class for order created, we can publish an order created integration
event to RabbitMQ using the Masstransit and this step is part of the order fulfillment and implementing
a Saga pattern for complex business transactions spanning multiple services.
So now let's get started for the first sub step, which is the getting project reference to building
Blocks messaging in ordering application layer.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Ordering Microservices folder.
And please go to Ordering Application.
So open the ordering application and right click the dependencies.
Add a project reference.
If you right click and add a project reference, you can see that we have already added ordering domain
according to Clean Architecture.
And we have also added building blocks which including the abstractions for the stacks and common operations.
And for now I am going to adding a new class library project reference, which is the building blocks
that messaging and ensure that ordering application has a get referencing from the Building Blocks messaging
project in order to access shared events and Masstransit extensions.
If you click the okay button and if you double click the ordering application, save this file, you
can see the project reference comes into the our project file, and we will successfully adding Building
Blocks messaging class library into ordering application layer.
By this way, we can access the shared events and Masstransit extensions from the Building Blocks messaging
library.
So the question is why we added building blocks and building blocks messaging class libraries into the
ordering application layer, why we don't adding the API or any other layers, because we were following
the clean architecture in ordering microservices and application layer, representing the application
and performing use cases with the abstractions.
So basket checkout, integration, event handling is a use case and it should handle inner application
layer.
That's why we have added in the application layer to perform basket checkout integration, event handling,
use case into order feature folder.
If you open the orders feature folder, you can see that we have commands, queries and event handlers.
In the event handlers, we are going to handle.
Basket checkout.
Integration.
Event handling.