In this video we are going to do the second sub step which is register mass transit.
RabbitMQ packages into ordering application dependency injection file.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering application layer.
But before that, make sure that you have added the configurations in the ordering API layer.
If you open the ordering API and go to the Application Settings Json file, make sure that you have
added the Message Broker section, including the host username and password information.
So we will add these RabbitMQ configuration settings in the application settings Json file.
In the previous videos that we are going to use in this video when we are registering in the ordering
application layer.
So if you go back to ordering application layer, we can modify the dependency injection file in the
ordering application layer.
If you go to ordering application and go to Dependency injection file, you can see that we will register
the services into the application layer from this location.
So I'm going to implement RabbitMQ and Masstransit configuration in the dependency injection file.
For that purpose I'm going to come here and using the services which comes from the I service collection.
And I'm going to use add message brokers.
So this is the extension method that we have developed in the Building Blocks messaging class library
that we can check from the Masstransit extensions.
And here you can see the add message broker extension method and the implementation.
So if you go back to our actual dependency injection class, you can see that this extension method
requiring the configuration and assembly information.
So that means we should paste the configuration object into this location.
But if you look at the Add Application Services extension method, we don't have any configuration parameter
that we can use into our add message broker extension method.
For that purpose we should paste the configuration object from the ordering API layer.
So if you go to the these method definition and go to the references, you can see that these will be
using from the ordering API Program.cs that we can paste the configuration from the builder object.
So we will modify the Program.cs in ordering API layer in order to paste the configuration object to
the Add Application Services extension method, please go to this location and come here and I'm going
to copy the builder configuration parameter and paste this extension method.
So we will modify the add Application services.
So after changing these boolean configurations in the process of the ordering API layer, if you go
to the extension method this time it is time to modify this extension method.
Parameters I am going to add a new parameter which will be the I configuration, and this will be the
representing our configuration objects.
And here you can see the configuration is added into our method.
These are the method definition for the Add Application Services extension method and the configuration
object.
From the application settings Json file is passed to add application services method, allowing to access
RabbitMQ settings into the Add Message broker method.
So I'm going to paste these parameters.
Now when we are developing and adding message broker settings, the first parameter is configuration.
And here you can see that we have also second configuration parameter which is the assembly information.
And this time we will populate these assembly information from the getting executing assembly.
So I'm going to use assembly dot get executing assembly method in order to passing the getting executing
assembly for the ordering application layer.
So this is the implementation of the add message broker.
First of all we have adding and passing the configurations in the parameters of the ordering API layer.
And after that, in the ordering application layer, we have go to the dependency injection class and
adding this line of code in order to register message brokers with passing the configuration and assembly
information.
And note that we have including the assembly information, which is essential for the registering consumer
classes in Masstransit.
If you go to the implementation of the Add Message broker from the R class library, you can see that
we have adding the consumers if the assembly information is not null in this case, in the ordering
application layer, our consumers are ordering microservices.
That's why we are passing the executing assembly from the ordering application dependency injection
class.