In this video we are going to learn integration events, how domain event leads to integration events
and transition from the domain to integration event, and the difference between domain and integration
events.
At the core, they are the same thing, a representation of something that happened in the past.
However, their purpose, use case and implementation details are different.
Let me see.
Domain events.
Domain events published and consumed within a single domain.
So you publish and subscribe to the event in the same application instance.
They are strictly within the boundary of the microservice or domain context.
They typically indicate something that happened within the aggregate and domain events happen in process
and synchronously sent using in-memory message pass.
As an example, we can give order created event.
So if you look at the integration event integration events used to communicate state changes or events
between different bounded contexts or microservices, they are more about the overall systems reaction
to certain domain events.
Integration events should be asynchronously sent with a message broker over a queue.
Integration events are consumed by other subsystems.
As an example, after handling the order created event, an order created integration event might be
published to the message broker like the RabbitMQ, which could then be consumed by other microservices.
So if you compare with the domain and integration event, we can say that domain events happen in process
and synchronously.
On the other hand, the integration event should be asynchronously domain events published and consumed
within a single domain.
So you publish and subscribe to events in the same application instance.
On the other hand, integration events are consumed by other subsystems.
Domain events are sent using in-memory message pass, and integration events are sent with a message
broker over a queue.
So let's see.
Each of microservices has domain and integration events.
So we will develop initially microservices that include domain and integration events.
And the first one is basket checkout integration event.
So basket checkout is an integration event that published from the basket microservices to RabbitMQ
and consume from the ordering microservices.
So we will develop basket checkout event during this section and basket checkout integration event that
will subscribe and consume by the ordering microservices from the RabbitMQ using the mass transit in
order to perform asynchronous event driven communication.
So in the second domain event, we can say that order created domain event and in ordering when consumes
the basket checkout integration event into handler class, it will create a new order into ordering
microservices.
So in ordering microservices, when a new order is created, it will raise an order, created domain
event and triggers internal operations.
And after that we can give order created integration event for the order fulfillment operations.
So when dispatching the order created domain event, a domain event handler class will publish an order
created integration event for the order fulfillment, microservices and implementing Saga pattern.
So this is the transition from the domain to integration event.
Once the order created domain event is handled and order created, integration event is published.
So this integration event can be used to implement complex workflows like a Saga pattern involving the
other microservices.
So here you can see the domain and integration events that we are going to create.
This is the end to end process of the domain and integration events for each of microservices.
And the process starts from the basket microservices that publish the basket checkout integration event.
And this will be consumed by the ordering microservices and handling the ordering microservices.
And when ordering microservices consume these integration event, it will create a new order and this
operation will raise an order created domain event.
And after that this domain event dispatch and handles in the domain handler classes of the ordering
microservices that will also lead any integration event which is the order created integration event
and this will be performed order fulfillment use case.
And this will be subscribing from the other microservices including the shipment, payment and notification
to performing end to end flow of the order fulfillment process.
So now we are at this point when we are consuming these basket checkout integration event in the order
microservices, that we will create a new order, and this will be raised at a domain event that lead
to integration event.