In this video we are going to do the third sub step, which is the Develop the Basket Checkout event
consumer integration event handler class to perform checkout and order create operations.
So here you can see the ordering application folder structure that we are going to develop orders feature
folder.
And in this feature folder we have commands queries and event handlers.
So in this case we will separate the domain and integration event handling.
And we will develop basket checkout event handler.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering API and ordering application layer.
And in this layer we can see that we have a orders feature folder.
And under the event handlers we have two domain event handler.
But this time we will handle the integration events.
So we should separate the integration event handler in a separate folder under the orders feature.
That means we will modify the orders feature folder to include the subfolders for domain and integration
event handler.
So I'm going to separate the event handlers.
So first of all we will right click these event handlers and create a new subfolder which is a domain.
Right click any add new subfolder which is domain.
And also I'm going to right click again event handlers and add new subfolder which name is integration.
So basically we have created two subfolder under the event handlers of the orders feature folder.
So that means we will separate the event handlers according to the event types.
These are the domain and integration folders in the domain subfolder.
These will be existing domain event handlers are moved to domain sub folder and in the integration folder
this will be.
Any integration folder is created for the handling integration events like basket checkout event.
So that means we should start with the domain events.
And we should move existing domain event handlers into domain sub folder.
And we will created a new integration event.
And we will create a new class which will be the basket checkout integration event.
So let me start with the domain and domain event handlers.
Here you can see that I'm going to select these two classes and move to domain sub folder.
This will be representing our domain event handlers.
These are the order created and order updated.
Domain handler.
Here you can see that these will be automatically updated to namespace according to sub folder structure.
After that we can create an integration event for our case.
Come to the this point and add a new class.
Which name is basket checkout event handler.
So this will be representing our integration event handler.
And the handler will be responsible for initiating the order creation process upon receiving the Basket
checkout event.
And in this class, we will basically implement a consumer Basket checkout event from the Masstransit
in order to handle this event.
So I'm going to start with removing unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And in here I'm going to implement this I consumer interface.
Here you can see the this interface comes from the Masstransit library.
I will choose the generic one and passing the generic argument which is the basket checkout event.
This will be representing our event object comes from the Or Building Blocks messaging class library.
Once we are implementing this interface, you can see that this will be create a new method.
Which name is consumer method?
This consumer method will be handled the basket checkout event consumer operation in the body of this
method.
And it is taking a parameter which is the consumer context and taking as a basket checkout generic argument
into context object and it provides to access to the event data and other message context features.
So now we are going to implement this consumer operation.
We will create a new order and start order fulfillment process when we are handling the integration
event.