In this video we are going to develop basket checkout event, consumer integration, event handler class
to perform checkout and order create operation.
So that means we will develop consumer method and we will implement create new order and start order
fulfillment process.
So in the beginning of this method I am going to logging the incoming event.
And after that I will create a new order with passing the create order command to the six.
For that purpose, I am going to use a primary constructor and I'm going to inject I sender and I logger
in order to communicate with the mediator, create command operation and logging the incoming event.
So please add the primary constructor into the basket checkout event and adding the is handled sender
object and I logger basket checkout event handler for the logging operations.
So in the beginning of this method I am going to performing the log information.
And I'm going to remove this throw statement.
And in here we will add a log statement which will be the logger dot log information.
So we are going to log incoming event with this message which is the integration event handled with
the integration event.
And we are going to passing the context message get type and the get type of the name of the message
which will be representing integration event in the log information method.
So this method will be provided to logging the incoming event.
And after that we will perform the create order operation.
So how we can create any order in the ordinary application.
Of course we are using and following the vertical slice and Seacrest design pattern.
So that's why if you expand the command folder under the orders, you can see the create order command.
And this use case can be handled with the create order command and handler.
So I'm going to use and create create order command in order to trigger create order handler to create
a new order.
So let me write first and explain after that.
Here you can see that first of all we are going to map to create order command from the incoming context
message which is representing our basket checkout event object.
We will convert these basket checkout event to the command object in order to send to our mediator Sanderson
operation.
So first of all, I'm going to make this function as an asynchronous function in order to run these
available standard send command operation.
When we are sending these command object to the mediator, mediator will be triggered the corresponding
handler method.
So we are preparing to create order command.
And if you open the create order command that means we will be create these create order command in
order to trigger our create order command handler in the ordering application layer.
So that means these handler class will be triggered when we are sending the mediator the create order
command and coming this handle method.
In this handle method, as you can see that we will create a new order entity and save the database
and return a result.
So that means we have created a new order entity and add these order entity in the orders collections
in the DB context and save changes async.
So this will be performing the create new order into our SQL server database.
So if you look at this line of code you can see that we are going to create new order in this function.
So in the incoming order DTO we are using to create a new order with using the order dot create method.
If you go to this method, you can see that this is staying into our domain driven design.
In the domain layer in the order aggregate order is responsible for the create their own entities.
For that purpose.
The create method is located in the order entity and in here after creating a new order, this is raising
any domain event which is the order created domain event.
So this will be triggered any order created event and this will be handled again in the ordering application
layer order created event handler.
And this will be logging the information so you can see the end to end process.
We are starting from the basket checkout event.
So now I am going to develop the private method for the map to create order command.
After the consume method you can see that we have developed private create order command and map to
create order command with getting the parameter which is the checkout event as a message.
So this will be method signature.
And in this method we will taking the event message and return back the create order command in order
to send the mediator sender.
So after that, inside of this method you can see that first of all I'm going to create address and
payment DTO which incoming event data using the message dot firstName, LastName or card name, card
number and so on.
This is typical value object creation into the DTO object for the address and payment information.
And after that I have created a new order ID with using new greet.
And in here you can see that we will use new order DTO with passing to incoming event and also created
value objects including the ID, customer ID, order name, shipping and billing address, payment status
and order items.
Here you can see that I have created some hardcoded order item value, and these are the order item
DTO that we can pass the order ID and these.
The representing our product IDs into our application.
Here you can see that the second parameter is product ID.
And I am passing the product ID that we have already populating and seeding data in the SQL server database.
So this is the new order data.
And after that we are passing these order data to the new create order command operation to responding.
This method and this method will be getting the command object send the mediator.
So basically you can see that I have using some of the hardcoded order items for demonstration.
In the real world scenario these would come from the incoming event data or external services.
So you can get this product data information from the incoming message from the RabbitMQ.
But for now, to make it simple, I'm using a hardcoded value and initialize essential fields like the
shipping address, billing address and payment, so on.
So if you look at the our order creation flow, we can say that the basket Publish basket checkout integration
event.
And this will be handled in the ordering microservices.
So if you look at the code this is the point where we are developing basket checkout event handler.
And this will be triggered our consume method.
And this will be basically sending the create order command in order to create order command.
So if you look at the our request lifecycle, you can see that we are at this point.
And this will be trigger ordering.
Microservices.
Send the create order command to its handler and this handler process to command and raise the order
created domain event.
So if you follow this process in the code, you can see that this will be hitting the Or handler class.
And in this handler class this will be creating any order.
And when creating any order this will be hitting the order dot create function.
This will be using.
We are creating a new order and adding the domain events which is the order created domain event.
So this domain event handler also triggering from the ordering application layer which is again event
handlers domain and order created event handler.
And this will be come to this point and logging the information.
So if you look at our request flow you can see that the order created domain event also comes to the
event handler in the ordering application layer.
And now we are going to publishing order created integration event in order to starting the order fulfillment
process and notifying the our external microservices.
These are the shipment, payment and notification.
So that means order.
Microservices should notify the other microservices, including the shipment, payment and notification
to start their respective processes to perform the order fulfillment process.
For example, shipment microservices send the shipment billing, microservices send the invoice and
notification microservices send the mail.
So in the next step, we will see how to implement Saga pattern and other advanced pattern to performing
these order fulfillment process in the external and other microservices.