In this video we are going to learn Saga pattern for distributed transactions.
The saga pattern is provided to manage data consistency across microservices in distributed transaction
cases.
Basically, Saga pattern offers to create a set of transactions that update microservices sequentially
and publish events to trigger the next transaction for the next microservices.
If one of the step is failed, then Saga pattern trigger to rollback transactions, which is basically
do reverse operations with publishing rollback events to the previous microservices.
By this way, it is managed distributed transactions across microservices.
As you know that it is used some principles inside of the saga pattern like publish subscribe pattern
with brokers or API composition patterns.
The saga pattern is a way to manage long running transactions that involve multiple microservices.
It is based on the idea of the saga, which is a series of local transactions that work together to
achieve end to end use cases.
The Saga pattern is especially useful in distributed systems where multiple microservices need to coordinate
their actions.
For distributed transactions.
The Saga pattern can help to ensure that the overall transaction is either completed successfully or
is rolled back to its initial state if any individual microservice encounters any error.
In order to use Saga patterns in a distributed transactions, we can use a compensating transaction
to undo the changes made by each microservices in the event of an error.
By this way, we can ensure that the overall transaction is either completed successfully or roll back
to its initial state.
The Saga pattern provides transaction management with using a sequence of local transactions of microservices.
Every microservices has its own database, and it can able to manage local transactions in atomic way
with strong consistency.
So Saga pattern grouping these local transactions and sequentially invoking one by one each local transaction
updates the database and publishes an event to the trigger the next local transaction.
If one of the step is failed, then Saga pattern trigger to rollback transactions that are a set of
compensating transaction that rollback the changes on previous microservices and restore the data consistency.
Here you can see the an example of how the Saga pattern could be used in e-commerce application for
order fulfillment process to handle the rollback scenario.
First of all, the customer placed an order on the e-commerce website and provides their payment information.
The application order fulfillment microservices begins a local transaction and send a request to the
inventory of microservices, asking it to reserve the item in the customer's order and the inventory.
Microservice begins a local transaction and reserves the item in the customer's order and the inventory.
Microservices send a response back to the order fulfillment microservices indicating that the items
were reserved successfully.
The order fulfillment process.
Microservices receives the response from the inventory.
Microservices and assuming everything went as planned and it charges the customer payment method and
commits its local transaction.
However, if an error are encountered along the way, the saga pattern provides a way to roll back to
changes made by each microservices.
For example, if the inventory microservice encountered any problem while resolving the items in the
customer order, it could send a failure response back to the order fulfillment.
Microservices.
In this case, the order fulfillment microservices would execute a compensating transaction in order
to undo the chart's operation for customer payment method and cancel the order.
That means it is rolling back to the entire fulfillment process.
As a result, the Saga pattern is useful tool for managing distributed transactions in microservice
architectures.
It allows us to ensure that the overall transaction is either completed successfully or is rollback
to the initial state, so this will provide a resilient and reliable distributed systems when it comes
to applying to end to end use cases.