In this video we are going to do fourth sub steps of the ordering subscribe consume operation which
is the publish order, created integration event for the order fulfillment process and microservices
and implemented Saga pattern.
So we will follow the last step in the ordering subscribe consume operation.
And if you follow the Icap microservice Domain and Integration event, we have developed the Basket
Checkout Integration event and consume these event into our handler class.
And after that we will raising order created domain event when creating any order into our consume operation.
And lastly, it is time to create order created integration event for the order fulfillment process.
So that means if you look at the our order flow you can see that basket microservices publish the basket
checkout integration event to the ordering microservices and ordering microservices.
Consume these event and create a new order and raising order created domain event that will handle in
this point.
And for this video we will publish order created integration event to performing order fulfillment process
and notifying order microservices like shipping, billing and inventory.
So when we are handling the order created domain event, we can also publishing the order created integration
event in order to perform order fulfillment process.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the event handlers under the ordering application
and go to the Domain Event Handlers and open the order created Event handler.
This will be accodomate the incoming order created domain event handler, and this will be leading the
integration event to our architecture.
In order to publish an integration event from this class, we should inject AI publish endpoint interface
from the mass transit.
So for that purpose, please come to the primary constructor point and inject any interface which is
the AI publish endpoint which comes from the mass transit.
And the second injection will be the AI logger object.
So with using these two objects we are going to perform our handle operation.
In the handle operation we will modify the order created domain event handler to publishing order created
integration event handler.
First of all, I'm going to look at the first parameter of the handle method, which is the order created
event which comes from the domain event handler.
So I'm going to change the name of the parameter notification to domain event handler.
I'm going to write domain event.
So this will be representing our domain event.
So I'm going to change the first log information operation and change the notification to domain event.
So this will be represent our domain event in the incoming parameter.
So before returning a task completed we will performing the our publishing integration event part.
So we will utilize I publish endpoint from the mass transit for publishing.
But before that we should map the order entity to the order DTO for the event data.
For that purpose I'm going to mapping the incoming event, which is domain event to the order DTO.
Here you can see the incoming domain event and this is the order which is representing our order entity.
And we will write an extension method which is to order DTO to converting order DTO for the order created
integration event.
And after that I'm going to use Publish Endpoint Object in order to publish an integration event.
And here you can see that we have available function.
That's why I'm going to change public async for the handle method.
And after that you can see that we are using await publish endpoint dot publish method and passing the
order created integration event.
This will be the order data and cancellation token.
This line of code provide to publishing an integration event to the RabbitMQ.
So now we can safely delete this return operation because we will perform available function with publishing
the integration event.
And this is the implementation of the handle method.
And we should now develop the two order DTO extension method on the order entity, as you remember that
in the application layer we have extension folder.
And under the extensions we have order extensions that I am going to develop to order DTO extension
method under this class.
If you open this class, you can see that we have ordered the existing to order DTO list extension method
for the IEnumerable order.
Now we are going to follow the same steps for a single order entity.
For that purpose.
Come here and develop our public static order DTO to order DTO method name and we will write this extension
method in the order entity.
So here you can see that we will returning DTO from Order Private method with passing the order entity.
And in here you can see that we will perform the actual operation under this private static order dto
dto from the order and taking order entity as a parameter and returning a new order DTO with passing
the incoming order entity members to the order DTO members.
Here you can see that ID, customer id order name, shipping.
And billing address.
In this case, we are creating a new address DTO to representing our value object and passing the order
entity value information.
Here you can see that we are passing the order shipping and billing address informations for these two
value objects, including the shipping and billing address.
And this is the pricing the payment information to create payment DTO in the order DTO object.
And we are passing the status as a order status.
And in here you can see that we are also passing the order items.
We are iterating the order entity order items and using the select link function in order to create
a new order item DTO and mapping this order id values to the new order item.
Details.
So this is the implementation of the extension method from two ordered DTO function, and you can save
the order extensions.
And you can see that this method is using to our handle method, which is the order created domain event
handler.
So after converting these DTO objects, we are passing these D2 object to the publish method of the
mass transit publish endpoint in order to trigger any integration event to the RabbitMQ.
But this is the new feature for our application.
We don't plan any integration event in the ordering domain event handler, because whenever we are creating
any order, this will be trigger an integration event, but we should be available this function when
only subscriber order fulfillment microservices are developed for that purpose.
Since that time it will create unnecessary event messages on the RabbitMQ.
For example, when the ordering microservices start up, we are migrating and sending database.
If you open the ordering infrastructure and expand the data folder, you can see the extension folder
and open the database extensions.
This is basically migrate the database and seeding async function that will seeding the order with items
data.
If you go to the function, you can see that this will be creating any orders on the database and this
operation will be triggered or order created.
Domain event.
And this handler will be leading to our integration event for application startup.
We don't want to raising and triggering and publishing integration event with using the seed function.
For that purpose.
We can make this operation as a feature.
So ASP.Net has very good feature in the out-of-the-box for the ASP.Net feature management.
For that purpose, let's develop ASP.Net Feature Management for these order fulfillment event publish
operation.