In this video, we are going to learn ASP.Net Feature Management to develop feature flags for order
created integration events.
So let me start.
What is feature flags?
Feature flags are a powerful technique in software development, allowing teams to modify system behavior
without changing the code.
They enable functionalities to be turned on or turned off dynamically, providing flexibility in deployment
and testing.
So ASP.Net core also providing feature management.
ASP.Net core support feature management integrating seamlessly with the existing configuration system.
Microsoft Feature Management ASP.Net is a NuGet package that offers a streamlined approach to implement
feature flags.
So why we need to use feature Flag for order fulfillment event.
The problem is we have unnecessary event messages in RabbitMQ and premature triggering of order fulfillment
process.
And as a solution, we should implement a feature flag for the order fulfillment event, allowing it
to be enabled or disabled based on the readiness of the other microservices looking for the configurations.
So for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio.
And here you can see that we have published an integration event in the order created Domain event.
But this is a new feature that should be available when the subscriber order fulfillment microservices
are developed.
Since that time it will create unnecessary message event message in the RabbitMQ.
In order to avoid that, it is good to manage this feature with ASP.Net feature management.
Also, as you know that when ordering microservice start up, it will migrate and seed the data in the
ordering infrastructure layer.
We have seen in the database extensions that will create order and publish these messages.
So it is good to skip this point for order fulfillment event creation using the feature flags.
So we will put the feature flag for these two line of code.
So the first thing we must do add a Microsoft Feature management ASP.Net core NuGet packages the feature
Flag Management library manage the feature flag lifecycle on behind of the scenes.
This gives us the ability to change feature flags at runtime without needing to restart the application,
but where we should install it.
Since feature management is a generic operation, it is good to install this package into building blocks.
Class library.
Here you can see that we have a building blocks that using from the common operations for each microservices.
So it is a best practice to using ASP.Net feature management NuGet packages, installing the building
blocks in order to reflect for each microservices.
So I'm going to install NuGet packages, which is Microsoft Feature Management, ASP.Net core.
For that purpose, I'm going to come here and go to dependencies of the building blocks.
Right click and manage NuGet packages.
So we will browse Microsoft that feature management dot ASP.Net core.
So here you can see the package that we are going to install in the building blocks dependencies.
And this approach centralizes the feature management for all microservices.
Please install these NuGet packages.
If you double click the building blocks and save this project file, you can see that we have added
the Microsoft Feature Management ASP.Net core under the building blocks.
So now every microservices can enable feature management using this package from the building blocks.
So now I am going to activate the feature flag for ordering microservices.
And we should register feature management in the dependency injection.
So we will go to ordering Application Dependency injection class to adding services for the add feature
management.
And if you go to ordering application and go to the dependency injection, you can see that we are registering
the services in this place, and we will adding the feature management that will enable feature management
in the ordering microservices.
If you come to the this point before add message broker, we can again use the services.
And this time I'm going to add a add feature management extension method.
By adding this line of code, we will enabling the feature management for the ordering microservices.
And after that we should configure the feature management configuration on the ordering API application
settings Json file.
After adding this line of code in the Dependency injection class, it is time to define the feature
flag configuration in the configuration file of the ordering microservices, which is the application
settings Json file for that purpose.
Please go to the ordering API and open the application settings Json file.
And just after the adding configurations for the message broker, I am going to add a new configuration.
Which name is Feature Management?
Here you can see that we have added a new section, which name is feature management.
And under this Json section we have a order fulfillment feature.
That value is true.
So we defined order fulfillment flag as a true that we can use it on the fly when running the application.
So we will use this feature flag in the event handlers for that purpose, we should go to the ordering
application layer and go to the orders event handlers, domain event handlers and order created domain
event handler that we are publishing integration event in this domain event handler.
So we will check the feature flag in the order created event handler before publishing the integration
event.
That means we will utilize it feature management interface in order to determine if the feature is enabled
or not.
So we will develop feature flag into order created event handler.
In our case, we would like to on off dynamically for the order fulfillment event creation feature according
to feature flag.
For that purpose, I am going to inject a new services.
After the I publish endpoint, I am going to inject AI feature manager interface which name is Feature
Manager.
So please inject AI Feature Manager into the primary constructor of the order created event handler.
So now we have three services.
The first one is I publish endpoint, the second one I feature manager and third one is Ilogger.
So now we are going to use these feature manager when we are publishing the integration event.
Actually we will check the if statement before publishing the integration event.
For that purpose.
I am going to use an if statement in the beginning of these integration event.
And in here we can put a inline bracket.
And in here I'm going to move this code block into this if statement.
As you can see that the if statement is including await feature manager is enabled async.
And we will passing order fulfillment.
That is exactly the same name in the application settings Json file in the ordering API.
This is our feature flag name, which is the order fulfillment and the value is true.
And if you come back to our order created event handler, you can see that if the value is true, then
we can publish integration event from the our domain event which is the order created event handler.
This will provide us to flexibility.
That means quickly enable or disable feature without redeploying and it will provide to easy testing.
We can facilitate AB testing and canary releases, and we can control and manage features, rollout
and rollback efficiently.
So as you can see that we have implemented a feature flag for the order fulfillment using the ASP.Net
core feature management.