In this video we are going to set up RabbitMQ for asynchronous communication using the docker compose
file.
So that means we are at the last step which is the developing asynchronous communication steps.
And this is the docker compose at RabbitMQ image in a multi-container environment in Docker compose
files.
So now let's see our microservices asynchronous communication.
Here you can see the RabbitMQ sitting between basket and ordering microservices.
And we are using the RabbitMQ message broker as a backing services of the basket and ordering microservices.
Basket will publish the basket checkout integration event and RabbitMQ store this event and send the
event to the ordering microservices which subscribe and consume these basket checkout event.
So we should download the RabbitMQ message broker docker image and run this docker image into our Docker
compose environment as a backing services for the basket and ordering microservices.
So we will configure the RabbitMQ in a multi-container docker environment for asynchronous communication
between basket and ordering microservices into the Docker files.
But before that, let's remember our e-commerce microservice deployment strategy.
According to our deployment strategy, we are at the deployment one, and we have developed the basket
and ordering microservices into our local development machines.
But now we need to connect the message broker as a backing services.
And we need to message broker IP and port number that we can connect from our local computer and local
microservices.
And here you can see the deployment two, which is basically orchestrate all microservices with Docker
compose and test inside of the full Docker environment.
But now we will focus on the first part, which is the deployment one.
And we have developed our microservices in local computer and we need to activate Message Broker as
a backing services in Docker environment.
For that purpose I'm going to open the RabbitMQ page on the Docker Hub.
Here you can see the RabbitMQ official image in the crop that we can see the details how we can activate
RabbitMQ in a Docker environment.
If you scroll down, you can see that the RabbitMQ can be run and activate with using this command.
Basically we will using the host name and name and we will pasting the image name as a RabbitMQ and
RabbitMQ is exposing as a default port is A5672.
And if you scroll down you can see the environment variables that we can set when we are activating
these RabbitMQ in our Docker compose.
And here you can see the default username and password that we can paste this configuration with, including
the hostname name RabbitMQ default user RabbitMQ default password.
And this is the image.
So these are the settings and configurations about the RabbitMQ that we are going to use when we are
activating RabbitMQ in our Docker compose environment.
So now we will follow the docker compose and add the RabbitMQ image into our docker compose file for
multi-container docker environment.
But before that, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running, and after that you should go
back to our Visual Studio and go to Docker Compose and open the docker compose Yaml file.
If you scroll down, you can see that we have listing the backing services in the beginning of the docker
compose file.
And we have already added the Microsoft SQL server image for ordering database.
And now we will follow the same configuration for the RabbitMQ message broker.
For that purpose, I am going to add a new image under the order DB, because this will be representing
the backing services for our microservices.
And I will put a message broker and the image should be the RabbitMQ management.
Here you can see that I put a required indentation and after that give the image name as a RabbitMQ
management.
So please add these two line of code into our docker compose after the order db definition.
So after that we can go to the override yaml file in order to configure these RabbitMQ message broker
image.
So if you double click the override Yaml file and locate the same location after the order db configuration,
we are going to configure our message broker.
Come to this point and arrange for the message broker.
At this point I am going to start the Message broker configurations and as a configuration I am going
to adding container name, host name and environment variables.
And after that restart always and the port numbers which is belonging to default port numbers for the
RabbitMQ message broker.
So please save the overwriting file and make sure that you have added the correct message broker configurations.
After the order db.
Please save this file and make sure that the configuration settings is same and correct as we are setting
up the our application settings Json file.
If you open, for example ordering API and go to Application Settings, you can see the message broker
configuration including the hostname, username and password.
So in our Docker compose file our username and password guest guest it is correct.
And the host name is amqp localhost.
And the default port number.
So this is the default port number.
And we are following the default port number.
When communicating from our local ordering and basket microservices, we can also validate from the
basket microservices application Settings.json file.
This is same as the configuration in the ordering microservices host username and password.
So that means we have successfully configured and set up the RabbitMQ in a Docker environment for asynchronous
communication.
Now we are going to run RabbitMQ message broker in a Docker environment in order to connect from the
basket and authentic microservices.