In this video, we are going to learn how to run Docker Compose within the Visual Studio in order to
set up RabbitMQ, which is a crucial component for asynchronous communication.
So please open the Visual Studio and let's getting started with Docker Compose in Visual Studio.
So you can see that under the our microservice solution we have a Docker compose file in the root folder.
If you right click the docker compose and set a startup project, you can see that the Docker Compose
learning profile comes into Visual Studio.
So now this will be run the docker compose using the Visual Studio.
But this time I'm going to run Docker compose without debugging.
Here you can see that next to Docker Compose learning profile you can see the start without debugging
option in Visual Studio.
So we will start without debugging in Docker Compose.
That means this will be run the docker compose project without debugging.
So hitting this button and this will be start to running.
And this process may take a few minutes during the first run as Docker pulls and build the necessary
images.
So when the first time running, it takes some time to spin up RabbitMQ images.
Because when we give the management image for RabbitMQ, it does not the base RabbitMQ image and management
dashboard image altogether.
Here you can see the docker compose Yaml file.
We give the image name as a management RabbitMQ that includes the base image Erlang and the management
dashboard.
So this is the overall HTML file that we have configured in the last time.
So you can see the progress in the output.
And also we can confirm the created image from the Docker desktop.
Here you can see the Docker compose has started successfully.
And also all microservices started successfully without debugging.
And if you scroll down you can see the message broker is started successfully for the RabbitMQ management
image.
This is our message broker container.
If you open the container, you can see the logs are created successfully and that means we are ready
to use these message broker as a asynchronous communication.
So now we can examine the RabbitMQ Docker image.
If you scroll the right hand side you can see that we have exposed the RabbitMQ port numbers in our
local computer.
And RabbitMQ management image has two port numbers, the one for the actual RabbitMQ image and another
for the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
So if I hit the 15672 port number, you can see that this will be redirecting to us RabbitMQ management
dashboard.
Here you can see the username and password.
You can give the guest and guest as a username and password and click the login button.
So this is the our RabbitMQ management dashboard that we can log in the credentials with the guest and
guest.
And here you can see the main sections including the connections channels exchange queues and streams
and the admin.
So exchange are representing the routes messages between the queues and the queues and streams representing
the storing messages that are waiting to be processed.
And we have also topics for routing mechanism for messages.
So if you scroll down in the overview page you can see that we have a node section.
And under the node section we will identify the node name as a RabbitMQ message queue.
Here you can see that this is the rabbit at e-commerce MQ.
As you remember that e-commerce MQ is our hostname when we are configuring our Docker compose.
And this is the our node definition.
And if you scroll down you can see the listening ports in different protocols.
Here you can see the Amqp protocol.
The port number is default port number for the RabbitMQ image.
And this is the Http protocol that we are going to use for the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
This is 15672.
And these are the other configurations in the RabbitMQ overview section.
So as you can see that we have successfully run the RabbitMQ using the Docker compose in Visual Studio.
And we have verified the RabbitMQ setup through the Docker desktop and the management dashboard.