In this video we are going to test publish checkout event in the basket microservices.
So we will understand how to publish basket checkout microservices to the RabbitMQ and using RabbitMQ
for asynchronous event driven communication.
And we will focus on the interaction between basket microservices and RabbitMQ message broker and the
underlying infrastructure setup.
As you remember, our e-commerce microservice deployment strategy or microservices will be in localhost
and developing in local environment.
And our RabbitMQ message broker will be on Docker environment and up and running as a backing services
on Docker environment.
So that means we will connect the basket microservices from local environment to docker environment.
RabbitMQ message broker.
Please open the Visual Studio and open the docker compose files.
Here you can see the our configurations on Docker environment for the RabbitMQ configurations.
And now we are going to open the basket microservices.
And we will connect these RabbitMQ from our local basket microservices.
And if you open the program yes you can see that if you scroll down we are going to adding required
services in this line of code with using the Add Message Broker extension method.
So if we go to this method here, you can see that we will passing the configuration from the builder
object.
And if you go to the implementation of this extension method, you can see that we will use this configuration
when getting the host username and password from the application settings Json file and adding required
Masstransit packages in order to connect RabbitMQ from our basket microservices.
And you can check these configurations in the application settings Json file under the basket API and
we have message broker section.
So that means we are ready to communicate with RabbitMQ from our local basket microservices.
So before we start we should verify the RabbitMQ.
If you open the Docker desktop, please ensure that the RabbitMQ Docker container is up and running,
which is a message broker.
And in here we have up and running and you can check the port numbers also exposing correctly.
So after that we can go back to our basket microservices and we can start to run our application.
But we should run the basket API with the discount gRPC microservices.
Because these services connecting when adding item in the basket.
So that means basket microservices and discount microservices need to run simultaneously because basket
API depends on the discount gRPC microservices for calculating discounts during the basket create operations.
For that purpose, I am going to right click the solution and if you go to properties I'm going to select
the startup project.
And this time we will select the multiple startup project and this will be basket API.
Come here and select the start.
And also you can go to the discount gRPC.
Come here and click the start and click the apply.
And okay after that you can see that our running profile has changed.
To start.
That means we will start the application from the Visual Studio by running two microservices simultaneously.
And we will arrange basket and discount microservices will be run together in order to perform our use
cases.
So our use case is we should create a basket.
First of all, it calls the discount gRPC to calculate the discounts.
And after created the basket we will check out the basket to perform asynchronous communication.
So before running the application I am going to put the required breakpoints.
So if you go to basket API and open the programs case you can go to breakpoint in the beginning of the
add message worker.
To understand how we can register Masstransit communications with using the RabbitMQ.
And after that, it is crucial to adding breakpoint for the important areas, which is the basket feature
folder.
And if you expand this folder, you can see that we will test our use case, which is the basket checkout.
If you expand this folder, you can see that we have Endpoint and handler class.
I'm going to open the endpoint first.
And I'm going to put a breakpoint in the beginning of the map post delegate handler function, which
is basically accodomate incoming http post request to this endpoint that we will send during this video.
And after that we can put additional breakpoint when leaving this method.
After that, we can put a breakpoint in the handler class.
If you open the checkout basket handler class and scroll down, you can put a breakpoint in the beginning
of the handler method, which is performing actual operation for publishing basket checkout event and
deleting the basket.
So after that, we can put additional breakpoint in the store basket in order to create a new basket
into our basket.
Microservices.
Here you can see that we have already breakpoints in this location.
So now we can run the application that will start with the basket API and discount gRPC simultaneously.
I am going to hit the start button and this will be starting our microservices locally.
And this will be communicate with the RabbitMQ to perform asynchronous communication.
Here you can see that the first point is our breakpoint hitting the add message broker extension method.
This comes from the our program.cs of the basket microservices that we.
Can see in this location.
So if you go to the extension method and debugging this extension method, you can see that we will
adding mass transit into dependency injection of the basket microservices.
And I am going to continue this debug operation.
And here you can see that we will adding and configuring the RabbitMQ configuration, getting configurations
from the application settings Json file.
And this will be returned services and continue adding other services to basket microservices.
After completed starting.
You can verify from the project consoles.
Here you can see the basket API ready to communicate and ready to accepting the Http requests.
And here you can see that mass transit bus has started in this location.
And also if we check for the other project console, which is the discount gRPC, that will hit the
discount gRPC from the basket microservices when adding item in the basket.
So now we can start our end to end use case.
If you remember the end to end use case we will check out the basket.
But first of all, we need a basket.
That means we need to create basket into basket microservices.
And the first step involves making Http post requests to basket API to create a new basket.
For that purpose, please open the postman and if you open the postman, you can see the Our Postman
collection which is the Icap microservices.
And if you open the basket microservices, which is a subfolder, here you can see the our Http get,
post, delete and post request for the checkout basket.
First of all, I am going to create a new basket with using http post request which is indicating the
http post and this URL is for the localhost.
And I'm going to change the environment as a docker to localhost, because basket microservices exposing
services in the local environment.
And we have run the basket and discard in our local environment.
After changing the environment to localhost, you can see the basket URL comes with 50 port numbers.
So that means this is indicating our local environment and slash basket which is the our endpoint in
order to create any basket.
So here you can see the URL payload that we have created in the previous videos.
This will include cart information including username and items.
We have two items in the basket that we are going to create iPhone X and Samsung ten.
So I'm going to hit the send button in order to send http post requests.
And this will be comes to our store basket endpoint class.
And this will be hitting our endpoint class under the store basket folder.
If you contain debugging you can see that first of all, we will adapting incoming requests to command.
And we will send this command to the mediator in order to trigger our command handler class.
Here you can see the handle method comes in here.
So the first step we are going to deduct the discount from the discount to our PC.
And this will be hit or discount gRPC microservices for each item in the shopping cart.
So here you can see that we will call gRPC method which comes to get discount method of the discount
gRPC microservices.
And we will check the coupon information with a given product name.
And if there is a deduct information we can deducting the coupon information.
But if not exist we will continue to our empty coupon information and log the information and return
back the coupon model.
If I hit the F5, this will be come to the point where the deduct operation.
Completing the coupon amount is 150.
We have a coupon information and we will deducting this information from the iPhone X price and if you
continue the next item, you can see that the second item also goes to the our discount gRPC.
And looking for the coupon information which is existing the coupon information.
That means there is a discount that we are going to return our basket microservices and deducting this
amount 100 discount from the actual price of the 500.
So these are completing the creating basket and deducting discount operation.
And this time with this line of code, we will insert a new item into basket database which sending
the command that cart operation.
So if you continue this code you can see that this will be hitting the store basket under the case basket
repository.
Because in basket microservices we will also use distributed cache as a caching operation.
And in here you can see that first of all we will store the basket in database using the Martin.
And after that this will also saving into distributed cache which is the redis in our case.
And if I hit F5 and continue this operation, you can see that we have got the 201 created successful
response.
That means we have created successfully as the villain username into our basket microservices.
So this was the first step of our basket checkout and 20 use case.
And after that we will check out the basket for checkout the basket.
I have created a new http post request under the basket folder.
Here you can see that this time this is again http post request, but the endpoint is changed a little
bit.
This is the basket URL slash basket and slash checkout.
So this will be the our actual checkout operation for the basket.
Microservices.
And this operation involves publishing a basket checkout event to RabbitMQ and then deleting the basket
from the basket API.
So here you can see the payload including the basket checkout DTO object.
This including the username, customer ID, total price, first name, last name, and so on.
These are the required parameters that we populate from the payload in the Our postman collection.
Now I am going to hit the send button in order to trigger http post request for the checkout.
Andpoint.
Here you can see that this comes or breakpoint in the checkout basket endpoint.
And this will be accodomate incoming requests.
And in this request we have a basket checkout DTO.
And at the first step we will convert these basket checkout requests to the command object.
And we will send this command object to the mediator in order to trigger our store basket handler class.
And in this class, first of all, we will get existing basket from the database with passing the username,
and if the database is getting basket information from the basket data here you can see that first of
all this will be checked to distributed cache and the cache information.
Returning a basket data.
And we can returning the De basket data from the cache which is the distributed Redis cache.
And after getting the basket information we will go to the second step which is the publish event message
to the RabbitMQ.
In here we will communicate to RabbitMQ using the publish endpoint.
But before that we will calculate the total price in here and set the event message total price.
And this is the our event message payload that we are going to publish using the publish endpoint and
masstransit to the RabbitMQ.
With this line of code, I am going to publish the basket checkout event to the RabbitMQ Message broker
and the publish operation complete successfully.
Just after that we will delete the basket from the basket microservices and this will be involving deleting
from database and deleting from the Redis distributed cache.
And this will be return back the response to the our client application.
And the response comes from the 200 okay.
And it is responding.
Is success true that indicating the whole operation completed successfully?
If you look at our architecture, we can say that our end to end process has started from the client
application with sending http post request to the basket microservices and basket microservices.
Publish the basket checkout event to the RabbitMQ message broker.
That means we should see our event in the message broker.
How we can see our events into message broker.
Of course we should check the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
If you go to localhost, the port number 15672 and login as a guest and guest.
You can see that we can get the information about the RabbitMQ queues and messages.
So in the overview you can see the we have get the message from the in here.
And if you look at the connections you can see the basket API connected to successfully into our RabbitMQ
message broker.
This is indicating the successful connections from the basket API.
And after that we can go to channels and we can see the channels from the basket API created.
But there is no consumer yet.
And we have open the channel from the RabbitMQ and basket microservices.
If you open the exchange we can see that exchange type created successfully.
In here we have created basket checkout event and integration event.
These are the exchange type.
When we are publishing these event to RabbitMQ from the basket microservices.
But there is no any queue because we have no binding from the any subscriber yet.
This is not consuming from the ordering microservice yet.
But the important thing that we will publish the basket checkout event that we can check the connections
from the basket API, and we can see the our channels and our messages that created into RabbitMQ message
broker.
So as you can see that we have successfully test basket checkout event in basket microservices.
And in the next step we will focus on how to consume from these event from the ordering microservices
and process the basket checkout event in the ordering microservices.