In this video we are going to test, subscribe and consume basket checkout event in the ordering microservices.
So that means we are at this point and we will consume these checkout event from the RabbitMQ to ordering
microservices.
And according to our deployment strategy, both basket and ordering microservices will be run locally
and interact with the RabbitMQ on the Docker environment as a backing services.
And if you look at the order creation flow here, you can see the end to end flow starting from the
basket microservices publish basket checkout integration event.
And we will handle these events into ordering microservices.
And in the ordering microservices we will create a new order.
And at this process we will raising order created domain event that will also handle in the ordering
application layer that will lead to integration layer.
And we will publish order created integration event in the handle of the domain event.
So this is the end to end process of the order creation in the ordering microservices.
When consuming these basket checkout event in order to perform order fulfillment operation and notify
the other microservices.
So please open the Visual Studio.
And I would like to start with putting breakpoints in the important points.
And here you can see the ordering application layer.
If you expand the ordering application layer you can see the orders feature folder.
And in here we will start with the event handlers and integration event handlers.
Here you can see the basket checkout event handler will be triggered when consuming event from the RabbitMQ.
If you put the breakpoint in the consume method, this will be hitting when consuming these event from
the RabbitMQ.
So in the consume operation we will again map to create order command to the command object and we will
send to mediator in order to trigger or create order command.
So also you can open the commands under the orders feature folder and see the command related use cases.
We will trigger the create order command operation in this line of code, and you can also put breakpoint
in the create order handler method that we have already.
Breakpoints existing in the handle method of the create order handler class.
In this method, we will create a new order, and whenever we create any order, this will be trigger
and raising order created domain event in the domain layer and this domain event also handled in the
ordering application layer which is under the event handlers.
And if you open the domain event handlers here you can see the order created event handler.
So whenever we create an order this will be hitting the order created event handler.
And you can also put breakpoint in the beginning of this handle method.
And in this method we basically logging the incoming information.
And we will check the feature is enabled or not.
And after that we will publishing additional integration event which is the order created integration
event.
So I'm going to put an additional breakpoint in the if statement that I am going to skip these if statement.
But at this point we have a concern when ordering microservices is start up it migrate and see the order
data that will create any order and publish these messages.
In order to avoid these operation, I am going to go to the ordering infrastructure and open the data
folder and go to extensions and open the database extensions.
You can put breakpoint in the seed orders with items, and I am going to put breakpoint in this if statement.
And I'm going to skip this order.
Create and seed operations in the beginning of the ordering microservices.
After that we can set up the are running profile in order to test our end to end use case, we should
run the microservices locally and this will be basket discount RPC and ordering microservices.
As you know that basket and discount gRPC microservices required to run together in order to depend
on each other when calculating a discount.
And now we are going to also consume these event from the RabbitMQ.
That's why we need to start ordering API additional with the basket and discount gRPC.
For that purpose, I am going to right click the solution and go to properties and select the Startup
Project and select the Multiple Startup project and see the basket and discount already started together.
And in here I'm going to select the ordering API and start the ordering API together with the basket
and discount microservices.
And click the apply button and click the okay button.
So now we are ready to perform our internal test.
Come to this point and click the start button in order to start our ordering basket and discount microservices
locally.
So by this way you can see that when I running this profile this is coming to add message worker.
If you open the call stack you can see that this comes from the ordering application.
And here you can see the ordering API and application has a dependency injection.
And we are adding message broker in this layer.
And we will also placing the assembly information.
So if you go back to our call stack and debugging our eight message broker extension, we can put the
breakpoint in the if statement.
And if I hit F5 this time, you can see that assembly information comes from the ordering application.
That means we are going to register our consumers in this line of code, and we will add consumers for
the ordering.
Sources.
I am hitting the F5 so add message blocker this time comes from the basket microservices.
Here you can see the basket microservices also adding mass transit registrations into dependency injection.
So in here we will again adding the mass transit.
But this time we don't have any assembly information because basket is only responsible for the publishing
event.
So I am hitting the F5 after performing the registrations.
It is come to the ordering microservices seeding operation and this time I am not going to see the orders
because this will be triggered, ordered domain event.
And in the handle of the domain event we will publish the additional integration event.
That's why I am going to skipping this point manually forwarding the debug point.
And after that I am hitting the F5 and we will skip the seeding order operations manually.
And after that we can confirm that from the R project console window basket, microservices is up and
ready and ready for the accepting our request and ordering microservices also up and ready.
And it is also connected.
Mass transit is the same as the basket microservices.
So now it is time to perform end to end use case by sending the http post request to the basket microservices.
And this will be consumed from the ordering microservices consuming from the RabbitMQ message broker.
So for that purpose please open the postman, go to the basket endpoints and go to the post basket operations
in order to create any order.
So here you can see the cart information including in the payload.
So I am going to send http post again for the newly created order.
And here you can see that we are going to hitting our store basket endpoint that we have already debugged.
In the last video, I am hitting F5 and continue and completing this process to deducting for discounted
operations and creating a new basket into basket database.
So here you can see that this operation is completed successfully and we have created a civilian username
into our basket microservices.
So now we have a basket.
And now we can check out this basket to convert these sales as a order.
For that purpose we can come to this point which is the Http post operations in the basket checkout
endpoint.
And this is the our actual payload that including the basket checkout DTO.
So I am going to hit the send button in order to trigger the basket checkout operations in the basket
microservices.
And this time I am going to hit F5 to publishing this basket checkout event into the this operation.
And here you can see that we will publish these operation into RabbitMQ and publish operation is completed
successfully.
And just after that the R consumer operations hitting into our breakpoint.
This is basket checkout event handled in the ordering application layer.
That means according to our slide, we have successfully publish the basket checkout event to RabbitMQ
and just after that ordering microservices already listening checkout event from the RabbitMQ and consuming
these event into handle method.
So if you go back to Visual Studio, you can see that this is the ordering application basket checkout
event handler.
So you can debugging these consumer operation.
And in this consumer operation we basically logging the incoming event.
And after that we will map to create order command and creating these incoming message to the create
order command in order to send to mediator for creating any order.
So after creating the command, we will send the mediator this command in order to trigger create order
command tender.
If I continue this debugging, you can see that this will be hitting the or create order handle method,
and this will be basically creating a new order using the Order Create domain method.
This will be also raising the order created domain event.
And after that we will again handle this event in the application layer.
So after that I am continuing this debugging.
And here you can see that we will create a new order.
And if I hit F5 you can see that it is execute operation and return a result.
But I understand that it is getting exception when we are creating a new order because we didn't hit
the order created domain event handler.
That means when creating any order, we get the exception.
So if you examine the logs, you can see that when creating any order with using the order dot create,
we will set the order name.
And when we are sending the and setting the order name, we will use order name value object of method.
And if you go to this method, you can see that we have two argument out of range exception.
And we are expecting that order name should be greater than default length, which is the five.
So in our case if you go back to our coding you can see the order name comes from the order detail.
And we will populate the order DTO when consuming the basket checkout event.
If you go to the event handler and integration event handler, you can see that when we are mapping
to create order command here you can see that order name coming from the incoming message username.
So.
If you go back to our postman and you can see the incoming event message, and if you check the username,
this is only three character that will not exist for the order name and default length is five and we
are sending the three length with the boolean username.
So in order to solve this exception and workaround, I am going to stop these applications and I am
going to comment it this argument out of range exception in the order namespace, which is located under
the ordering domain, layer value objects and order name.
Please comment this line of code in order to avoid this kind of exceptions, and I am going to save
this order name and restart the whole application, including the basket discount and ordering microservices.
So please hit the start button and we will perform end to end use case from the scratch.
When we are starting our applications.
This will be hitting the Add message broker.
And if I hit F5 this will be comes from the ordering microservices that including assembly information.
In order to add consumers and if I hit F5, this will be again calling the add message broker.
But this time this will be comes from the basket microservices that not including the assembly information
due to publish basket checkout event queue.
And I'm going to hit F5.
And in here you can see the ordering microservices.
Try to see the order information.
For now I am going to manually skipping this point by pressing this breakpoint under the De-seed operation
and hit F5.
So after that we are ready for the accepting requests and perform end to end use case.
I'm going to open the our postman and make sure that your application are started from the project console
window.
And in here we are again creating a new order with sending http post request in the slash basket and
point.
With this payload.
Hit the send button and this will be trigger our store basket and point class.
I am hitting F5 and hitting F5.
We will communicate and integrate with the get discount from the discount gRPC to calculate the latest
discount and creating the boolean username basket successfully.
Just after that we can go to the second http post operation in basket microservices, which is the post
basket checkout endpoint.
So I'm going to hit the send button.
This will be start our asynchronous communication.
First of all this will be hit our checkout basket endpoint.
And I am going to hit F5.
And this will be trigger the checkout basket command handle.
In this handle method we will perform the several operations which is the get existing basket with database.
And if basket is exist we will basically create event message which is the basket checkout DTO.
And we will publish these event messages with using publish endpoint to the RabbitMQ.
So I'm going to continue these operations and delete the basket.
And we will perform this delete operation.
Then just after that you can see that ordering microservices consume these event.
And this will be comes to the basket checkout event handler.
In the ordering application layer we can verify from the class from the ordering application orders,
event handlers and integration event handlers.
That means we will handle these integration event from the RabbitMQ.
And I'm going to continue the debugging.
And here you can see that since we are debugging the asynchronous communication, the debugging operation
is very hard to locate the correct location.
This is the different process.
But I am going to continue the hitting F10 and we will debug the our actual consume operation and map
to create orders command.
And this will be create an order DTO for us.
And we will send this order DTO to do our create operation in order to create order handle method.
So I'm going to come here and mediator send to this command in order to create a new order with using
the ordering application.
This comes from the Create Order handler class which is located in this location.
And we will create a new order with incoming order information.
Incoming order will be ordered DTO and we will create a new order using the Order Create function.
This time we will pass the argument validations.
So now you can see that we are commenting this section that we can accept or order name.
I'm going to continue debugging and if I hit F5, you can see that this time we will successfully come
to order create operation in the ordering domain layer.
And in here we will add a domain event which is the order created domain event.
And I'm going to hit F5.
And this will be dispatching the event whenever we are raising this event.
And this will be come to the point where we are located.
Order created event under.
If you look at the location, you can see that this time we will handle the domain event.
This is the domain event handler for the order created event.
So if you open the order architecture you can see that we are.
At this point we will create an order, an order creating and raising order created domain event.
And we are handling this domain event in the ordering application layer.
And we are going to expose and publish order integration event.
So if you go back to our debug point you can continue to log information.
And here you can see the order feature manager is looking for the order fulfillment feature.
And this feature is true.
That's why it is creating an order, creating integration event.
And we are again publishing the second integration event to the RabbitMQ which is the order created
integration event.
But this time there is no consumer.
That's why I am hitting F5 and complete this process.
Here you can see that we have completed successfully the end to end process of our order created operation.
So now we can verify the result.
For that purpose, I am going to open the postman and open the ordering microservice endpoints.
And here you can see that I am going to get orders with pagination.
In here I am going to retrieve the orders that we have created during the end to end process.
Hit the send button.
This will be triggered or get orders endpoint and I am hitting the F5 and get the result of the operation.
Here you can see the orders comes into the result page.
You can see the Http get response from the orders that including our newly created order comes from
the ordering microservice databases.
Also, we can verify asynchronous communication from the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
If you open the management dashboard, you can see the lots of events are publishing and consuming.
In the RabbitMQ dashboard that you can see the connections, channels and exchanges.
If you open the connections, you can see that this time we have two connections, one for the basket
microservices.
This is the publisher and another for the ordering microservices.
This is the consumer and subscriber.
And if you open the channels you can see that we have several channels that opening from the basket
and ordering microservices.
You can also exchange in here.
This time we have basket checkout and integration event.
And also we have additional channels that including the order consume operations for example order DTO.
So you can follow the queues and streams.
This time we can see the queues which including the basket checkout, event handler and error.
If you open the basket checkout event handler, you can see the interactions that publish and consume
these events from the basket and ordering microservices.