In this video, we are going to use ASP.Net Feature Management to removing and disabling these order
created integration event part into our end to end flow.
So that means we will set the order fulfillment feature as a false and we will expect to behave system
correctly without publishing integration event in the handle of the domain events.
Because we don't have any fulfillment subscriber microservices yet and RabbitMQ is not created queue
if there is no subscriber for that purpose.
Since fulfillment microservices is developed, it is good to set the flag false for the order fulfillment
message in order to avoid unnecessary queue messages.
So please open the Visual Studio and in here please go to the ordering API and go to the Application
Settings Json file.
As you can see that I have started the application which is started the ordering basket and discount
microservices that I am going to change the configuration on the flight when running the application.
So this is the power of the ASP.Net feature management.
I am going to change the feature of the order fulfillment from true to false.
So save this configuration file.
And if you open the ordering application event handlers and order created domain event handler, you
can see that we have a breakpoint that will not be entered.
The breakpoint due to our order fulfillment feature is false.
So now I am not going to skipping any breakpoint and I am going to continue with the F10 and we will
see that these if statement will not be entered.
So now I am going to perform the intent use case.
Please open the postman and go to the basket microservices and send the http post request in order to
create any basket.
So I am going to hit F5 to pacing these breakpoints when creating a new basket.
And here you can see that our basket created successfully.
Now I am going to perform asynchronous use case which is the basket checkout.
Please go to this http post operation and this endpoint and click the send button.
This will be hit the basket checkout operation and I am going to hit F5.
Since we will consume this basket checkout event from the RabbitMQ.
Here you can see the consume operation performed.
This is the ordering microservices consume operation.
Again I am hitting the F5 and this is go back to our basket microservices delete operation.
This will be continue to consume operation from the basket.
I am hitting the F5 since we are coming to domain event handler part.
So this is the order create operation and this is dispatching order create domain event.
And in here we can handle the order created domain event handler.
In here you can see the if statement comes to this point.
And I am going to hit F10.
So you can see that the feature is false.
And we can see that this feature is disabled when we are changing the application settings on the ordering
API, and the application has started before changing the configuration, that means this is powerful
feature from the ASP.Net feature management that we can change the behavior of the application on the
flight without changing any code.
So I am hitting the F5 and you can see the basket checkout Antoine process complete successfully.
And you can also check the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
And we don't have any integration event.
This is for the basket checkout event.
And we don't see any additional event for the order created.
Operations.