In this video we are going to containerize and configure basket and ordering microservices into docker
compose file for Multi-container docker environment Containerizing.
And configuring the basket and ordering microservices in a docker compose environment involves defining
the configuration in a docker-compose.yml file and the override file, which is the docker compose override
YAML file.
So here you can see that basket and ordering microservices using RabbitMQ as a backend services in Docker
environment.
But we are using the basket and ordering microservices locally.
So if you remember the our e-commerce microservices deployment strategy, you can see that so far we
have built the deployment one, which is the developing locally basket and ordering microservices that
connect to RabbitMQ message broker as a backend services in Docker environment.
So now it is time to orchestrate all microservices with Docker compose and test inside of the full Docker
environment.
Here you can see that we will go to deployment tool which is Docker compose all micro services and banking
services together.
So for that purpose we will check the Docker compose configuration for RabbitMQ basket and ordering
microservices.
So please open the Visual Studio.
Here you can see the our Docker compose file.
If you open the docker-compose.yml file we have already added the message docker image in here.
Also we have already containerized basket microservices in the docker-compose.yml file.
So after that, if you look at the docker compose original file, you can see the overriding configuration
in the message broker RabbitMQ, including the container name, hostname, environment, variables,
port numbers and so on.
And if you scroll down you can see the basket API override configurations when containerizing in Docker
environment.
So these are the environment variables, depends on ports and volumes.
So now we are going to configure basket API in order to communicate with the message broker in Docker
environment.
For that purpose I'm going to open the basket API.
And you can see that if you look at the application settings JSON file, there is a message broker settings
that we can override in the Docker compose override YAML file.
In order to communicate RabbitMQ in Docker network.
So here you can see the host address, username and password.
In host address.
We will choose the localhost for the connected server name from the local environment to the RabbitMQ
Docker environment, but this time basket microservices also include in Docker network.
For that purpose, instead of choosing the localhost, we should put the docker name of the RabbitMQ.
That means we should change the localhost and overwrite the acronyms with the hostname of the message
broker, which is the e-commerce dash MQ.
So that means we should override this message broker configurations in the docker compose.
Override YAML file for the basket microservices for that purpose.
Please open the docker compose or writing file and go to the basket API part.
And here you can see the environment variables that we are going to override for the message broker
settings.
So I'm going to come to this point.
And just after that I'm going to create a message broker settings which including the message broker
host username and password.
Here you can see that the message broker including these parameters.
And we can override these parameters in the basket API or writable configuration under the Docker compose
or write HTML file.
And the important configuration in here is a message broker hostname.
Here you can see that we will replace the localhost to the e-commerce MQ, which is the hostname of
the R message broker, and after that we will put the port number, which is the default port number
for the RabbitMQ.
By this way we can communicate basket and RabbitMQ microservices full docker environment.
So please make sure that you have added these environment variables under the basket API.
After that, we should not forget to add the Dependson for the message broker, because now basket API.
Also depending on the message broker container name and this will be also dependent from the basket
API.
I am going to add a message broker as it depends on the basket API.
So please add this line of code and also this line of code for overriding environment variables.
So we have completed the Docker configurations for the basket microservices.
Now it is time to configure our ordinary microservices to consume events from the RabbitMQ.
For that purpose, if you go back to and open the Visual Studio, and if you open the ordinary microservices,
and if you open the ordering API and open the application settings JSON file, here you can see that
the same message broker sections comes to the ordering API that we need to override in the docker compose
override YAML file.