In this video, we are going to containerize an orchestrate ordering microservices with Docker and Docker
compose.
So far, we didn't include ordering microservices into our Docker compose files.
For that reason, we should start to containerize and orchestrate ordering microservices with Docker
and Docker compose files, which is involving several steps.
Here you can see the steps in here.
This will be including creating a Docker file for ordering microservices and configuring it in the docker
compose file, and also overriding settings in docker compose or write HTML file.
So we will follow these steps for the ordering microservices from the scratch.
So please open the Visual Studio.
And we are going to start with Containerizing ordering microservices with Docker file.
And if you open the ordering microservices you can see that we have already created Docker file.
But this is auto generated by the Visual Studio when we are creating this application.
And this file defines how to ordering API container is built for that purpose.
I am going to re containerize with docker file for ordering microservices.
So please come to ordering API.
Right click the project file, add docker support and this will be Linux target operating system.
And we can overwrite existing Docker file with clicking yes button.
So here you can see that the Docker file is overriding again.
And this will be adding new copy blocks including the building blocks and ordering different layers
including the domain and infrastructure.
And these are the adding our newly created Docker file from the ordering API.
Docker file includes several steps, including the preparing the base image and building the application
with getting reference from the required dependencies and publishing the application.
And finally, we will create a final image to publish and running this ordering microservices in here.
The important thing that when we are containerizing ordering API, you can figure out that bullying
blocks and bullying blocks messaging class library added.
And also you can see clean architecture layers added according to our implementation of the ordering
API.
So this is important to containerizing ordering API to building ordering image with latest implementation.
So after containerizing ordering microservices, the second step is configure docker compose file.
If you open the docker-compose.yml file, you can see that we don't have ordering microservices and
docker file including in this docker-compose.yml file.
And this file defines how our containers are orchestrated.
And for ordering microservices, we didn't orchestrate yet, and we need to add a section similar to
Catalog Basket and discount microservices.
For that purpose, I am going to right click again the ordering API, and this time I am going to add
a container orchestrator support.
Here you can see that we can add a Docker support in the last time.
And now I'm going to click the Container Orchestrator support and select the docker compose and select
the target operating system as a Linux.
And click the okay button.
Here you can see that just after that the ordering microservices comes to our Docker compose Yaml file.
In this definition you can see the image which is defined the Docker image name for the ordering API.
And here you can see the build operations which is the build context and docker file path.
Specify where the Docker file for the ordering API is located.
After the definition of the docker-compose.yml file, we will go to the last step, which is the override
settings in the docker compose override HTML file.
For that purpose, I am going to open the docker compose override file, and if you scroll down, you
can see that ordering API related configurations generated from the Visual Studio when we are adding
the container orchestrator support.
But we need to modify these configurations according to our ordering microservice configurations.
For example, we need to modify the port numbers and adding the environment variables according to the
ordering API, application settings, Json file, and so on.
Let me start with the port numbers.
If you look at the port numbers in the slide, you can see that ordering microservices, exposing 5003
and 5053 for the local environment, and exposing 6003 and 6063 for the Docker environment.
So that means we will expose ordering microservice port numbers with starting to 60 numbers.
And if you go back to our configuration I'm going to modify the port numbers.
And here you can see that we will modify and exposing 880 and 881 ports with 6003 and 6063.
After defining the port numbers and mapping the port numbers, we can go to environment variables.
When we are setting the environment variables, we should check the ordering API application settings
file.
If you open the ordering API application settings file, we need to overwrite all these custom configurations
under the environment.
Variables on the docker compose override HTML file.
That means we will set the.
Next in string database, message worker settings, feature management, and so on.
And whenever we are settings and overriding these configurations, we should change the server name
from the local Los to the local name for database.
We will change these local Los to order DB, and for message worker we will change these local Los to
e-commerce MQ.
And just after that we should also override feature management and order fulfillment when overriding
environment variables.
So you can see these configurations.
I'm going to override these configurations under docker compose override HTML file and ordering API
section.
So here you can see the environment variables.
I'm going to modify all the environment variables according to our architecture.
Here you can see that we will override environment variables with the connection settings.
And put two double underscore and database connection settings.
Here you can see the server name as order db database.
Also order db user id sa and password is the boolean 1 to 8.
You can see in here and incorrect, false and trusted certificate is true.
And just after that you can see the message broker settings.
According to message broker settings, we can set that the hostname as Amqp and message broker name
and the port number and username, guest and password guest and feature management for the order file.
Movement is false.
So the important thing is again the server names we set the order DB which is the SQL server database
container name that you can verify from the beginning of this file.
The order name container name as the order name that we can connect and communicate from our ordering
microservices to order database.
And also we will communicate with the message broker from the ordering microservices.
For that purpose, I'm going to edit Dependson sections under the environment in order to dependent
for the ordering microservices to the different services, including the order db and Message Broker.
So please save this file and make the configurations ordering API in this way.
By this way, we have completed the container rising and orchestrating microservices with Docker and
Docker Compose that ensure services can run in environment like production.