In this video we are going to test our deployment tool, which is the Docker compose all microservices
and backing services.
So we will run our application on Docker environment with Docker compose and test all microservices,
including the backing services in Docker network.
So we will perform and testing, publish and subscribe basket checkout event using the mass transit
between basket and ordering microservices in a Docker compose environment.
So please open the Visual Studio and open the our application solution which is the microservices.
So one of the best features of the Visual Studio is using the Docker compose running profile in your
application.
This is one of the elegant feature from the Visual Studio that we can debug our microservices with running
Docker compose profile in the Docker environment.
But before that I am going to prepare the environment.
You can right click the docker compose and select the properties that you can select the launch actions
for each microservices.
Here you can see the basket API do nothing.
When we are running Docker compose, you can change other microservices and set launch actions as a
do nothing Catholic microservices discount, gRPC and ordering API do not apply.
And okay, this is docker compose running profile.
So now I am going to right click the docker compose and set a startup project.
As you can see that when we are using the VGG studio, it is very easy to configure the Docker compose
launch settings to start necessary microservices.
Here you can see the docker compose running profile come to our Visual Studio, but if you are not using
Visual Studio, you can start Docker Compose manually.
Here you can see that if you go to the docker compose Yaml file location and run the docker compose
up command with specifying the docker compose and override Yaml file, you can start the necessary microservices
manually, but I would like to use Visual Studio tooling when running the docker compose in docker environment.
For that purpose, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running.
Here you can see that we have started Docker Compose before we are running our application.
But now I will again start Docker Compose, including the our newly develop authentic microservices
with communicating the RabbitMQ basket and discount microservices.
In order to start our Docker compose profile, you can come to this point and this time I am not going
to debug our operation.
That's why I will choose the next button, which is the start without debugging for Docker compose and
click this button.
This will be start docker compose up command on behind of the scenes and start microservices, including
the ordering microservices fully Docker network with connecting as a backing services like RabbitMQ
and order DB as a SQL server.
So this will take some time to spin up the microservices for the first time.
And we will see authentic microservices, including our Docker compose running profile.
After waiting a certain of time, you can see that our microservices is up and running on Docker network,
and you can watch the output window.
In order to understand authentic microservices started successfully.
You can also verify from the Docker desktop if you open the Docker desktop and see the Docker compose
running containers.
Here you can see the ordering API comes to the picture, and if you open this container, you can see
the logs that will start with seeding and migrating database and inserting new data.
When starting ordering microservices here you can see the insert into commands, which is the seeding
operation.
And at the end of these logs you can see that ordering microservices successfully connected backing
services as a RabbitMQ message broker.
So now we can start our testing.
But before start testing our intent use case I would like to verify the ordering DB.
If you come here and open the SQL Server Object Explorer and connect the localhost for the SQL server
database order db.
Open the database.
Here you can see the order db is created successfully, and if you open the an Expanding Tables and
right click the orders view data, you can see that we have two seeded data when ordering application
is starting successfully.
So I'm going to delete these rows in order to understand how we can insert any order when we are performing
end to end use case for publish subscribe basket checkout event.
So please delete these rows and we can see and verify how we can insert any record in the order table.
And after that we can start our intent use case.
We can start by verifying the container health checks.
Please open the our postman and if you open the postman you can come to the basket.
And please get the health of the basket.
Microservices with sending Http get requests to the health endpoint.
But before that of course we should change the environment localhost to Docker, because now we are
running full docker environment.
In order to send Http request, we should change the environment as a docker and you can verify the
basket URL is starting 60.
So after that you can send http get request to the health of the basket and verify that basket.
Microservices is healthy and under the entries you can see that basket microservices successfully connected
RabbitMQ.
You can see the mass transit entry.
And if you scroll down you can see the successfully connecting PostgreSQL database and Redis distributed
cache.
And at the same way I am going to following the ordering microservices health status.
If you go to the ordering and health endpoint, you can also see that the ordering URL is starting with
the 60.
That means Docker environment and this is the end point.
Slash health and send http get request to ordering microservices and verify that ordering is also healthy.
And as the entries, you can see that we have successfully connected RabbitMQ from the ordering microservices
and successfully connected SQL server from the ordering microservices.
That means it is time to perform end to end use case.
So we will start by creating a new basket into our application, and after that we will send http post
request for the checkout basket in the basket microservices that will publish the basket checkout event
to RabbitMQ and consume from the ordering, microservices and ordering microservices will be create
a new order record under the SQL server database.
So please open the our postman and go back to basket Microservices Http request and go to the Http post
request to store basket that we will create a new basket with this payload.
I'm going to hit the Http send button.
This will be send http post request and return back to us a created any username basket.
As you can see that we didn't debug this process and this is fully running on the environment we have
started without debugging on our Docker compose profile using the Visual Studio.
That's why this will be performed successfully and created a username and basket into our basket microservices.
Just after that we can check out the basket into our application.
That means we will send another http post request to initiate the checkout process.
Please come to this post request for the basket checkout endpoint.
And here you can see the our payload for the basket checkout DTO.
And after that I am going to hit the Http send button.
In order to send http post request to basket checkout.
This will be start asynchronous communication with organic microservices using RabbitMQ.
Here you can see the response back to the success.
That means the asynchronous communication is started successfully.
We can verify from the RabbitMQ dashboard.
If you open the RabbitMQ dashboard and connect to username guest and password guest, you can see that
we have hitting the new event into RabbitMQ message broker that will consume by the ordering microservices.
And this is the basket checkout event that you can confirm from the queues and streams.
This is the basket checkout event handler.
And this will be hitting one record in the five minutes before.
And that consumed from the ordering microservices.
You can check the connections and channels which is consuming from the ordering API comes to the channels
in the RabbitMQ dashboard.
So that means this event consumed from the ordering microservices that we can confirm the newly created
order from the postman.
If you open the postman and go to ordering microservices, and if you get orders with pagination, you
can send Http get request and you can get the one record which is newly inserted item from the consuming
the Basket checkout event.
You can see the order name, shipping address, billing address, and so on.
And this is only one record into our orders table.
You can also verify from the R SQL server.
And here you can see the SQL Server Object Explorer under the R Visual Studio.
If I refresh this page, you can see that newly created orders comes to the picture when consuming the
basket checkout event.
That means we have successfully publish and subscribe basket checkout event and consume from the ordering
microservices.
So now I am going to stop docker compose profile and this time we will testing with debugging.
So that means we will rerun the docker compose environment with debugging enabled to step through the
Rbac points.
So here you can see that this time you can click the Docker compose run profile.
That will start docker compose up command on behind of the scenes.
But this time we will debug our microservices.
Here you can see the our microservices is started successfully.
Now I am going to open the our Visual Studio.
Here you can see that the order seed operations come to the our breakpoint.
And I am hitting F5 and verify that every microservices is up and running under our Docker compose network.
And you can open the ordering API and see that ordering API also started successfully with seeding and
migrating data.
That means we can perform our internet use case using the postman.
If you open the postman and go to the basket post store basket.
If you hit the send button this time, you can see that we can debug incoming event from our Visual
Studio fully docker environment.
That means I am debugging now from the Docker network and docker containers in the basket microservices.
So I am hitting F5 and creating a new basket in to do our application.
And this will be communicating with the discount gRPC microservices in order to get latest discount
and calculating the price here you can see that our basket is created successfully.
And again I am going to check out this basket from the basket microservices that will start event driven
communication.
And we will accumulate checkout basket event endpoints.
And here you can see that we will adapt and send the mediator.
This will be triggered the checkout basket command handler.
And in this method we basically get the existing basket.
And after that we will publish the basket checkout event to RabbitMQ and delete the basket.
And here you can see that we have started the event driven communication.
And this will be consumed from the ordering microservices that will basically perform these operations
with clicking F10.
Step into these two processes at the same time.
You can see that we have created a new order DTO in order to send this command to the mediator and this
will be handled create order handle method.
This will be create a new order and whenever we are creating any order, this comes from the ordering
domain and raising order created domain event.
And this will be also consumed by the ordering application layer.
Here you can see the intercepting and dispatching to domain events that will handle in the order created
event handler.
We are going to logging the information and we are looking to our feature which is the order fulfillment.
And according to our Docker compose override environment variables, we will set the order fulfillment
feature as a false.
That's why it is not entering this if statement.
And I am hitting the F5 and completed the process.
You can also verify the newly created order from the SQL Server Object Explorer.
If you right click and view data and refresh this page, you can see that we have created new data in
here.
As you can see that we have successfully tested basket checkout event for event driven asynchronous
communication.
Applying the publish subscribe design pattern.