In this video we are going to learn microservice communication types, which are the synchronous and
asynchronous communications.
Client and services communicate with each other with many different types of communications.
Mainly those types of communications can be classified by two axis synchronous and asynchronous communication.
What is synchronous communication?
Basically, we can say that synchronous communication is using Http or gRPC protocol for returning synchronous
response.
The client sent the request and waits for a response from the service.
So that means the client code blocked their thread until the response reached from the server.
The synchronous communication protocols can be used Http or Https.
In synchronous communication, the client sends a request with using Http protocols and waits for a
response from the service.
So that means the client call the server and block client data operations.
The client code will continue its task when it receives the Http server response.
So this is the important topic that client block their code when synchronous to calling and after receiving
an Http server response, it continue their task.
So this operation called synchronous communication, it has advantages and disadvantages that we would
consider when we pick this way.
But now I am going to continue to what is asynchronous communication in microservices.
Another communication type is asynchronous communication.
So what is asynchronous communication.
Basically in asynchronous communication the client send the request but it doesn't wait for a response
from the service.
So the key point here is that the client should not have blocked a thread while waiting for a response.
The most popular protocol for these asynchronous communication is Amqp, which is the Advanced Messaging
Queue protocol.
So with using Amqp protocols, the client sent the message with using message broker systems like Kafka
and RabbitMQ.
The message producer usually doesn't wait for a response.
This message consumed from the subscriber systems in asynchronous way and no one waiting for response
suddenly.