In this video we are going to learn microservices, synchronous communication and best practices.
As we said before, in synchronous communication, the client sends a request with using Http protocols
and waits for a response from the service.
So the synchronous communication protocols can be mainly Http or Https.
You can also see the image that represents Microsoft Sync communication client application called microservices
and microservices.
Return response by visiting several internal microservices using the Http and gRPC protocol.
For synchronous communication, we understood that we should follow request response communication model
with Http and Rest protocols, and we can extend this gRPC and GraphQL.
So under these synchronous communication model we can also divide by four.
The first one is Rest Http APIs when exposing from microservices.
The second one is gRPC APIs when communicate internal microservices.
The third one is GraphQL API when structured flexible data in microservices, and the last one is WebSocket
APIs when real time bidirectional communication.