In this video, we are going to learn gRPC for high performance remote procedure calls.
gRPC is an open source remote procedure call system initially developed at Google.
gRPC is a framework to efficiently connect services and build distributed systems.
It is focused on high performance and uses the Http two protocol to transport binary messages.
It relies on the protocol buffer language to define service contracts.
Protocol buffers, also known as protobuf, allows you to define the interface to be used in service
to service communication regardless of the programming language.
It generates cross-platform client and server bindings for many languages.
Most common usage scenarios include connecting services in microservices style architecture and connect
mobile devices browser clients to backend services.
So the gRPC framework allows developers to create services that can communicate with each other efficiently
and independently from their preferred programming language.
Once you define a contract with protobuf, this contract can be used by each service to automatically
generate the code that can sets up the communication infrastructure.
This feature simplifies the creation of the service interactions and together with high performance,
makes gRPC the ideal framework for creating microservices and communicating between inter service communications.