In this video, we are going to learn how gRPC works.
A RPC is a form of client server communication that uses a function called, rather than usual Http
call.
So in gRPC, a client application can directly call a method on a server application on a different
machine like it is a local object, it making it easy for you to build distributed applications and
services.
As with many RPC systems, gRPC is based on the idea of defining a service that specifies methods,
and these can be called remotely with their parameters and return types.
On the server side, the server implements this interface and runs a gRPC server to handle client calls.
On the client side, the client has a setup that provides the same methods as the server.
gRPC client and servers can work and talk to each other in a different of environments, from servers
to your own desktop applications, and that can be written in any language that gRPC supports.