In this video, we are going to see an example of gRPC usage in microservice communications.
Think about that.
We have a shopping cart microservices that expose ad item into shopping cart RESTful http API to the
client application.
This shopping cart.
Microservices receives a single request from a client and dispatch it to various microservices.
Aggregate the results and send them back to the requesting client application.
Such operations typically require synchronous communication as to produce an immediate response.
In this example, backend calls from the shopping cart microservices are performed using the gRPC.
gRPC communication requires both client and server components.
You can see the image that shopping cart microservices implements gRPC client.
The client makes synchronous gRPC call to the backend microservices.
This backend microservices are implemented as a gRPC server.
In our case, backend microservices are product and discount microservices.
Shopping cart refers to product detail information and also latest discount information before adding
item into cart.
As you can see that the gRPC endpoints must be configured for the Http two protocol that is required
for the gRPC communication.
In microservices world, most of the communication uses asynchronous communication patterns, but some
operations require direct calls for the immediate response.
gRPC should be the primary choice for direct synchronous communication between backend microservices.
It is high performance communication protocol based on Http two, and protocol buffers make it a perfect
choice.