In this section we are going to develop shopping web application microservices with rapid Http client
factory library.
And this application will be the client application for our reference application architecture.
Here you can see the big picture that we are going to develop one by one.
As you can see that we are at this point and we will start the building shopping, web application,
microservices.
And this will be the ASP.Net web application razor page and the bootstrap for Tema.
And here you can see the internal architecture of the shopping web client application with refit.
Basically this application will be interact with the our backend microservices through the IRB API gateway
using the Refit and Http client factory.
And we are going to cover web UI shopping microservice application.
And we will build presentation layer.
And this will be the ASP.Net application razor page with the Bootstrap Fatima implementation using the
ASP.Net Run Basics repository.
And we will use ASP.Net Core Razor tools including the web components, partial weaves, tag helpers,
model building, and so on.
So we will start with creating catalog basket ordering models for shopping web application in order
to consume irb API gateway endpoints using the Revit library, which generated Http client factories
and refit client factory library includes automatic type saved rest library and we can create generated
clients using the Refit library and we will also develop a catalog service, AI Basket Service and AI
ordering service interface with the refit library for Http client factory libraries, and we will develop
index card product detail checkout and ordered HTML and see pages to consume IRB, API gateway and trains
with using the AI service interfaces into the IRB page with the ASP.Net application.
And lastly, we will containerize and orchestrate shopping web application in our Docker compose environment.
So now let me explain the steps of developing shopping web client application.
The first step is web UI shopping web application microservices.
And we will create ASP.Net web application using the razor page.
And this application will be using the ASP dotnet run basics repository as a starting point.
And this application styled by using bootstrap four.
And also we will utilize ASP.Net core razor tools including the web components, partial waves, tech
helpers, and so on.
And the second step is creating of the data models.
We will define the models for the catalog basket and ordering that will represent the data structures
used within the shopping web application.
And after that we will consume the ERP API gateway.
That means these models will be used to interact with the ERP API gateway endpoints.
And the third step we will implement refit Http client factory library.
So we will use refit library which is an automatic type saved rest library in order to create generated
clients.
This will simplify the consuming Rest APIs by abstracting Http calls into a simple interface, and we
will generate clients with Refit, developing the catalog service, AI basket service and AI ordering
service interfaces with Refit, and we will leveraging the Http client factory for efficient Http communications.
And in the fourth step, we will develop the razor page and we will create various pages such as the
index card, product detail checkout and order HTML page with the C sharp files, and each C sharp page
model will consume the ERP API gateway endpoints using the services like catalog service implemented
with the Refit and Http client factory.
And the last step, we can say that containerization and orchestration.
We will containerize the shopping web application and orchestrate it within the Docker compose environment.