In this video we are going to learn the background of the project.
So we said that we will develop shopping web client application and we will develop this application
as a ASP.Net web application razor page and bootstrap four.
And this will be include ASP.Net core razor tools.
And this will be consume job API gateway endpoint using the Revit library into our shopping web client
microservice application.
And when we are developing this application, we will use base repository of the shopping web application.
That means we will develop this application based on these GitHub repository.
Here you can see the GitHub address.
And we are going to use these base repository for shopping application.
And this will be the ASP.Net Run Basics repository that you can find on GitHub.
And this application has implemented monolithic architecture with using the ASP.Net Core and Entity
Framework core.
So we will convert this application for consuming the Erb API gateway and converting the page consuming
according to our ERP API gateway.
So let's check this GitHub repository.
If you open this link, you can reach the point where we have developing ASP.Net run repositories.
If you open the ASP.Net run repositories, you can see that this will be included as several repositories
to leverage your ASP.Net skills, including the microservices, Identity Server, DevOps, gRPC, and
so on.
So now we will focus on the run ASP.Net Core Basics repository in order to convert this application
to our shopping web client.
Microservice application.
If you open this link, you can scroll down.
You can see the as an example of the these e-commerce application that we are going to use this template
which including the bootstrap four and other details.
And if you scroll down, you can see that this is only one solution that means monolithic application.
And we are choosing the ASP.Net Core and Entity Framework core and also using the razor page, middle
phase dependency injection and so on.
So we will convert this application to consume our ERP API gateway.
If you open this application folder you can see that these will be including the pages.
These are the shopping cart checkout, confirmation error index order and so on.
So I am going to convert these application with consuming from the ERP API gateway instead of using
the repositories and databases.
So you can examine the details of this repository.
We are going to clone this repository and convert these pages to our according to our microservice architectures.