In this video we are going to do domain analysis of the shopping web microservices.
This will be include domain models, application use cases, presentation layer and underlying data
structures.
So let's start with the domain analysis of the shopping web microservices.
We have only three main domain model per microservices.
These will be include catalog basket and ordering domain model.
And we will create sub domain models per microservices.
And we will go to Andpoint classes and use response object of the microservices.
For example, for catalog we will use product Getproduct response and get product by id response.
For basket we will get the and create the shopping cart, shopping cart item basket checkout models
for ordering.
We can create order DTO, order item, DTO and value objects and so on.
So the next thing we can check application use cases of the shopping web microservices.
We should define our shopping web use cases.
And our main use cases are listing products and categories.
Add product into shopping cart and checkout the shopping cart and create order.
So we will use Erb API gateway endpoints in order to perform these use cases.
These will be including the Http Get to Catalog Service products.
And after that we will create a new basket with Http post request to basket service basket.
And after that we will check out this basket with sending http post request to these endpoint.
And lastly, we can get the orders with ordering service slash orders with sending Http.
Get request to ordering microservices over the Erb API gateway endpoints.
And after that we can check the presentation layer for the Shopping Web client application.
As a presentation layer, we will use ASP.Net Web Application Razor page and this will be includes index,
product list, product detail, cart checkout, confirmation order list, contact error and privacy,
CSS, HTML files to representing our client application and presentation layers.
And just after that, we can check the underlying data structure of the shopping web.
As a shopping fact, we have no any data store and no any underlying data structure because this page
are consumed.
Erb API gateway endpoints using the Revit library, which generated Http client factories in order to
perform its use cases.