In this video we are going to do technical analysis of shopping web microservices.
This will include application architecture, analyzing pattern and principles libraries, NuGet packages
and project folder structure.
So let me start with the application architecture style.
As an application architecture style, we will use traditional and layered architecture that will include
presentation layer which is the CSS, HTML, razor, web page and business layer which is the services
classes that calls Erb, API gateway and Data layer, which basically Erb API gateway calls to downstream
microservices with using models folder.
And just after that, we can examine the pattern and principles that we are going to use.
We will use Typesafe raised Http client factory Implementation service Proxy pattern, and ASP.Net razor
pages.
And just after that we can examine libraries and NuGet packages as a NuGet package.
We will use refit Http client factory and this will be provide generated clients for efficient Http
communications.
After that we can examine the project folder structure.
And here you can see the our project folder structure including the presentation model and services
folder.
So as you can see that in the presentation folder we have pages and root folder.
You can see in here this will be representing our presentation layer page folder and WW root folder.
And after that you can see the models folder including the catalog basket and ordering data models.
These will be staying under the models folder.
And lastly we have services folder including the catalog basket and I ordering service interfaces to
communicate and interact with the internal downstream microservices over the AAP API gateway.
And this will be located under the services folder.
So this is the our shopping page client application.
And if you look at these picture you can see the full folder structure with expanded folders.
According to this picture you can see the shopping web client application and we have modules folder
including the catalog basket and ordering domain models and data models.
And we have also pages folder including our cart checkout, confirmation, contact index, order list,
product detail and product list page that represent our E-shop and e-commerce client application page.
And here you can see the services folder, including the Eye Basket Catalog and Eye Ordering service
folder that represents an interact with the ERP API gateway in order to perform end to end use case
and expanding data into our pages.
And lastly, we can check the deployment of the shopping web client application.
According to deployment, we can say that we will containerize our servers with Docker and ensuring
deployment and integration with the shopping web client application.
And we will implement Docker file and docker compose file for running shopping web client application
in fully docker environment.