In this video, we are going to start developing shopping web client application into our microservice
solution.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the solution of the microservices.
So first of all, I'm going to create a naive solution folder under the our solution because we are
going to develop client application in a separate folder.
For that purpose please right click the solution add new solution folder and give the name as a web
apps.
By this way, we can encapsulate all client applications under the Web Apps folder, but this folder
is a solution folder that need to required creating a real folder.
For that purpose, I am going to create a new folder when creating a new client application project.
So now let's create a new project.
I'm going to right click this folder Add New Project and this time we will use ASP.Net Core Web app
razor page.
Here you can see the template of the R project ASP.Net Core Web Application razor page.
If you double click this template, you can see the project name and location configurations.
I'm going to give the project name as a shopping dot web.
And location is important because we are going to select the source folder first of all.
And after that we are going to add a Web Apps solution folder in order to create a new folder under
this web apps and under the web apps, we are going to create shopping dot web client application as
a ASP.Net core Web Application razor page.
So please make sure that your project name and location is correct.
After that, you can click the next button and you can configure our ASP.Net web application.
I'm going to set a framework.
Net eight authentication type none, configure Https, enable Docker and Docker operating system as
a Linux.
So I am leaving as it is for all configurations and click the create button.
And this will be create our first client application which is a soap shopping web application.
So you are going to right click and open File Location and verify that this is created under the source
Web Applications and Shopping Web under source.
We have web application services, building blocks and API gateways as the same with the solution view.
So we have created shopping web client application under the web application folder.
And now we are going to examine our ASP.Net Core Web Application razor page under the our solution.
First of all I would like to show you there is a page and WW root folder created due to our template
project template which is the ASP.Net Core Razor template.
And here you can see the pages including the index error.
And these are the default pages.
And under the page we have a subfolder which is a shared that is containing layout and validation script.
Partial says HTML files.
So under the root you can find Ccjs and library folders for the client side page.
And after that you can see that except this file this is typical ASP.Net web application that you can
see the Program.cs application settings Json file and so on.
So if you open the program says, you can see that there is a difference comes from the adding the razor
page into ASP.Net building dependency injection container.
Because we have selected the project template of the razor template, and after building the application,
there is some configured Http request pipelines which including the use http redirections static files,
routing authorization and map the razor pages.
And by this way, this application is become a razor web application and client web application.
If you look at the application settings Json file, this will be the include all configurations for
the client applications.
So now I am going to set the port numbers for the shopping web client applications.
But before that, let's check the port numbers into our slide.
Here you can see that we have created shopping web client application.
And in the local environment this will be expose 5005 for the Http port and 5055 for the Https port.
But in the Docker environment we will expose 6005 for Http 6065 for https ports.
So now we are going to set local environment port numbers with these port number values.
Please open the Visual Studio and open the Shopping Web application.
If you open the properties and open the Launch Settings Json file, you can see the Http and https ports.
So now I am going to modify the application URLs for Http.
We need to set the 5005.
And just after that if you go to https profile you can see that we have again http port number which
is 5005.
And for https port numbers we need to set 5055 and save this file.
By this way we can run our application into our port mappings.
And this time we will set launch browser as a true.
Since this is the client application, we need to see client application into our browser.
For that purpose, I'm going to right click the shopping web application set a startup project and.
After that you can change the the zoning profile docker to https and click this button in order to run
https mode or shopping with client application.
So this will be start our client application and you can verify that this time we will open a browser
and locating the index page.
Here you can see the localhost 5055.
And this is the https port.
And here you can see the our index page of the ASP.Net razor web application.
You can find these page details under the page and index.
This is our HTML of the first page.
And you can see the first page.
See files under the index page.
Also, you can check the project console log that is similar with the other microservices, exposing
our ASP.Net web application into Http and Https ports.
As you can see that we have successfully created and running shopping web client applications under
our solution.