In this video we are going to create models folder for shopping web application microservice to consume
irb API gateway endpoints.
So let's remember our main use cases.
These are the listing products and categories.
Add product to shopping cart and checkout basket and create order.
These are the main use cases that can trigger from the are client side page, and we will use irb API
gateway endpoints and consume these endpoints with following these http, get and post methods.
So when we are sending these http get and post methods, we need to store incoming and outgoing messages
into our models, folder and domain models.
For that purpose, I'm going to create three domain model.
Here you can find the our domain models including the catalog basket and ordering.
And as a sub domain model we can say product get product response get product ID response basket shopping
cart, shopping cart, item basket, checkout, ordering order item address, payment, get order response,
so on.
So we will create these domain models into our application.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And first of all we are going to create models folder.
Right click the Shopping Web application and add a new folder.
Which name is models.
Inside of the models folder we will encapsulate domain models for the shopping, web application and
models folder should match the responses of the IRB API gateway endpoints and the internal microservices
endpoint responses.
So let me explain and give an example.
For example, when we are send http get request to product and catalog related page, this will be go
to the irb api gateway and irb API gateway will be redirect to this request to the downstream microservices
and specifically catalog microservices.
So we can go to catalog microservices.
And if you open the products vertical slice feature folder, and if you go to the Get Products folder,
and if you open the Get Products endpoint, and this will be hit the get products and paint with according
to request and response object.
That means when we are sending Http get request from our catalog and product page in the client application,
this will be goes to irb API gateway and this will be triggered to get products endpoint class with
sending the get product request and response back to the get products response.
So that means we are analyzing response of all microservices and the endpoints.
For that reason, we will check all endpoint classes and in our case we will create get product response
model with including the IEnumerable product model when responding to our shopping client web application.
So here you can see that I have created a required use case and domain models.
Here you can see that this is for the get products endpoint.
When we are retrieving product into our client application, we need data models according to request
and response object.
And we need as a product model.
And here you can see that we can also filter by category into our client application.
For that reason we need a request and response object including again IEnumerable product model.
And here you can see that we can open a single product into our product detail page, into client application
that need to request and response object, including a single product model.
For that reason, we should create all these wrapper requests and response object with the same format.
And here you can see that we will create product model and we will create get product request.
And we will not include the page number and size load from the query parameters.
But we need at least create a wrapper classes for the product model in order to get response from the
client application and Erb API gateway.
And here you can see the our additional domain models that we are going to create according to our use
cases.
So let's get started.
So if you go back to our actual project which is a shopping web, and go to the models folder, I'm
going to create a subfolder under the models add new subfolder, which name is catalog.
So we are going to create domain models according to microservices.
First of all I'm going to create product model under the catalog sub folder.
Add a new class which name is product model dot CSS.
And in this model class I'm going to create a product model which is belonging to parameters and members
in the product entity class.
Here you can see the guild id string, name list, string category, string, description, string,
image file and decimal price.
This is typical product entity when we are developing catalog microservices and at the same format,
I have created product model under the our shopping web client application.
And just after that we can create record types for the wrapper classes in order to accommodate incoming
and outgoing requests to our API gateway and catalog microservices.
Here you can see our wrapper classes get products response, including the IEnumerable product model
which is the products, and this is the get products by category response, including the IEnumerable
product model.
Which name is products?
And this is the last record type, which is a get products by ID response, including a single product
model which is name is product.
So these are the comes from the Our services catalog micro services and the product endpoints.
You can check the get products endpoint response.
And here you can see the get product by ID endpoint.
And this is the our response.
And here you can see the get product by category.
And here you can see the our get product category endpoint response.
And we will simulate all these data model under the our client application under the models catalog
and product model CSV file.
By this way we can capable to accommodate incoming requests from the response of the Erb API gateway
and populate the data inside of the our domain models into the catalog.
As you can see that we have created catalog domain models.
In the next video, we will continue basket and ordering data models.