In this video, we are going to develop basket domain models for shopping web application.
And these will be consumed Erb API gateway and points for the basket checkout and get basket use cases.
Here you can see the basket.
And these are the basket sub domain models that we are going to create in this video.
For that purpose please open the Visual Studio.
And before we start we should go to check for the microservice of the basket.
Here you can see that we will create a basket sub folder in order to create domain models.
But before that let's understand our use cases and creating domain models in the shopping web because
shopping web application will be consumed basket microservice APIs over the AAP API gateway.
If you open the basket API, you can go to the basket folder which is the feature folder.
And here you can see the our endpoints.
And these are the use cases that we can define our endpoint and the handler class.
If you open the gate basket and get basket and print, you can see that we will interested into our
request and response object that we are going to create data models for these types.
So these will be the our wrapper classes and record types.
And these will be the our actual domain model classes which means shopping cart domain model.
And if you go to shopping cart you can see that these will be stored under the models.
These will be including the shopping cart item.
That means we are going to create shopping cart model and shopping cart item model into our shopping
web application.
And this is only for the get basket use case.
If you look at the our other use cases, for example store basket.
In order to create any basket, we should send http post request to this endpoint.
Here you can see the request and response object request object again, recording the shopping cart
model and response object requiring the username string parameter.
And as the same way we can check the checkout basket and checkout basket endpoint is requiring to request
and response object.
In the request object, we need basket checkout model and the name of the parameter basket checkout
DTO.
And in the response we have a boolean is success parameter.
So you can also check the delete basket endpoint and understand that we will create this kind of wrapper
classes.
And these kind of are actual data models for the basket API in the shopping cart model.
For that purpose, I have analyzing which domain models that we are going to create.
During this video here you can see that first of all, we need shopping cart model and shopping cart
item model in order to model the our shopping cart entities.
And we need also basket checkout model.
These are the base models that we are going to use these models into our endpoints.
Wrapper record types.
Here you can see the get basket use case get basket response requiring the shopping cart model.
Here you can see the store basket use case in the request.
We will facing the shopping cart model.
And in the response we will passing the username.
And here you can see the checkout basket use case and index.
We are passing the basket checkout model as the name of the basket checkout DTO and basket checkout
response is getting the success.
And lastly we can define delete basket response with a boolean is success.
So now let's create these domain models and develop our basket domain models into our shopping web client
application.
If you scroll down you can go to the our actual operation.
But before that let me close this basket and focus on the shopping web client application.
So go to models folder and I am going to right click and add a new subfolder.
Which name is basket.
Because we will create basket related domain models.
And our first domain model is shopping cart model.
So for that reason I'm going to create a new class shopping cart model dot CSS.
So in this class we will define shopping cart related operations including the shopping cart item.
And here you can see the shopping cart model and shopping cart item model.
This will be exactly same with the models under the basket.
Microservices including the username items and total price and items required, and the shopping cart
item model.
And this will be include quantity, color, price, product ID and product name.
So please save this class and develop these two shopping cart model and shopping cart item model for
the basket.
Microservices.
After developing base domain model classes, we can define the wrapper classes that represent our use
cases.
For the shopping cart use case, we need to adding use case for get basket, store basket and delete
basket.
For that purpose.
I'm going to come at the end of this class and writing the wrapper classes, including the public record,
get basket response and getting and taking parameter as a shopping cart model, which the parameter
name as a cart.
So this is the representing our get basket use cases.
And here you can see that we have store basket use cases including the request record type request record
type taking shopping cart model which name is cart as a parameter.
And in the response you can see the string username.
And lastly we have a delete basket response use case.
For that purpose, we will define additional public record type for the delete basket response.
And as a parameter it is taking Boolean is success.
So these are the.
Or get stored and delete basket use cases over the basket API and defining shopping cart model and shopping
cart item model.
In order to perform these use cases over the ERP, API gateway services into the basket microservices.
But we have additional endpoints and use cases.
If you expand the basket, you can see that we have also checkout basket use cases that we need to also
define the data models under the shopping web application.
To perform this use case.
For that purpose, I am going to create additional class under the basket folder, which name is basket
checkout model X.
So in this class we will basically define basket checkout model.
That is the same with the basket microservices.
Here you can see that I am going to develop basket checkout model including the variables username,
customer ID, total price, first name, last name, email address, address, line, country, state
zip code, and the payment details including the card name, card number, expiration, CVV and payment
method.
So please develop these basket checkout model or you can copy from the basket microservices.
If you go to the Basket Microservices Details folder, you can reach the basket checkout DTO that including
same members that we can modeling into our shopping web client application.
So please copy these members from here and paste into the our basket model folder and basket checkout
model class.
After that we can develop our wrapper record types under the.
This class come to this point and after this class you can come to this point and developing wrapper
classes.
And the first one is checkout basket request and the second one is checkout basket response.
If you look at the class definitions this will be public record checkout basket request and getting
the basket checkout model and basket checkout parameter name as a parameter.
And these will be the public record checkout basket response.
This will be taking a success as a parameter name, but at this point I have very important concerns,
especially in this line of code.
If you develop these wrapper classes and the parameter names like this way, you will end up with exception
and can't populate parameter values when communicating with the irb API gateway.
Why?
We can get the exception with this definition, because when we are working with the refit library and
generated Http client factories, we should define request response parameter names.
Exactly.
Same with the API gateway responses.
In here you can see the request parameter name.
And for example in here you can see the checkout basket use case and data model class.
And for example let's check the checkout basket use case under the basket.
Microservices.
If you open the basket API and go to basket checkout use case and go to Basket Checkout and point as
the request type.
This will be requiring basket checkout DTO and the name of the parameter is basket Checkout DTO, not
basket checkout.
So that means we should define exactly same parameter names when we are defining our data models.
Instead of writing the basket checkout because if these parameter names is not matching with each other,
these data cannot be populated when communicating with the ERP API gateway.
For that reason, we should change the parameter name of the request record type as the same as the
basket checkout and point class definition.
That means I am going to come here and copy the parameter name, and go back to our data model and paste
in here, which is the basket checkout DTO.
So this is the latest implementation of the basket checkout request.
And this is very important concern.
So please make sure that you have give exact same parameter names for each wrapper class record type
with comparing with the actual microservices end point class.
So I'm going to also compare with the other definitions.
In here you can see the basket checkout model is the same.
And if you go back to shopping cart model you can see the parameter name as a cart.
So I'm going to for example go to the get basket end point and see that parameter name as a cart.
So we are checking the actual endpoint class.
You can define all parameter names accordingly.
As you can see that we have successful develop basket domain models, including the our shopping cart
model and basket checkout model to perform all use cases from the basket microservices into our shopping
web client application.