In this video, we are going to develop ordering domain models for shopping web application.
So here you can see that our domain and domain submodels that we are going to represent and integrate
with the ordering microservices.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the shopping web application and go to the models and right
click the models and add new subfolder which name is ordering.
So we will encapsulate ordering related data models in this folder.
Before we start we can check the ordering microservices use cases.
For that purpose.
You can go to the services ordering and open the ordering API project and go to the endpoints that we
are going to consume from the our Shopping web client application.
Here you can see the endpoints.
I am going to focus on the get endpoints when we are consuming from the client application.
The first one is get orders.
Here you can see the get orders requiring the request and response object.
In the response object, we are accepting paginated order DTO orders as a parameter.
So that means I need a create order model.
And this model should be encapsulated with the paginated result.
And this will be encapsulated with the get orders response record type.
First of all, we can go to the order DTO that we are going to create order model with the same parameters.
And if you look at the parameters, you can see that this will be include some sub parameters which
is the orders, DTO payment, DTO order status and order item DTO.
So all these classes, I am going to convert these as a model classes under the Shopping Web Client
application.
In order to communicate with Http, get methods from the ordering microservices.
For that purpose, you can go back to our shopping web application and close the ordering and go to
the ordering subfolder under the models folder and add new class, which name is order model dot CSS.
So we will adding a record type as a order model and order item model, and including the address and
payment model.
So I'm going to start with the order model.
Instead of using the class.
This time I'm going to use record type is the same as the are ordering microservices.
And here you can see the ordering model including the ID, customer ID, order name, shipping and billing
address, payment status and order items.
So we will continue define these submodules including the address model, payment model, order status
and Order item model.
So just after this record type definition I am going to add these line of codes.
These are including the public record order item model including the order ID, product ID, quantity
and price as a parameter, and record type members.
And if you look at the address model, you can see that we have defined these address model, including
the all these members copying from the orders DTO from the our ordering microservices that you can copy
and paste these record types from the order DTO models and change the class names, address DTO to model
order item, detailed model, order DTO model.
And also you can continue with the payment model including the card name, card number, and so on.
These members comes from the DTO classes, from the ordering microservices.
And lastly, we have a order status including the all members from the order DTO classes.
So this is the order model definition under the are ordering microservices to accodomate Http get requests
into our client application.
Just after that we can define the wrapper classes, but before that we can check again our endpoints
and use cases.
These are the get orders.
Here you can find the get order response record type that we are going to create from the order models.
And after that you can see that get orders by customer.
Here you can see the record type.
And we will also use get orders by name.
And here you can see the order record type that we can define in the shopping web application.
And all these response types requiring the some parameters.
This one is requiring the IEnumerable order model.
And this one is requiring the again enumerable order model and get orders only requiring for the pageant
result that we are going to create this class into our shopping web client application.
So let's focus on our ordering model and go at the end of this class definition.
Now I'm going to define our wrapper classes, including our endpoint use cases.
Here you can see that the first one is get orders response record type.
As a parameter.
We can define paginated result order model, generic type and orders.
And the second record type is a get orders by name response as a parameter.
It is taking IEnumerable order model orders, and the third one is get orders by customer response and
parameter as a enumerable order model orders.
So please define these wrapper classes.
As you can see that this time we need a page entity result.
For that purpose, I'm going to create additional class under the ordering which is the page entity
results.
This will be represent arpeggiated wrapper to our response of the order data.
With the order model.
Here you can see that I have created page entity result which is the entity generic type and.
These are the primary constructor parameters page index, page size, long and data and where t entity
is a class.
So these definitions comes from the our actual page entity result definition from the ordering microservices
that I am going to copy and paste all these members page index, page size count and data so you can
save this page entity result and go back to order module.
And you can see that our exception is disappeared.
As you can see that we have successfully defined our wrapper classes and our order model.
From the ordering domain model, you can right click and build the shopping web application and verify
that our domain models are created successfully.