In this video, we are going to develop service classes for consuming API gateway with using Revit Http
client factory library.
So that means we are at the third step, and we will use Revit Http client factory to developing a catalog
service.
I basket service and I ordering services to communicate with ERP API gateway.
Here you can see that we have using the traditional linear architecture into our client application.
That means now we will implement the service classes as a business logic and consume the ERP API gateway
endpoints.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Shopping Web application to Creating
a Business layer.
I am going to right click the shopping web and add a new folder.
Which name is services?
This will be represent our business logic and I am going to add a new interface under services which
name is AI Catalog Service.
And this interface will be responsible for the communicating ERP API gateway using the Revit library.
But before that, let's analyze which methods we need to consume from the ERP API gateway.
For that purpose, I am going to open the catalog microservices under services.
And if you open the catalog API and open the products feature folder, you can see that these are the
our use cases that we can available for the AI catalog service.
Since we used catalog operations for reading data and representing shopping web index page, we only
use get methods into our shopping web client application because we will only get the products and representing
on the shopping web client, application index page, product page and so on.
So now we should create these methods into our AI catalog service interface and consume these endpoints
from the ARP API gateway using the Revit generated clients.
So if you open, for example, Getproducts endpoint, you can see that these will be the R request and
response.
And we will create these kind of methods to getting incoming request object with page number and page
size and return back a IEnumerable product response.
So if you open the get product by ID, you can see that we have sending a Guid, ID and returning with
a single product model.
And here you can see the get products by category and paint.
We will use a category information as a string category and respond back the IEnumerable product model
products.
So we will arrange these kind of operations under the R service layer as a catalog service that I am
going to create these method bodies in here.
So you can come here and develop the R methods.
These are the task get products methods, get product by ID and get product by category.
So the first one is task and return back the get products response and the method name as a get products
and as a parameter it is taking page number and page size.
And the second method is returning get product by id response and which method name as a get product
and taking grid id as a parameter.
And the third method name is get products by category response.
Returning this response and the method name is a get products by category and taking string category.
As a parameter of this method, you can go to these response object and see the including the product
model and IEnumerable product models in the wrapper classes that we have developed in the last videos.
So this is the implementation of the AI catalog services.
And we have created our AI catalog service methods in order to consume Erb API gateway endpoints from
our service layer.
Also, we can enhance the code readability.
I am going to move these using statement under the global using.
Come here and add new class at the top of the shopping web client application and adding the class name
as a global Usings.
So at this point, I am going to remove all the codes and go back to our AI catalog services and moving
these using statement under the R global Usings and put the global keyword save this file.
Go back to our main class and this time we can remove these using statements into our AI catalog interfaces.
So now how can we send a Http get request to consume these Erb API gateways into a catalog service methods.
So there is very effective way to handle this.
Without implementing these interface members.
We will use Refit for consuming Erb, API gateway and twins.
If you look at the method body of these catalog services and these method body structure same as the
microservice endpoint definition, it is taking request parameters and return back a response.
So how this could consume API's with using only interface method bodies.
The answer is using the Refit.
Refit is mapping the request and response objects of the Erb API gateway endpoint using the generated
client endpoints, without implementing actual these methods.
So now let's learn the refit.