In this video, we are going to learn what is Refit library and how we can create generated clients
using the Refit library.
So let me start with the what is refit?
Refit is the automatic type safe rest library for the dotnet core and Xamarin.
And it is type Safe rest Http client factory implementation that we can use when we are consuming our
APIs.
So now we will implement our service layer classes for business logic and consume the Erb API gateway
endpoints.
And we will use Refit for consuming Erb API gateway endpoints.
So how can we use Refit with dotnet?
DotNet has several options when we are consuming an API.
If you look at this article, you can see that we can implement I http client factory with dotnet in
a several ways.
If you scroll down, you can see that there is a I http client factory type and we have several consumption
patterns.
This was including basic usage, named clients, type clients and generated clients.
So during the course we will use generated clients.
If you click this link you can see that we can use I http client factory in a combination with the third
party libraries.
In our case we will use refit.
Refit is a Rest based library for DotNet and it allows for declarative Rest API definitions mapping
the interface methods to the endpoints.
So here you can see an implementation of the to do list consuming to to do API.
This is the to do domain model.
And if you scroll down we can rely on the refit Http client factory NuGet packages.
And this will be basically create an interface which is the I to do service.
And this is the method with the request and response object.
And there is annotation that will specify the consuming endpoint which is a slice todos.
And we can specify request parameters as a user id which comes from the parameter of this Getuser todo
method.
And this method will be provided to consume to do service without implementing this action method,
and this will be generated client using the refit Http client factory.
And if you look at the NuGet packages, you can see that we need to install refit dot http client factory
packages.
And just after that, you can see as an example of the implementation to consuming GitHub API for specific
user.
Here you can see that we have defined a GitHub API interface, and the method is getuser with a given
username and returning a specific user for the GitHub user.
So this is the annotation that we can specify the endpoint which is a slash user slash username.
So if you scroll down you can see that we can add the services with using the Add Refit client with
passing the GitHub API as a generics to this extension method.
And just after that we can configure the Http client with base address and additional configurations.
By this way, we can call this GitHub API with sending the GitHub API dot get user and get back to this
username information into the R variable.
So this is the simple implementation of the refit into.
Net and we will use refit when we are consuming our API gateway and internal e-commerce microservices.