In this video we are going to install and configure Revit Http client factory library in our shopping
Web client application for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Shopping Web application.
You can close the catalog microservices and locate the Shopping Web application and right click dependencies
and manage NuGet packages.
And this time we will browse for the Revit Http client factory and select these NuGet packages and install
these packages into our shopping web.
So you can double click the Shopping Web project file, and you can verify that we have installed successfully.
After installing these packages, I am going to go to the Application Settings Json file and adding
a new sections for the API settings and the gateway address.
If you come to this point, I am going to add a new section, which name is API settings and including
this section I have specified gateway address and this is the https localhost 1664.
This is erb api gateway docker address and the port number.
When we run the docker compose all we will consume this URL from the shopping web client application.
And after that we need to register Revit library into our ASP.Net Dependency Injection tool.
For that purpose, I'm going to go to the Program.cs and locate the our add services to container part.
And just after the Adding Razor page I am going to add the refit client libraries.
In here you can see that I'm going to type Builder Services add Revit client extension method with passing
the URL catalog service as a generic type.
And this is the extension method for adding Revit client related objects into our ASP.Net project,
which is the shopping web client application.
And just after that, I am going to configure these Http client with specifying the base address that
we have defined into our configuration file, which is the builder configuration API settings gateway
address into our application settings Json file.
That means we will create an Http client factory for our catalog service with connecting base address
as a these gateway address.
This is representing our Erb API gateway worker endpoint and URL.
So this is the configuration of the our catalog service and Refit client for the shopping web client
application.
By this way, Refit will create generated clients for our catalog service interface and consume from
these base address which is Yarp API gateway docker URL.
But of course we should define annotations in the Catalog Service interface before proceeding a catalog
service interfaces.
It is good to move these using statements into our global using CSS.
I am going to move these using statements.
Go to the global using and ending at this point with adding the global keyword.
So after adding these global using statements, we can go back to Program.cs and make sure that your
code is working properly.
So now we can go to the Eye Catalog Service interface.