In this video, we are going to develop a catalog service interfaces with using Revit Http client factory
libraries.
So before that we should understand which APIs that we will consume from the our shopping web client
application.
If you think that this is the first page of our e-commerce client application, and in the first landing
page, you can see that we are listing the products.
In order to listing these products, we will consume to catalog microservices with product list from
our client application using the refit and API gateway.
And when sending the request, we need pagination because the product list cannot be listing in the
first page without pagination, and we will send paginated products from the catalog microservices and
consume this API over the web API gateway and listing products into our landing page and the first page
of our microservices and in the client application.
Also, we need filtering the category.
When we are sending the category, we will retrieve the orders by the category.
In order to perform this action, we will send additional Http get requests to the catalog microservices
over the ERP API gateway.
And also we can select the specific product.
That means we will go to the product detail page.
And in this page we need get product by ID with full details.
For that reason I am going to again send http get request and get product by ID request to our client
application.
For that purpose, I have created APIs that we are going to consume from the client application.
Regarding the catalog, these are the get all products, get products with pagination, get products
by category and get product by ID here you can see that in every request we are sending these API endpoint
URL, which is the Erb API gateway, and this is the slash catalog service indicating that our request
is redirecting to downstream catalog microservices.
And this is the slash products.
And this will be retrieving the all products with pagination with category and with get by ID information.
So if you go back to our Visual Studio we should understand the endpoint structure from the services
catalog microservices.
And here you can see the product use cases get product by category by ID and get products.
If you open the endpoint classes, you understand the structure of the request and response that we
are going to use these request response when communicating to our catalog microservices.
So if you look at the all endpoint definitions and also you can check the are modules under the catalog,
we have defined the modules to accodomate all these endpoints with given request and response object.
And we can handle with the wrapper classes to accommodate incoming requests in this product model list.
So we will use these model objects into our service class which will be the our business use case layer.
And here you can see that our catalog service requiring the annotation in order to consume Erb API gateway.
So now I am going to add annotations one by one for each method.
Here you can see the the first method Getproducts with pagination.
Here you can see the http get operation.
With annotation.
We put the get method and inside of this get method I have specified the endpoint URL, which is the
slash catalog service.
Slash products and paginated details and page number and page size will be getting from the request
parameters, which is indicating our Getproducts method parameters.
And at the same way, I am going to define the second method, which is the get products by id here
you can see that again, we will use the get method and passing the slash catalog service.
Slash products and ID information and ID will be taken from the request parameters which will be the
are Getproduct method, parameter name.
And as the same way, I am going to define the last operation, which is the get products by category.
And here you can see that we will use slash catalog service slash products category and category name.
Category name.
Again taking from the request parameters which is our request parameter of the these get product by
method.
So now I am going to splitting these operations according to annotation type.
And by this way we can consume three microservices over the API gateway from the our shopping web client
application.