In this video, we are going to develop a basket service interface with using Revit Http client factory.
So if you analyzing basket operations from our shopping web client application, we can create basket
operation.
And after that we will check out the basket.
And of course we will get the basket and the details.
So for that reason I am going to create these endpoints that we are going to consume from the shopping
web client application.
These are the get basket with a given username, post basket with creating a new basket, delete basket
with a given username.
And lastly our asynchronous use case which is the checkout basket operation with sending http post request.
So we will consume these APIs over the web API gateway from the Shopping Web client application using
the Revit Client factory.
So for that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the our shopping, Web and Services Catalog
service.
In our case, I am going to create a new interface which is the I basket services.
Create new interface under the services folder which name is I Basket Services.
So in here we are going to consume our basket related operations.
You can check the basket related operations from the services basket basket API.
And if you go to the basket feature folder you can see the basket use cases under this folder including
the get store, delete and checkout basket.
And you can expand these Get Basket folder and see the endpoint classes in order to understand incoming
request and response object.
And here you can see the store basket operation http post operation.
We will send shopping cart module and get response as a username.
And if you look at the checkout basket, we basically send our basket checkout DTO module and response
back.
The boolean is success.
So according to these request and response object, we have already created our DTO and module classes
under the module class of the Shopping Web Client application.
If you expand the basket, you can see that we have shopping cart module to academic incoming requests
and perform Crud operations using the shopping cart module and consuming from the basket microservices
and populate data into these module classes when consuming APIs under shopping web application.
And you can find the basket checkout module to performing basket checkout use case with using these
wrapper classes.
And we will use these wrapper classes to accommodate incoming requests and consume these requests from
our business layer, which is the I basket service.
For that purpose, I am going to create method bodies into this interface and create annotations.
Here you can see that we will perform these operations into the I basket service.
And I am going to add a record using statement for get basket response.
I'm going to using the shopping web models basket namespace.
And basically we can move these using statement to our global using.
So I'm going to go to the global using and paste in here.
And we can add a global keyword.
And basically this will be representing our shopping web models catalog basket.
And also I can add a ordering because in the next video we will adding ordering related operations and
refit and web services.
So save this file and go back to our I basket service.
Here you can see that our classes are activated.
And here you can see that we have four methods that we will consume from the basket.
Microservices over the Erb API gateway from our shopping web client application.
The first one is get basket with a given username.
And here you can see the annotation get slash basket, service slash basket and username taking from
the request parameters which is the get basket method.
And as a response we will expecting get basket response which including the shopping cart module from
the R models.
So the second method and the consume operation is store basket Http post operation.
As a request parameter we will send store basket request which name is request and response.
As a store basket response you can see the annotation is post and as a parameter we can see basket,
service, slash, basket and point that we are going to send http post operation.
And the third consume operation is delete basket method.
And in this method we will passing the username as a request parameter.
Here you can see the delete method.
And as a parameter you can see the endpoint definition which is the slash basket service slash basket
slash username.
And the last method and last consume operation is post basket checkout operation.
Here you can see the checkout basket as a parameter which is taking checkout basket request which is
the payload and getting response checkout basket response.
Here you can see the Http post operation.
And the endpoint definition is basket service slash basket and slash checkout.
And of course these endpoint definitions are belonging for the Erb API gateway.
And we will perform basket operations with this method using the refit.
At this point I would like to explain one of the important considerations.
For example when.
We are developing our interface methods and method parameters.
These parameter names should be exactly same as the Andpoint class definition.
Otherwise, Refit won't map the outgoing request object to the consuming API.
For example, if you look at the store basket, this is the parameter and this is the parameter name
as a request.
So in the basket API, if you go to the store basket and print, these request parameter should be same
as the this basket definition which is request.
Otherwise refit cannot be mapping this request object to the sending payload and sending consuming operation
and it won't be work.
Please consider this thing.
For example.
You can see the delete basket if you go to the delete basket and print, you can see the string username.
And this is the exactly same parameter name into our interface members.
As you can see that we have completed the I basket service interface and consume operations.
And we will continue with the I ordering service.