In this video, we are going to develop AI ordering service interfaces with using Revit Http client
factory.
If you look at our e-commerce application, we will sending Http get requests from the ordering microservices
over the http api gateway in order, the listing orders by customer, and so on.
And here you can see the or using Http get methods.
We will get orders get orders by Paginating and we will get orders by name.
And we will get orders by customer ID.
Here you can see that we will use Erb API gateway endpoint.
Of course this should be 6064 for the environment.
And here you can see the our endpoint URL which is ordering dash service slash orders.
With pagination we can add page index and page size as a request parameters.
For get orders by username we can adding slash order name for customers.
We can adding orders slash customer and customer ID which is the grid.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the R services.
I am going to create a new interface which is the I ordering services under the services folder.
And this will be representing our interface and consume operations into the I ordering service.
But before that you can examine the ordering microservices from the services.
Ordering microservices.
If you expand the ordering API, you can expand the ordering endpoint.
And here you can see the all get orders, get orders by customer and get orders by name use cases listing
under the endpoint folder.
So if you open the get orders, you can see the get order request and response structure.
And at the same way you can check the get orders by customer to understand which the getting request
and response object from the actual ordering microservices.
And we will accodomate these ordering microservice consume operations under the modules ordering with
the order module, with defining the wrapper classes and getting result from the IEnumerable order model
orders parameters.
And here you can see the pageant result defined in the order module that we can get the orders with
pageant results.
So now we are going to define our methods in order to consume ordering microservices over the Erb API
gateway.
Here you can see that I have created annotations and methods for the Http get operation, get orders
with taking the page index and page size parameter.
And here you can see the returning a response.
And in this response we will expecting pageant result in the order models.
And if you go back to our method you can see the annotation which is the Http get with the parameter
name of the our ordering service slash orders and page index and page size.
This value comes from the request parameters of this method, and in the second method we will define
get orders by name and parameter name as a string order name.
As a response, we will return back get orders by name response, which is a wrapper class including
the IEnumerable order model, and this will be http get operation and the endpoint definition should
be ordering service slash orders and order name will be taken from the request parameter.
And lastly we will perform get orders by customer with taking with customer ID returning get orders
by customer response.
And this is the Http get method and the endpoint definition to consuming Erb API gateway and getting
response from the ordering microservices from our shopping web client application.
As you can see that we have developed our business layer.
Now it is time to go to the building presentation layer with using the razor page and ASP.Net basics
repository.