In this video we are going to build presentation layer.
That means we are at the fourth step and we will be develop ASP.Net Web Application Razor page with
ASP.Net Run Basics repository.
Here you can see that we will develop index card, product detail checkout order HTML and see page.
And we will consume the Erb API gateway and prints from the eye service interfaces with using Revit
Http client factory libraries.
So please open the Visual Studio.
And here you can see the our shopping web client application that you can see that we have developed
our model folder service folder.
And now we are going to develop our presentation layer which includes the page WW route and so on.
If you look at the root folder you can see that this will include Ccjs and leave folders.
And each folder has include the required operations.
For example, in the leaf folder we will implement Bootstrap Fatima.
So this is the front end implementation and all details under the WW root folder.
And if we expand the page folder this will be represent our page in the front end application and including
the index error and shared folder.
So if you expand the shared folder this will be include shared HTML operations during the implementation
of the other pages.
And you can see the layout and validation scripts partial.
So if you look at the index.html you can see that this is typical HTML page, but also including some
of the C-sharp models which including the model index model in order to populate data inside of these
HTML pages.
And where these index model comes, this will be comes from the our C sharp file of these HTML file.
If you click this button, this will be expanding to C sharp file of these index css HTML.
And if you open this class you can see that the class definition comes from in here.
This is implementation of the page model.
And the name of the class is index model that we can develop our properties in order to populate data
when consuming the API gateway.
So in this class we basically inject our I service interfaces.
And we will communicate with the Erb API gateway using the Revit Http client factory.
And after that we will populate the data into our HTML page with placing the module inside of the class.
So now we can start to develop our e-commerce microservice client application.
But as you can see that we need to develop Ccjs lib and also develop all pages HTML files into our application.
But I'm not going to develop front end operations in this course.
Instead of that, we will take these HTML, CSS, js files from the repository.
Which repository?
I have mentioned that we have run ASP.Net Core Basics repository that include implementation of the
basic real world e-commerce web application project in one solution.
Here you can see the details of the pages of the e-commerce application in this repository that we are
going to copy these files from our microservice application client application.
And if you scroll down, you can see that this is only one solution and one web application project,
including the ASP.Net Core and Entity Framework Core, and using the ASP.Net core components, which
including the razor pages, Middlewares, dependency injection configuration and logging.
So we will use this website when developing our client application, especially copy from the HTML,
CSS, and JavaScript files in order to build these e-commerce web application.
So before that, let me explain these repository.
If you open this folder, you can see the folder structure of these one ASP.Net core solution.
And I am going to focus on the WW root and page.
Here you can see that it is including required CSS and image folder.
We will copy from these website.
And also if you go to the page folder you can see that these will be including the index product, cart
checkout, confirmation order and so on.
So these are the related for the e-commerce and e-shop pages when we are making our e-commerce application.
For example, if you open the index.html, you can see that this is typical HTML page, one representing
in the landing page, including the all products with pagination.
And these are the are including the partial name and partial operations.
Partial HTML.
When populating the products here, you can see that these will be populating the product partial,
which is getting the first order default from the product list.
And if you scroll down here, you can see the for each iteration and listing all products with using
the partial again, which is the product item partial.
So where this partial storing in this application under the page we have a shared folder.
And under the shared folder you can see that this is the product item partial, representing each product
in a HTML format and populating the product data, for example.
Model summary, model, model price and so on.
And if you look at the top product partial, again, this is the single product for the top product
in the landing page.
So we can use common HTML operations with using the shared folders and partial weaves.
And if you scroll down and go back to index.html, you can see that as a model we will use index model
and populate the are products according to index model.
And if you go to the see page, you can see that in the index model we basically retrieve the products
from the repository, because this is the single application using the Entity Framework code that communicating
the database and retrieve the products.
But in our case, we will inject our AI service interfaces in order to consume Erb API gateway endpoints
and retrieve the products from the catalog microservices over the Erb API gateway.
So as the same way you can examine the other pages, including the product, product detail, and so
on.
Here you can see the product HTML page that including the listing all products in here and here you
can see the see page that retrieving the products from the database.
In our case we will retrieve from the Erb API gateway.
And here you can see the product detail which representing a single product with detail information.
And here you can see that we will use razor page and model in order to reach the product name, price
and so on.
And these will be populated from the RC page.
And as the same way here you can see the order page.
And also here you can see the shopping cart page.
And here you can see the checkout page that we will start with the asynchronous communication.
So now I'm going to start to copy from the R project.
And I will start with the root folder.
In order to perform these front end styling for each page here you can see that we have including the
front end styling, CSS and image files that include the bootstrap for and CSS image folder that.
We are going to copy these folders and paste into our shopping client web application to representing
our shop page.
So let's build the presentation layer from this ASP.Net basics repository.
For that purpose, I'm going to go to on top of this GitHub repository page I'm going to come here,
click the code and copy to clone link of this repository.
And just after that I am going to open Additional Visual Studio and click this clone a repository and
paste in here.
So we are going to create a new repository.
But I have already clone this repository before.
For that purpose I have go to that location and open this project solution file.
And this will be our ASP.Net run basic repository that we are going to use when we are developing our
client application.
So let me come here and close all the tabs.
And if you expand this page and close all files, you can see that we will use these root folder.
When we are styling our each page.
For that purpose, we can copy these CSS and image files from the ASP.Net basics repository.
Right click and I'm going to copy these files.
And after that I'm going to open our actual Icap microservices repository.
And this will be include shopping Web client application and go to the root folder.
First of all I'm going to delete these Ccjs and lib folders.
So right click these folders and delete all these Ccjs and lib folder under the Shopping Web client
application.
Okay, we can't delete leaf folder.
It doesn't important for us because we will copy from the styling, including the CSS and image from
the ASP.Net basics.
Right click and copy these files and paste into the root into our Shopping Web client application.
Right click paste.
Here you can see that we have added requiring CSS and image folder for our microservices and client
application.
After that we can continue the copy operation under the page folder.
If you go to page folder and go to subfolder shared.
Here you can see the underscore layout HTML page that including all common operation for each page under
the page folder.
So we are going to copy these layout page from the ASP.Net basics.
So I'm going to open the page open the shared and go to layout.
And I'm going to select all copy these layout CSS HTML and go back to our actual repository and delete
all file from the our shopping web client application.
And paste in here and save this file.
So as you can see that this file is including all required operation for the common operation in the
page, including the CSS files and arranging the our header, including the our index product card order
and contact page links in this file.
And here you can see the form for submitting the button for the search operation and so on.
So by changing this layout page, we can access and reach the front end application with using these
footer and header operations.
Here you can see the header and footer that we are going to arranging our layout.
And after that we will develop our index product categories and other pages.
And at this point if you run this shopping web application, you can see that our layout prepared successfully.
And this will be open the Chrome page.
And here you can see that we have header including the product card order and contact links.
And we have also footer including the about information and other links.
And this is the actual index page that we are going to modify in the next video.