In this video, we are going to develop index HTML and CSS files with shared partial razor pages.
So here you can see that we have a index page but not implementing and listing the products.
But in the e-commerce application in the index page we should listing the products.
For that purpose.
I am going to copy the index page from the ASP.Net Run Basics repository.
Here you can see the our repository and I am going to go to the index says HTML and copy all this file
and come here and paste in here.
And save this file.
Here you can see that this is the HTML page of the index operations.
And we have a div definition.
And in here you can see that we have a partial razor page which is the top product partial and modal.
We can give the modal dot product list first or default.
So here you can see that product list is getting exception that we are going to define in this video.
But before that let's focus on this partial razor page that we are going to create as a partial view
into our shared folder.
If you scroll down you can see another div.
And here you can see we have iterating the product list.
And each product is representing again as a partial razor page which is the product item partial.
And as a modal, we can pass the product information which comes from the modal dot product list.
So if you scroll down you can see additional div.
And this will be performing the same operations.
So that means first of all we will focus on these partial names which are representing a common HTML
page.
As a partial.
So here you can see that this is the product item partial.
And we have also the product partial.
So I'm going to copy this partial base from the ASP.Net Run Basics repository.
If you open this repository you can go to Page Shared subfolder.
And here you can see the product item partial and the product partial.
If you copy these two items, right click and copy and go back to our repository and go to the page
shared subfolder.
Right click and paste.
So here you can see that we have successfully added product item partial and top product item partial.
So if you look at the product item partial you can see that this is typical a product representation
including the product details, summary detail and so on.
And at the end of this form we have a add to cart button in order to adding these product item into
shopping cart.
And also if you look at the top product partial, it is also again the same structure.
We have a single product and we can see product details in here.
And we have also redirection page which is the product detail with clicking this product.
So first of all I'm going to change product item partial model.
As you can see that model defined as a product.
But we don't have any product class into our shopping web client application.
Instead we are populating the product under the models catalog and product model.
We can save these partial view.
And you can go to the this location.
If you go to the models folder and open the catalog models.
Here you can see that our product model that we can represent product details in here.
When consuming the API gateway for that purpose, I'm going to change the models of these partial waves
in order to access these model operations.
Here you can see the model ID and model summary instead of the summary.
I can change the description if I come here and write description.
Yes, because we don't have any summary information.
Instead, you can change the summary property to description anywhere into partial view and index HTML
files.
So after that you can see that we don't have any exception in this product item partial.
And I'm going to also go to the next partial one which is the top product partial.
Again I'm going to change this model to models catalog and product model.
And if you look at the model ID and we don't model price and we have model ID and model price and we
don't have model summary in here, you can now navigate to model class item ID members and other ones
from the ah HTML page with using the razor page.
So we have prepared all partial waves with changing the models and looking the members that we don't
have any exception which is the top product partial and product item partial, and we don't have any
exception.
So now we can go back to our index page and we can use these partial views in here.
So here you can see that we are using the third product partial at this point.
And we are using the product item partials with iterating the products.
And in here you can see that when we are iterating the products we are looking for the model dot product
list.
But we don't have any list property yet.
So if you go to the model of this class, you can see that model is a index model, which is the C-sharp
file of this HTML page.
We can expand this C sharp file, come to here and open the C sharp file of this index page.
And at this point I am going to add a new property.
Which name is product list.
For that purpose I'm going to come to the class definition.
And after the Ilogger operation I'm going to create a new property which is the public IEnumerable product
model and name is Product list, which is the getter and setter.
I'm going to create a new list product model in the index model class.
So just after that you can go back to HTML page and scroll down.
You can see that now we can access the product list in order to verify that, you can right click the
Shopping Web client application and build the project and see that we don't have any exception when
we are developing our index page.