In this video we are going to develop index see page to consume irb, API gateway and print using the
catalog service which is implementation of the Http client factory.
For that purpose, I am going to start by removing these logging operations, because I am going to
inject by primary constructor instead of the normal constructor, and come to this index model class.
And I am going to inject these two classes.
The first one is a catalog service and the second one is Ilogger index model and logger.
So we will use these two services when implementing of these index model see our page.
So in here you can see that we have defined product list.
Now I am going to populate the product list with communicating with the IRB API gateway.
For that purpose I am going to use one get method.
But this time I will use one get async method.
In order to make this function available.
Here you can see that public async and this will be return task.
This time we are going to return task and this will be returning I action result.
Okay, so now we can start the implementation of the one get async method.
In this method we will start by logging the information which is the logger log information and index
page visited.
And just after that we will use Catalog Service to communicate with the IRB API gateway and send request
to the catalog downstream microservices.
So here you can see that I am going to use await catalog service Getproduct method.
If you go to this method, you can see that this method will be generated client with refit in order
to send Http get request to this endpoint.
So if you go back to our index page, we will return back the result.
And in this result we have a products collection that we can paste this product collection into our
product list property under the Index model class.
Here you can see that I have assigning the results dot products to the product list, which is the IEnumerable
product model, and just after that we can return the page.
So this is the implementation of the asynchronous on get async method.
That means this method will be triggered when the index page opening in the browser, and this will
be retrieving the products from the API gateway to make it more readable.
I am going to move these using statements to the global using class.
So cut here and go to the global using and paste at this point and put the global keywords.
If you go back to index.cshtml you can see that our class is more readable.
So now I am going to perform quick test our shopping web client application.
But as you can see that if you open the application settings Json file, we should activate the our
API gateway in Docker environment.
For that purpose, please run the Docker desktop and just after that you can right click the Docker
compose and set a startup project and you can run without debugging.
This will be activate baking services including the Erb API gateway.
And just after that we will run the our shopping Web client application in order to communicate with
the Erb API gateway and consume products from the catalog microservices and populate the product data
in the landing page.
Here you can see that our Docker compose is up and running, and Erb API gateway is started successfully
and we can verify from the postman.
If you go to your API gateway catalog and get product and select the Docker environment and send Http
get method, you can see that products responding successfully.
So that means we can also call these API from our client application.
For that purpose, please go back to our Visual Studio.
And if you go back to our shopping web application, right click and set a startup project.
And I'm going to run and debug this client application.
But before that you can put the breakpoints in the program.cs of the Or register operation, which is
the Revit client and a catalog service.
You can come here and check the base address.
And also we can go to the index Cshtml C-sharp page and put the debug point on get async method.
So now I'm going to run the or https mode shopping web client application.
See how we can consume these erb API gateway from the shopping web client application.
So when the browser is opening, it is going to set a or base address, which is basically our Docker
address of the Erb API gateway.
You can get these configurations from the application, and if I hit the F5 this will be triggered on
get async method.
And we are going to retrieve information from the catalog microservices which Revit generated clients.
If I hit F10, you can see that results come successfully.
And here you can see the product count as nine.
So we have set the product list into our product list object and return the page.
So if you hit the F5 you can see the index page is populated successfully.
And here you can see the top products.
And here you can see the our last products.
And if you scroll down here you can see the best products and so on.
This is.
Arms from the catalog, microservices and matching to our product image into the shopping web client
application.
So this is how we can consume the products from the catalog microservices and representing into our
index page of the shopping web client application.
But in the product endpoint you can see our postman.
We have also pagination that we can send page number and page size.
But in the index page we don't have pagination object in here.
And you can put the pagination item in the index HTML page and get the products with pagination.
Let me give an example how we can implement this pagination.
After putting these pagination item in here, you can come here and go to the on get async method.
So in here I'm going to comment this line of code.
And just after that I'm going to send additional request to the get products.
But this time we can pass two and three.
Two is a second page three is three item.
You can see the page number and page size.
So after setting this line of code we can use Hot Reload.
Come here and click this Hot Reload and refresh the page to enable the debug point.
Here you can see that debug point comes again in here.
If I hit F5 this time, we will refresh the page in order to get items with pagination.
You can see that this will be triggered on get async method.
This time we will retrieve the products according to pagination.
So here you can see that product list comes to three because we are retrieving the second page.
And if I hit F5 this will be comes to second page of the product that including the Xiaomi, HTC and
LG.
As you can see that our API is capable to applying the pagination, we need to adding the pagination
object into our HTML page.
But for now, I'm going to skip this pagination from the front end layer and I will rollback the change
which comes from the get products.
I'm going to uncomment this line of code and comment this line of code that you can develop the pagination.
Okay.
If you look at our landing page and index page, you can see that we have listing the products, but
we can't go the product details or add the item into shopping cart because these buttons is not working
yet.
But before that we should handle the another operation in index page.
Index page has two actions.
The first action is listing the products, and the second action is add item into cart.
So we should focus on the eight item into shopping cart.
If you go to the HTML page.
If you go to the page and shared folder, you can see that we have a product item partial, and at this
point you can see ASP page 100 as add item to cart.
And in here you can see that we will post operation into these index page in order to adding item into
shopping cart.
And we will passing the model ID which is the product ID that means in the index C-sharp file, we can
create a new method which is the on post async to Accodomate incoming post operation and adding item
into shopping cart.