In this video we are going to develop add item into shopping cart in the Index.cshtml page with using
the I basket service.
So if you open the shared page which is the product item partial shared page, you can see that there
is a form tag and which is the add to cart.
And this is the http post operation.
And there is a button.
And on click we will submit the form which is the index page.
And this is the hidden input type which is passing the model id product id as a parameters.
So this button basically submit the form in the index page.
In order to handle this method, we should create method in the index page which name is on post add
to cart async.
So if you go back to index C-sharp file, you can see that we have a on get async method.
And we are going to create on post add to cart async.
And in this method we will use I basket service to communicate with the basket microservices over the
API gateway.
But before that we have to register our basket service into our ASP.Net dependency injection tool.
For that purpose, we have to go to the program case and when we are registering the catalog service,
we should also register the basket services.
At this point, I am going to copy the catalog service part and paste in here.
And this time I am going to change my catalog service to I Basket Service.
And the base address is the same which is the Erb API gateway.
And this time refit will be generate Http client for the I basket services.
To perform these get, post, delete and post checkout operations.
By this way we can use an inject I basket service any page in order to interact with the basket microservices
over the web API gateway.
After adding thrift client for the basket service, save the program case and go back to our index C
file.
And now I am going to inject and use I basket services to create an add item into product into shopping
cart.
At this point, I am going to go to the primary constructor.
Just after the catalog service injection, I have injected the I basket services.
Here you can see that we have injected three services I Catalog service, I Basket service and I logger.
And after that we can use I basket services into our newly created method which will be create our own
post add to cart async method.
Here you can see the async method that accodomate the submit operation form of the product item partial
partial page, and in here when add to cart operation submitted in the HTML, this method will be trigger.
That's why we have created public async and task I action result and name of the method is on post add
to cart async and as a parameter we will pass with product id that will retrieve the product id in the
hidden item in the product item partial, which we will pass when we are add to cart item and submit
this button.
So if you go back to our index C file, we will implement these method.
First of all, I am going to add a log information for adding item into cart.
And just after that we can basically get the product with a given product ID inside of this parameter.
So I'm going to retrieve the product from the catalog services with get product method in order to get
single product details when adding item into cart, because we will need some additional information
about the products like the product name, price and so on.
For that purpose, it is good to retrieve a product from the catalog services.
And just after that, I am going to get or create a new shopping cart.
For that purpose, I have created a new method which is the await load user basket and passing the basket
services and get back the basket.
This method will be getting or creating a new basket that we will develop in soon.
And after that we can continue our operation, which is the using this basket and adding item into basket.
Using the basket dot items dot add method and passing the new shopping cart item model including and
populating the product ID, product name, price, quantity and color.
Product ID comes from the Our Method parameter.
Product name comes from the R product Response product name, and we get the price from the again product
response product price and quantity is one color is black for hard coded value.
So now we can see that we have adding the basket items with using the basket dot items method.
Basket will be our shopping cart model object that we have defined under the models.
And just after the adding item into basket, we basically passing this basket object into the store
basket.
Request wrapper classes and send to basket service dot store basket method.
In order to send http post request to the basket microservices and create new basket.
So after created new basket we can.
Link to the page, which is the card.
That means we will redirect you to page card from index to card page.
So now we can implement the load user basket method.
Basically we will get or create a new basket according to if it is exist or not.
In here you can see that I have adding the private static async function which is returning task shopping
cart model, and the method name is a load user basket, and as a parameter it is taking I basket service
basket services.
So in this method we basically get or create new basket with default username which is the boolean.
Since we don't have authentication username for now, we can use default username as the boolean for
the workaround in order to get or create new basket.
After that we will add the product into shopping cart.
Here you can see that we have a try catch block.
We basically get the basket using the basket service interface.
And here you can see that we will return the response dot cart object if it is existing.
If not existing, we will creating any basket object with empty items that we can adding new item into
shopping cart.
And here you can see the load basket is using into our actual method.
And once we get the basket, we will add a new item and we will paste this basket object with adding
the new item into the store basket.
Request variable class and hit the http post request to the Basket Services Store basket endpoint.
Now we can refactor our code.
If you look at the our method, you can see that we always relying on the load user basket method.
And this method is a private static method.
And we are using this method for each page when we are developing and loading the basket.
So this is the pain point.
And we should move this function and this method into the I basket service interface.
Here you can see that we can move this method into the our I basket service interface.
Because C sharp has default interface methods feature that comes with the C sharp eight.
Here you can see the article default interface methods that we can explicitly implement interface methods
in here.
So if you scroll down you can see an example of the implementation of the interface methods that we
can use this feature in here because we will requiring to using the load async method load user basket
method in each clusters and in each pages.
For that purpose, it is good to move this method in the eye basket services.
So please go to the eye basket service.
And at this point I am going to develop our actual method which is the load user basket.
Here you can see that I have adding the same method in here.
But this time we will make it public async and return back as a task shopping cart model and method
name is a load user basket.
We will use worker and username as a boolean, and just after that in the try block we will get basket
with a given username.
Get basket methods comes from the interface and once we are getting the basket response, we will populate
the basket and return this basket.
But if there is no basket, we will catch the API exception.
And also we will check the API exception status as a not found.
That means there is no item and basket in the basket.
Microservices.
Then we should create a new basket with a new shopping cart model and empty items.
And after that, we can return back this basket to this method that we can use this method into all
operations when we are loading the user basket.
So if you go back to our index.cshtml file now I am going to delete all these private static method.
And whenever we are using this load user basket this time I am going to use basket service dot load
basket method.
And we don't have any parameter.
So it is now more readable and more clean to implementation of the our add to cart operation.
So as you can see that we have completed the implementation of the Add to cart into our index page.
In the next video we will continue to developing our cart page.