In this video we are going to develop shopping cart razor page in shopping web client application.
Here you can see that we have completed the index page.
Now I am going to develop card, CSS, HTML and CSS file for developing the shopping cart related operations.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the shopping web and pages.
And under the page I am going to right click and add Razor Page and we will develop our shopping cart
related operations and select the razor page empty template and click the add button.
And this is a shopping cart razor page empty.
For that purpose, I'm going to change the name as a cart dot css, HTML and click the add button.
This will be create cart, css, HTML under the page that you can see in here.
This is the HTML page.
And this is the C sharp page that we are going to develop for the shopping cart related operations.
So whenever we are creating any page, we should get the HTML codes from the ASP.Net run basics.
For that purpose I'm going to open the our ASP.Net Run Basics repository and go to the cart says HTML.
And I'm going to copy these operations from the weave data I'm going to copy from here.
And at the end of the code copy these HTML codes.
And just after that paste in here.
And here you can see that we have copied the our cart model and cart operations in here.
And this is the including the div.
And we have a table.
And in this table we will iterate the shopping cart items and we will listing the shopping cart items.
And here you can see that we have a form which is remove to cart.
And this is the button.
When submitting the this button this will be send http post request in order to remove item from the
cart, and this will be placing the cart ID and cart item ID when removing the cart.
And here you can see that there is a total price that we can see at the end of this table.
And at the last of this table, you can see that we have redirection page for the product and checkout
operations.
As you can see that we have developed the cart HTML page.
But here you can see that we need to create cart object into the C sharp file.
That means in the next video we are going to develop this cart model class.