Trong video này, chúng ta sẽ phát triển cart page C# file và tiêu thụ các endpoints của aap API gateway
bằng cách sử dụng I basket services.
Để làm được điều đó, tôi sẽ bắt đầu bằng cách loại bỏ unnecessary using statement và đến class chính của chúng ta
đó là cart model class.
Và trong class này tôi sẽ inject hai services.
Đó là I basket services và Ilogger.
Ở đây bạn có thể thấy rằng chúng ta sẽ sử dụng primary constructor.
Và cái đầu tiên là basket service và cái thứ hai là logger.
Vì vậy sau khi inject hai services này, chúng ta có thể phát triển on get async của riêng mình.
Nhưng trước đó, nếu bạn nhìn vào cart cshtml, chúng ta cần một cart property để đại diện cho shopping
cart của chúng ta.
Để làm được điều đó, tôi sẽ tạo một property mới trong class này.
Nếu bạn đến điểm này ở đầu class, tôi sẽ tạo một property mới đó là
public shopping cart model cart getter setter và chúng ta sẽ tạo một shopping cart
model mới khi mở cart model page này.
Và chúng ta sẽ đại diện dữ liệu shopping cart vào property cart này khi điền dữ liệu vào HTML file của chúng ta.
Vì vậy sau đó, chúng ta có thể phát triển method thực tế của mình đó là on get.
Trước hết, tôi sẽ thay đổi on get này thành on get async method và chúng ta sẽ gọi các API của API gateway
cho mục đích đó.
Vui lòng thay đổi method signature thành public async task I action result và on get async.
So we will return the page at the end of this method.
For that purpose, I will return the page here.
So now we will use Erb API gateway by using basket services that we have injected into primary
constructor and populate our shopping cart model, which is cart.
So here I will say that cart equal await basket service dot load user basket.
As you can see, we will load user basket from basket services.
And if you remember that this is interface method that we will implement to get or
create any basket into our shopping cart basket of microservices.
Microservices.
Here you can see that in try block we will send Http get requests with a specific username to basket
Microservices over Ocelot API gateway.
If basket exists, we will return this basket.
If it does not exist, we will check API exception and Http status is not found.
We will create any basket with empty items with a specific username.
So then we will populate the shopping cart which will represent our shopping cart model into HTML
file.
So this is on get async method.
But we also have some submit operations.
If you open cart HTML page you can see that we will also submit operation in remove to cart.
That means this button will represent and submit when removing cart item to shopping
shopping cart.
And here are the cart items.
But when removing an item from the shopping cart, I need the product ID instead of these cart IDs.
I will remove these input statements and pass it here as a product ID, which includes
our cart item, and we have a for each statement from modal dot cart items and get this cart item
and cart item, which includes the product ID that we can add here.
So, please add hidden product ID before implementing our remove cart.
But whenever we change the cart item ID, you can see that there is an exception getting
the product name.
We already have the product name in the cart item.
So that's why I'm about to change the code this way.
Here you can see that now we don't have any exception.
And this is the representation of the for each statement and looping through each item in the shopping cart model that
we can delete cart for each item by passing the product ID.
So after changing our HTML this way, I will go back to CSS, HTML and start implementing
our remove cart operation.
So here I will create a new method that is public async task I action result and
the name of this method is on post.
Remove the cart async and as a parameter we are getting product id coming from hidden
object of ours.
So the method name is very important in razor page because on post is representing what.
This is the post remove operation.
Cart is the submit operation method and async is.
This will indicate whether the function is available or not.
So here I will implement this method.
First we will log that the remove cart button has been clicked and then
I will again get the cart information from our basket services with the load user method.
And after getting the cart information, we can remove the item by product id.
Here I will use cart items dot remove all method by passing in product id filter operation
by getting the product id from parameters and checking the product ID into our remove all method
as a condition.
Here you can see we will use x dot product id, which means iterate through all items and check if
product ids are equal or not.
If they are equal, this will remove these items from the shopping cart items, and right after that
we can perform our store basket operation.
This means we will send an http post request to save the latest cart information.
So here you can see we will use await basket service store basket and we will pass in new store
basket request by passing in the cart information that we have.
Remove items from the cart by this operation.
And with this line of code, we will send an http post request and save the latest cart information to
database và distributed cache.
Vì vậy sau khi thực hiện operation này, tôi sẽ return redirect đến page.
Điều đó có nghĩa là chúng ta đang redirect page của cart sau khi thực hiện post removed cart operation.
Vì vậy đây là implementation của cart model của chúng ta và điều này sẽ được included vào property trên get async method.
method và on post async method để removing cart từ items.
Vì vậy bạn có thể right click và build shopping web application và verify rằng shopping cart và cart operations của chúng ta đã completed vào client application.