In this video we are going to develop product list razor page in the shopping web client application.
So we are at this point and we will develop product list, CSS, HTML for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Shopping Web client application.
And go to the page and right click Add New Razor Page and we will select the razor page empty template.
Click the add button and give the name as a product list dot CSS, HTML and click the add button.
This will be create product list CSS HTML file representing the list of the products.
At this point, before proceeding to HTML codes, we should change the layout link redirection.
Here you can see the.
Under the shared folders we have a underscore layout, CSS, HTML, CSS.
This file representing our layout operation, including the header and footer.
If you scroll down you can see the our header links listing in here for product page.
I am going to change slash product to slash product list because we are creating a product list CSS,
HTML and we would like to redirect this page why we are doing this change.
Because we have a product model class under the models.
If you go to models catalog you can see that we have product model class.
So whenever we create a new razor page, razor page also adding model suffix in order to avoid duplication,
we are changing the name as a product list.
If you open the product list, you can see that we have created product list model class.
By this way, we can separate the our model and the actual product list page.
So now we can focus on the HTML part and copy the HTML of this product list from the ASP.Net run basic
repository.
For that purpose, please open the ASP.Net run basic repository and go to the pages product page.
And in here I am going to copy from here and paste into our product list page.
From this point.
And here you can see that we have copied our HTML page that including the product list details.
At this point, I would like to say some of the important concerns.
Whenever you create any razor page, make sure that your class name seems a green.
If the class name doesn't seem green, that means the class cannot introduce for the HTML page.
We have to recreate this razor page.
So after that we can examine our HTML page.
Here you can see that we are using model dot selected category.
That means we have to define this property into our C sharp class.
If you scroll down we have a for each statement and we have iterating category list.
That means we have category list object into our C sharp class and representing our categories.
If you scroll down, you can see that we are giving details about the product list of the last product
details, name, summary and price.
That means we need product list object.
If you scroll down, we can also iterating the product list and for each product, we are showing the
product in the partial HTML, which is the product item partial and facing the our product information,
and so on.
So that means we will develop these HTML C sharp page in the next video.
And we need a product list category list.
And also we will facing the product in the product item partial.
If you look at the product item partial you can see that this will be include all product details.
And also we need to handle add the cart operations into product list css, HTML.