In this video, we are going to develop product model page and consume the Erb API gateway and trains
with using the API catalog and I basket services.
So for that purpose, let me start the development.
I am going to remove unnecessary using statement and come to the class definitions in order to add our
primary constructors, which will be the catalog service, our basket service.
And also we need a Ilogger which is logging operations for the product list model.
I'm going to change the Ilogger operation as a product list model.
Okay.
Here you can see that we have injected required services.
Now we can start to development of the our properties.
If you come to the beginning of this class definitions I'm going to create I enumerable string category
list.
And also I enumerable product model product list.
And these are the empty lists that we can represent into our product list HTML file.
And we are iterating these objects into our HTML page.
When our listing the categories and listing the our products.
After that.
After defining these properties, we can continue our defining to HTML members.
One of the important HTML member is the selected category and we are using the razor bind property attribute.
Features and support gets as a true.
That means we will set the selected category when the application opens the page.
And now we can check these HTML object into the HTML.
If you search for the selected category, you can see that we have a Li object that we can change and
set the selected category.
When opening this product list page.
And after defining these objects, I'm going to continue to implement our methods.
We have two methods.
One is on get async and another is on post add to cart operation.
First of all, let me implement on get async method.
I am going to change the method signature which is the public async task.
I action result and name of the on get async as a parameter, we are taking string category name, so
this category name can be come from the selected category.
So in the beginning of this method we are going to get the products with using the catalog service.
Here you can see that I have used Await catalog service, get products and get products into response
object.
And just after that we can populate the category list into our object I enumerable string with using
this response object.
In here you can see that we have set the category list according to the incoming response object products
and Selectmany.
And we have selected categories under the our products with a distinct method.
That means we will select all categories and populate the category list object in this line of code.
And just after that I am going to check the Or category name is null or empty, if not null.
We will filter the products according to our category name.
Category name comes from the.
As a parameter of this on get async method that is populated from the selected category property and
we have checked these if statement.
If category name is not empty, we are going to get the products from the response object with using
the where keyword, and we are going to filter by category which contains category name and return back
the product list and populate the product list according to category name.
And just after that, we will set the selected category as a category name, which comes from the parameter
of this on get async method.
And if this category name is empty, we basically populating the product list with incoming response
object from the R Catalog Service products list and setting this product list into our application.
And lastly, we can return a page after performing these operations and complete the on get async method
operations when opening the R product list page.
And just after that we can continue develop our second method, which is the on post add to cart operation.
In here I am going to create a new method which name is on post add to cart async method and this will
be implementation of adding item into cart and why I am implement this method in this product list page.
Because if you open the HTML, you can see that we are listing the products and we are using the partial
product item partial.
And if you open this partial HTML page, you can see that this page has a form and submit the form with
the add to cart operation that we need to implement this method when submitting the product list page,
and this will be submitting this page, and we will implement these operation inside of these product
list see file.
And we will accepting product ID as a parameter.
And we will perform at the cart operations.
And first of all I am going to logging the information which is the cart button is clicked.
And just after that I'm going to get the products with a given product ID using the catalog service
Getproduct and passing the product ID and populating the R product response.
And just after that I'm going to loading a basket information.
Using the basket services and get the basket information from the await basket services load user basket
method.
And after that I am going to add a new item which is including the product response.
Here you can see that we will use basket items add method and passing the new shopping cart item model
and we will populate the product ID, product name, price, quantity and color with incoming product
ID parameter and product name comes from the product response of the Getproduct operation and get the
price from the product response again and set the quantity one and set the color as a black fixed value.
And just after that, we can send the await basket store basket and sending new store basket request
and passing the basket in here.
By this way we will send http post request in order to save this basket information in the basket.
Microservices distribute cache and database and after confirming this operation we are redirecting to
page as a cart.
So that means whenever we are adding item into cart, we will redirecting to the page of the cart operations
to see our cart in the latest status.
And after implementing this on post operation, we have completed to our product list page and we are
developing category and product list property.
And we have selected category which is the Bindable property.
And we have implemented on get async method with a given category name.
And we check the category name is null or empty is not null.
We will filter the categories and return the product list.
If the category name is null, we will return the product list with sending get product request to the
catalog microservices.
And if you scroll down, we have additional on post operation which comes from the our partial view.
And in here we are taking the product ID and we will basically perform add item into cart operation
which including the get product load user basket and store basket operations and redirecting to page
as a cart.
So after developing this page I am going to right click show me, create and build the project.
And this time we will get some of the exceptions because our HTML page is not ready for these operations.
If you open one of the exception, you can see that for example, HTML page is requiring the ID information,
but we don't have any category table and category ID.
That's why I am going to modify this HTML page according to our product model.
So according to our product model, our category list including the string object.
That's why I'm going to remove these ID operation and passing on the category name as a in here.
So after that I'm going to scroll down and see the exceptions.
Here.
You can see that we have a summary and we don't have summary property into our product list.
I'm going to change the summary to the description in here.
And after that you can scroll down and check the for exceptions.
If there is no exception I'm going to rebuild again and see if there is any exception.
Yes, there is no exception for our product list page.
And we have completed the HTML and also C-sharp file for listing the products into our client application.