In this video we are going to develop Product Detail Razor page into our client application.
So we are at this point and we will develop HTML part for that purpose.
Please open our Visual Studio and go to the shopping web and page.
Right click the page add new razor page.
Select the razor page empty template, click the add button and give the name as a product detail dot
css HTML.
Click the add button.
This will be create our product detail model.
So when I'm creating this css HTML file, I didn't see product detail as a green.
That's why I'm going to recreate from the scratch by deleting.
So I'm going to right click Add New Razor page, select Empty Template and change the name as a product
detail dot css HTML.
Click the add button.
And this time we can introduce product detail model into our HTML page.
And this is the RC file that we can populate our data from here.
So now I am going to focus on the HTML part and copy this product detail from the our ASP.Net basics
repository.
If you open this repository, you can go to the product detail page.
And you can copy from at this point and copy from the ASP.Net basics and come here and paste from here.
Save this file.
Ở đây bạn có thể thấy trang HTML của chúng tôi.
Nếu chúng ta kiểm tra trang HTML này, bạn có thể thấy rằng đây là một trang sản phẩm đơn điển hình bao gồm
tất cả các chi tiết về sản phẩm, bao gồm hình ảnh sản phẩm, tên sản phẩm, giá sản phẩm, màu sắc,
và những thứ khác.
Vì vậy ở đây bạn có thể thấy các phần ngoại lệ.
Ở đây chúng tôi sẽ phát triển mô hình sản phẩm vào trang C sharp của chúng tôi.
Và sau đó chúng tôi sẽ sửa tất cả những lỗi này để biểu diễn một sản phẩm duy nhất trong trang chi tiết sản phẩm.
Và ngoài ra bạn có thể thấy rằng chúng tôi lại thêm thao tác giỏ hàng và biểu mẫu mà chúng tôi có thể gửi để
thêm mục vào giỏ hàng mà chúng tôi sẽ xử lý trong trang chi tiết sản phẩm.