In this video we are going to develop product detail page and consume Erb API gateway and using the
API service interfaces.
This is very similar with the product list page.
And I am going to develop the same way, removing the unnecessary using statement and come to this point
and inject our recurring services.
These are the eye catalog service and eye basket service.
And also we need to inject product detail module as a Ilogger interface.
And this will be primary constructor of the three services that we are going to use when implementing
on gate and on post async methods.
And after injecting these services, I am going to define our properties.
And the first and main property is public product module product get set and default value.
This will be representing our a single product that we will represent in the product detail C-sharp
HTML file.
And just after that we have some Bindable properties which are the color and quantity that can be settable
on the HTML page.
That's why I have added these two property with bind property attributes.
After developing these color and quantity properties, we can start to implement our own gate async
method.
First of all, I'm going to change method signature according to available function.
This is the public async task I action result on.
Get async and we will get product id with value as a parameter of this get method.
And after that I'm going to implement this function which basically send http get request to our catalog
service Getproduct method.
This will be representing to calling Erb API Gateway to Catalog services with passing the product ID
and respond back to us a single product, and this is available function.
After getting the single product, we are passing this product into our product model.
Product property.
After populating our product data, we can return the page and we can completed our on gate async method.
And just after that I'm going to continue with the on post add to cart operation.
And I am going to copy and paste all method at the same way with the product list.
And this will be including add to cart operation with incoming product ID.
And this is the exact same method that we have developed into the product list.
See page.
Here you can see that we have similar method in the on post add to cart method in the product list.
So the idea is that we will put this method whenever we are submitting to add the cart operation, and
whenever we are using and submitting add to cart operation into product item partial HTML page.
So please copy also this method and available into our product detail module class.
And after that I am going to right click and build the project and validate.
Our HTML page is validate or not.
So after building the project we can see some of the exceptions.
Yes, we have two exceptions.
Regarding to summary, we don't have summary property under the property.
Instead of that I am going to using the description and just after that there is no exception.
I'm going to right click and build again.
And here you can see that this time we have built successfully and we have completed our product detail
page.