In this video, we are going to develop checkout and confirmation HTML page into our client application.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Shopping Web client application and Pages
folder.
And I'm going to right click and add New Razor page.
And we are going to create a razor page empty.
And the name should be checkout dot css HTML file and click the add button.
After creating checkout page, we can copy the HTML codes from the ASP.Net Run Basics repository.
You can open the ASP.Net run Basic repository and go to the page, checkout Csharp HTML page, and come
to this point and copy from this line of code and paste into our checkout page into the Shopping Web
client application.
And here you can see that this is the checkout HTML page of the.
Our client application and checkout page is one of the important page into our client application.
Because in the checkout page we basically check out the basket with a given information.
And this will be start asynchronous communication on behind of the scenes in the downstream microservices
basket.
Microservices publish basket checkout event RabbitMQ and it will consume from the ordinary microservices
in order to create any order and start order fulfillment process and all these end to end process starting
from the client application.
And in this page, if you look at these HTML page, you can see that these will be also including these
shopping cart item details.
Here you can see that we have seen item count.
And we will iterate the shopping cart items and representing shopping cart items into checkout page,
including the total price.
And that's why we need a cart property into our C class.
And if you scroll down, you can see actual form operation that we are going to submit this form when
checkout these operation.
And this will be performing the on post checkout operation and start asynchronous communication.
And in this form we have getting the first name last name username, email address, address, line,
country, state zip code and so on.
So in order to retrieve this information, we need to define order Bindable property into our C sharp
page.
And after getting this information at the end of this form, you can see that this will be also getting
other details.
We have a button and in this button we will submit the form with checkout order.
And when submitting the this form, we will accodomate this event into the on post checkout order operation.
And this will be basically called http post.
Request to irb API gateway and call the basket checkout operation into the basket microservices over
the irb API gateway.
So that means according to these HTML, we need order and cart property into our C sharp page.
And if you look at the client side experience after clicking the checkout button, this will be redirecting
to confirmation page for that purpose.
I am also going to create any razor page which is the confirmation page.
I am going to right click Add new Razor page and Razor empty and the name of the page is confirmation
dot css, HTML.
This page only representation of the plain HTML page to verifying the confirmation.
For that purpose, I am going to open the ASP.Net run basics and go to confirmation and copy this line
of HTML codes and come back to our actual client application and paste in here.
As you can see that this is only requiring the message information, and this will be verifying the
confirmation into our application after checkout operation.
As you can see that we have completed the HTML part of the confirmation and checkout page.
Now it is time to implement C sharp page.