In this video, we are going to develop checkout and confirmation pages and consume the AAP API gateway
endpoint with AI basket services to perform asynchronous use cases.
So for that purpose, I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement into checkout model class.
And just after that I am going to inject interfaces to primary constructor.
So here you can see that our checkout model requiring two services.
These are the AI basket services and Ilogger.
Of course I'm going to change Ilogger generic type as a checkout model, and we will perform our checkout
operation using the basket service interfaces and using the Basket services checkout basket and point
that we are going to send http post request to AAP, API gateway and basket microservices and start
asynchronous communication over the RabbitMQ that will consume by the ordering microservices.
If you go back to our actual checkout model classes, we can continue our implementation.
And I'm going to start with defining our property.
First of all, I'm going to define our Bindable property which is basket checkout model and name of
the or property as the order.
And this will be the our main property that we are going to collect.
Order and basket checkout details in the form of the basket checkout HTML.
If you open the HTML you can see the order form.
In this form we are basically getting order first name, last name, username, email address and so
on.
And these members are representing basket Checkout model into our model class.
You can go to definition of the basket checkout model.
This is located under the models folder and basket folder.
This time we will populate these basket checkout model as the name of the order property under the checkout
Csharp file.
Here you can see the order property definition and we will bind the order details in here.
And just after that also we have a property which is the shopping cart model.
And in here you can see that we basically define shopping cart cart object in order to retrieve cart
details and represent in the checkout page.
So after that we can start to implement on get async method.
First of all I'm going to change method signature.
Here you can see that our typical method signature for the available functions.
And when the checkout page is opening I'm going to populate the cart data from the basket services load
user basket method.
And just after that I'm going to return the page.
Because in this page when we are opening this page, we will see basket details including the total
price.
And after that we will loading the our order and basket checkout detail in order to start and checkout
this basket and convert this basket to the order.
Just after that we can start to implement our main operation which is the on post checkout async.
Here you can see that I have created method body which is the public async task.
I action result and the method name as a on post checkout async method.
This will be calling and triggering when we are submitting the checkout operation in the form and in
the HTML page.
So in the beginning of this method, basically I am going to logging checkout button clicked operation,
and just after that again I am going to loading the cart information with using the await basket service
dot load user basket method.
And just after that we can validate the modal state.
In here you can see that we will check the modal state.
If the modal state is not valid, we can return the page.
What is mean modal state.
If you open the checkout page when we are collecting the order data, if the data is not valid, we
have a validation errors that not acceptable empty value for this basket checkout data.
So after validating these modal state we can populate the basket checkout data including the customer
ID username and total price.
In here I'm going to type order dot, customer ID username and total price.
Since we don't have implementing any authentication mechanism, we can pass the customer ID from the
UI, which is assumption of the authenticated user.
So this is the customer ID and this is the username comes from the cart.
And this is the total price calculated from the shopping cart also.
And we will passing these values in the order which is representing our basket checkout data before
sending the data.
So now it is time to send http post request over the basket service checkout basket and passing the
new checkout basket request in a wrapper of the order data order is our basket checkout modal that we
can hit the http post request to erb.
API gateway will trigger our basket microservices and basket microservices perform actual logic for
the checkout operations, and just after that we can return the directory page of the order confirmation.
We set that after checkout this order we are redirecting to confirmation page with order submitted messages.
So this is the implementation of the on post checkout.
Under the hour basket checkout model.
And these are the properties on get async method.
And this is the inbox checkout method.
In order to complete this checkout operation and redirect the page of the confirmation.
So now I am going to implement confirmation page.
Here you can see that confirmation page including only messages to verify the confirmation.
And in here we need a message property.
For that purpose.
I'm going to go back to our c page of the confirmation and now implement our these message type.
First of all I'm going to add a message property in the beginning of this confirmation model.
And just after that I'm going to change.
And adding the on get methods.
In here we get on get contact method and also on get order submitted method.
And we will use this message your order submitted successfully.
This is the generic confirmation page where we are submitting the form.
We are passing the our operation.
In our case we are passing the order submitted when checkout order.
That's why we will hit the message as your order submitted successfully.
After developing confirmation, we can right click the Shopping Web Client application and build the
application to verify our HTML page and see our page is working fine.
So here you can see that shopping cart model does not contain a product definition.
You can see checkout HTML page.
And we are iterating the shopping cart items.
And in the shopping cart item we don't have product information.
Here you can see that we are trying to reach name and some information that we can use item dot product
name and remove product name operation.
And instead of summary we can write the item dot description or product name again.
So instead of the description we need to use product detail operation.
As a workaround I am going to pass product name instead of the description into our listing the shopping
cart in the checkout page.
After that, I'm going to right click and rebuild again and see that the build operation is succeeded
and we have completed the checkout and confirmation.
See pages.