In this video we are going to develop, order, list and contact HTML pages into our shopping web client
application.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Shopping Web and Pages folder.
Right click Add New Razor page and select the razor page empty template and give the name as a order
list dot CSS, HTML and click the add button and this will be create Order list page of the shopping
web application.
So now we are going to copy this order list from our ASP.Net basics.
I'm going to open ASP.Net basics and go to the order page.
This will be representing and listing orders.
So I'm going to copy from here and paste into our shopping web client application.
And here you can see that our HTML page of the order list model under the Shopping Web Client application.
Before explaining this HTML page, I am going to fix our layout.
As you can see that we have a layout including the headers and footers.
If you scroll down we have a orders page, but in this case I'm going to create an order list instead
of the order in order to avoid ordered models from the AR model folder.
And here you can see that I have changed the slash order to slash order list in order to navigate to
our order page.
Just after that, we can go back to our order list HTML page and start to explain these HTML.
Here you can see that this is the order list page, and this will be basically listing the orders in
a table format.
Here you can see the order columns.
And this is the for each statement for each of the order rows including the first name, last name,
email address and so on.
So this order model need the orders collection of the property into the sea page.
But before that I am going to modify this table, including the Our order model.
If you open the models and go to ordering and look at the order model, our order model includes additional
properties that we can add and adjust into the our order list HTML.
Here you can see that we have customer ID order name, shipping and billing address, payment status,
and so on.
And these are representing a different record types that including the first name, last name, email
address and so on.
So now I am going to change our order list HTML, these table rows and columns according to our order
model.
So I'm going to come here and changing these columns adding some additional columns.
Here you can see that I have added email address, line cart name and order students as an example of
to accessing the order model.
So again, it's the same way if you scroll down you can change the Or rows in the row definition.
I'm going to come here and modify this row definitions according to our columns, including the first
name, last name, email address, address, line and payment card, and the status of the order order.
So this is the implementation of the order table into order list HTML page of our client application.
And if you scroll down, you can see that we have an action which is redirecting to product with a continue
shopping button.
So we will have also additional actions for the redirection to product page.
And this is the our order listing for the HTML page.
So after developing this order list we are going to create contact page as the same way I am going to
right click the page, Add New Razor page and select the empty and select the class definition name
which is the contact dot, css, HTML and click the add button.
And this page will be only plain HTML page that we are not going to implement any action for that purpose.
Please open the ASP.Net basics and go to the contacts page, and you can copy from here and paste into
our project and contact HTML page.
And this is the HTML of the contact page.
This is regular contact page including the address and other details for our client application.