In this video we are going to develop order lists, see page and consume the Erb API gateway and print
with using AI ordering service and using the Revit Http client factory.
For that purpose we will implement the order list module.
See page.
So whenever we are using an implementing order list module, we need to inject AI ordering services.
Because this page is basically representing and listing the orders into our ordering microservices over
the arb API gateway.
For that purpose, we have to inject AI ordering services.
But we didn't register AI ordering services into our application and ASP.Net dependency injection tool.
That's why the first thing we should register AI ordering services into our Program.cs.
Please go to the Program.cs.
And in here you can see that we have registering AI Catalog Service and AI basket service.
And it's the same way.
I am going to copy this line of code and paste in here.
And this time we will register AI ordering services into our Revit client with a given base address.
And the base address is same as the.
For each catalog basket and ordering services, you can reach the application Settings.json file or
base of this is always erb API gateway docker network address.
And if you go back you can see that we have registering all these interfaces into our Revit client.
And this will be generated client.
In order to consume authentic microservices over the Erb API gateway, if you go to AI ordering services,
we can send Http get methods in order to get orders with pagination, get orders by name and get orders
by customer.
During this video, I am going to get orders by customer with a given fixed customer ID into our application.
So now we can start to implement our actual order list page.
In here I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and come to this point in order to use primary
Constructor and inject our AI ordering service, which is the ordering service.
And I am going to inject AI logger service to logging operation.
And just after that we will create our orders property in order to represent in the HTML page in here
you can see that we have a AI enumerable order module, which is the orders property with getter setter
that we are going to use in the HTML page of the order list.
When we are listing on the table here, you can see that this is not getting any exception.
Now we will iterating the table and listing the rows including the these informations.
So after defining the orders property it is time to develop on get async method and populate orders
data with integrating with the erb API gateway in here again I have an assumption about the customer
id.
Since we don't have implementation any authentication layer, we can pass the customer ID as a hardcoded
value.
You can see that I have set the customer ID with this great value, and which we can assumption that
comes from the UI authenticated user.
And just after that, we can integrate with the Erb API gateway in order to get orders by customer.
Here you can see that we are using await ordering services.
Get orders by customer method with passing these customer ID, and just after that we can set the orders
property with incoming response of these Erb API gateway.
And after populating the orders, we can listing orders on the HTML page.
Also, I am going to change method body from task to task.
I action result and return the page.
So this is the implementation of the order list.
See page and this is the getting orders from the ordering microservices using the http api gateway.
And here you can see that we have used hardcoded customer ID.
And you can get this hardcoded customer ID from the ordering microservices.
If you open the services and go to ordering microservices and go to ordering infrastructure and data.
And if you expand the extensions and go to the initial data, you can see that these customer ID comes
from here.
And we have injected and creating a customer ID when starting ordering microservices and seeding with
this data.
So this is the ID information comes from these seeding operation.
That's why we are using this ID when we are populating order list with a given customer ID.
Now we can build the shopping web client application and verify that our HTML and see page are working
fine.
So right click and build client web application.
And we have successfully build our client application.
As you can see that we have completed the razor page of the shopping web client application, including
the razor page and see page.
That means we can ready for the testing our application to consuming Erb API gateway and perform our
actions under the C3 microservices.