In this video we are going to test shopping web client application using the API gateway microservices
as a reverse proxy.
So here you can see that we will perform the our test in order to consume our downstream microservice
endpoints from the API gateway and using these data into the client application.
But before that, let's clarify our deployment strategy of the e-commerce microservices.
Here you can see that so far we have built our shopping web client application into our local environment.
That means now we need to connect to your API gateway.
And we need to Erb, API gateway, IP and port number that we can connect from our local computer.
So that means we should activate the Erb API gateway and the downstream microservices as a backing services
in Docker environment.
And we will connect these services from our local shopping web client application and perform the deployment
one.
For that purpose, please open the Our Visual Studio.
And before we start, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running.
In order to activate baking services, I'm going to right click the docker compose and set a startup
project.
And I am going to run Docker Compose without debugging.
Click this button and this will be start our docker compose without debugging and activating the backing
services, including the Erb API gateway and all microservices databases.
Distributed cache and RabbitMQ message broker.
After running the Docker compose, we can verify all microservices is up and running from the Docker
desktop.
If you open the Docker desktop, you can see the microservices and backing services are up and running.
We will interesting in the ARP API gateway, if you open the ARP API gateway, you can see that your
ARP API gateway is up and running on your Docker environment.
So you can also verify from the ARP postman if you open the postman and send to the ARP API gateway
docker URL into the ARP postman collection, and you can get the products from the Getproduct endpoint
over the ARP API gateway.
That means we will now send Http requests from our client application to the ARP API gateway.
For that purpose, we can go back to our Visual Studio.
And this is very important that without stopping this Docker compose, we should right click the Shopping
Web client application and set a startup project.
By this way we can run and activate Docker environment, and also we can run https shopping web client
application in our local computer.
And that can connect from the Docker environment.
If you stop this Docker compose you cannot connect the ARP API gateway on Docker environment.
So after setting startup project for shopping web client application, I am going to put a break points.
So if you open the page here, you can see that we have an index page.
And in the index page we have a breakpoint on get async method.
So whenever this application is starting and open a browser for the index page, we will hit this breakpoint
and retrieve the products from the catalog microservices.
And also I am going to put additional breakpoint on the on post add to cart operation.
When we are adding item into cart, we will hit the breakpoint in this method.
And after that I am going to continue with the product related page.
Here you can see the product list.
If you open the product list see page, you can put a breakpoint on get async and also you can put a
breakpoint again on post add to cart async.
And here you can see the product detail.
If you open a single product you can come to this point and put a breakpoint on.
Get async.
In order to retrieve a single product with a given product ID, and again we can add to cart operation
in here.
So after that I'm going to add a order list.
Here you can see the order list Cshtml.
And I'm going to put a breakpoint on get async method in order to get orders by customer ID.
And lastly we have a asynchronous use case which is the checkout use case.
If you open the checkout page, see our page and you can put a breakpoint on the beginning of the on
get async.
And also you can put a breakpoint on post checkout async method, which is basically start the asynchronous
communication and event driven architecture into our microservice architecture.
So after putting this breakpoints I'm going to run the application.
But before that let's remember our use cases.
According to our e-commerce application, our main use cases are listing products and categories, add
product to shopping cart, checkout basket and create order.
So we will use Yarp API gateway endpoints to perform these use cases.
And we will send requests to these microservices http, get and Post requests in different microservices.
In order to perform these use cases, I'm going to go back to our video and start shopping web client
application in https mode, and we will follow these use cases and debug our points when we are opening
browser and browsing our e-commerce client application web page here, you can see that in the beginning
of these application we are put a breakpoint on.
Get async of the Index.cshtml that we are going to retrieve the products in the landing page.
Here you can see that we are logging incoming information, and just after that we are sending http
get request to catalog.
Resources, and this is the result of the products that including nine products.
And we are going to populate the product list that will represent in the HTML page and return the page.
I hit the F5 and see that we will have a landing page, including the all products, into our microservice
architecture that comes from the catalog microservices over the ARP API gateway and representing our
shopping web client application.
When we are opening this landing page, we basically send a http get request to the ARP API gateway
and catalog microservices.
You can see these interactions from the shopping Web project console logs.
Here you can see that we have a sending logs which is the Http request.
Get to do these.
Address this including the localhost 6064 which is the Erb API gateway and catalog.
These services representing this will be redirecting to downstream catalog microservices.
And this is the endpoint that we are going to retrieve slash products and page size and page number
including and responding these products.
So we can follow these interactions from the our project console logs.
And now I am going to follow our use cases.
Our use cases are listing products and categories.
So first of all if I list our products and categories you can see that these are the products.
And if I am going to open the products page, I am also listing the products from the product list page.
And here you can see the on get async method.
And in here you can see that we again get products from the catalog microservices and populate the category
list.
And if there is a category name we can filter.
If not, we can retrieve the all products and populating the product list object.
If I hit F5, you can see the all products coming to our application.
In this page, we basically listing the products on the product list page.
You can see and scroll down and see all the products into our application.
And here you can see the applied pagination with using this element.
So if you scroll up I'm going to open one of the product which is the iPhone X, and go to the product
detail list and listing the one of the single product.
That means we are going to open product detail.
See page, and this will be retrieving the single product with a given product ID.
Here you can see that we are retrieving the single product and sending Http get request to catalog microservices
and respond back the single product into our application and the product detail page.
Here you can see the product detail page, including the all details about the iPhone X, and we can
change the color and add the quantity and add item into cart.
So now I am going to add item in the cart.
For that purpose I am going to click this button and trigger the on post add to cart async method.
So this is the post operation and submit the form in the product detail page.
That's why we will hit the breakpoint in this method, and we will passing the product id as a parameter
of this method.
In this method, we basically get the product from the catalog microservices.
And just after that we will load the user basket from the basket microservices.
This will be create new or update existing basket.
And just after that we will add items into shopping cart which including the product informations,
product ID, product name, price, quantity and color that will get these information from the client
application and our web page.
And just after that we will send http post request to store basket into the basket microservice database
and distributed cache.
And we will paste Neve store basket request and passing the our newly created basket and items added
into basket.
And I am going to send http post request using the basket services.
And just after that redirect to page cart page.
So I'm going to hit F5.
And you can see that this time we will go to the cart page just after the adding item into cart.
This is representing all the cart items into our application from the basket microservices that we can
remove item from the cart and we can continue shopping.
And we can also check out the basket that will convert this basket record to the order record.
So before proceeding to checkout, I am going to show orders.
If you click the order page, you can see that this will be.
Hit the breakpoint on the order list on get async method.
This is basically retrieving orders for this customer, and I am going to check the orders for this
customer.
If I hit F5, this will be getting orders and we have only one order, which is the order one and this
will be populating when the application start up and seeding the databases.
So now I am going to continue shopping and we will check out the basket after adding one more item into
cart.
First of all, I am going to go back to products and retrieve the all products.
And in here I am going to add new item which is a Samsung ten into cart.
As you can see that this time we will hit the product list on post async method because I am going to
hit this button in the this page.
So this will be perform exactly the same things from the other application.
In this method we basically get products for a given product ID, and after that we will load user basket
and we will add item into basket with a newly coming product ID.
And just after that again we will store basket.
That means we will send http post request.
To the basket.
Microservices.
In order to store newly adding item into basket information as a Json format, into database and distributed
cache.
And if I hit F5 and go to and redirecting to page as a cart page, and you can see that this time we
have two items into cart iPhone X and Samsung Tank.
You can also follow sending Http requests from the Project console log.
Here you can see that we will sending Http post requests when we are store basket into database.
So here you can see that this is the Erb API gateway endpoint.
And this is the basket endpoint that we are going to post request including the basket Json data.
And we will represent these two items from the Erb API gateway and basket microservices.
And after that I am going to continue checkout operation.
And this will be processed and start asynchronous communication from the are client application and
click the checkout page.
This will be opening the checkout page including the cart information.
Because on the checkout page we are listing the cart and cart details with the total price and returning
the page.
Here you can see that this is the total price and including the cart information.
We have two items and these are the prices and total price is in here.
So I am going to filling the billing and shipping address.
And if you scroll down you can see that after populating the data we will check out the order and start
asynchronous communication to creating basket checkout event to RabbitMQ that will consume from the
ordering microservices to create a new order record.
So please populate the data in the form.
I'm going to give my name as a form and giving the email as a method Metcom and address giving the random
address and select the country.
Select the state and give the zip code.
And just after that you can click these links and populate the card information.
In here you can give random credit card information and give as a expiration and CVV information.
And just after populating this data you can click the checkout order and this will be triggered on post
checkout async method.
And in this method we basically logging incoming information and load user basket.
And just after that check the modal state.
If valid or not, modal state is valid.
And just after that, we have an assumption that we are going to create a new order according to this
customer ID, and we will set the username and total price for the order, which is the basket checkout
modal.
And after preparing this basket checkout modal, we will use basket service dot checkout basket method
that will send http post requests with a given Json payload, including the order information which
is the basket checkout model, and hit the http post request to our API gateway and basket microservices
that will start the event driven communication and publish event to the RabbitMQ.
And just after that we will redirect to confirmation page which including the your order submitted successfully.
And now we can check the orders.
But before that I'm going to check RabbitMQ.
In here you can see the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
If you log into management dashboard you can see that we are publishing the event, which is a published
checkout event that will consume from the ordering microservices.
You can see queues and streams and see that our event is basket checkout event and that will publish
from the basket microservices into RabbitMQ that consume from the subscriber microservices, which is
the ordering microservices.
We can confirm the ordering microservices consume this event in order to create a new order record.
So if you go back to our client application and click the order page, you can see that we will retrieve
the orders for a given customer.
That will include now two orders into database.
Here you can see the newly ordered record that we have created from the our client application.
Also.
So if you refresh this page more than five times in ten, second rate limiting will work and you will
not return data into our application.
As you can see that we have performed end to end tests into our shopping web application.
We will listing products at product in the shopping cart and check out the basket and see the asynchronous
communication and create any order.