In this video, we are going to containerize an Orchestrate Shopping web client application in Docker
Compose.
You can see the e-commerce microservice deployment strategy that we have completed, the deployment
one, which is the local machine to connect the Docker compose backing services.
And now we are going to implement deployment tool which is the Docker compose all microservices and
backing services.
That means we will containerize and orchestrate shopping web client application and communicate with
the IRB API gateway inside of the docker compose environment.
When we are running the docker compose, Docker run the all containers into its own network and access
each other with Docker container names.
For that purpose, we should give the container names instead of the localhost and the port numbers
for the ARP API gateway configuration in the shopping web client application.
So let's get started.
I'm going to open the Visual Studio and we will start by Containerizing shopping web client application.
For that purpose you can right click the application add Docker support and select the target operating
system as a Linux.
And here you can see the Docker file is created successfully.
This is typical Docker file including several stages.
In order to containerize our shopping web client application.
I'm not going to explain deeply, and just after that we can go to the second step, which is the orchestrating
this shopping web client application.
That means we will include shopping web container into our Docker compose file for that purpose.
Again, I am going to right click the Shopping Web project file and add container Orchestrator support.
This time we will select Docker Compose as a container orchestrator and select Operating System as a
Linux.
Click the okay button and see the docker compose Yaml files.
After that, if you open the docker-compose.yml file and go at the end of this file, you can see that
shopping web application and container added into our docker-compose.yml file.
And if you expand the docker compose of HTML file and go at the end of this file, we can see that this
shopping web client application configurations are stored at the overridable file.
So now we are going to change these Overridable configurations into shopping web application according
to our architecture.
And here you can see the environment variables port numbers that we are going to modify in here.
So we should change these configurations.
Let's configure it for our microservice endpoints and start with port definitions.
If you look at our table you can see the shopping web application, port numbers, local environment
and Docker environment.
Here you can see that we will expand this Docker environment into 6005 and 6065 as a Http and Https
ports.
For that purpose, go back to our V studio and change the port numbers, exposing these 6005 and 6065
So just after that we will focus on the environment variables.
For environment variables we should referring the shopping web client application application settings
Json file.
If you open the application settings Json file, you can see that we have API settings and gateway.
Others we are using the localhost 6064 inside of the docker.
We should change this as a container name into docker name.
So for that purpose I'm going to go back to our docker compose, overwrite Yaml file and overwrite this
configuration into environment variable.
And this time I'm going to type as a API settings underscore underscore gateway address.
And this will be http api gateway and 880.
The ARP API gateway is the container name of the Docker compose environment that you can confirm.
From here.
And here you can see that I'm going to use Http and 880 port.
Why I'm using these Http and 880 port.
Because if I'm going to use 8081 and https port number, this will be throw an exception requiring SSL
connection and certification.
In order to avoid certificate configuration, I am going to use Http port number to communicate with
shopping web client application and the ARP API gateway.
So that's why we will put 880 port number to connect http port of the ARP API gateway inside of the
fully docker compose environment.
So after setting these configuration and the port numbers, we can also add a depends on section in
here.
After the deployment I'm going to add a new section which is the dependency on.
Here you can see that I have added the depends on because shopping web client application totally depends
on the Erb API gateway endpoints.
In order to consume and perform end to end use cases.
So please configure these client application as the same way I have did in here.
And within this configuration, our shopping Web client application now ready to run fully Docker compose
environment and to consume Erb API gateway and perform the use cases that we have defined in our slide.