In this video we are going to test shopping web client application inside of the docker compose environment,
and we will consume the Erb API gateway inside of the Docker environment from our client application,
which is also included in the Docker compose environment.
And we will perform these use cases into our Docker compose environment to perform internet use case
from the shopping client application in fully docker environment.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio.
And this time we are going to set a startup project in Docker Compose.
And I am going to run the docker compose without debugging.
And this will be start all microservices, including the our newly adding shopping web client application
into fully Docker environment, and we will consume the irb API gateway inside of the Docker environment
using the shopping web client application that will expose the 1665 endpoint from our local computer.
This is building shopping web client application as a container and adding into our Docker compose environment.
Here you can see that our Docker compose started successfully, and if you scroll down, you can see
that all microservices and backing services is up and running.
And also we can successfully edit shopping web client application into our Docker compose environment.
Now I am going to hit the our localhost and 6065 port in order to consume our Yarp API gateway inside
of the docker environment using the our client application.
If you type your browser https localhost 6065, you can reach the landing page of our shopping client
web application and in the shopping client application in the landing page, we are retrieving the all
products from the IRB API gateway and from the catalog microservices that you can see the logs on the
our Docker desktop.
If you open the Shopping Web client application, this will be sending Http request to this URL, which
is the irb API gateway 880 Catalog Service products with pagination.
And just after that we will continue to implement our intent use case.
First of all, I'm going to listing the products here.
You can see that we have successfully listing the products under the product list page.
And this is also listing the categories on the left hand side.
And also I'm going to select one of the product and go to the product detail page including the product
ID.
And this will be include a specific and single product details inside of this page.
And at this page we can change the color and quantity and add item into cart.
I am going to click the Add to Cart button, and this will be adding item in the cart and creating a
new shopping cart and adding item into shopping cart, which is the Samsung trend and resurrecting to
us cart page.
And I am going to continue the shopping by clicking the product list page.
And I am going to add new item which is the iPhone X into our cart.
Here you can see the go to product list and click the Add to Cart in the product list.
And this will be again redirecting to you a cart page, including the second item into basket items
into your cart page.
And just after that we can continue to checkout operation.
But before that I am going to show you orders into our application.
If you open the order page, you can see that we have only one order, including into our client application.
That comes from the ordering microservices seeding operation when startup to container.
So now we are going to continue the cart operation and I am going to check out the cart and this will
be published basket checkout event from the basket microservices that will consume from the ordering
microservices.
And we will create any order under our client application.
So let me start the checkout operation.
If you click the checkout button this will be redirecting to your checkout page including the cart details.
Here you can see that we are listing the cart details, including the prices and total price.
And here you can see the form data that we are going to fill this form in order to check out the basket
and start the asynchronous event driven communication.
So now I'm going to come here and complete all these form items with a valid data.
I'm going to give a random name, and I'm going to specify the email address.
And you can fulfill all the blank items with a valid data.
Here you can see that we have loaded all items in the checkout form that we are going to check out this
page by clicking this button, click this checkout order button.
And this will be redirecting to your confirmation page and your order submitted successfully.
That means this will be the checkout to Basket Microservices and Basket Microservices will publish the
basket checkout event to the RabbitMQ.
So after that, authentic microservices consume these events from the RabbitMQ.
First of all I'm going to check the RabbitMQ dashboard.
And in here if you go to the queues and streams, you can see that our basket checkout event is published
successfully from the basket microservices.
And this will be storing in the RabbitMQ that will consume from the subscriber system which is the authentic
microservices.
In order to verify order consume operations, we can go back to our client application and open the
order page.
Here you can see that newly adding order comes into the page.
That means this order created from the basket checkout operation for our client application.
We can again check the cart operation and this time cart is empty.
That means this card checkout from the client application and creating a new order record into ordering
microservices.
As you can see that we have successfully completed end to end test fully on docker compose environment
and sending the Http requests from our client applications.