In this section, we are going to develop discount gRPC microservices with SQLite for inter service
communication using the gRPC.
So let's check our big picture.
What we are going to build one by one.
As you can see that we are in here and start to developing discount gRPC microservices with SQLite database.
And we will build highly performant inter-service gRPC communication between discount and basket microservices.
And here you can see the internal architecture of the discount gRPC microservices.
According to these architecture we basically expose a gRPC and paint to the basket microservices with
developing protobuf files.
And these protobuf files will be implemented in C sharp application, which is our discount gRPC application
and will be trigger our business logic.
And as an application architecture we will use n layer architecture and we will communicate with database
using the Entity Framework core ORM tool.
And our database will be SQLite.
And after that we will containerize these discount gRPC microservices.
In the current moment.
So that means we can say that we will develop discount gRPC microservices.
And this will be ASP.Net gRPC API application template.
And we will build highly performant inter service gRPC communication.
And this communication will be held by the proto files.
To perform Crud operations.
We will expose gRPC services with creating protobuf message files.
And we will use SQLite database connection and conversation with discount gRPC.
And we will use Entity Framework core ORM system which using the SQLite data provider.
And this will be perform the migrations and simplify the data access and ensure the high performance.
And as an application architecture we will follow the Unlayered architecture implementation.
And finally we will containerize discount microservices with SQLite database using the Docker compose.
So now let me explain why we use these discount gRPC microservices and what is our main use case.
Our main use case is add item into shopping cart in this country RPC microservices we are going to expose
gRPC services for basket API microservices.
And when the client add item into shopping cart basket, microservices will consume this discount.
gRPC services in order to get latest discount on that product item.
That's why we will develop discount gRPC.
And the main idea of this microservices will be be performant as much as possible, because discount
microservices will synchronously call from the shopping cart.
Microservices and shopping cart will wait a response in order to calculate latest discount.
So the service invocation time will be shortest.
That means we should achieve maximum performance and reduce the service invocation time and ensuring
the discount microservices respond quickly to synchronous call from the basket.
Microservices.