In this video, we are going to create discount gRPC project into our microservices.
For that purpose, please go to the our solution and go to the services folder.
Right click the Services Add new folder and this will be the discount folder.
And inside of this folder I'm going to create a new project.
Right click Add New Project.
And this time we will use gRPC template.
If you search for the gRPC you can see the ASP.Net core gRPC service template.
If you select this template and click the next button, you can see the project name as a project name.
We will give discount dot gRPC.
After that we will define location.
For that purpose we can click this button and we can go to Microservices source folder and Services
folder.
And in here I'm going to create a new folder which will be the discount folder.
Here you can see that I have added discount in here.
And location should be at the same format in your computer.
And after that we will create discount gRPC in this location.
Click the next button and configure our gRPC ASP.Net core application.
The framework should be done at eight and we will enable Docker.
And we will operating system Linux.
And we will leave as it is for the default configurations to using top level statement and enable our
minimal APIs and click the create button in order to create our ASP.Net core gRPC application.
Here you can see that newly created gRPC located under discount folder.
We can verify from the right click open Folder in File Location, and you can see that this file is
created under Micro Services Source Services and Discount.
And here you can see discount gRPC Micro Services.
So now we will explore these gRPC project.
Let's quickly check the files.
And this project generated by default template of gRPC.
And you can see that we will check the NuGet packages under discount gRPC.
And we will check the protos folder in here.
And we will check the services folder application settings launch settings and so on.
Let me start one by one.
The first one is check the NuGet package.
If you double click the project file, you can see that the gRPC dot ASP.Net core NuGet packages already
installed and included our ASP.Net core gRPC project.
And this will be comes from the template.
And we can right click and manage NuGet packages and see installed package in here also.
And here you can see that we have two updates.
And I'm going to update these gRPC and another package.
And if you select all packages and update we can update the latest gRPC ASP.Net core package for our
ASP.Net gRPC web API project.
And after installation, you can see that our versions are updated with 2.60 and save this file.
So if you look at the our project file, you can see that there is additional item group included in
here.
And inside of this we have protobuf definition.
And this is include protobuf file location and gRPC services as a server.
So in here we can go to that location.
That location is addressing under project and under the protos file.
And we have Greta Proto file.
That means these proto folder contains proto files defining gRPC services and messages.
For example, if you double click this Greta proto file, you can see that there is a definition of
the gRPC services which name is greeter.
And here you can see the RPC method is say hello and this is the request and response for the particular
greeter services.
So we can also right click this greet proto and check the properties in the properties.
You can see that there is different configurations that we can define.
The first one is build action.
Build action is protobuf compiler.
That means when we build the application this will be create a C sharp compiler in order to interact
with the proto files and exposing gRPC services.
And here you can see the gRPC stub classes.
And this is the server only.
That means this will be generating class for the server only that we can also create client only or
client and server.
So I am leaving as it is for now and continue to build our project.
If you right click and build the project.
This time we will check all the classes that we have created from the gRPC template.
The build is complete and if you come here and select all files, if you click this link and you can
show all files after clicking this button, you can go to the object debug dotnet eight and Protoss,
and you can see the grid and grid gRPC class is generated.
And if you open this class you can see that this is the generated code.
Basically invoke the gRPC services with using these generated C-sharp client object and server object.
And this will be generated by the Visual Studio when building the application.
So if you close this one and come here and hide again this all files.
And now we can go to the services folder and you can see the greeter service C sharp class.
That means under the services folder we will include the implementation of the gRPC services such as
the greeter services.
Here you can see that our service class is inherited from the greeter base.
This is generated class from the Visual Studio.
When building the application, if you right click and go to definition, you can reach the generated
resolver object for the gRPC operations.
So if you go back to our greeter service in this service class, we basically implement gRPC methods
and perform our main use cases.
Here you can see the say hello method comes from the Greek proto file.
And we will implementation of Sayhello method in the greeter services by inheriting from generated stub
class.
And in this method we basically perform our business logic.
This will be return a hello reply to the client application.
So also we can check the application settings Json from our application.
If you double click in here, you can see that in Application settings Json.
This time we have a kestrel definition and the endpoint defaults is using the protocol as a Http tool.
So we see that kestrel configuration arranged for the Http two protocol because gRPC works on the Http
two protocol.
And lastly, we can check the Program.cs.
If you double click in here and come here.
This is the configuration of the gRPC services and sets up the Http two protocol.
And here you can see that we basically add gRPC related classes into our ASP.Net dependency injection
container.
And after that we will configure the Http request pipeline according to our gRPC services.
First of all, we will map gRPC services and add our greeter service class into the services folder.
And after that we will map the get operation.
And this is Http get operation and explaining this is the gRPC endpoint.
And you should call the gRPC client not Http get method okay.
We can see the registrations and the middleware mapping in this line of code.
And after that we can modify the project configuration.
At this point we can check the our port numbers for this gRPC microservices.
In this gRPC microservices we will use 5002 and 5053 for Http and Https endpoints for local environment.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the properties and launch settings of the
discount gRPC.
And I'm going to change this Http protocol as a 5002.
Come to Http protocol and change 5002 and come to Https profile and change Http to 5002 and Https should
be 5052.
Save this file.
After setting our application URL, we can run our application.
If you right click the discount gRPC, set a startup project and select the running profile as a Https
and click this button in order to run our discount gRPC application, our application has started successfully.
You can see the port numbers and localhost exposing in here, but this time we will use Http two protocol
and gRPC protocol in order to invoke our greeter services.
For that purpose, I am going to open postman and this time we will start with File New and we will
choose the gRPC as a preparing our endpoint.
And in here we will specify the URL which is the gRPC localhost 5052.
This is indicating our application.
And in here we can select the method.
This will be select the proto methods.
And normally we should import the protobuf file in order to reach our methods.
But this time I will look at the new API button.
And this will be seek our project and identify greeter service for Sayhello method available for now
and click this method and before invoking our gRPC server.
Make sure that you are selecting and enabling TLS.
And after that we can invoke our gRPC services on the Http two protocol.
If I click this invoke method, you can see that this response comes from the RPC services message.
Hello.
But we also specify the name information as an input.
For that purpose, I am going to send a message including a Json object and name property and we will
give dotnet.
If I click the invoke method we can see the message comes hello.
Net.
We will also debug these operations into our application.
If you come here and put breakpoint and send again invoke method.
This time you can see that we can also debug these gRPC services as usual, unlike the Http methods.
As you can see that the Discont gRPC project is now successfully set up and ready for the further development.