In this video we are going to do domain analyzing of the discount microservices.
And we will start with the domain models.
As a domain model, we can say that we have only one domain model which is the coupon.
And including the coupon model.
We have several attributes ID, product name, description and amount.
So the coupon entity represents the discount information linking to the products.
And after that we can go to the application use cases.
Our main use cases are Crud operations on discount coupon model including the get discount with product
name and create update delete discount operations.
And these use cases cover all the basic operations for managing discounts.
And along with this, we should design our gRPC methods according to these use cases.
And here you can see the gRPC methods and use cases that we are going to implement as a presentation
layer and gRPC API.
So instead of the exposing traditional Rest APIs, the discount microservices will expose gRPC endpoints.
And in discount microservices as a presentation layer, we use Http two gRPC protocol to expose these
endpoints.
Here you can see the gRPC methods that we are going to expose from the discount microservices.
These are the get, create, update and delete discount and performing the Crud use cases from our application.
And here you can see the request URIs.
That means every gRPC method will accept the request and respond back to the response object that we
can define in the protobuf file.
So gRPC services are defined using protocol buffers which are more efficient than traditional Rest API,
particularly for inter service communications.
So if you look at the infrastructure and underlying data structure of discount microservices, we can
say that we have only one data store, which is the SQLite database.
And in this database we will store coupon table in a lite databases.
So why we use SQLite database?
Because SQLite is a C language library that implements a small, fast and self-contained, high reliability,
full featured SQL database engine.
SQLite is a chosen for its simplicity and efficiency, especially for small scale data like discounts.
It is embedded within the application and reducing the need for the additional infrastructure.
And there are lots of advantages of SQLite we can use embedded within the application, providing high
performance and suitable for lightweight and straightforward operations, and it simplifies deployment
without needing a separate database server.
So this setup aligned with the need for the high performance in the discount microservices.