In this video we are going to do technical analysis of discount microservices.
Let me start with the application architecture style.
If you look at the application architecture style of discount microservices, we are going to use traditional
and layered architecture.
And layered architectures basically consists of three layers.
These are the data access business layer and presentation layer.
In data access layer, we will only database operations performed on this layer and this layer perform,
add, delete and update and extract data from the database.
And after that we can implement Business layer.
In business Layer.
We will implement business logics on this layer.
And this layer will process the data taken by the data access and implement the actual logic and actual
use cases into our project.
And after that we will implement presentation layer.
This layer includes the user interactions.
It could be Windows Forms, Web applications or console application.
But the main purpose is here to show the data to the user and transmit the data from the user to business
layer and data access.
And after that we can check pattern and principles of discount microservices.
The first pattern is we will use gRPC protobuf files and endpoints for the inter service communication.
And after that we will use Entity Framework Core for all database operations.
And we will use SQLite database which is embedded SQL database for efficient data storage.
After that, we can check the libraries and NuGet packages that we are going to use for discount microservices.
The first one is generic packages including Master and Fluent validation, and the second one is a gRPC
which is ASP.Net core gRPC.
NuGet package comes from the template.
And for database infrastructure operation we will use Entity Framework core SQLite provider.
And we will use Entity Framework Core tools to migrate our database with discount operations.
And lastly we can check the project folder structure.
Here you can see the our project folder structure.
And we are planning to create these layers.
First of all we will create models folder including coupon entity.
This will be the SQL entity.
And after that we will create data folder including Entity Framework, Core Data Context and Migration
Extensions.
And after that we will create services folder and these services folder including actual gRPC service
implementation.
And we have Protoc folder and this protos folder including gRPC exposing API in proto files.
So these are the layers that we are going to define.
And we can map these layers into the layered architecture.
So that means in models folder we can say this is the domain layer and data folder this is the data
access layer and services folder are business layer and proto folder is representing our presentation
layer.
After that we can check the deployment of the discount microservices.
Basically, we will containerize discount microservices with Docker and Docker file.
And after that implement this Docker file and update our docker compose file for running discount microservices
and SQLite database in a Docker environment.