In this video, we are going to start to developing discount gRPC microservices with creating entities.
Please open the Visual Studio.
Right click the discount gRPC, add new folder, which name is modules.
And inside of this folder I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is coupon and this will be our coupon model.
And the coupon model represent the primary data structure for discount microservices.
For that purpose, I am going to add several attributes under the coupon class.
These are the including ID, product name, description and amount.
So ID serve as a primary key in the database and product name.
Also act as a identifier for the product associated with the discount and index can be created for the
faster query operations, but we will use product name as a query for coupon table, and you can see
the description and amount is representing the discount amount.