In this video we are going to develop discount proto protobuf file under the protos folder for exposing
Crud services in discount gRPC microservices.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And now we are going to start with deleting greet, proto, file and grid services.
For that purpose we are going to go to the protos folder and remove and delete this proto file.
And after that go to services, delete the greeter services.
And of course we should also delete Program.cs and point middleware.
If you open the Program.cs you can put command in here in order to remove greeter services.
Of course, we should also remove these unnecessary using statements.
And now we can ready to create our discount proto file.
If you go to protos folder and add new item, which name is discount dot proto add new file this protobuf
file.
Here you can see the image comes for the protobuf files and now we are going to develop these proto
file for discount operation.
So which services we should expose from this protobuf file.
At this stage we can open the Or slide and see that these are the gRPC endpoints that we are going to
expose from the discount protobuf file.
These are the including Crud discount operations.
Get create update and delete discount.
And here you can see the request and response object.
To perform these use cases please open the or discount proto file and start developing our gRPC services.
It is starting with syntax definition Proto3.
And after that I am going to define the namespace with options keyword.
Our namespace is discount gRPC.
And after that we can create a package which is namespace.
For our case this is the discount.
And after that we can develop our discount proto service and the RPC methods under the service definition.
In here you can see that we have created a new gRPC service which name is Discount Proto service.
And these are the RPC functions that we are going to exposing as a gRPC protocol.
And these are the request objects that exists from the RPC functions and return back to the response
models.
So we can define these request and response models after the service definition.
For example let me start with the get discount request object.
Here you can see that these objects are only required for the product name.
And after that we can define the coupon model.
This is the generic model that we can pass for the request and response object, and including the all
attributes for the coupon, model ID, product name, description and amount and the order of the parameters
can be give one, two, three and four.
And after that we can continue to define other message types which are the including create discount,
request, update, discount, request and delete discount request.
And these are the parameters incoming parameters that accodomate our request and response object.
So let me explain these protobuf file.
So first of all the syntax statement tells the protobuf compiler what syntax we are going to use.
It is important to specify which protobuf versions we are using.
And after that the second statement is optional and it is tells the protobuf compiler to generate C-sharp
classes within the specified namespace, in our case discount gRPC namespace.
After that, we have defined the discount proto service definition.
This service definition includes four RPC methods get discount, create discount, update discount,
and Delete discount corresponding to Crud operations, and each method uses specific request and response
message types.
For example, Get Discount requests takes a product name, and returns a coupon model into response
of these.
Get discount RPC method.