In this video, we are going to generate proto service class from the discount proto file that we have
developed in the last video for that purpose.
First of all, let me check the proto file properties and we will set the actions.
If you come here and right click the Discount Proto file and click the properties, you can see the
advanced properties that we are going to set the actions in here.
The first advanced property is Build action.
As a build action I am going to select Protobuf Compiler.
Okay.
After selected the protobuf compiler, we can see that there is any attribute comes here, which is
the gRPC stub classes.
So for this count microservices I'm going to select the stub classes as a server.
Okay.
Discount microservices will be served only to expose gRPC methods into discount proto file.
After setting these properties, we should add these proto file into our project file item groups in
order to attach and generate proto file C code.
For that purpose, please go to the discount gRPC project file and double click this project file.
Here you can see that we have several item groups, but when we are setting the properties for discount
proto file, new item group comes in here including the proto path and include these folder structure
which is the discount proto file and gRPC services is server only.
So this will provide to generate C sharp proto class when building the application.
So now we can build the project if you right click and build the project.
When we built the project.
It compiles the proto file and it will generate the C sharp proto class and build complete successfully.
Now we can check the our generated class.
So if you select this gRPC project file and click the this button which is the show all files, you
can see that we have seen object folder.
And under the object folder we can go to the debug.
Net eight Protoss and you can see newly generated class for our application.
This is the discount gRPC generated from the R protobuf file.
And by this file we can use gRPC methods into our service classes in order to invoke gRPC methods and
exposing these methods using these discount gRPC class.
For example, if you open the discount class generated class and expand the messages, you can see that
get discount messages are listing in here.
And also you can check the class names that you can see Crud operations request and response object
is generated from the Visual Studio.
We can go back to our Visual Studio solution and select the gRPC and show all files again to remove
these files.
So what we have done for this video we basically create discount proto file and right click properties
and edit the properties for build action as a protobuf compiler and gRPC subclass should be served only
after that, we can see that if you double click the project file, we can see our item group edit successfully
as the same way.
And after that we build the project and see that all generated classes listing under the Our object
folder.
As you can see, that discount proto service class generated by Visual Studio and it will provide to
connect gRPC services as a server role.