In this video we are going to develop Discount service class to implement gRPC proto service methods
in our microservices.
Here you can see that now we are going to develop services folder and Discount Service class.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and locate the services folder.
And now please create a new class under services folder.
Which name is Discount Service Class.
After that, we should inherit from the Proto service class which is generated from the Visual Studio
in the last video for that purpose.
Come here and inherit from the discount proto service Dot Discount Proto service Base.
This class is generated from the Visual Studio when building our application.
If you right click and go to definition, you can see the service class and all related operations under
the service class.
These are the create, delete, gate and update discount operation.
You can go to the method call and examine the generated codes, but the idea is that this is the generated
class from the Visual Studio and exposing create, delete, gate and update operation as a gRPC method
to the outside of the world.
So that means this generated class.
You can think that this is the presentation layer.
And in order to hook up the gRPC call, we will inherit our discount service from the generated class.
And we will implement actual business logic into our service classes.
So this will be our application logic business layer that we should implement our use cases.
Our use cases will be Crud operations on the coupon model.
And we will overwrite these base methods from the Discount Proto service base class in order to implement
our specific use case for performing Crud operations on discount.
So let me start one by one.
For example, if you come here and write for the override method, and if you can see that these are
the Overrideable method that we can use from the inherited generated class.
For example, if I click the get discount that means we can override this method when gRPC call comes
from the our microservices.
So now we will perform these operations one by one.
I'm going to start for the get discount and continue with the our other operation which is the create
discount.
And after that we will override for the update discount.
And lastly we will override delete discount method.
So here you can see the implementation of the Discount Service class.
We will implement these functions interacting with databases.
For example for get discount operation we should add the todos statement in here.
Get discount from the database.
Because this class is application logic layer for handling use cases to perform Crud operations.
But before that, let's understand how gRPC services exposes from the discount microservices and how
can we trigger these methods with making gRPC calls?