In this video, we are going to configure discount gRPC service to our request pipeline in the Program.cs.
And we will invoke our gRPC call.
So as you can see that under the services we have developed the discount service.
And in order to activate these discount servers for exposing gRPC calls, we should map the gRPC service
in the Program.cs to configure the Http two request pipeline.
Please open the Program.cs.
And here you can see that we have already added services into container gRPC services.
And here you can see that we will configure Http request pipeline according to our discount service
gRPC services.
So for that purpose I'm going to open this command line.
And instead of the greeting service we are going to write in here discount service.
By this way, we can make ready this application to accommodate incoming gRPC calls, and we will specifically
invoke discount proto methods, RPC methods with gRPC calls.
And this will be trigger our discount services.
Because we have configured our services in the ASP.Net Http request pipeline.
For that purpose, I'm going to come here and put breakpoints into the each method for gRPC calls,
and we will understand how we can trigger and invoke these methods using the discount gRPC microservices.
Now we can run our application.
If you come here and run https mode, this will be start our discount gRPC microservices.
You can see that our application has started successfully.
And now listening on the localhost and 5052.
And we will use gRPC protocol in order to send Http two requests with gRPC calls.
So that means now our application ready to accept gRPC calls.
How can we invoke a gRPC method into our application.
Of course we will use postman.
Please open the postman in here you can see that we have using the greeter say hello method when invoking
gRPC method.
But now we will invoke our discount service methods.
So as you can see that I have created a separate collection because postman is not accepting Http and
gRPC methods at the same collection.
So I have created new collection and now we are going to create a new method.
If you right click and duplicate this, say hello.
So now we are going to make that this will be discount service.
After that we can select the gRPC method.
If you come here and you can see that this is say hello.
We would like to change the service definition.
If you click this button you can see that we can use different schema or import a proto file.
I'm going to import a proto file and we can choose a file from the our repository.
So if you come to your project file.
Under the repositories.
I'm going to define each of microservices source services discount discount, gRPC protocol and Discount
Protocol and click the open button.
This will be import our discount gRPC methods.
And after that you can come here.
And if you close this response and scroll down you can see the next button comes in here for the service
definition.
Click the next button.
And this will be import as an API.
And we can use that import discount API as a new API and import as API.
So now we can come here and select the get discount methods are available now.
So in here for example I'm selected the get discount.
And after that we can invoke as a gRPC call.
Please save this gRPC call and click the invoke button.
This will be suddenly trigger our discount service get discount method that you can see in here.
Breakpoint.
Hit from the gRPC call that we invoke from the postman so you can continue our code.
And this will be throw an exception because we didn't overwrite yet for that purpose.
This is throwing an exception.
And you can see that the status code is 12 unimplemented.
So you can test the other methods for the other create discount and other Crud operations.
You can see that this is very fast to invoke our discount service, because this time we will use Http
two protocol and gRPC call.
It is very performant for inter service communication.
Again, you can see that each method returning unimplemented response that we are going to implement
these methods into our discount services.
So after verifying these invocations, we can save the discount service method on the gRPC.
And you can create any discount gRPC collection.
So now it is time to implement our actual discount service method in override functions in order to
interact with database using the ORM system.