In this video we are going to install Entity Framework core and SQLite database connections in discount
microservices.
As you know that when we are analyzing underlying data structure of discount microservices, we said
that we have one data store which is the SQL database.
In order to store coupon table in a lite database SQLite database chosen for its simplicity and efficiency,
especially for small scale data like discounts, and also it is embedded within the application, reducing
the need for additional infrastructure to implement SQLite database into our discount.
Microservices.
We should install some of the NuGet packages, including Entity Framework, core, SQLite and Entity
Framework Core tools.
So as a ORM system, we will use Entity Framework Core when communicating the SQL database.
That's why we should install SQL Lite Data provider for Entity Framework core into our ASP.Net applications.
Please open the Visual Studio and right click the discount gRPC and manage NuGet packages.
And we are going to install Microsoft Entity Framework core dot SQLite database.
To communicate with the SQLite, please install this database, click the exit button and install this
package.
You can verify by double click to your project file and see that our SQLite ORM NuGet packages installed
successfully.
We can save this project file, and after that, the next thing we should do that we should create a
data folder in order to encapsulate data related operations.
In here, if you right click and create a new folder, add new folder.
Which name is data.
This will be represent our data access layer according to our n layer architecture implementation.
And in this class we are going to create a new context class.
Which name is Discount Context to perform database operation in this context.
So basically we will create discount context object inherited from the DB context object.
This comes from the Entity Framework core and this is typical DB context object.
In the Entity Framework core db context classes, we should define the table name as a property.
So you can see that we have one model as a coupon.
So we should create coupon table as a DB set property under the Discount Context class.
For that purpose, I have added the DB set coupon as a coupon table property of the Discount Context
class, and after that, we should also provide the constructor which is inherited from the base constructor.
Passing the options.
In here you can see that we will create a discount context constructor and this will be passing the
Discount context DB context option to the base.
So this is typical context object from the Entity Framework core.
And this class is a DB context class that maps to our SQLite database and coupon table.
Specifically table represent the coupon entity and after that we can configure these Discount context
object from our Program.cs and application settings to communicate with the SQLite database.
First of all, let's add connection string to Application settings file.
If you open the application settings file, we can add a connection string in here.
Since SQLite is an embedded database, the connection string is simple and typical, just the data source
of the file path.
For that purpose, I am going to add a connection string in the beginning of this file, and in here
you can see that connection string.
And we put database string.
And this only including data source and database name.
That means SQLite database located inside of our application server.
So when we give data source as a discount DB, this discount DB SQLite database will create a new database
into the root directory of our application.
And we will see a discount db SQLite database under the discount gRPC project file.
After that we can continue configuration part.
We will configure the application with using the Discount Context object.
And this will be communicate with SQLite database.
And this configuration should be done in the program case.
Please open the Program.cs and we are going to locate before building the application.
And we will add services into dependency injection container.
So in here I'm going to add DB context object which comes from the Entity Framework core with communicating
with the SQLite database, with passing the options as a use SQLite and giving the connection string
into the parameter of the SQLite extension method.
So in here, first of all, we will use a db context method which is used to register our discount context
object with Entity Framework Core, and we will specifying that SQLite database will be the database
provider for our discount gRPC application.