In this video, we are going to create a SQLite database using Entity Framework Core tools in discount
market sources.
For that purpose, I am going to install Microsoft Entity Framework Core Tools NuGet packages into our
application.
But before that I would like to explain one important thing.
I am using Visual Studio as an IDE when developing our micro services, we always using Visual Studio.
So when we are using Visual Studio, we should install Microsoft Entity Framework Core tools NuGet packages
in order to run Entity Framework commands like Add Migration Update Database into the Package Manager
console.
Because Visual Studio has Integrated Package Manager Console that we can run direct commands into the
Package Manager console with installing tools packages.
But if you are using dotnet CLI or any other IDE like Visual Studio Code that has not package Manager
console inside of this IDE, that means you should download dotnet tools install command first of all
globally, download dotnet f commands into your computer and it also requires to Microsoft Entity Framework
Core Design packages.
And after adding this package you can run add migration or update database command running the net F
migration command or net f database update commands.
So this is very important.
And please consider this according to your Entity Framework core usage I am using Visual Studio.
So I'm going to install two library to interact with Entity Framework Core and add Migration and update
database.
So please open the Visual Studio and right click the discount gRPC and manage NuGet packages.
For Visual Studio, we should install Entity Framework Core Dot tools for that purpose.
Please browse this NuGet package and install into your discount gRPC.
Except.
And if you double click the project file, you can verify that this time we have two Entity Framework
packages, one for the SQLite data provider.
And we have also installed tools packages in order to add migration and update the database.
Save this project file and after that we can start to run our commands that we seen in the slide here
you can see that we will create add migration and update database.
Add migration command.
Basically scaffold a migration to create a initial set of tables for the model and the update database
command.
Create the database and applies the new migrations into the database.
So we will follow these commands for that purpose.
Open the Visual Studio.
And this time I'm going to open Package Manager Console.
If you come here you can see the Package Manager console comes in here.
And make sure that your default project is discount gRPC.
Here you can see that you can select the default project.
And we are going to run this commands under the discount gRPC.
So this is important.
And after that we can run the add migration command with a giving the name migration initial create.
So this command create a new migration which name is initial create based on the our model defined in
the discount context object.
If you hit enter, you can see that this will be.
Create a migration folder under the our discount gRPC and we will see the model up and down methods
in here.
Here you can see that migration folder is created.
And in the migration folder we have a initial create C class.
And in this class we have two primary methods.
These are the up and down.
In the up method we basically define the database schema change that we apply.
And in the down method we basically revert back the changes defined in the up method if we need it.
So this is the migration file.
And after created migration file we can go to the second step which is the create database.
For that purpose I am going to open a package manager console again.
And this time we are going to run the command which name is update database.
And this will be apply this up method into the our database.
And if I hit the enter this will be.
Apply this migration to the database and creating necessary tables and structures as defined in the
migration file.
And here you can see the logs.
This will be executed DB command.
And this will be basically create a new coupon table into our SQLite database.
After running the update database command you can see a newly created file which name is discount DB
under the our discount gRPC project and this is under the project directory.
And you can see this country be created on our project directory which is the SQLite.
And it is a good fit for simple and performant data operations.
But this is not a good way and not best practice to open package manager console and run the add migration
and update database command.
Instead of that, we should auto migrate database on application startup because when we containerize
this discount microservices with Docker, how can we run these commands when container is up and ready
for that purpose?
Entity Framework Core provide a very good feature like auto migrate the database model when the application
start up.