In this video, we are going to see an auto migrate SQLite database using the Entity Framework core
in discount microservices.
That means we will ensure created SQLite database and running migration classes.
When the application start up.
For that purpose, please go to the Discount Context class under the data folder.
And this time we are going to overwrite all model creating and after constructor come here and create
a new function which is the on model creating function.
And basically in this function we will use model builder object to see it initial data.
For that purpose I am writing Model builder dot entity and we will specify the coupon entity and we
will use has data method.
By this method we basically add some new coupons when the application start up as a initial data.
Here you can see the the whole implementation.
I have added two coupon and the first one is ID, one product name iPhone description and the amount
is 150.
And the coupon two is in located in here.
So that means with using the has data method, we basically see the database with initial coupon entries.
And this is important to have some data when application start up for the first time.
After saving these context class, the next thing we will focus on auto migrate SQLite database to ensure
these DB is created and migration codes are running when the application start up.
So for that reason I'm going to create a new class under the data folder which name is extensions.
Because we are going to develop an extension method to auto migrate our database.
And in this extension method, we basically make this class static in order to create an extension method
for the I application builder.
So we will create use migration extension method for automating database migrate operations.
Here you can see the signature of the method use migration extension method from the I application builder.
And in this method we basically create a scope in the beginning of method.
So this scope will be help to us getting our db context object.
The scope is creating from the application builder, and after that we can reach the db context object
which is in our case discount context.
Here you can see that we are using word db context, and this time we will using the scope that we have
created in this line of code.
And with using this scope, we can reach the discount context with running the get required service
method.
So in this method we will get the db context object which is the discount context.
And after that we will perform the migrate auto migrate operation with running the DB context database
that migrate async method.
If you read the documentation of the migrate async method, you can see that this method provide asynchronously
applies any pending migrations for the context to the database, and it will also create the database
if the database not already exist.
So this is very powerful database method which provides to ensure created database and also apply the
migrations in the migration folder.
And after that we can return app to complete our extension method.
And after developing this extension method, we can register and use these migration extension method
into Program.cs.
If you open the Program.cs, we will utilize this extension method in the Program.cs and after the building
the application, we can configure the Http request pipeline.
So in the first line of this code App.use migration extension method in here we are using the app dot
use migration method.
In the beginning of the configuring Http request pipeline.
So placing this extension method at the start of the Http request pipeline, ensure that the database
migration occurs before application start up processing and before accepting any requests.
So please save this Program.cs.
And after that, we can remove the migration folder and discount database into our application.
And now I'm going to remove existing migration folder and discount database that we have created in
the previous video.
And we will reflect the changes to our discount context.
Because whenever we change Discount context class, we have adding a new method in here.
We should also delete the migrations and recreate the migrations in order to reflect the newly adding
haste data operations.
For that purpose, I'm going to delete migration folder and also I'm going to delete discount DB.
This time.
This will be create automatically when the application start up.
Okay after deleted these operations.
So basically we will perform any migration operation to create migrate folder again for that purpose
please open the Package Manager console and select the default project.
Discount your PC and run this command.
Add migration initial create hit enter.
This will be build the application and create a migration folder.
And in here again you can see the app method, but this time in app method we have created coupon table
and after that we will insert the seeding database.
Data operations comes from the discount context that all model creating.
So now we are ready to update database.
But this time I'm not going to run update database command using the package manager console, because
in the program.cs we have developed use migration extension method to handle the database update operations.