In this video we are going to test our seeding and auto migrate operations SQLite database.
For that purpose, I'm going to open the Program.cs and put breakpoint in the use migration extension
method.
Also, we can go inside of this method and put additional breakpoint.
And after that I would like to put breakpoint under the data discount context class and put a breakpoint
on the on model creating overwrite method.
And we will see how we can add initial data into our coupon table.
So after that we can run the application.
As you can see that we have created migration folders in the previous video.
And according to migration folders we will run this up method.
When the application start up in up method, we basically create a coupon table and also we will insert
some initial data.
So please run this application as a https mode and see how we can seeding and auto migrate our database.
You can see that the first thing is comes our use migration extension method before accepting any request
from the external systems.
So inside of this method you can see that we will create a scope.
After creating the scope we basically get required services which is the discount context object.
When we reach the DB context object we can run db context database migrate async method in order to
migrate this folder up method to create new database and create coupon table and insert and seeding
our newly created records.
So when we are running the migrate async method, it is start to run migration up method.
And in this up method you can see that we will basically insert initial data and this will be trigger
our discount context overwrite on model creating method.
And in this method we basically adding two items into coupon table.
And after that we will continue the Margate operation with creating table and initial insert data.
And this will be provide additional details and creating our table in a schema format.
If you hit the F5 this will be performed the Margate and Seed operation.
If you open the project console window, you can see the logs that we are going to run create table
command on the SQLite database.
And after that we will insert some predefined and seeding database in here.
This is the insert into statement for the first record.
And this is the second record insert into statement.
So that means we have successfully created our database.
And you can see the discount DB is created successfully under the our project folder.
And after that we can see that our migrate SQL commands is running on that database.
So now let's check the database tables and rows on the database window.
So how can we check this data inside of the SQLite database.
We should download db browser for SQLite.
Here you can see that db browser for SQLite.
If you go to this address, you can see the official home of the DB browser for SQLite.
So please download this application into your computer.
And after that we will explore the tables and rows and make sure that when you are installing these
application, adding the shortcut on your desktop or taskbar.
Otherwise I can find the application location.
So this is a quick tip.
And after install the application I have already installed before, you can open the SQLite for DB browser.
And in here I am going to drag and drop for our discount DB.
If you select this discount DB and go to the our browser which is the SQLite browser and put in here.
You can see that now we can actually see our tables listed under our SQLite database, which is the
discount DB.
If you come here and select the discount, you can see the properties.
And in order to browse data you can select the table and click the browse data.
And here you can see the two newly created data comes from one the application startup of the discount
microservices.