In this video we are going to develop discount service class to implement gRPC proto service methods.
So far we have exposed gRPC services with developing the protobuf files and we will generate C sharp
class to accommodate incoming requests into our application.
And also we have set up our SQLite database and Entity Framework core ORM tool to communicate with the
SQLite.
And we have created Discount Context class.
And now we will implement the actual logic which is the Crud operations on the discount service class
with communicating Entity Framework, core and SQLite.
And we will inject the Discount Context Entity Framework Core Object into service class in order to
interact and perform Crud operations with database.
Of course, this will be automatically incoming gRPC request and perform database operations.
Open the Visual Studio and go to the discount gRPC services folder and open the Discount Service class.
In this class, we basically inherit from the Or generated C sharp class from the protobuf file.
And also in this class we are going to inject two services.
These are the discount context which is the db context object and ilogger classes.
So that means we will inject discount db context object to performing database operation.
And we have injected Ilogger used for the logging purpose.
Okay.
Now we can start to implement our main methods of discount proto contract file.
Here you can see that the first method is get discount and this is Overrideable method comes from the
R base class which is generated from the discount protobuf file.
And we have overriding all the functions in this class to implement an academy incoming requests and
communicate with database and perform these Crud operations.
So for that purpose, let me start with the get discount operation.
And first of all I am going to create a coupon object.
And we will retrieve this coupon object from the database using the DB context object and DB context
is our discount context.
That is the Entity Framework core ORM tool.
And now I am going to reach the coupons.
And after that, after reaching the coupons, we can use first or default async method in order to get
coupons with a given product name.
Here you can see the R filter operation.
We will basically check the product name from the incoming request object.
Here you can see the incoming request object, including the product name that we have confirmed from
the Discount Proto file.
If you open this Discount proto file, you can see the get discount method, getting the get Discount
request object.
And in this object we can reach the product name.
So by this way we can test the product name in here.
And we will filtering the coupons as per the product name.
And after that we will check the coupon is null or not.
If coupon is null that means there is no discount to our SQLite database.
We will create any fake or dummy coupon object because instead of throwing an exception, we would like
to continue to use case of the add item in the shopping cart.
For that purpose, we have created new coupon with a given property product name as a no discount.
And the important property is amount is zero and description is no discount.
Description.
So this is for null case.
If there is no any coupon and discount into our SQLite database and if not null, we will basically
return our coupon object.
But how we can return this coupon object?
We have to convert this coupon object as a coupon model.
Because again the get discount method return back to coupon model.
We can confirm from the Discount Proto file.
And this is returning the coupon model and including the all information of the coupon object.
For that purpose, we will go back and convert to our coupon object, which comes from the Entity Framework
Core Entity object that need to convert to our coupon model.
If you right click and go to definition, you can see that this is the generated C stub class from the
R protobuf file that we should return this coupon model from our methods.
So if you go back to our discount service now I am going to using the adapt method which changing our
coupon to the coupon model and return back to the coupon model.
And after that of course we forgot the logging operation with using the logger.
So before return back to our coupon model, I basically logging with log information with including
the discount is retrieved for product name and passing the product name and amount with the incoming
coupon, product name and amount from the SQLite database.
So as you can see that we have implemented the get discount method.
And this method basically queries the coupon table for a matching product name.
If no coupon is found, it returns a default coupon model indicating no discount with zero amount value.
If we found any value, we will return this coupon object with converting the coupon model.
And if you look at this line of code.
You can see that we forgot to install one of the package, which is the Napster, when adapting our
coupon to coupon model.
So we should install the Napster NuGet package to simplify this mapping operation and using the adapt
method for our classes.
How can we install maps to NuGet packages?
Normally, when we are developing any microservices, we will get reference from the building blocks
that include all common NuGet packages, including the map sir.
But discount gRPC is not a typical microservices.
For that reason, we shouldn't inherit from the building blocks.
Instead of that discount, focus on the performance.
That's why we have to install maps in here and avoiding some unnecessary packages into discount gRPC.
Right click and manage NuGet packages and browse for the maps there and install maps package into our
discount gRPC by manually.
And if you double click, you can verify that our mapper comes in here and save this file.
And if you go back to Discount services you can now add a using statement for the map store operation.
Now we have finished the get discount method implementation.
And we can test this method with sending the gRPC call.
For that purpose, I'm going to run discount gRPC as a https mode.
And after that we will send get discount gRPC call and we will debug this operation.
Our application has started successfully with running the migrations before starting the application.
And now this will be ready for the exact gRPC calls.
For that reason, please open the postman and open the discount gRPC collection and go to Discount Service.
Here you can see the are connected discount service and we will hit the create Discount gRPC call.
Before invoking this method, we should arrange the message according to our request object.
If you look at our discount proto file for the get discount operation, it is expecting get discount
request for that purpose, we should send the product name into the Get Discount Request object when
calling the get Discount RPC method.
And in here, it is important to send product name as the same format because this message should be
match.
Exactly.
That means this is the case sensitive and we will send the product name as the same format.
Please open the postman and we will send get discount method for that purpose.
Select the method name as a get discount and after that change the payload with the product name.
P is lowercase and is uppercase.
And our product name is iPhone X, and we will retrieve these iPhone X coupon from the SQLite database.
And please click the invoke in order to invoke our gRPC method.
Here you can see the get discount method is triggered, and if you come to the request object, you
can see the product name comes as a iPhone X.
And the first thing we should do that we will retrieve this product into our database using the Dbcontext
object.
Here you can see the coupon is not null.
That means we found a coupon and discount information and the amount is 150.
And after that we will log the information.
And in here we will convert our coupon object from the coupon model.
And after that we will return back the coupon model our gRPC client.
Here you can see that we can successfully get the response from the gRPC method retrieving this information
from the SQLite database.