In this video we are going to develop great discount method in our discount service class.
So as you can see that the first method is done and now we are going to develop the second method to
create discount method.
So this will be Academy incoming gRPC request and perform the database operation and return back to
the gRPC client with coupon model.
So here you can see the method signature.
And this signature is aligned with the Our discount profile.
If you open the discount profile you can see that this is the RPC create discount.
And this will be get the create Discount request.
And in this request we are expecting coupon model complex object.
And in this complex object we are expecting all members for the coupon object.
And after that this will be returned again.
Coupon model with including all Coupon Object members.
So for that purpose please go back to Discount Service and locate the Create Discount method and remove
the base statement.
Now the first thing we should do that we should get the incoming request object and reach the coupon
object from converting the our coupon to the Request Coupon object.
So in the Request coupon, you can see that this is the coupon model.
And we will add up this coupon model into our coupon object in order to save into this our table.
So after that we will check that is this coupon is null or not.
If two coupon is null, we basically throw an exception.
Since we are implementing gRPC method, we will sending throw new RPC exception and providing the status
and status code is a invalid argument and we will pass the message invalid request object.
So this is the throwing guard for our method implementation.
And after that, if the coupon is not null, we can perform the database insert operation for the create
discount method.
So this is very easy.
We will use Dbcontext coupons add method and adding the coupon object into our coupons array.
After that we will perform await Dbcontext save changes async method.
In order to reflect these changes into database.
Of course, we should make this method as an async method to use available functions in here.
So after that we will basically log this operation log.
Successful message for completing create discount operation Logger.log information discount is successfully
created and we will provide the product name which incoming coupon object as a product name.
And lastly, we will return back to our client with the Coupon Model object.
For that purpose, we need to again adapting changes to our Coupon to coupon model and return back the
coupon model to the gRPC client.
And here you can see the implementation of the Create Discount method.
In this method, we basically use Entity Framework core DB Context object and create new coupon into
our discount database, which is the SQLite database.
Before testing the application, I would like to emphasize one thing which is the logging operation.
Here you can see that all methods we are using the logger log information.
That means we will logging our methods for information level.
But if you open the our application settings of the discount gRPC, you can see that log level is warning
for the ASP.Net core namespaces.
Log level is warning.
That's why we cannot see logs for our method operations.
I'm going to copy the information for default value and changing ASP.Net core log level to Warning to
information and save these application settings Json file.
So now we can ready to test our create discount and see our log information to the Our Project Console
window.
In order to run this application, please click this button and run the Https mode.
And this will be start up our application and Accodomate incoming gRPC call for create discount.
And here you can see that our application has started successfully.
Now we can open the our postman and in the postman.
This time we are going to use create discount method.
And in this method we have to change this payload.
So if you open the our Visual Studio and go to the Discount Proto file, and we can see the our payload
into create discount which is the create discount request.
It is expecting coupon model as a coupon name.
The naming is very important.
And in the coupon model we should specify these parameters into our payload.
For that purpose, please go back to our postman.
And in here I'm going to prepare a payload.
The coupon name is coupon is the same with the proto file.
And inside of this coupon I'm providing product name, description and amount.
And the ID will be generated by the SQLite automatically.
And this is the create discount payload.
We are going to invoke this payload and invoke our create discount operation.
And inside of the request you can see the request including the coupon object.
And in the coupon we can specify the amount, product name and description information.
So with incoming coupon object we basically convert the our coupon object for the Entity Framework Core
entity.
If coupon is not null, we will basically add this coupon into our coupon.
Dbcontext and save this change into database, and after that log the information to perform successfully
and return back to gRPC client with converting again coupon model and go back to response to our application.
Here you can see the response comes to our create discount.
And this time newly created ID comes as a three.
If you open the Project Console window, you can also confirm that this time we can log our operations
successfully.
Here you can see that the information log comes as a discount is successfully created and the product
name is new iPhone 15.
Also.
Lastly, we can confirm from the database if you select the discount tab and drag and drop to our SQLite
browser, you can see the tables come in here.
We can browse the data with selecting the table as a coupons.
And here you can see that newly created coupon item is comes into our database.