In this video we are going to develop update discount method.
So this is very similar with the create discount method.
But this time we will expect the ID information when request coming in.
Here you can see the update discount and update discount request also accepting the coupon information.
But this time we will expect the ID information in order to update these values.
So if you go back to Discount service, I'm going to copy the whole code from the our create discount
and paste into the update discount method.
And in here the first line of codes are similar.
We will check the coupon and if coupon is null we will send the exception and the second line of code
we will change when interacting database.
First of all, I'm going to change the coupon add method to the update method.
So this will be update coupon information with the existing value into database.
And after that we will make this method as an async method to perform changes to the database.
And when we are logging this information, we will change successfully created to the successfully updated.
And also the product name passing in the same value from the coupon object.
And lastly, we will respond back with converting to coupon model.
In this update discount method, we basically use Entity Framework core DB Context Object and update
existing coupon into our discount database.
So now we can start to test our application.
Please run the discount gRPC application.
And after that we will send with the postman.
So if you open the postman after running the application you can come here and change the method name
as a update discount.
But this time I'm going to paste the ID information in here.
I'm going to change the whole payload and adding the ID information and changing the value as a updated
value for product name, description and amount.
So this is the latest payload for the update discount operation.
And if we invoke this operation this will be trigger update discount method.
And if we continue the debug we will basically convert to our coupon object.
And after that update the coupon object using the Dbcontext coupon update method and reflect the change
to the database.
And after that, log the information and return back to the coupon model to the gRPC client application.
Here you can see the updated values comes into our response.
In order to verify this, we can open our database and locate the third row.
If you refresh this coupons table, you can see that values has changed with the updated values including
product name and description.