In this video we are going to develop the late discount method.
Please go to Delete Discount method and in here you can see the request and response object.
And if you look at the Discount Proto file we can see the delete discount RPC method accepting delete
discount request.
And in this method you can see that message only accepting product name.
And the response is only returned a boolean success or not.
So if you go back to our implementation, we can start to implement our delete discount.
The first thing we should do that we are going to retrieve the coupon information from the database
with a given product name.
And of course this method should be async and perform the available functions.
And these available functions is getting the coupons.
And we will get first of all default coupon with a given product name from our delete discount request
object.
And after that we can check the coupon is null or not.
If the coupon is null, that means there is no any coupon information to the database.
We will throw an exception which is the RPC exception, and we will pass new status and status code
is not found and the message is discount with product name is not found.
And we will passing the product name with incoming request object.
And after that if coupon is not null, that means is there any coupon in the database.
We basically perform Dbcontext dot coupons, dot remove and passing the incoming coupon object from
the database, and we will perform delete operation with running the Dbcontext dot save changes async
method.
And after performing the delete operation we are logging log information.
That is, the discount is successfully deleted and product name is given product name into the request.
And lastly, we will return back to the RPC client as a return new delete discount response and passing
the success property as a true.
So this is the implementation of the delete discount method.
In this method we basically use Entity Framework Core.
First of all, we retrieve existing coupon information.
If not exist, we will return an exception.
After that, we use DB context object to remove and delete existing coupon into our discount DB database.
So now we can run the application and test these delete discount method.
So after running the application you can open the postman and in the postman.
This time we will change the method name as a delete discount and as a delete discount method.
We basically pass the message as a including only the product name, which is the updated new iPhone.
I'm going to remove newly added and updated this product name for that purpose.
I have changed the payload as a.
Including on the product name with P is lowercase and is uppercase, and the name of the iPhone is exactly
same.
What including in the database.
And if you invoke these gRPC requests, this will be trigger or delete discount operation.
And in here we basically retrieve the incoming product name into database.
Into coupon is found here you can see that we found coupon is successfully.
This is the information.
And after that we will remove this coupon into coupons array using the DB context and save changes async
method and log the information and return back to delete discount response with a success message,
which is a true.
If you hit F5, you can see that there is a success.
True response comes to our gRPC client.
If you open the Project console window, you can see that we have successfully log delete operation
with a given product name.
And if you open the our database and if you refresh this table, you can see the third row will be disappeared.
And here you can see that we have successfully delete our record into our database.