In this video we are going to containerize discount gRPC microservices with Docker.
Here you can see that our discount gRPC microservices using the SQLite database as a backing services.
But SQLite database located inside of our application server and not connecting from the Docker backing
services environment.
For that purpose, we will containerize our discount microservices, including to our SQLite database,
and we will containerize with using Docker and continue with the Docker compose environment.
The first step is Containerizing application server for that purpose.
Please open the RV studio and right click the discount gRPC.
You can click the Add Backer support and target operating system should be Linux.
And here you can see the generated Docker file from the Visual Studio.
And as you know that this Docker file including different layers including the the first layer, will
be retrieving the base image, which is using the ASP.Net runtime image version eight.
And this will be exposed 8080 and 8081 ports.
And we will set up the building stage.
In here we build the environment using the dotnet SDK image, and we basically create a publish layer
with running the dotnet publish command.
And lastly we will creating a final Docker image layer and defining Entrypoint with dotnet discount
gRPC dll.