In this video, we are going to orchestrate the second gRPC microservices with Docker Compose.
That means we will modify the Docker-compose.yml file in order to include the discount gRPC service.
So discount gRPC service is defined similarly to other services with its own Docker file.
You can open the Visual Studio and you can see that we have created our Docker file.
And now we are going to add container orchestrator support.
Please select the discount gRPC project.
Right click add and this time we will select Container Orchestrator Support and choose Docker Compose
and Target.
Operating system should be Linux.
And after click okay we can go to the Docker compose Yaml file and see that this time discount gRPC
is generated under the our microservices.
And this is the Docker-compose.yml file and discount gRPC added like other microservices indicating
the Docker file, which is the discount gRPC docker file.
After this definition, we should also check the docker compose overwrite Yaml file.
Here you can see the docker compose of retinal file and this file used for the settings environment.
Specific configurations like ports, environment variables, and volume mappings.
If you scroll down and go to end of this document, you can see that discount gRPC configurations also
generated in Docker compose of HTML file.
But we need to modify these configurations with the port numbers and environment variables.
So if you look at our slide you can see that for discount microservices we will follow the 6002 and
6062 ports for Docker environment.
For that purpose, if you go back to our Visual Studio, we can configure our port numbers according
to our slide.
And also we should add some environment variables.
For the environment variables we can check the application settings of the discount gRPC.
If you double click application settings, you can see that we should overwrite connection settings
database and these data source operation which is the SQLite discount DB database.
And we will also add these database connection strings and add the environment variable for discount
gRPC.
To perform these configurations, I'm going to add a new environment variable and change the port numbers.
Come here and I'm going to paste new configurations including the connection settings in the environment
variables.
Here you can see that for this country RPC, the SQLite database is configured with the connection string,
data source and discount DB which is the SQLite database.
And this points to SQLite file within the container.
That means, unlike the other services using the PostgreSQL and other databases, discount gRPC uses
an SQLite database which doesn't require a separate database.
Services.
The database file is managed within the discount gRPC container itself.
After the environment variables, we have set the port numbers according to our slide.
So for port numbers we use 6002 for Http and 6062 for Https in Docker environment.
So within this configuration we can say that the discount gRPC microservices is now part of our Docker
compose orchestration files.