In this video we are going to test Docker compose discount gRPC microservices with SQLite.
That means we are at the second stage and we will test our Docker compose all commands including the
discount, gRPC and SQLite database.
Please open the Visual Studio.
In here we are going to use Visual Studio to link for running the Docker compose environment for that
purpose.
In Visual Studio you can go to Docker Compose, right click in here and set a startup project.
After that you can see the Docker compose running profile comes in here.
Alternatively, you can execute the docker compose up commands manually in your terminal.
But I am going to use Visual Studio to link before running this application.
I'm going to confirm that the desktop is up and running, and after that, I'm hitting this button to
run the whole docker compose.
And on behind of the scenes this is running docker compose up commands and this will be spin up.
Every microservices and database in docker environment.
Specifically, we will build and recreate again this gRPC microservices, including the SQLite database.
After running the Docker compose, you can see that newly created containers comes under Docker Compose,
including the discount gRPC.
If you come discount gRPC, you can see all details in here.
Also, we have confirmed from the Docker desktop.
In here we have the Docker compose and including the newly created discount gRPC.
If I open the discount gRPC, we can check the logs.
And if you check the logs, you can see that our Entity Framework core is newly created SQLite database
under the container within the container.
And here you can see there are migrations and seeding operations performed before running this discount
gRPC application.
So that means we can confirm that our SQLite database created within the container.
To verify this database under the our container, you can open this container PC and go to files.
And under the files.
If you open the app folder, you can see that newly discount DB created under the container application
folder.
And this is performed by the Entity Framework core when the application start up, and you can reach
the discount db SQLite database under the application folder within the discount gRPC container.
So now we can start our testing applications because our discount gRPC is ready for the existing gRPC
calls.
For that purpose, I'm going to open the postman and go to the discount gRPC collection and go to the
discount service.
So we are going to start with the get discount method.
For that purpose, please change the method name as a get discount.
And after that the important part is the URL which is including 5052 port.
But this is the development port.
I'm going to change this port as a 6062 for sending requests to the Docker environment.
And also I'm going to change the request file because this is for the get discount.
Get discount only required for the product name.
And make sure that your product name is writing correctly.
P is lowercase and n is uppercase.
After that, I'm going to invoke this gRPC call in Docker environment.
And here you can see that our debugger is triggered and Jesus comes to get discount.
And we will check discount information from the database which giving the product name.
And you can see that our coupon is comes from the database which is iPhone discount.
And this is the first ID.
And we will see these data when application startup using the Entity Framework core.
That's why we can see this coupon information.
Log the information and return back to the client application.
Here you can see the response comes from the client application including the ID, product name, description
and amount.
So you can also confirm from the Docker desktop.
Here you can see the newly added logs.
Basically we will perform the select operation.
And after that you can see newly created information log which is the discount is retrieved for product
name.
Which name is iPhone X.
So after the get discount operation we can test the create discount operation.
Please change the method name.
And also we should change the payload in the payload.
I'm going to send a new coupon and make sure that you have correct Json payload for the coupon, sending
the create discount operation and invoke this gRPC method.
This will also trigger our create discount operation.
And in here you can see that we will check the coupon.
And after that add this coupon into our database and log the information and return back to the client.
If you hit F5 and see the response that is newly created item added into the our discount and coupon
table.
The ID is four and this is the new record.
And you can also confirm from the our Docker desktop.
Here you can see that we will use insert into command this time in order to create new.
Item and you can see the log information discount is successfully created with new product name.
And after that we can continue the next operation which is the update operation in here.
I'm going to update this newly created iPhone with changing the product method name as a update discount,
and after that the payload will be required for the ID information.
I have added the ID and edit the product name and description with adding the updated keyword, and
if we invoke this gRPC call this time, we will invoke the update discount method.
And in this method we will check the coupon is null or not, and after that we will update the coupon
using the Dbcontext object and log the information as the same way.
If we hit F5, we can see that update successfully, and you can also confirm from the Docker desktop
to update operation completed successfully.
And lastly, we will perform the delete operation.
In order to do that, I am going to change the method name as a delete discount.
And in here I'm going to change the Or payload as a product name, which is the updated product name.
And if we invoke this gRPC call you can see that this will be trigger delete discount.
And if you continue this operation, this will be removed coupon from the database and perform operations.
Return back to the client as a success.
True.
Also, you can confirm from the Docker desktop that we have run delete from commands to perform delete
operation.
And here you can see the information log which is the discount is successfully deleted.
As you can see that we have successfully test our discount gRPC and perform Crud operations in Docker
compose environment.