In this section we are going to develop ordering domain layer with tactical domain driven design patterns.
So if you look at our big picture we are still developing ordering microservices.
And if you look at the ordering microservices internal architecture that we have implementing clean
architecture, we are at the domain layer which is representing the beginning of the Korean architecture
layers.
And we will develop ordering domain layer.
So during this section we will learn and develop tactical domain driven design patterns like entities,
value objects, aggregates, aggregate routes, patterns for ordering entities when developing the ordering
domain layer.
As you know, that domain driven design has divided two types, which are the strategic and tactical
domain driven design.
In strategic domain driven design, we basically understand and modeling the business domain, but in
the tactical domain driven design, we will implementation details and provides the design patterns,
including the patterns like entities, value objects, aggregates, and so on.
So let's understand what is the tactical domain driven design?
Tactical domain driven design is a set of pattern and principles that help in modeling complex software
systems.
It focuses on the domain and domain logic, emphasizing the importance of a model that reflects the
business and the rules, and tactical domain driven design patterns include a set of the patterns.
These are the entities, value objects, aggregates, and aggregate rules.
So now let's delve into some key tactical domain driven design patterns and see how they can be implemented
in the ordering domain layer.
In a clean architecture setup, the first one is entities.
An entity is an object that identified by its identity rather than its attributes.
The identity makes each entity unique even if other attributes are the same.
Entities are used to represent objects in the system that have a distinct identity and life cycle.
They often correspond to real world objects that need to be tracked or managed.
As an example, we can give ordering microservices.
An order can be an entity.
It is unique identified by an order ID, even if the other attributes are identical to another order.
Here you can see an example of the order implementation as an entity, and you can see the order ID,
which makes it each entity as a unique.
So the next item is value objects.
A value object is an object that describes some characteristics or attributes, but carries no concept
of the identity.
Value objects are used to describe aspects of the domain with no conceptual identity.
They are immutable and are often used to encapsulate complex attributes.
As an example, we can give address used in the order might be a value object, as it is important for
the order, but doesn't define the order's identity.
Here you can see the address value object, including street and city information belongs to the order
entity and another item is aggregates.
And aggregate is a cluster of domain objects, which is the entities and value objects that can be treated
as a single unit.
An aggregate will have one of its component be aggregate root.
Aggregates.
Define a boundary around related objects.
Operations within the boundary should maintain consistency of changes to the data in the aggregate.
As an example, order can be an aggregate containing the order items, payment details and so on, and
these will be within it of the entity.
The consistency of an order like total price calculation stock validation is maintained within the aggregate
boundaries.
Here you can see an example order as an aggregate and order will be managed consistency between the
items with order items, price calculation, validation and so on.
And the last item is aggregate roots.
Aggregate root is the main entity is an aggregate through which external objects interact with the aggregate.
It provides a gateway to the aggregate, ensuring that the aggregates invariants are enforced and consistency
is maintained.
As an example, we can give order.
Aggregate order itself can be the aggregate root.
External object would interact with the order to effect change within the aggregate.
We can see example code into aggregate root of the order.
So we can apply all these concepts in the ordering domain layer.
When developing the ordering domain layer in a clean architecture setup, these concepts help in creating
a rich domain model that encapsulates business logic and rules.
Entities and value objects define the nature of the data and their relationships, while aggregates
and aggregate rules organize the model to ensure integrity and consistency.