In this video, we are going to develop domain driven design abstractions, including entity aggregate
domain events in the ordering domain layer for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering domain layer.
And in this layer we are going to create an abstraction folder.
And we will add AI entity related classes into abstractions.
So I'm going to right click the ordering domain and add new folder which name is abstractions.
And in this abstraction classes we will start with the AI entity interface.
For that purpose, select the abstraction folder and create AI entity dot css file.
And in this file we will create interface which name is AI entity and make this interface as a public.
And after that we are going to add some common properties for each entity into our ordering domain.
So these are the created at created by last modified and last modified by.
So these are the date, time and string properties that we are going to use as a common property for
AI entity interface and removing unnecessary using statement.
And this is the AI entity abstraction interface for us.
And at the same file I'm going to create additional interface, which is the generic version of the
AI entity.
For that purpose, I'm going to write public Interface, and this time we will create AI entity and
accepting generic T and inherit from the AI entity interface.
And inside of this AI entity generic type, we basically create one property, which name is id and
the id type is a t generic.
So we have developed AI entity interface.
And these AI entity includes common properties like created ID and created by for auditing purposes.
And in here you can see the AI entity which is defined a generic interface for all entities with a unique
identifier of type of the T, so that we will use for implementing the entity classes.
And after that I'm going to create entity base class.
For that purpose I'm going to create an entity class under the abstraction.
If you add a new file which is the entity dot CSS, this entity class will be our base class.
For that purpose, I'm going to change modifier as a public and make this class as a abstract class
in order to use as a base entity class and make these entity as a generic to inherit from the AI entity
generic type.
And we can give generic as a T, and inside of the these abstract class we should implement AI entity
members.
These are including the id created at created by last modified and last modified by.
So you can copy and paste these properties from the interface definitions of the AI entity.
We will accumulate these properties inside of the abstract entity class.
And you can give this way.
And you can remove the unnecessary using statement.
And this is the abstract class definition into our abstraction.
So this is the abstract class and provide a base implementation of the AI entity.
And it is a generic class that can be used to define entities without various type of identifiers,
including string, integer, even the custom types.
After entity based definitions, we can continue with the other domain driven design abstractions.
This time I am going to create domain event, which will be the AI domain event interface to perform
an exposing these domain events from our aggregates and entities.
For that purpose, please go to the Visual Studio.
Under the abstractions, I'm going to create a new file which name is AI Domain Events.
So in this file we will implement domain event related operations.
But this time we need a mediator package to use AI notification interface.
Because I want to inherit from the AI notification from the mediator to perform domain events.
Because mediator provides very good interface to implement domain event operations inside of the domain
layers.
For that purpose, I'm going to add a NuGet package into domain layer.
This is the only package for domain layer to perform domain event pattern.
I'm going to right click dependencies and manage NuGet packages, and browse for the mediator and install
the mediator into our ordering domain layer.
So if you go back to our our domain and you can see that we can add a notification using the mediator
and remove unnecessary using statement.
And this will be the only one package for the ordering domain to implement domain event pattern into
the ordering domain layer.
And when implementing this pattern, I'm going to adding some members for the I domain event.
The first one is event.
ID, which is the width and defining newly created domain event, and after that we can add a occurred
on DateTime property to specify the date when event is occurring.
And lastly, we can specify the event type that we can get the event type from the current assembly
qualified name, which will be which class throwing this domain event understanding from the assembly
information into these interface.
So as you can see that we have created a domain event which extends from the eye notification mediator.
So why we use eye notification interface.
Because it is allowing domain events to be dispatched through the mediator handlers.
So by this way we can use mediator handlers in order to handle these domain event using the mediator
libraries.
And each event has a unique ID, a timestamp and event type identifier inside of the interface definition,
we can continue the other domain driven design abstractions, which is the aggregate route and aggregate
route and aggregate is defining from the entities, which is a special kind of entity can handle a domain
events.
That means aggregate should have domain event list that you can clear and add domain events into the
aggregates.
So please open the Visual Studio and create eye aggregate interface.
Under the abstractions I aggregate dot CSS and in this interface we basically implement from the eye
entity.
This is the special kind of the entity, and we will make it public and remove unnecessary using statements
in the eye aggregate interface, we are going to define domain events as a ID on list.
Here you can see that we have a property which is the ID only list.
And in this list we will expect eye domain event related interface objects.
And the property name is domain events.
So in here you can see an exception which is inconsistency accessibility.
This is giving for the eye domain event accessibility.
If you go to the eye domain event if you go to definition you can see that we forgot to change these
access modifier internal to public.
Make this public and go back to eye aggregate interface and see that the error is disappeared.
And we will adding domain events as an ID on list into eye aggregate.
Because eye aggregate is a special kind of entity that can handle the domain events.
And of course, after this domain event property list, we need to clear domain events.
For that purpose, I have added additional property and method, which is a clear domain events that
can return eye domain events array.
After this definition, we should also define generic type of the eye aggregate interface.
For that purpose.
I'm going to come here and paste this line of code.
This will be basically define an interface of the eye, aggregate with the generic type, and inherit
from the eye aggregate interface that we defined in here.
And eye entity generic type T.
After these interface definitions, we should create aggregate base class, which means that we will
implement these interfaces into our abstract aggregate class for that purpose.
Go to abstraction folder and add new class.
Which name is aggregate CSS.
This class should be base class of our aggregate related operations.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and change internal to public abstract class to make
it as a base abstract class and inherit from the entity.
And I aggregate.
First of all, I'm going to make it as a generic with t id and inherit from the entity with specifying
the t id as a generic.
And also we will additional implement I aggregate interface passing to the id generic.
And if you come here and implement I aggregate members, you can see that we should define domain events
and define clear domain events method.
So in the first line of this class we will define a read only object which is the our domain event list.
These are the private read only list I domain event and underscore domain events variable with a newly
created list object, and after that we can return the domain events property with using our newly created
private list object, which is the underscore domain events.
And I'm going to convert as read only in here, so we can return as read only copy of these domain events
to the domain events property, which is expected from the I aggregate interface.
After that, we can develop the methods related to domain events.
These are the add domain events and also clear domain events functions.
So in here I'm going to develop add domain events function with getting parameter to I domain event
into the parameters and adding these incoming domain events to our domain event list, which is the
defined in the first line of code.
So basically this will be provided to a domain events into our list.
And after that we can implement the clear domain events.
In this method we basically get the domain events to the array.
As you can see that in here I have created I domain event array which name is dict events.
And we will get this array from the domain events list.
And after that we can clear the domain events by using the domain ones dot clear function.
And after that we can return these Dequeued event list to the response of this method.
Because even I deleted the domain events, I can return the domain events before deleting these operations
in this clear domain event function.
As you can see that we have finished the aggregate base class and also finished the abstraction folder,
including the entity, aggregate and domain events abstractions.
By developing these domain driven design abstractions, we have laid the groundwork for our domain model
in the Ordering Domain project.