In this video, we are going to do domain modeling with using tactical domain driven design patterns
for ordering microservices.
Domain driven design provides a framework that lead us to create a set of well designed microservices
and we will define entities, aggregates, value objects, domain services, and domain events for ordering
microservices.
That means within the ordering bounded context, we will apply these tactical domain driven design patterns
in order to define entities, aggregates, domain services and so on.
We are going to particularly interested in the entity and aggregate patterns, and applying these patterns
will help us to identify natural boundaries for the services in our application.
Let's remember the application use cases for ordering microservices.
We said that we have Crud ordering operations including get order with items, create, update, delete,
order and add and remove item from the order and also we have asynchronous ordering operations including
basket checkout and order fulfillment to perform fulfillment operations for other microservices.
So that means we will raising order created domain event that leads to integration event to see our
domain events into analyzing the ordering microservices and according to these ordering application
use cases, we can start to perform our domain analyzing into the next slide.
And here you can see the our domain analyzing with applying the tactical domain driven design pattern
in ordering microservices.
So in this diagram we illustrate the relationship between aggregates entities, value objects and domain
events.
So it shows the how order aggregates encompass the order items, which in turn reference to customer
and product entities.
And let me explain these domain modeling.
First of all we have a order aggregate.
This is the central focus of the ordering microservices, which coordinates the entire order process.
And after that we have order item which is the one to end relationship.
And this is represent each product item in an order.
And we have also customer in here customer entity and order item.
Also entity only order will be aggregate in the customer entity.
It represents the customer who placed the order.
And here you can see the product entity.
It represents the products being ordered.
Entities like customer and products might be sharing in other microservices indicating the bounded context.
You can see these are the different bounded contexts from the ordering model context.
And now we can defining value object in the order aggregate.
For example, address is an value object from the order.
You can see the order aggregate route.
And these are the attributes and methods.
In the attributes, we can see some of the value object that we can define in here.
Address is a value object that can represent shipping or billing address in the order aggregate.
And we have also payment aggregate which is also value object that encapsulate payment details for an
order and value.
Objects like these are the crucial in reflecting real world scenarios and constraints in our domain.
And also we have domain events that we can analyze.
We can see that our domain event is order created event.
It is a domain event that gets triggered when a new order is successfully created.
This event could lead to various integrations like inventory checks or notifications, and this is event
driven approach.
Enable.
The reactive and decoupled architectures is especially important in microservices.