In this video, we are going to developing the domain model for ordering microservices.
That means we will create ordered domain entities, aggregates and value objects that represent our
business logic and requirements.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering domain.
And this time we are going to create a new folder.
Right click Add New folder.
Which name is models.
This will be represent our domain models.
And the first domain model is Order Aggregate.
I am going to add a new class which name is order dot css and this will be our aggregate.
For that purpose I am going to remove using statement and make it public.
And the important thing is we are going to inherit from the aggregate class, which is the our base
abstract class from the abstractions.
And I am going to define the t id as a grid.
That means order entities, id type as a grid.
So you can right click the aggregate, go to definition and see that aggregate inherits from the entity.
And if you go to right click and go to definition of the entity, you can see that there is a t id property
which represents grid for our order model.
So please go back to the order model definition and continue to our business domain model properties.
And the first property is order items.
If you go back to our architecture and you can see domain modeling, analyzing order has one to end
relationship with the order items.
That means I am going to create a order item list into the order aggregate.
If you go back to our code, you can come here and we are going to create a list which is including
the order item, which is the private read only list, and this is the order item list that we are going
to create newly in the order class.
And I am going to return back the Order items property with returning this private order items as a
read only.
This is one of the important thing that returning read only list when reaching these order items from
the outside of the world, and this is the definition of the one to end relationships.
So please ignore these order items.
Exceptions that we are going to develop a few minutes later, but continue the implementation of order.
Entity order has customer order, name, shipping address, billing address, payment, and so on.
So let me define these attributes one by one.
The first one is customer ID.
As you can see that we will define with customer ID in order to access the customer ID information from
the customer bounded context.
And after that, the second thing is we can define the order name.
This is the public string order name property.
And I am using the get and private set because this property cannot be settable from outside of the
world.
And after the order name we can define two address information.
These are the shipping address and billing address.
And these address informations should be value object of the address that we will define after this
definition.
So please make sure that you have added the two address, one for the shipping and one for the billing
address.
And this will be the representing our value objects in order aggregate.
And after that we have one more value object which is the payment.
And we will define payment property from the payment value object.
And lastly we will define order status which is the enum.
And in here you can see that order status should be our enumeration.
And the property name should be status.
And the default value should be order status dot panning for order aggregate.
And finally I am going to create a total price decimal property, which will be calculate the order
items and iterating the order items with using the sum function.
Price and quantity.
Multiplexing the price and quantity information.
So this is calculating of the total price into the property of the order aggregate.
So these are the order aggregate definitions that we are going to build one by one.
You can find the whole class in here.
Basically order is the aggregate root including all related entities and value objects.
Order item is a list of the order item entities and order aggregate include customer shipping, billing
and payment details, and total price is computed from the order items.
After that, we will continue with the next entity, which is the order item.
I'm going to create a new class under the models folder, which name is order item dot CSS and this
will be entity from the our order aggregate.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And after that I'm going to inherit from the entity abstract class and specify the ID information as
a grid.
Here you can see the definition of the Orderitem entity.
And in this orderitem entity we basically have some of the attributes including the order ID, product
id, quantity and price.
So I'm going to add these properties under the Orderitem entity class.
Here you can see the order ID which is the great value.
And product ID is also great value and quantity integer and decimal price.
So also I would like to add an internal constructor to create a new Orderitem with a given properties
as a parameter of the constructor.
Here you can see that we have an internal constructor in the Orderitem accepting the order id, product
id quantity and price as a parameters of the Orderitem that we will create new Orderitem.
So Orderitem represents individual items within an order, and it contains product information and quantity
information, and so on.
The next entity is customer.
So I'm going to create a new file under the models which is the customer X and customer also be entity.
I'm going to change the public class customer and inherit from the entity and the ID value also with.
So in here we can define customer related attributes that I'm going to add only name and email as a
string value of these properties.
Please make sure that also you have defined customer entity.
And after that we can define product entity.
Under the models.
I'm going to add a new class which name is product X.
And in this class I'm going to follow the same steps, make it public and inherit from the entity with
value.
In the product class we have two attributes, which is the name and price.
These are the string name and decimal price attributes defined in the product class as an entity.
So you can see that we have completed domain modeling, including the order Orderitem customer and product.
And you can see that even it is the ordering microservices.
We have customer and product entity.
Why we should use customer and product entity in the ordering.
Microservices.
Microservices can duplicate data like product from the catalog microservices in order to reduce interservice
communication.
But when you duplicate the microservice data from other microservices, this time it needs to be updated
in eventual consistency way.
We will learn it in in coming videos.
So for now we will continue to our domain modeling.
We have finished the models and this time I am going to create value objects.
So right click the order domain add new folder.
Which name is value objects.
We will adding value objects inside of this folder.
I'm going to start with the address dot CSS.
Create a new class with the address definition.
And I'm going to remove the unnecessary using statement.
And I'm going to change the public.
And this time instead of using the class we are going to use record type.
Because record types is very good for defining value objects in terms of the comparing and removing
the ID operations.
So that's why we are going to use address as a value object.
And this is very powerful for the C sharp that we can define domain driven design value object as a
record type.
And in the address I'm going to define lots of the attributes and properties including the first name,
last name, email address, address, line, country, state, and zip code.
All of these attributes are string properties under the address value object record type.
So basically we will define an address as a value object and utilize the C sharp record type for immutability.
After that we can define the payment value object.
I'm going to add a new class which is the payment dot CSS, and following the same steps as the value
object, make it public and record type and after that define the attributes including the card name,
card number, expiration, CVV, and payment method.
Payment value object basically encapsulates the payment details.
After that we can define the enumerations.
For that purpose.
I'm going to right click the order domain and add new folder, which name is enums.
And in this folder I'm going to create our enum which is the order status.
So create a new class which is the order statistics.
And I'm going to remove the unnecessary using statement and make it public.
And this time we will define enum for order status and as an enumeration order status we have several
values.
These are the.
Planning completed and cancelled.
So these are the possible states for ordered as an ordered status.
And finally we can go back to order domain aggregate.
You can go to the models and go to the ordered aggregate.
Here you can see that we can define these address payment and order status as a complex type.
If you come here and using the value objects address and payment comes into our order aggregate.
And if you come here and using the ordered domain enums, you can see that our order aggregate is now
ready.
But as you can see that we have three using statements that we can remove these unnecessary using statements
to the global using CSS.
For that purpose, go to ordering domain level and add new class which name is global using dot CSS.
And in here we are going to write global using statement directly.
And I'm going to copy paste these global using statements including abstractions, models, value objects
and enums folder.
If you go back to our order model now, we can safely remove these using statements.
Save these orders.
Yes.
And if you go to order item we can also remove these ordering domain abstraction using statement.
Save this item and go to product and also check the customer.
So as you can see that we have cleared unnecessary using statement and we have finished to our domain
modeling into the ordering domain project.
If you right click and build this class library, you can see that we have successfully finished the
definition of the ordering domain model.