In this video we are going to learn primitive obsession and strongly typed IDs in domain driven design.
So let me start with the what is primitive obsession?
Primitive obsession is a code smell where primitives like string, integer, grid are used for the domain
concepts, leading to ambiguity and errors.
For instance, using a grid or string for an order ID, customer ID, or product ID makes it easy to
mix these identifiers up as they are all of the same type.
So how can we solve these primitive obsession?
The solution is using strongly typed IDs.
So now let me answer these questions.
What is strongly typed IDs pattern?
Strongly typed IDs involves creating distinct types for each kind of ID in your domain.
This makes your code more expressive and less error prone.
It clarifies which type of ID is expected and prevents accidentally using one type of ID where another
type of ID is intended.
So now let me show you how can we use strongly type ID pattern into the orderitem?
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the models and Orderitem.
If you go to Orderitem and go to the constructor of the Orderitem, you can see the first two parameters
are order id and product ID and when we are creating Orderitem, it is very easy to pass wrong IDs into
constructors.
That means you can create Orderitem with the wrong order ID and product ID, you can simply replace
wrong ids them into the parameter.
Instead of sending order ID, you can send product ID in here and send order ID in here.
So we call.
This problem is a primitive obsession.
And in order to solve this problem we can define strongly type IDs.
That means instead of using the grid for order id, I can create an order id type and we can pass the
order id parameter into Orderitem constructor.
And at the same way we can create product id type for product id definition.
By this way we can avoid the setting value by mistake.
So using the strong type IDs giving lots of benefits.
The first benefit is type safety.
Mistakenly passing a product ID where an order ID is expected is now a compile time error, and we cannot
pass the order ID instead of the product id with a type saved values.
And the second benefit is readability.
The constructor clearly indicates that what type of id is required.
And lastly, we can say that it is also beneficial for refactoring support IDs can easily distinguish
between these types and adding in refactoring and navigation very easily.