In this video, we are going to develop strongly typed IDs for ordering entities.
So we will start by changing primitive types to strongly type IDs in order CSS.
If you open the order CSS, you can see the primitive types are with string enlisting into the order.
So I'm going to change the customer id primitive type gid to customer ID you can change in here.
And also I am going to change order name string primitive type to the order name concrete type.
So here you can see that the customer id and order name is become concrete types.
And we will create these concrete types as a value object record types classes in very soon.
And these are the are strongly type IDs under the order aggregate.
And except these files we don't have any primitive types under the order aggregate.
And now the step two is creating value object for these new strongly type IDs.
I'm going to define customer ID and order name as a value object.
For that purpose I'm going to go to the value objects.
And in here we can add new class under the Value object folder which name is customer ID.
And this will be the record type as a customer ID and include value information as a guide value.
So we can remove the unnecessary using statement.
And you can define the customer ID record type.
This is the value object and these will be the are strongly type ID, including the value primitive
object inside of the customer ID concrete type, and is the same way we can follow the order name as
a value object.
Come to value object.
Create new class which is the order name dot css.
And I'm going to create order name record type.
And if you remove the unnecessary using statement come here and create order name record type.
And you can also give the value this time value should be string as a primitive type and we can create
order name value object which will be the strong type in the order order aggregate class.
So these value objects encapsulate the id and name values and providing clear and domain specific type
for each operation.
You can see that these will be encapsulate customer ID and these will be encapsulate order name including
the value properties.
If we open the order aggregate, you can see that our strongly typed value objects comes in here successfully.
So the next object we can check order item class.
If you open the order item class we are going to convert these order ID and product ID as a strongly
typed ID for that purpose, I'm going to change these great value to order ID and change the product
ID with value to product ID, so we will follow the same steps for the properties change order ID,
guide to order ID and change product ID to product ID.
Also, at this point I'm going to add an order item ID in here.
You can see that when we are creating order item, we also add and set ID information which is representing
order item ID.
So I'm going to make it strongly type ID and here you can see that we will also use order item ID.
And I will explain the off method in the next videos.
And we will passing the newly created guide in here to generating new ID when creating order item under
the order entity.
So as you can see that we have successfully set the order item ID, order ID and product id now using
strongly type IDs and this.
Ensure that the correct type of the ID is used and prevents mixing of different types of IDs.
So the next step we can define these ID types as a value objects.
For that purpose.
I'm going to start with the order id and create order id value object.
Under the Value object folder, create new class order id x and add under the value objects.
In here I'm going to remove the unnecessary using statement and define order id as a record type and
put a great value inside of this record type, and this will be represent our order id strongly typed
value, and after that, following the order id, we are going to create product ID I'm going to create
product ID dot CSS under the value objects and remove the unnecessary using statements.
And we are going to create product ID record type.
And inside of it we will put great value and we will represent the strongly typed product ID with these
value object.
And lastly I'm going to create order item ID.
If you add a new class order item id dot CSS and.
Remove the using statement.
We will follow the same steps.
I'm going to remove this code and create order item ID, record type and the value with object inside
of it.
So as you can see that we have created order item ID, product ID and customer ID that we can define
for each type of ID clearly defined as a separate value object, and it will enhancing clarity and type
safety.
So if you go to the models and look at the models order, order, item, product and customer, you
can see that these are the inherited from the aggregate and entities.
And inside of these aggregate and entities, it is taking the type object as a ID type information.
So you can see that these classes using target as an entity type ID information for the product customer
and so on.
So we should remove these good information and update the entity base class types for the strongly type
IDs.
If you go to the order CSS, you can see that it is inheritance from the aggregate GID.
And I am going to change it to order ID, because now we will use order id as the ID of the order entity,
and this will be represent all the type of the order id strongly typed value.
And I'm going to change these aggregate.
And I'm going to follow the same step for the order item inside of the order item, you can see that
it is inherited from the entity.
And we have created a order item ID as the ID of this class, and change the guy to order item ID in
the signature of the class definition.
And if you go to the product and customer in the customer CSS, you can remove the unnecessary using
statement and come to the entity place and we will change the guy to customer ID for the customer entity
and follow the same steps for the product entity.
Remove the using statement and change to go to product ID for product entity.
By this way, each entity explicitly specifies the type of the IDs which must have strongly type IDs.
This approach reduces the risk of the errors and misunderstandings in the code, making it more maintainable
and understandable.