In this video we are going to learn anemic domain model and rich domain model entities in domain driven
design.
In domain driven design, the concepts of the anemic domain model and rich domain model are crucial
in understanding how domain logic is encapsulated in your entities.
Before starting, I would like to ask questions for order entity.
If you open the order entity, you can see that we have encapsulated order items is a private read only
variable.
And now how can we add or remove new items into order aggregate?
We know that order item is one to end relation with the order aggregate, but we should add and remove
items in the order item for the specific order.
So how can we do that?
If you make the order items as a public?
Everyone can add and remove items in this list, so we should not make the public for the order items.
Everyone to edit the order items with reaching the order.
So we have to encapsulate these add and remove item operations in the order itself.
Because these add and remove item operations belongs to order domain aggregates.
To understand these operations well, I'm going to come back to slide and explain what is anemic domain
model entity.
An anemic domain model is characterized by entities that have little or no business logic.
That means that has no domain logic.
And these entities are essentially data structures with getters and setter methods.
But the business rules and the behaviors are typically implemented outside the entity, often in service
layer.
Here you can see the example.
In this example, the order class is anemic because it only contains data and lacks of any domain logic
or behavior.
So what is rich?
Domain model entity A rich domain model entity is an approach where the entity is encapsulated both
data and behavior.
This model enriched entities with methods that embody business rules and domain logic.
Here you can see an example of the rich domain model with the order.
Entity order is a rich domain model as it include methods add order item and remove order item, which
encapsulate the business logic for manipulating the order items.
So if you compare with the anemic versus rich domain model, you can see the image at y axis.
We can see workers and complexity and x axis we can see time and sadness.
As you can see the image, you can see that anemic model starting very less efforts if you compare with
the rich domain model.
But when the time goes anemic model is going to more complex and spanning more workers and leading to
sadness.
So if you compare with the anemic and rich domain model, we can start with the anemic domain model.
Business logic is scattered across the application, often in services.
Entities are simple data containers and easier to understand initially, but it can lead to issues with
maintainability and understanding the business logic by time.
And if you look at the rich domain model, it encapsulates the business logic within the entities more
closely, represent the real world business domain, and it can be more complex to design, but leads
to a more maintainable and cohesive model.
So for our ordered domain aggregate, the goal should be to create a rich domain model.
This involves encapsulating the logic for adding or removing orderitem objects within the order class
itself.
This encapsulation ensures that the operation follow the business rules and invariants of the order
aggregate.
Here you can see that we can add the two methods, including the add Order item and remove order item
to perform the order item, related operations and business logic inside of these functions under the
order aggregate entity class.