In this video we are going to develop rich domain modal entity for ordered entities in the order domain
layer.
So if you open the order CSS under the modal, you can see that under the order entity.
Now we have only data related properties including the order entity.
But we have a set of questions.
The first question is how to create an order.
We should use naive object.create operation and every domain should responsible with its own create
operation.
And the question two is how to add or remove new items into order aggregate.
So we should not adding and removing collections over the order entity and reaching the order items
with a public manner.
These add and remove operations are domain use cases and should be responsible for the order entity.
So after defining these responsibilities, domain rules and the domain events, we can start developing
the domain methods.
I would like to start with the basic entity, which is the customer case.
If you open the customer case, you can see that we can start by enhancing the customer entity to include
domain specific operations and validations.
So customer entity is responsible for creating its own instance and managing its state.
Let's add a create static method to encapsulate these create logic.
I'm going to come here and write public static and return back a customer and create method including
the parameters customer ID, name and email.
And in this method we will basically return back a new customer.
But before that we can perform some of the validations.
I'm going to use argument exception throw if null or whitespace extension method, checking the name
and email values in the parameters.
And after that I'm going to create a new customer which including the ID name and email information
passing from the parameters.
And lastly, we can return a customer.
So the create method is a factory method that encapsulates the creation of customer instance in this
create method, and it includes domain validations to ensure the integrity of the customer instance.
These are the domain validations and after that we have create a new customer using the default constructor
and return the customer in the create method.
So basically we have created static create method that create customer in the customer entity, but
customer entity using strongly typed IDs which is the customer ID value objects.
So these objects also need to create its own type.
For that purpose we will create off method.
So that means in order to separate entities and value objects for the create responsibilities, we will
develop the static create method for each entities under the model folder.
And we will also develop the static off method for each value objects under the value object folder.
For that purpose, please go to the customer ID value object and this is the value object.
And this value object also responsible to create its own type with accepting the Guid value.
So we will develop a static off method in order to create instance of customer id for that purpose.
I'm going to start with the private constructor.
The value objects are the record type, and I'm going to create a private constructors in order to set
the value information.
And after that we will create a static off method.
In order to instantiate this customer ID here you can see the static customer ID off method, and we
will use off method for each value objects, and we will use create method for each domain models.
So in the off method you can see that we will perform the domain validation and after that contain the
domain validation and throwing a domain exception.
And after that returning a new customer ID with passing the volume information in the parameter of the
off method.
And these customer ID is a private constructor located under the customer ID record type.
So customer ID is a record type with a single property, which is the value, and this off method provide
a clear and domain specific way to create customer ID instances.
This method includes a domain rule that validate the GID is not empty.
In here you can see that value cannot be null, and after that we have throwing a domain exception so
we can both use argument exception and custom exception in here.
So domain exception represent.
These error happens in the domain layer in the domain logic.
So that means we should create custom domain exception class for representing our domain related operations
under the ordering domain.
And in order to handle domain specific exceptions let's create a domain exceptions under the exceptions
folder.
I'm going to right click the ordering domain and add new folder, which name is exceptions.
And under this folder I'm going to create a new class which is the domain exceptions.
This is typical to custom exceptions.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make it public and inherit from the exception class.
And as a constructor, we have defined a custom constructor with incoming message, which is a domain
exception and throwing from the domain layer.
Okay, after defining domain exception, you can see that domain exception is a custom exception type
that represents the error that occurred within the domain layer, and it enriched the exception message
with the domain specific context.
And after defining these domain exception, I'm going to move these namespace into the global using
statement.
If you open the global using statement, I'm going to add a new using statement which is the ordering
domain.
Exceptions.
And after that, if you go back to customer ID value object, you can see that domain exception introduced
in here.
So we have developed static of method under the customer ID.
And we have developed static create method under the customer entity by developing customer and customer
ID with domain specific methods and validations, we created a rich domain model that encapsulate domain
logic within the entities.