In this video, we are going to continue to develop value objects with the rich domain model entity
in the ordering domain layer.
So we will continue with the IDs.
Here you can see the customer ID completed with the static of method.
And I'm going to continue with the order ID.
The order id value object should also be responsible for its own instantiation.
And here we will use a static off method in order to create instance of the order id.
First of all, I'm going to create a private constructor and we will use this constructor into the off
method.
And here you can see the static off method.
And we will perform the static off method accepting the grid value information.
And we will apply the domain rules and validations in the beginning of this static method.
And here you can see that we will throw if null exception and we will check with empty and throwing
domain exception.
Order ID cannot be empty and we will return a new order using the private constructor passing the body
information.
So this is the order id and I'm going to continue with the order item ID.
If you go to Order Item Entity class, you can see that we have already used order item ID that of static
method when creating new order item.
So we will implement this off method under the order item id value object.
Please go to Order Item id value object and we will use a static method of method to create instance
of order item id.
First of all, I'm going to create a private constructor, and after that we will follow the same steps
to create public static of method returning the order item id.
So in this method we will getting the volume information and we will performing the domain validations
in here.
And after that returning new order item ID with passing the value in the private constructor.
So this is the implementation of the order item id and we will continue with the next one, which is
the product ID.
If you go to the product ID you can come here and follow the same steps.
Create the private constructor.
and after that we will develop the off method following the this code.
And here you can see that we are doing exactly the same operations with the other value objects.
I'm not going to explain again and please develop it the same way like me.
And after that we can go ahead to the next value object which is the order name.
The order name value object should also be responsible for its own instantiation.
And here we will use a static off method to create new instance of the order name.
And we set that value.
Objects can include domain rules and apply these rules when creating the value objects.
So I'm going to focus on these domain rules for that purpose.
The first row of this order name value object I'm going to create private const integer default length
as a five.
So we will put a constraint when creating order name.
And after that we will create a private constructor as the same way with the previous value objects.
Private order name.
Accepting the value information as a string and passing the value inside of these value property of
the order name value objects.
And finally, we can create our off method in order to create instantiate these order name.
And this is the public static order name of method accepting the volume formation.
And in here you can see that we have used out of the box extension method of the argument.
Exceptions.
In order to perform domain rules and validations and constraints, the first row we are checking if
null or empty the incoming value operation, and the second row we basically throw exception.
If not length operation is the same that we defined in the default length in the beginning of the order
name value object.
So this is the finished of the order name and the next value object is address.
If you go to address the address value object represents a shipping or billing address in the order
aggregate.
This object encapsulates all relevant address information and provide a method to create a fully initialized
address object.
If you go to the order aggregate, you can see that we will use address value object for shipping and
billing address.
If you go back to address value object, we will define the off method in order to create an instantiate
address information.
But before that I would like to start with the constructors.
I'm going to create a default constructor, which is the protected address.
This is required for Entity Framework core.
I will explain later, but passing this point for now, and after that we will create a private constructor.
As usual, when accepting all the parameters in the constructor parameter, you can see that private
address and including the first name, last name, email address, address, line, country, state
and zip code as a parameter and passing this value inside of this private constructor.
So after that, we will use this private constructor in order to develop off method.
So here you can see that our public static address off method And we will passing all these parameters
at the same way in the private constructor.
And after that we have running the domain rules and violations by using the argument exceptions.
And after that we will use private constructor with passing these parameters into our off method.
So these domain validations ensure the mandatory fields are provided.
We are expecting email address and address line as a mandatory when creating a new address information.
So after defining these address value object with the private constructors and the static off method,
we can go to the payment value object.
If you go to payment case, the payment value object represents the payment information associated with
an order.
You can go to Order Aggregate and you can see the payment located under our order aggregate.
That's why we will define payment and payment also required to instantiate its own entity.
We will follow the same steps as the address.
I'm going to create a protected constructor in order to align with the Entity Framework core.
And after that I'm going to create a private constructor including all members into payment record type.
These are the card name, card number, expiration, CVV and payment method and passing these incoming
parameter into our properties.
And after that we can ready to create our public static payment of method, including all the same parameters
in the parameter line of this method.
And after that we can perform domain logic in here.
And after that we will return a new payment.
With passing these parameters and using the private constructor, you can see the domain validations
that we have used out-of-the-box.
Argument exception extension methods.
First of all, we will check if null or empty for three parameters, and after that we will check throw
if greater than three the length of the CVV, and we will check these conditions before creating a payment.
So as you can see that we have completed the creating static of method for each value object you can
go to for each value object and verify that we have created auth method for each value object.
By this way, we can encapsulate the relevant properties and business rules within the auth method for
each value objects.