In this video, we are going to develop rich domain model for other entities in the order domain layer.
For that purpose we will use static create method for each entity.
As you know that in the previous videos we.
When we developing the value objects, we have used all static methods.
But this time we will develop entities and we will develop create static methods for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the modules and go to the customer entity.
Customer entity is responsible for creating instance of itself and ensuring that all the necessary validations
are applied during the creation.
Here you can see that we have already developed static customer create method, and the create method
allows for the instantiation of the customer object, ensuring that all the necessary properties are
provided and valid.
And you can see that we have used argument validation and argument exception used for the validate input
parameters So we will follow the same steps and we will create a new create method for the rest of the
entities.
I'm going to open the product case and the product entity similarly encapsulate its own create logic.
For that purpose, I'm going to develop a create method which is the public static and product create
method with including the all the parameters.
So in here you can see that we have developed the static create method.
And in this method the parameters including product id name and price.
We get the ID information in the beginning of these create methods to explicitly set the ID information
for each entities, and in the beginning of this static create method, we always perform the validations
and domain rules.
Here you can see that I'm going to use out-of-the-box argument exception extension method.
Check if null or empty for the name property and check the price is positive and greater than zero.
You can see this validation and after that we can use the default constructors to create new product,
safely passing the ID name and price.
And lastly, we will return the newly created product to the create static method.
So the create method is responsible for constructing product objects, and it validates the name and
price and ensuring they meet the domain rules.
And after that we can go to the next domain model and entity which is the order item.
If you look at the order item, we don't have any responsibility for this entity because all the responsibilities
of these order item entity belongs to aggregate which is the order aggregate.
We can see the constructor access modifier is internal for order item, because order item should only
be created from the aggregate, which is the order.
If you open the order, you can understand that all order item related operations should be responsible
in the order aggregate.
So the order entity is the aggregate root and it is responsible for managing its own state and the state
of its associated order items.
That means ordered domain model is responsibilities are create and update an order for the existing
entity, and also add or remove items for the order items related to order aggregate.
So let's implement these functions under the these data related properties.
If you scroll down and go at the end of these order aggregate class, the first thing we should develop
is static create method.
So I'm going to write public static order and create method with passing all the members inside of the
this class.
And here you can see that we have created the public static order create.
And after that this will be include all the information including the order aggregate.
We will start with the ID in order to define this ID explicitly.
When creating any order and continue with the customer ID order name address, shipping address and
billing address.
Payment and so on.
So this is the body of the arcade operation that we will define when creating a new order.
And in the beginning of this code, I'm going to directly create a new order using the default constructor
with passing all these parameters and members for the order entity, and we are passing the status for
order status pending for the initial status.
And after that I'm going to use order dot Add Domain event.
If you come here and write to order, and if you check the method you can see that we have a domain
events.
And these methods comes from the our aggregate base abstract class.
In order to adding domain event into our order aggregate, I will explain the domain events in the next
videos.
But now I'm going to put this line of code adding new domain event, which is the order created event
with passing the newly created order.
And after that we can safely return order.
So this is the static create method for responsibility of the creating an order for the order entity,
and after that we can continue with the update operation.
I'm going to follow the same steps, but this time we are going to create update method and this will
be using when updating an order.
So this is typical public void update method.
And we will be passing the order name address shipping address and billing address payment and order
status.
So in here we will using the update operations.
So I'm going to update these incoming parameters with the property values of the current order aggregate
entity class.
And after that I'm going to use a domain event function again in order to throw any domain event which
is the order updated event with passing this order aggregate entity class.
So these are the create and update method responsible for the order entity.
And as you can see that I'm not using any domain rules and validations in the beginning of the create
operation.
Because if you check these parameters, all parameters are the value objects.
And if you go to the value objects, you can see that we have already applied domain rules in the beginning
of the.
These create operation of the value objects.
And for each value object we have adding enough domain rules and validations that we cannot pass the
invalid data when creating any order under the order CS file.
After this method, we can continue with the next responsibility, which is the add or remove item from
the order aggregate.
And that's why I'm going to create a new method, which is the public void add, and the parameters
representing required for the new order item operation, which is including product ID, quantity and
price.
So this method is responsible for adding new item into order aggregate.
That means we will create new order item id.
So before starting we will check the domain rules and validations using the argument out of range Outofrange
exception, I'm going to check quantity and price information with incoming to our add method, and
after that we will create a new Orderitem with passing these values to our Orderitem constructor.
Here you can see that I am using a new Orderitem variable and using new Orderitem constructor, which
is the internal constructor that we can only reach access in the ordering domain layer, and we will
be passing the ID information, which is the order ID.
This ID information the current ID of the entity of the order and passing the product ID, quantity
and price.
If you right click and go to definition of the Orderitem constructor, you can see that we will be passing
order ID in the beginning of the parameters and continue to product ID quantity and price.
And in the inside of this constructor, we will newly create order item ID and continue to set order
ID, product ID, quantity and price information.
If you go back to our order and locate our add method After defining and new orderitem, we basically
add these orderitem into the orderitems of the current order aggregate so we can use order underscore
Orderitems private readonly list object and click the add button, and we will use add button and placing
the Orderitem inside of the this list.
By this way we can encapsulate the order items into the order aggregate.
We can see order items and go to the definition of the order items, which is in the beginning of the
order aggregate.
We basically create new private readonly list order item underscore order items with the new keyword
and when we need to return order item list to the outside of the world, we basically use order items
property.
And for this property we basically return read only copy of the original list of the order items.
So if you go at the end of the this class and continue to our the next method which is the remove items
from the order.
For that purpose, I'm going to use and create a new method which is the public void remove, including
the product id because we will remove items according to product ID for that purpose.
First of all, we need to find order item regarding to this product ID and we will use order items that
first or default method, and we will passing the product ID inside of this method body.
And by this way we can reach the order item.
And if the order item is not null, we can remove this order item in our current list.
Here you can see that we will check the order item is not null.
We can remove order items that remove method and passing the order item in order to remove this item
into our list.
As you can see that we have completed the order aggregate behavior with developing add, remove, update
and create methods inside of the order Aggregate class.
By this way, each entity is responsible for its own behavior, validating its own state and ensuring
the consistency.