In this video we are going to learn domain events in domain driven design.
And we will compare domain versus integration events.
And we will see in a real world examples.
So let me start with what is domain event in domain driven design.
Domain events represent something happened in the past and the other parts of the same service boundary
and same domain need to react to these changes.
A domain event is a business event that occurs within the domain model.
It often represents a side effect or a result of a domain operation.
Aethes.
It's a technique that is used to achieve consistency between aggregates in the same domain.
For example, when an order is placed, an order placed event might be triggered.
These events are crucial in capturing the intention and outcome of domain actions, and they can be
used to trigger side effects or notify other parts of the system about the changes within the domain.
So how to use domain events in domain driven design.
Domain events are used to encapsulate the event details and dispatch them to the interested parties.
Typically they are used to communicate changes within the domain to external handlers, which may perform
actions based on these events.
So here you can see the domain events in the ordering microservices.
For example, let's assume that we have e-commerce application.
And in our ordering microservices we have a customer entity.
Whenever an order is created, the related user becomes a customer.
So we can say that we need two aggregates in the same domain for the ordering microservices order aggregates.
And also we can say customer aggregate.
So when customer place an order several things happen.
That means like updating the inventory, notifying the shipping department, and sending an email confirmation
to the customer.
So these actions can be triggered by an order placed domain event.
And we can raising and dispatching these domain events within the order aggregates.
You can see order aggregate when the order is placed, it adds a domain event which name is ordered
placed event and dispatching this event.
This will be typically done in the infrastructure layer.
It's often in the repository or unit of work.
After saving changes to the database, the domain events are dispatched to their respective handlers.
So now let's compare domain versus integration events.
At the core, they are the same thing, which is a representation of something that happened in the
past.
However, they propose use cases and implementation details are different.
So let me start with the domain events.
Domain events published and consumed within a single domain.
So you publish and subscribe to the event in the same application instance.
They are strictly within the boundary of the microservice or domain context.
They typically indicate something that has happened within the aggregate domain.
Events happen in process or synchronously sent using an in-memory message bus.
As an example, we can give order placed event.
But if you look at the integration events, integration events are used to communicate state changes
or events between different bounded contexts or different microservices.
They are more about the overall system's reaction to certain domain events.
Integration events should be asynchronously sent with a message broker.
Over a few integration events are consumed by other subsystems.
As an example, we can give.
After handling the order placed, domain event and order placed integration event might be published
to a message broker like RabbitMQ, which could then be consumed by other microservices.
You can find example illustration on the slide.
We have a bounded context in domain driven design and we have aggregate.
And in this aggregate we can create a domain event.
And this domain event can be handled with the handlers.
And this might be published a message broker with creating an integration event in order to notify other
subsystems.
And here you can see the our E-shop domain and integration events.
As you can see that we have a orders bounded context.
And in this bounded context we have order aggregate and Orderitem entity.
So in order aggregate we will publish order created domain event within the ordering microservices and
this domain event handled by the internal components like updating customer within the same microservices.
And after that we can lead the integration event.
So once the order created domain event is handled in this domain, an order created integration event
is published.
These publish operations performs by using the message brokers and following the asynchronous communication,
and after that the shipping and inventory microservices.
Subscribe to this event and when it receives the event, it begins the process to shipment and other
subsystem operations after consuming this integration event.
So we can say that domain events happen in process and synchronously.
On the other hand, the integration events should be asynchronously.
Domain events published and consumed with a single domain.
So you publish and subscribe to the event in the same application instance.
On the other hand, integration events are consumed by other subsystems.
Domain events are sent using in-memory message bus using the mediator lifecycles and integration events
are sent with a message broker over a queue.
So understanding the difference between domain and integration event is crucial in designing a system
with a clear boundaries and responsibilities.