In this video we are going to develop order created and order updated domain event in organic microservices
and these events are crucial in domain driven design approach as they help to communicating significant
changes within the domain.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Order Aggregate class and if you scroll down, you can see
that in the Create and Update method, we use Add Domain Event method.
And if you right click and go to definition, you can see that this method comes from the aggregate
abstract base class that we can use for order aggregate.
So now I am going to start to developing order created event in here.
In the order case you can see that we are triggering order created event to defining and developing
these order created domain event.
I am going to right click the order domain and add a new folder.
Which name is events.
So under this folder I'm going to create a order created domain event so you can add a new class.
Which name is order?
Created events.
And for defining these domain events I am going to use a record type.
But before that let me remove unnecessary using statement.
And in here I'm going to use public record and give the name of this domain event, which is the order
created event and passing the order as a parameter and inherit from the I domain event.
So this event class inherit from the I domain event, which is a marker interface that can be used by
infrastructure services to identify the domain events.
So if you right click and go to definition, you can see that domain event is developed under the abstractions
in the ordering domain.
So we can inherit by domain event.
To identify the domain events in here you can go back to events order created event.
We can mark these order created event as a domain event with inheriting a domain event.
The order created event also carrying the order data as a parameter of the domain event, and this can
include all the details of the order that was just created.
And after that we can start to develop the other domain event.
If you save this file, go back to order CS and if you scroll down you can see that we need one more
domain event when updating the order, which name is order updated event, I am going to copy the name
and create a new class under the events folder which name is Order Updated Events.
So we will following the same steps again.
This will be the record type.
I am going to develop public record and order updated event.
Here you can see that order updated event.
Also taking the order and inherit from the I domain event.
That means it is similar to order created event and this event signifies that an existing order has
been updated.
It also carries the order entity in order to provide context to event handler.
So save also this file.
And now I'm going to add a global using.
You can see that we have created a new namespace.
In order to add this namespace available for each module, I am going to add a global using Go Global
using and add new line of code, which is the ordering domain events.
And if you go back to order CSS, you can see that we will activate Order Created and order updated
event when updating and creating a new order.
So if you right click and build the ordering domain, you can see that we can build succeeded for our
domain layer.
As you can see that when a new order is created or updating an existing order, the respective domain
events is raised and we will dispatch these events into infrastructure layer with using Entity Framework
Core.
So that means we have finished the ordering domain layer and we will continue to develop ordering infrastructure
layer.