In this section we are going to learn why dot net and what is naive.
Net eight and C 12.
So we are going to explore the transformation of dot net.
It is developing popularity and why it is increasingly becoming the go to choice for developers around
the world.
Dot net has undergone a dramatic evolution since its inception.
It started as a windows focused framework, has now become a fast moving, open source and cross-platform
project.
Here you can see the dot net build anything anywhere.
With Dot net, you can target any application type running on any platform.
This unified platform approach means that you can develop web, mobile, desktop, games, IoT and more,
reusing your skills and codes in a familiar environment.
This versatility accelerates the development and reduce costs significantly.
Here you can see the net momentum.
The momentum behind that net is undeniable.
With over the 6.1 million monthly active users, a community of 53,000 plus members, and accolades
such as the Most Admired Developer Framework on StackOverflow and a top programming language on GitHub.
The.
Net footprint in the development landscape is expensive.
So what do developers really think about the net?
It is not just liked.
Most of the developers are love net.
Net has been ranked as the first most loved framework in the StackOverflow of developer survey.
It is modern, innovative features and open source community support make it a delightful platform for
developers.
So we said that the.
Net ecosystem is vast with millions of.
Net developers in the worldwide.
The platform provide benefits of the shared knowledge, libraries and tools.
The NuGet package manager and the Visual Studio Marketplace are treasure troves of the resources that
enhance the developer productivity and capabilities.
So now let's look at the performance of Net eight.
Net eight brings the most performant release to date.
It is not just the fast, it is blazingly fast, offering incredible response time and reduced to compute
power requirements.
Whether you are serializing Json or accessing databases or rendering server side templates.
Dot.
Net sets the benchmark for the speed.
Here you can see the Techempower benchmark.
The popular Techempower benchmark compares the web application frameworks with the task like Json serialization,
database access, and server side templating.
Rendering dot net performs faster than any other popular frameworks.
So dot net is the best for modern application.
It is designed for the modern workloads from the web two client side, from AI to cloud native developments,
dot net language features, productivity tools and modernization capabilities, positioning it as the
framework of choice for the forward thinking developers.