In this video we are going to learn cloud native development With.net eight.
Cloud native is not just a buzzword, it is a robust approach to building applications that leverage
the full potential of the cloud.
DotNet eight implements the foundational pillars of the cloud native, which are the observability,
resilience, scalability, and manageability.
With the Net eight, we can build services that scale effortlessly with demand and ensures that high
scale and high availability services using dotnet eight within your application.
So with dotnet eight there is a built in out of the box services provided under the resilience Health
Checks, Testing and Fakes and Observability.
So the cloud native stack in dotnet eight is a comprehensive toolkit for creating observable, production
ready cloud native applications.
We will cover how DotNet supports the creation of distributed applications that you can monitor, manage
and maintain with ease.
So let me start with the resilience.
You can see the resilience package in here dotnet offers to handle resilience like extension resilience
and extensions Http resilience packages.
They ensure that your applications stay responsive under the load and recover from the setbacks.
And after that we can say health checks and observability packages.
You can see that health checks are a crucial part of the maintaining cloud native applications.
And DotNet provides extensions that diagnostics that health checks that common packages.
In order to help you implement these health check features for observability.
The.
Net provide extensions that telemetry NuGet packages is our go to for insight into our applications,
performance and behaviors.
Also for testing and fix testing is the mandatory of the cloud native development with dotnet eight
ASP.Net core testing NuGet packages that we can use, and we can create reliable test suites that mimic
the real world scenarios, helping us to catch the issues before they hit on the production.
And also DotNet has open telemetry support.
DotNet eight integrates with the tools like the Prometheus and Grafana, allowing us to create rich
dashboards and alerts that you can see on the picture.
This is the typical Grafana page and dashboard that keeps us informed about our application, health
and performance.
So we can say that the Net eight handles foundational pillars of the cloud native.
These are the observability, resilience, scalability, and manageability.
Under these pillars, the Net eight provides a tremendous of development that you can think that under
observability, we can use built in metrics with dimensions, dependency injection, integration for
metrics and better for logging, enrichment and reductions.
Under the resilience, we can use new Polybase resilience packages and SignalR stateful reconnection.
And under the scalability, we can get benefit from the IoT performance and other container based developments
that we can see in the next videos.
Vậy điều đó có nghĩa là tất cả những cải tiến này cung cấp cho ứng dụng của chúng ta hoàn toàn cloud native bằng cách sử dụng.
.NET 8.