In this video, we are going to learn new enhancement of containerization and Docker images in dotnet
eight.
Let's start with a significant advancement in dotnet eight, which is the introduction of chiselled
containers.
These chiselled containers are lean version of ubuntu and stripped down to only the essential packages
needed to run your net applications.
This approach results in images that are not only smaller but also have a reduced attack surface, enhancing
both performance and security.
So what are the benefits of these smaller, chiseled images?
These small images are a game changer because they mean faster pull times, reduce storage requirements,
and quicker deployments.
This is especially crucial in environments where the bandwidth and storage are at a premium.
So another benefit is composite ASP.Net core Docker images.
We delve into composite ASP.Net core Docker image.
These images represent a more customizable form of ahead of time compilation, which does mean that
Aot based images for coreclr based images.
So this innovation allows developers to tailor their container images for optimal performance in their
specific use case.
And another benefit is running containers as a non-root users.
This is one of the important thing is using the Non-root.
By default, a major shift in dotnet eight is supports for running container images with Non-root users.
This is not just a requirement for chiselled containers, but also best practice in container security.
Running as a non-root user minimizes the potential impact of any security vulnerabilities in the container.
And another improvement of ASP.Net core and Port 80 over 80.
You can see in here default port is now 8080.
With the move to Non-root, users come a change in the default port for ASP.Net core applications in
dotnet eight.
The standard port is now 8080.
This change aligned with the container best practices and enables easier integration with many container
orchestration platforms like Kubernetes.
So you can see that these are the.
Net container enhancements that we can use for deploying cloud native applications with dotnet eight.
You can see in here how dotnet eight has achieved remarkable improvements in container size, both container
size and runtime size.
You can see the picture.
This is the container size is reduced and the runtime size also reduced dramatically.
And another big improvement in dotnet eight is compiling with native Aot.
So native Aot or ahead of time compilation is a technique where the.
Net applications are precompiled into native code.
This process significantly reduces the runtime size and improves the startup performance of the application.
So in a containerized environment, this means leaner image and faster deployment times.
So the use of the native Aot in dotnet eight has a direct impact on reducing container size.
You can see the image on the slide half significantly reduced the runtime size when we use native Aot.
So you can see the reducing the runtime size in here.
This provides faster pool and startup times and lower bandwidth consumption, which is very vital in
the cloud native environments.
So as a result, we can say that these enhancements in dotnet eight proves that Microsoft commitment
to making dotnet leading platform for containerized applications.