In this video we are going to learn what is new in Net eight.
The first one is dotnet aspire.
DotNet aspire is a naive, opinionated, cloud ready stack designed for building observable, production
ready, distributed applications.
It is delivered through a collection of NuGet packages targeting specific cloud native concerns.
Now available in preview for.
Net and another new feature is called.
Net libraries.
Core.
Net libraries have seen significant improvements, including the serialization enhancements, time abstractions,
UTF eight improvements, and methods for working with the randomness and performance focused types like
the system numerics and system runtime intrinsics.
And another new feature is metrics.
Net eight introduces new capabilities to attach key value pair tags to meter and instrument objects,
and allowing for more nuanced differentiation in aggregated metrics measurement in your applications.
And another new feature is networking.
Networking in.
Net eight includes support for Https proxy, ensuring encrypted communication even in the proxy scenarios,
thus enhancing the privacy and security.
And if you continue for newest features, which is the extension libraries.
Extension libraries have been updated with the new functionalities like the options validation logger,
message attribute constructs, extended metrics, hosted lifecycle services, kite dependency injection
services and system numeric tensor tensor primitives, and so on.
And another new feature is garbage collection.
The garbage collection mechanism now allows on the fly adjustment of memory limits.
A crucial feature for the cloud service scenarios where dynamic scaling is mandatory.
And another improvement is reflection improvements.
Reflection capabilities have been enhanced for better performance and more efficient memory usage.
Function pointers also added reflection capabilities, and another new feature is native to support
that we have already explained.
These are significant additions allowing for more efficient compilation and execution, particularly
beneficial for cloud native applications.
And lastly, we can say that dotnet SDK improvements the.
Net SDK itself has seen updates making it more robust and feature rich, aligning with the evolving
needs of modern net development.
So enhanced net published and Jetpack Commandos is coming with new net eight.