In this video we are going to learn what is naive in C sharp 12.
The first feature is primary constructs that we will also use so much when developing our application.
Primary constructs have been extended beyond the record types.
As you know that in the previous versions, primary constructs already included in the record types.
But now we can use in the class types.
So that means parameters are now in scope for the entire class body.
In order to ensure all primary constructs parameters are definitely assigned, we should explicitly
declare constructs must call the primary construct using the this syntax, we can see an example of
in.
Here there is a person class, and we can define the parameters that will be the primary constructs.
And after that we can use these name and age parameters in the inside of the class, which is the in
scope for the entire class body.
Another new feature is Collection Expressions.
The collection expressions are now a new addition, introducing a more concise syntax to create common
collection values.
This syntax simplifies the way collections are initialized and manipulated.
You can see an example in here.
The previous versions.
We should use this syntax, which is a bit confusing.
And now with dotnet eight and C-sharp 12, we can define the collections with only writing these values
inside of the brackets.
Another new feature is inline arrays.
Inline arrays enhance the performance by enabling developers to create fixed size arrays in the struct
types.
This feature is useful for optimizing memory layout and improving runtime performance.
You can see an example in here we have a buffer struct and using the inline arrays.
Another new feature is optional parameters in lambda expressions.
C-sharp 12 introduces the ability to define default values for parameters in lambda expressions.
These mirrors the syntax and rules for adding new default values in the methods.
Making lambda expression is more flexible.
You can see an example in here with defining optional parameters in the lambda expressions.
Another new feature is ref Read-only parameters.
The addition of ref Read-only parameters enhanced the way read-only references are passed in the C sharp.
This feature is a significant improvement for optimizing memory usage and performance in scenarios involving
the large data structures.
You can see in.
Here we are using the enlarge data data and including and processing data without the risk of the modification.
And another new feature is alias.
Any type C 12 expands the using alias directive to include any type, not just the named types.
This allows for the creation and semantic alias for the complex types like tuples, arrays and pointer
các kiểu dữ liệu.
Bạn có thể thấy một ví dụ.
Chúng ta có thể sử dụng coordinate alias cho tuple, và chúng ta sẽ sử dụng coordinate để định nghĩa tham số location.
Vậy chúng ta sẽ sử dụng một số tính năng mới của C# 12 trong các ứng dụng microservice của chúng ta.
Nhưng đặc biệt chúng ta sẽ sử dụng primary constructs, collection expression, inline arrays và default lambda
parameters.