In this video we are going to learn C sharp top level statements.
Global Usings and pattern matching.
When developing our microservice project, we will use additional C sharp features that comes from the
previous versions.
These are the top level statements global using and pattern matching.
So now let me explain these features one by one.
The first one is top level statements.
Top level statements in C sharp simplify the entry point of your applications.
Instead of wrapping your main logic in a main method, you can directly write the code at the top level
of your file.
Here you can see an example.
We can just start the application logic with using an console write operations.
So this code automatically be part of the main method and making it simpler to write and read.
We will develop Program.cs classes without main method and using the top level statement during the
whole course.
And another feature is global.
Using global Usings are a new way to make namespaces available across your entire project.
Instead of repeating using statement in every file, we can declare them globally in one place.
We can see an example in here.
We can use global syntax in here global using system and generics.
By this way, this feature is especially useful in a large projects and we can reduce the clutter and
improving maintainability.
We will also use global using statement in every microservices with a separate class in our course.
So if you continue our features, the next feature is C sharp pattern matching.
Pattern matching in C sharp provide a more expressive syntax for checking and deconstructing value in
your code.
Here you can see an example.
The keyword and property patterns.
We are defining a person class, and after that we can create a new person.
And after that, in this if statement, we can see that we can pattern matching.
This person is keyword and the title is manager.
That means we can filtering the person with checking the title property.
So this feature allows for more readable and concise conditional logic.
Now let's explore another powerful aspect of C sharp pattern matching, which is the using switch expression
statement.
In order to compare the discrete values.
Here you can see an example.
There is a perform operation method.
Taking the operation command as a parameter.
In this code, command is a enum value and you can see that there is a switch statement.
The switch expression evaluates this value and execute different methods based on the specific enum
value.
So you can see the command is a enum value and according to command switch block, we can check that
operation start stop, reset and different enum values and performing different operations.
So it is a concise and readable way to handle multiple condition logic paths based on the value of a
single variable.
And at the last of the statement you can see underscore, which is the discard pattern, catching any
values not explicitly handled in the cases above, in this case throwing an exception for invalid values.
So throughout the course we will be integrating these C sharp features into our microservice development.