In this section we are going to develop API gateways with ARP reverse proxy.
Applying the gateway routing pattern here you can see the big picture that we are going to build one
by one.
As you can see that we are in here and start building API gateways with ARP reverse proxy and applying
the gateway routing pattern.
And here you can see the internal architecture of the API gateways using the ARP reverse proxy.
The API gateway serve as an entry point for all client requests, and it routes these requests to the
appropriate microservices and aggregates the result and send back to the client.
And the ARP is highly customizable.
Reverse proxy solution designed to help manage the routing of the requests in microservice architectures.
So we are going to cover Erb API gateway microservices.
We will apply gateway routing pattern, which is explains how the API gateway wrote the requests to
various microservices.
And also we will apply API gateway pattern.
We will see overview of this pattern and its role of the microservice architectures.
And we will learn back end for front end Bpph pattern to understand how to tailor back end responses
to fit the needs of different front ends.
And of course, we will learn Yarp as a reverse proxy and explore Erp's capabilities as a reverse proxy
in handling requests and responses.
And we will implement API gateways using the ARP step by step guide on the setting up the ARP in a.
Net project and configuring it as an API gateway, and we will apply rate limiting in Yarp.
Implement the rate limiting to manage the number of requests a user can make to the microservices through
the ARP.
And lastly, we will containerize and orchestrate the ARP API gateway, and we will learn how to package
the Erb API gateway into a Docker container and manage it using the Docker compose.
So we will analyze and architect the API gateway using the ARP, understanding how it fits into our
existing microservice architecture.
So if you look at the steps of developing your API gateway, we will start by creating a new project
as a Erb API gateway microservices.
And this will be set up any ASP.Net core web application to serve as our API gateway.
And after that, in the second step, we will adding Erb reverse proxy into our microservice project.
We will install and configure the Erb NuGet packages into our project.
And after that we will configure the routes.
That means we will define the routes in Europe that map incoming requests to the appropriate microservices.
And after that, we will testing the gateway and ensure that the requests are correctly routed and responses
are aggregated.
And after that we will apply rate limiting.
That means we will implement and test rate limiting in order to control traffic flow through the gateway.
After that, we will perform the localization.
That means containerize the API gateway for deployment and orchestration with Docker compose.
And in the last step we will follow the docker compose orchestration testing.
We will test the entire setup, including the API gateway and microservices in a Docker compose environment.