In this video we are going to learn Gateway routing pattern.
Gateway routing pattern is wrote request to multiple microservices with exposing a single endpoint.
This pattern is useful when we want to expose multiple services on a single endpoint, and route them
to the internal back end microservices based on the request.
When the client needs to consume several microservices.
Gateway routing pattern offers to create a new endpoint that handles the request and route these requests
for each services.
For example, you can think an e-commerce application might provide services like customer shopping
cart, discount, and order history.
You can see the image on the slide.
The gateway routing pattern is exposing one single endpoint to the client application when the client
hit this endpoint.
The routing pattern routes to the request several internal microservices which including the customer
shopping cart, discount and order.
So that means the gateway routing pattern is useful if you have such a case, like a client is consuming
multiple microservices.
If one of the microservices are changed or replaced with other microservices, the client doesn't know
anything and not need to change any code.
On client side, it can continue to continue to making requests to the gateway, and the only change
will be the configuration of the routing changes.
By this way, API gateway abstracts your backend microservices from the client applications with allowing
you to keep client codes simple.
Even back end services are changed on behalf of the API gateway.
Also, this pattern can be very useful when you have multiple API versions of the same microservices.
That means if you deploy our microservices APIs with Bluegreen or Canary deployments, you can gradually
shift your requests to new API with using the gateway routing pattern.
Gateway routing pattern gives you the flexibility to use different API versions.
Routing to the request.
If the new version of API has got exceptions, it can be quickly reverted back to making only a configuration
change at the API gateway.