In this video we are going to learn what is API gateway pattern?
API gateway is a single point of entry to the client applications.
API gateway sits between the client and multiple back end services.
API gateways, manage routing to internal microservices and able to aggregate several microservices
requests in one response.
API gateways also can handle cross-cutting concerns like authentication, authorization, protocol,
translation rate limiting, logging, monitoring, load balancing, and so on.
The API gateway pattern is recommended if you want to design and build complex, large, microservice
based applications with multiple client applications.
API gateway pattern is similar to facade pattern from the object oriented design, but it is part of
a distributed system reverse proxy or gateway routing for using synchronous communication model.
We said that it is similar to facade pattern of object oriented design, so it provides a single entry
point to the APIs with encapsulating the underlying system architecture.
API gateway pattern provides a reverse proxy to redirect or route requests to your internal microservice
endpoints.
API gateway provides a single endpoint for the client application, and it internally maps the requests
to the internal microservices.
In summary, the API gateway located between the client application and the internal microservices.
It is working as a reverse proxy and routing requests from client applications to the back end services.
It is also provide cross-cutting concerns.
You can see the image on the slide that is, collect the client request in a single entry point and
route the request to the internal microservices.
So there are several client applications connect to single API gateways in here.
We should careful about this situation because if we put here a single API gateway, that means it is
possible to single point of failure risk in here.
If these client applications increase, or adding more logic to business complexity in API gateway,
it will be anti-pattern.
API gateway service can be growing and evolving based on many different requirements from the client
applications.
That's why the best practice is splitting the API gateway in multiple services or multiple similar API
gateways.
We will see the back end for front end bpph pattern later.
In summary, we need to be careful about using single API gateway.
It should be segregated based on business boundaries of the client applications, and not be a single
aggregator for all the internal microservices.