In this video we are going to see main benefits of API gateway pattern.
So the API gateway pattern provides several benefits.
Since we accommodate the client requests and route the internal microservices, we can handle main useful
features into API gateway.
The first feature is reverse proxy and gateway routing.
This is part of gateway routing pattern.
Features.
The API gateway provides reverse proxy to redirect requests to the endpoints of the internal microservices.
Usually it is using layer seven routing for Http requests for request redirection.
This routing feature provides to decouple client applications from the internal microservices, so it
is separating responsibilities on network layer.
Another benefit is obstructing internal operations.
API gateway provides abstraction over the backend microservices, so even there is no change on backend
microservices, it won't be affect to the client applications.
That means don't need to update client applications when changing backend microservices.
Instead, API gateway will only change configuration file to redirect new services.
And the second main feature is request aggregation and gateway aggregation.
This is part of the gateway aggregation pattern.
Features.
API gateway can aggregate multiple internal microservices into a single client request.
With this approach, the client application sends a single request to the API gateway.
After that, API gateway dispatches several requests to the internal microservices and then aggregates
the result and sends everything back to the client application in one single response.
The main.
The main benefit of this gateway aggregation pattern is to reduce chattiness communication between the
client and the back end services.
Another main benefit is cross-cutting concerns and gateway offloading.
This is part of the gateway offloading pattern.
Features.
Since API gateway handles client requests in centralized places, it is best practice to implement cross-cutting
functionality on the API gateways.
The cross-cutting functionalities could be authentication, authorization, service discovery, integration,
response, caching, retry policy, circuit breaker and other operations for resilience, rate limiting,
throttling, load balancing, logging, tracing, correlation and IP listing, and so on.
You can find the all cross-cutting concerns that can be handled from the API gateway in this list.