In this video we are going to learn back end for front end pattern.
Backend for frontend pattern basically separates API gateways as per the specific frontend application.
In current design we have several backend services which are consumed by the front end applications,
and between them we put API gateway for handling the routing and aggregate operations.
But this makes a single point of failure.
So in order to solve this problem, backend for frontend offers to create several API gateways and grouping
them the client applications according to their boundaries and split them different API gateways.
A single and complex API gateway can be risky and becoming a bottleneck into your architecture.
Larger systems often expose multiple API gateways by grouping client type like mobile, web, and desktop
functionality.
Back end for front end pattern is useful when you want to avoid customizing a single backend for multiple
interfaces.
So we should create several API gateways as per user interfaces.
These API gateways provide to best match the needs of the front end environment, without worrying about
the affecting other front end applications.
The back end for front end pattern provides directions for implementing multiple gateways.
The main purpose of using back end for front end pattern is to provide client applications.
Has a focused interface that connects with the internal microservices.
For example, data consumption by a mobile user interface could be different from data consumption by
a web browser.
In that case, for better data representation, two backend for front end pattern can be used one for
the web, one for the mobile.
Let's have a look at the image on the slide with using multiple backend for front end API gateways.
There are three API gateways one for the web, one for the mobile and another for the desktop applications.
So with following backend for front end pattern, we have created three API gateways that can provide
a different APIs tailored for each client application type.