In this video we are going to learn URP reverse proxy for API gateway.
But before that, let's understand the basics and as a basics we will learn what is reverse proxy.
A reverse proxy is a server that sits in front of the web servers and forwards client requests to these
web servers.
You can see the image as a reverse proxy.
It is basically sits in front of the web servers and forwards the client requests to these web servers,
and it is implements gateway routing and API gateway pattern.
It acts as an intermediary for requests from the clients seeking resources from servers that provide
those resources and functions, including the load balancing, which is distributes incoming traffic
across multiple servers to ensure no single server bears too much load, and it is also provide offloading
that can perform tasks like the authentication, SSL encryption, caching, and so on.
And also it provides security.
It is adding additional layer for the security, hiding the true details of the backend servers from
the external access.
So now we can understand what is Microsoft Reverse Proxy?
Which name is URP?
URP is a lightweight, highly customizable reverse proxy solution developed by the Microsoft and tailored
for.
Net applications.
It is open source and primarily developed by Microsoft.
It is designed to integrate seamlessly with.
Net core and making it easy to add to existing.
Net projects.
It aims to simplify the routing of requests to different backend services, offering capabilities for
request transformation, load balancing and more.
So we will examine this project on GitHub.
But before that, let's understand the Microsoft Reverse Proxy URP features.
The first feature is customizable routing rules.
It allows detailed specification of how requests should be routed to the backend services, and the
second feature is Cross Platform.
URP is built on.
Net and making it Cross platform, it can run on any platform that supports.
Net core, including the windows, Linux and macOS, and it also supports latest protocols.
URP supports modern networking protocols including gRPC, Http two, and WebSockets.
It has great performance and optimized for high throughput and low latency, making it suitable for
the scenarios requiring high performance proxying, and it is also include health checks, monitor the
health of the backend services, and reroute the traffic as needed.
And we can say it is using the modern Http client and uses the latest Http client features in.
Net for improved performance.
Now we can examine our GitHub project of the URP and documentation.
So if you click the links on the slide and go to the GitHub page, you can see the reverse proxy is
storing under the Microsoft repository on GitHub.
And if you scroll down you can get details about this project, which is the URP project.
And it is stand for the yet another reverse proxy.
And this is developed by the Microsoft for cross-cutting concerns and applying the reverse proxy.
And in here I'm going to click the Getting Started link that is opening the documentation of the URP
reverse proxy.
And here you can see an example of the how to getting started with URP using the dotnet eight.
Here you can see that this will be creating a new web application.
And after that this will be adding a project reference which is the URP reverse proxy NuGet package.
And after that this will be arranging the middleware by adding the builder services.
Add reverse proxy and loading configurations from the application settings and the section of the reverse
proxy.
And after that you can see the configurations including.
At this point, this will be including a low cost reverse proxy routes.
Route definitions, clusters, destinations, and so on.
And lastly, we can run the project with dotnet run command in order to route incoming requests to back
end services.
And after that, in the left hand side, you can see that there is different documentation.
For example, we can examine the how to configure these URP with advanced configurations.
In this section you can read this documentation to understand how we can load and how we can structure
of the configurations for any redirect operations, including the rod, cluster, ID, match and destinations.
And also you can check the configuration providers that include of the structure of the providers and
routes, clusters, memory config lifecycles and so on.
And you can see configuration filters that including how we can filter the configurations with coding,
and also configurations using the AI proxy config filter interface.
This is the an implementation and example of these features.
And if you look at the these left hand side you can see the features of the URP reverse proxy.
If I scroll down, you can see that we can provide authentication and authorization with only settings
on the configurations Json file.
And also.
So you can see that we will apply the rate limiting with changing the configuration.
Or we can use these operations by coding on program says that you can handle different rate limiting
algorithms in the program says.
So you can see we will apply course requests in the reverse proxy ARP.
And we can apply session affinity load balancing.
And we can check the destination health checks, gRPC support, distributed tracing support, WebSockets
and so on.
So these are the features that can handle in the ARP reverse proxy.