In this video we are going to explain IRB architecture with the pipelines and extensibility.
So here you can see the IRB architecture with pipelines.
And we will start with the ASP.Net core front end and Http client backends.
We are leveraging ASP.Net core for its front end.
Handling the incoming requests and Http client for communication with back end services.
It integrates seamlessly into ASP.Net core infrastructure, working as a middleware that can be combined
with other components like API calls.
And also it includes configuration and route loadings.
Routes are loaded from the configuration sources, with ASP.Net Json file being the default.
These routes are then loaded into ASP.Net route table, enabling the IRB to match incoming requests
to specific routes.
And also we can define routes to cluster mapping after receiving a request that match a route.
Your maps this route to a cluster.
Determining the potential destination or back end services for the request.
And after that we can say dynamic configuration via config provider model.
IRB allows for dynamic configuration through a config provider model, enabling runtime changes and
adjustments based on various factors like back end, server status or application requirements, and
also IRB provide session affinity and load balancing during the proxy process.
IRB can maintain session affinity cookie sessions, ensuring that requests from a particular client
are consistently routed to the same server for load balancing.
IRB employs algorithms like power of Two choices, which select two random destinations and chooses
the least loaded among them.
And also this will be providing health checks.
IRB support both active and passive health checks.
Active health checks regularly ping configured endpoints in back end services to assess their health.
Passive health checks observed the response codes from the back end services as traffic is forwarded,
marking servers as unhealthy based on certain criterias.
And also we can say request and response processing during this process.
IRB can transform requests by modifying URLs, headers, and other attributes.
It typically avoids modifying the body to maintain performance.
The transformed request is then forwarded to selected back end server.
And this is the pipeline of the process.
And we can also add the pipeline modularization and extensibility.
IRB also is designed as a pipeline, with each step being a module.
You can see for these steps as a module.
Every module like route matching, load balancing, health checks, request transforms and so on can
be customized or replaced with custom implementation.
So this modular architecture provide immense flexibility to tailored IRB to specific requirements.
And here you can see the extensibility points of the IRB.
IRB is highly extensible using the C sharp.
It allows you to customize almost every aspects of the request processing and forwarding.
Developers can extend or replace components of the IRB pipeline to seat specific requirements, and
we can say that we can develop our custom configurations, and custom configurations can be written
in C sharp.
For more complex scenarios where Json based configurations are not sufficient.
This provides developers with the flexibility to program complex logic into their proxy behaviors.