In this video we are going to do domain analysis for the API gateway microservices.
As always, we will check domain models, application use cases, Rest API endpoints and underlying
data structures for your API gateway microservices.
So let's get started with domain models.
Your API gateway doesn't have traditional domain models or entities like other microservices.
Instead, it primarily deals with the configurations for routing and reverse proxy settings.
That means we don't have any domain model in your API gateway, and we will only develop a configuration
file for reverse proxy settings.
After that, we can check the application use cases for your API gateway.
So we should define your API gateway use case.
Analyzing.
Overall, we can say that these use cases are e-commerce microservice use cases.
And we can start with the catalog microservice use cases.
It is including get all products and categories with product ID and category and create, update, delete
product and following that we can start and continue Crud operations on basket microservices that including
get shopping cart with items, store shopping cart with items and delete shopping cart with items.
And just after that we can go to the ordering microservices Crud operations including the get orders
with items, create, update and delete order and add and remove item from the order.
And after that we can say asynchronous ordering operations that include basket checkout, which is the
consume basket checkout event from the RabbitMQ using mass transit.
And another one is order fulfillment that perform order fulfillment operation to notify other microservices,
including the billing, shipment and notification.
So these are the application use cases for your API gateway microservices that we are going to expose
services to implement these kind of use cases.
So here you can see the rest API endpoint of internal microservices.
You can see that we have already exposed these microservices when developing our microservices for product
catalog microservices basket and ordering microservices, you can see that the endpoints are listing
in here.
And use case explanations.
Come to the next column and we will follow and implement these endpoints.
And we will expose these endpoints from the API gateway to the client application in order to redirect
incoming requests to internal microservices.
And here you can see the Rest API endpoints for the Erb API gateway microservices.
Basically, Erb API gateway will expose with microservices, putting microservice name as a prefix of
the internal URL.
So here you can see that we will put the microservice name as a prefix of the internal URL.
And this is an example of the implementation of the endpoint microservice name slash microservice internal
URL.
So as an example you can see the for example getting products with slash products from the catalog microservices.
And when we are exposing this service into Erb API gateway, we will put the microservice name as a
slash catalog.
And after that the rest of the endpoint comes from the internal microservice URL.
So you can follow the other endpoints following the same principles.
We will put the microservice name in the beginning of the endpoint from the Erb API gateway.
And continue of these operations comes from the internal microservice request API to performing these
use cases, get products by ID category and Crud operations on catalog and following the same structure
in basket microservices.
Here you can see the basket microservices internal exposing endpoints when performing the get, post
and delete operations on basket microservices and basket operation.
And we will expose these endpoints in the Erb API gateway with putting the slash shopping cart in the
beginning of the endpoints.
By this way, we can separate the catalog and shopping cart microservices with incoming requests on
the Erb API gateway.
And following that, here you can see the ordering microservices that perform from the Erb API gateway.
We will put slash ordering microservice name, and after that we will continue the orders collection
and endpoints to implement order related use cases.
So these are the exposing services that we are going to expose from the Erb API gateway.
Here you can find all services that exposing from the Erb API gateway listing in three tables for catalog
basket and ordering microservices.
After that, we will analyze the underlying data structure of the Erb microservices.
Basically Erb API gateway microservices has no database.
So for your API gateway, the infrastructure focus is more on the routing and configuration rather than
data structures.
It doesn't interact with databases or manage state directly, but ensures efficient and correct routing
of requests to the services that handle the data.
So we can say that Erb API gateway is a critical component in microservice architecture, and handling
the routing of the requests to various backend services efficiently.
It abstracts the complexity of the underlying services from the client and providing a single point
of entry.