In this video, we are going to do technical analysis for your API gateway.
Microservices that include application architecture, analyze pattern and principles libraries, NuGet
packages and project folder structure that we are going to analyze.
So let me start with the application architecture style for your API gateway.
We don't have any architecture which is simple application settings configuration for reverse proxy
irb.
API gateway doesn't follow any application architecture and focus on the configuration based approach
to route requests to different microservices.
That means we will implement reverse proxy.
Reverse proxy is a server that sits in front of the web server and forward the client requests to these
web servers.
If you look at the pattern and principles, we can say that we will implement gateway routing pattern
to manage routing of the requests to various services handling the path based routing.
And we will implement API gateway pattern irb API Gateway Server as a single entry point for multiple
microservices and simplifying the client side interaction.
And we will also implement the reverse proxy pattern IRB act as an intermediary for requests from the
client seeking resources from the microservices IT roster.
After that, we can analyze libraries and NuGet packages that we are going to use, and we will use
airport reverse proxy packages, and we will install these packages to enable the implementation of
the reverse proxy capabilities within the application.
So we said that IRB is a lightweight and highly customizable reverse proxy solution developed by the
Microsoft.
And it is tailored for the.
Net application.
That means it is designed to integrate seamlessly with dotnet core.
That's why we will use airport reverse proxy NuGet packages.
And if you look at the folder structure, you can see that we will develop our irb API gateway project,
including the Program.cs and application settings Json file.
Program.cs is the entry point of the application where IRB and other services are configured, and here
you can see the application settings Json file, which is a central to irb API gateway functionality.
And this file contains all the routing configurations for the microservices.
And here you can see as an example of the application settings configuration.
It includes.
The routes and routes are defined pointing to the different services like catalog basket and ordering
microservices.
And we can also implement load balancing, health check and other middleware configurations with this
file.
And lastly we will analyze the deployment of the IRB API gateway.
We will basically containerize our service with Docker and ensuring the deployment and integration with
the IRB API gateway.
And we will implement Docker file and docker compose file for running irb API gateway in a docker compose
environment.
As you can see that we have completed the domain and technical analysis for irb API gateway microservices
and we will start to development.