In this video we are going to create Erb API gateway microservices into our microservice solution.
Here you can see the our folder structure that we are going to develop.
During this video I'm going to start with setting up the solution structure.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Recap Microservices solution.
I am going to create a new solution folder like building blocks services and so on.
So we will create a new solution folder which name is API gateways.
Right click the solution add new solution folder and give the name as a API gateways.
And this folder will encapsulate all API gateway related projects.
After that, we will add a new project under this API gateway solution folder.
That means we will create an ASP.Net core empty solution, which name Erb API gateway under this API
gateway solution folder.
So let's get started.
Right click this solution, add new project and select the ASP.Net core empty project.
Double click this project template and give the project name as a Erb API gateway and select the correct
location.
For that purpose.
We can click this button and select the source folder, and under the source folder we are going to
create new folder.
Which name is API gateways.
First of all I'm going to select this folder which is the source folder.
And also I am adding API gateways solution folder in here.
That means we have created API gateway solution folder under our solution.
And we will create physical folder with following the source backslash API gateways that we are going
to create Erb API gateway.
Under this folder structure.
Please also create the correct structure of your Erb API gateway, and make sure that this will be the
correct folder path for your API gateway.
And after that, I am going to click the next button and selected framework as a.
Net eight.
Configure the Https.
And also we will enable the Docker and Docker operating system should be Linux.
And I am not checking these top level statement because we will follow the top level statement in Program.cs.
Yes, please make these configurations like this way and click the create button.
This will be create our Erb API gateway ASP.Net m2 project inside of the our microservices solution.
Here you can see the microservices created successfully.
And if you go to Program.cs, this will be the entry point of our ASP.Net project.
We can arrange our project according to our minimal setup.
First of all, before building the application, we can put a command and section for adding services
into ASP.Net built in dependency injection container.
And after building the application, we can again put a command for configuring Http request pipeline
with removing these Mapkit operation.
And this is the minimal configuration for any ASP.Net microservice application for our solution.
That means this code sets up a minimal ASP.Net core application and services, and Middlewares configuration
specific to your will be added in the next videos.
But before that, if you look at the port numbers for your API gateway, microservices, we can see
that we will expose the Erb API gateway in development and local environment for 5004 and 5054, and
we will expose 6004 and 6064 for the code environment in the Erb API gateway.
So I am going to set these local environment port numbers into our ASP.Net empty project.
In our solution, if you go back to Visual Studio, you can right click the Erb API gateway and go to
the properties.
Or you can open the properties and go to the Launch Settings Json file.
In here I am going to edit our API gateway http and https port numbers.
Here you can see the http.
I'm going to change this port number to 5004.
And again under the https.
I am going to select the http one and change http port number as a 5004.
And just after that for https port, I am going to change 5054.
So please set the port numbers according to our slide with 5004 for the Http and 5054 for the Https
in the Erb API gateway project.
And finally we can run the application.
I am going to right click the http api gateway and set a startup project.
After that, we can go to the running profile.
If you change the running profile from Docker to Https, we will run our application in the https mode.
And if you click this button, this will be run your API gateway project in Https mode locally.
And this will be exposing our services in 5054.
And you can verify the starting and exposing services from the project console window that you can see
that we have successfully started our API gateway under our issue of microservices solution.
Also, we can change the launch browser from the true to false in order to avoid to see our browser
when we are starting to our application.
So that means we have completed the creating our API gateway project and ready to implement the reverse
proxy into our ASP.Net application.