In this video we are going to develop ERP reverse proxy.
That means we will setting up the ERP reverse proxy into our ERP API gateway microservices, which will
act as an API gateway for our ERP microservices.
So the first step is we will install ERP reverse proxy NuGet packages for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the API gateway folder.
Open the ERP API gateway project and go to the dependencies.
Right click and manage NuGet packages.
And this time we will install Brose ERP Reverse Proxy and we will install ERP reverse proxy NuGet packages
into our ERP API gateway ASP.Net project.
So I'm going to install these NuGet packages.
So installation completed you can double click the project file.
And you can confirm that we have successfully downloaded ERP reverse proxy NuGet packages into our API
gateway project.
Please save this file.
And the second step is we should register Erb in ASP.Net Dependency Injection tool.
That means we will update the program CSS in order to include Erb services and middleware.
Please open the Program.cs.
And just after that we will add the required services to the container.
At this point I am going to use builder dot services dot add reverse proxy extension method and also
we will use load from config method in order to passing the section of the reverse proxy under the application
settings Json file.
So this code sets up the Erb reverse proxy.
Required objects included ASP.Net dependency injection, and just after that, in the configuring Http
request pipeline, I am going to use app dot map reverse proxy extension method in order to configure
the Http request pipeline according to reverse proxy.
So with adding these two line of code in the configuring Https request pipeline and adding services
to registering the container, we will set up the Erb as a middleware in the ASP.Net core application
and enabling it to act as a reverse proxy based on the configuration defined in the application settings
Json file reverse proxy section.
So that means in the third step, we can configure the Http reverse proxy in the application settings
Json file.
So I'm going to define routes and clusters in the application settings Json file.
For reverse proxy settings, please open the Application settings Json file and go to this location.
After the load host we can define our reverse proxy configurations in here.
Here I'm going to copy the reverse proxy configurations in the Application settings Json file that you
can see in this Json part of the reverse proxy.
So this is the basic settings redirect all the requests to catalog microservices.
So basically the app reverse proxy using the concepts of the routes to represent the request patterns
for the proxy.
Here you can see the routes.
And after that we have also clusters which is represent the services to forward those requests.
So these configuration redirect all incoming requests to the catalog microservices.
Here you can see the the catch all part of the match operation.
And this catch all pattern will capture all the routes and forward them to the specified destination.
And this example Yarp configuration with the catch all pattern routing to all incoming requests to the
destination address, which is our catalog.
Microservices.
In Docker environment, you can realize that our destination address, which is indicating our catalog
microservices, is using Http, not Https, because we are going to avoid SSL certification exception
when we are redirecting requests from irb API gateway to catalog microservices, and after that, these
6000 port number is belonging to Http endpoint for the catalog microservices.
And these will be the our destination address for each request coming from the IRB API gateway.
So before running the irb API gateway we should activate our destination address which is the catalog
microservices.
So how can we start catalog microservices on Docker environment?
Of course we can use Docker Compose for our microservice solution.
For that purpose I'm going to right click the Docker compose and set a start up project and make sure
that your Docker desktop is up and running for now.
And just after Docker Compose setting up the starting project, I am going to click this button in order
to start without debugging and activate all microservices and backing services on Docker environment.
So this will be start all these Docker compose and related services available on Docker environment,
including the our catalog microservices that we will redirect the requests from the local irb API gateway
to the Docker catalog microservices.
So you can verify all microservices is up and running on Docker desktop.
And if you look at the catalog API, you can see that catalog API is exposing 6066 ports.
So we will use 6000 Http port when we are redirecting the request.
So after running these microservices we can verify our destination is working.
King or not.
You can copy this and print and paste into the Our Postman.
If you open the postman and create a new Http get request, you can send a http get request to our destination
address, which is the catalog docker address.
Here you can see that our destination address returning products for us.
So that means we are ready to redirect our request from the Erb API gateway.
For that purpose, I'm going to come back to our Visual Studio, and when we are running the Docker
compose without stopping this docker compose, I'm going to right click the Erb API gateway and set
a startup project.
Since we are running this ERP API gateway from our local computer, we can run both Docker compose and
local erb API gateway.
For that purpose, I'm going to click https run button in order to start Erb API gateway from our local
development environment.
After running the Erb API gateway, we can verify from the project console log.
Here you can see the Erb API gateway exit configurations, and this will be loading proxy data from
the configuration successfully.
And now it is listening to port numbers which is the https localhost 5054.
So now I am going to send random requests to this URL.
And this will be redirect to us catalog microservices Docker environment which is our destination address.
For that purpose please open the postman.
And in here I'm going to come here and I'm going to write the https localhost 5054.
And this will be redirect endpoint to our catalog.
Microservices hit the Http send button.
And here you can see the our products are listing in here successfully.
That means we have successfully redirecting these requests to the Erb API gateway to Destination catalog
microservices.
We can again verify from the console logs.
Here you can see that the ARP reverse proxy forwarding the request to the our destination of the localhost
6000 products endpoint.
We can also send additional requests including the catalog microservice endpoints, for example get
product by id category, and so on.
For example, let's open the postman and send by id and this will be getting a specific ID of the product
from our catalog microservices over the Erb API gateway.
So as you can see that all requests redirect to catalog API and get the products with the ID information.
As you can see that we have successfully demonstrated basic functioning of the ARP as an API gateway,
handling the request and routing them to the appropriate microservices.