In this video we are going to implement API gateway using the reverse proxy.
So we will explore how to implement an API gateway using the API to efficiently route requests to internal
microservices in our microservices.
So we can use Yarp to build an API gateway.
By providing the configuration for the services, we want to route the traffic.
And we have three microservices.
These are the catalog basket and ordering that we are going to route the traffic and this will be our
downstream microservices.
So if you look at the API gateway Rest APIs the API gateway will expose these endpoints.
Here you can see the ARP request API and internal microservices.
This is for the catalog microservices catalog has get product, get product by ID category and Crud
operations.
And we can put the catalog microservice name in the beginning of the endpoint.
And after that the rest of the URL can be same with the internal microservice URL.
So we will follow the same steps for the shopping cart basket and also ordering microservices.
So the idea is that we should put the microservice name in the beginning of the URL and continue with
the microservices internal URL.
So if you follow this principle into our architecture, the API gateway will act as an intermediary,
routing incoming requests to the appropriate downstream microservices such as catalog, basket and ordering,
and to fully integrate basket ordering services.
Similar route and cluster configurations need to be added into the application settings Json file into
your API gateway project, and each microservices specific route are mapped to accordingly to ensure
request Proxied to correct destination.
So now I'm going to explain and show our Visual Studio.
If you open the Visual Studio, you can see that in the last configuration we have added the reverse
proxy configurations under the Application Settings Json file into your API gateway project.
And according to these configurations, we will map the incoming order requests to the destination of
the catalog microservices, and we will develop API gateway configurations for redirecting each request
to downstream microservices for each microservices.
For that purpose, we are going to define our microservice parameters.
That means microservice names for the path naming.
For the path naming, we can give catalog basket and ordering services.
And this is the path naming that we are going to expose the external client requests with separating
these microservices according to the incoming requests.
So that means if you look at the order architecture, the client application send the requests according
to our path naming.
For example, if you send the catalog services, we will redirect the request into downstream catalog
microservices.
And if the request comes from the basket service and continue with the basket service endpoints, we
will redirect to internal basket microservices and so on.
So this is the path naming that we have defined into our route configurations into the Yarp configuration
file.
And after that we can define the configuration structure that including the route cluster path and destination.
So now if you go back to our Visual Studio, you can see that this reverse proxy settings starting with
the route definitions.
And after that in the route definition, we have a cluster ID that need to define just after the route
definition.
This is the cluster definition that we need to define cluster one, and using cluster one in the routes
of the reverse proxy settings.
And after that we can continue with the path definition.
If you continue the configuration, you can see that after cluster ID in the routes we will use path
definition.
That is, indicate that the matching pattern for the path information that we are going to redirect
to this destination.
So that means in the last step we have a destination configuration.
This will be including a destination address for internal downstream microservices.
In our case, we will match the incoming order requests and designate to catalog microservices.
But this time we will define for each microservices.
That means we need to create route, cluster, path and destination for each microservices.
For example, for catalog microservices, we can use route as a catalog route, cluster as a catalog
cluster, path as a slash catalog service, and slash catch all for incoming all requests into catalog
microservices.
As a destination, we can give localhost 6000, which is a Docker address of the catalog microservices.
So that means we need a route naming and structure.
We define the routes for each microservices.
For catalog we need to catalog route.
For basket we need to basket route for ordering, we need to ordering route.
And each route is mapped to a corresponding cluster which is then directs to request to designated service.
So in here you can see that we will define three route services.
And these will be three destination services for internal microservices.
So now let's apply these configurations into our application Settings.json file.
And.
For catalog service, I am going to change the configuration.
So first of all, I am going to remove all reverse proxy settings and replace with the catalog microservices.
And here you can see the our latest reverse proxy configuration.
And this is only for catalog microservices.
And according to these configuration you can see that the root is catalog root which is mapped to the
cluster of the catalog cluster.
And you can see the path starting with the slash catalog service.
And catch all that captures all the requests prefixed with the catalog service and route them to the
catalog.
Microservices running at the localhost 6000.
And the catch all pattern syntax is used to forward the path and query string from the original request
to the destination service, and here you can see the route definition, which name is catalog route,
and the cluster ID we have defined catalog cluster that is under clusters.
These are catalog cluster.
And we have defined path and transform data and destinations.
According to these catalog rod and catalog cluster.
And make sure that your destination address should be Http and point for the internal microservices.
And using the 6000 or 60 related port numbers.
In our case, I am going to use catalog microservice internal docker address, which is the http localhost
6000.
So as you can see that we have defined catalog microservices, reverse proxy rod and cluster definitions.
And in the next video we will continue with the other microservices.