In this video, we are going to continue to configure Yarp reverse proxy in the Yarp API gateway.
Microservices.
In order to route the traffic for catalog basket and ordering microservices.
That means this time we will extend the configuration file including the basket and ordering rod and
cluster definitions.
If you look at our example, it's the same way with the catalog.
We will create basket and ordering route, and we will create basket and ordering cluster and continue
with the basket and ordering services for the endpoint.
Definition and destination will be the r localhost and 6000 for Docker address for the basket and ordering
microservices.
If you look at the port numbers that we are going to expose during the course, here, you can see the
microservices and microservices, local Docker and Docker inside port numbers for Http and Https.
So during the course I'm going to use http port when redirecting from the Yarp API gateway in order
to avoid SSL certificate exception for that purpose.
For catalog basket and ordering microservices, we will use 6000, 6001 and 6003 port numbers in Docker
environment.
And after that, when we are deploying Yarp API gateway in Docker network, we can use 8080 port numbers
with these catalog basket and ordering API container names.
So now let's focus on the Docker environment and Docker port numbers.
Please open the application settings Json file and locate the reverse proxy configurations under these
application settings Json file.
And we will extend the configurations to include routing for the basket and ordering microservices in
addition to catalog services already configured in here.
So now I am going to remove these reverse proxy configuration.
And I'm going to replace with the including all microservices.
So if you come here and replace these configurations you can see that we have including all microservices
with this configuration.
So let me explain one by one.
Basically each microservices now has a dedicated route definition.
These are the routes collection which including the catalog route basket route and ordering route.
And according to this route, for each route we have defined cluster ID which is the catalog cluster
basket cluster and ordering cluster.
And these cluster definitions is comes after the route definitions.
Here you can see the cluster definitions catalog basket and ordering cluster.
And each cluster has the destination address that including Http port numbers for catalog 6000 Docker
port number and continue with the basket localhost 6001 again http and ordering http localhost 6003.
So this is the catalog cluster and destination address definitions.
And this is the route definition for each microservices including catalog route and matching pattern
is.
You can see the catalog service for incoming requests from the client application.
And we will redirect each request with coming from these endpoint to the destination address.
And in here you can see the path expecting from the basket cluster and basket route basket dish service
in the beginning of the request.
And for ordering microservices the matching pattern expecting slash ordering dish service, which is
the incoming request, comes from the endpoint to the irb API gateway, resurrecting to corresponding
route and cluster definitions.
So please develop these configurations into your computer.
We basically start with the route definition.
And each microservice has dedicated route.
And these routes are mapped to their respective clusters with the catch all path pattern, and allowing
any path under these routes to be captured and forwarded.
So each route act as an entry point for the request targeting to specified microservices.
And we said that this catch all pattern in the path ensures that all requests under a specified route,
which in this case catalog service, are captured and redirected to belonging destination address.
And we have also transformed configuration and the transform configuration with the catch all is used
to forward the incoming request path and query to the destination.
Microservices.
And after defining this route definition, we have a cluster definitions and cluster represents a groups
of destinations microservices that Earp can forward to request to, and each cluster has one or more
destination.
In our case, each cluster has a single destination pointing to the Docker address of the are microservices.
After defining these configurations on your computer, we can see as an example of the reverse proxy
redirection.
Here you can see as an example usage.
If you send the https localhost 5054, this is the URL address for the irb api gateway.
And if you send the slash catalog service slash products, this will be redirect to us http localhost
6000, which is the Docker catalog microservice address and slash products.
So that means these are.
This will be replaced from the this address.
So as the same way we can see the basket service example.
If you center slash basket service slash basket and slash then this will be get the http localhost 6001
which is the basket microservices docker URL address.
And this will be contained with the slash basket and slash w n which is the end of the our irb API gateway
endpoint.
So this is the example usage of the irb API gateway and reverse proxy configuration.