In this video, we are going to test the ARP Reverse proxy as an API gateway into our ARP API gateway
microservices.
So this involves routing the request from the API gateway to the respective internal microservices,
which are the catalog basket and ordering microservices.
If you look at our microservices deployment strategy, we are at the deployment one, and we have developed
the ARP API gateway from our local computer, and we will redirect the request to the Docker internal
microservices.
That means we accodomate the incoming client requests into our local ARP API gateway microservices and
redirect these requests to the Docker network, which is internal microservices for catalog basket and
ordering microservices in Docker network.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio.
And before we start, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running, and we will start with
activating our backing services and our internal microservices in the network for that purpose, I'm
going to use Docker Compose, right click Docker Compose and set a startup project.
Just after that you can come here and click this button running Docker Compose without debugging.
So this will be activate our backing services and internal microservices in the network.
By this way we will activate Catalog Basket and ordering microservices that we can redirect the requests
from the local computer to the Docker network.
So after running this docker compose, you can verify the Docker compose profile on Docker desktop and
make sure that your internal microservices is up and ready into Docker environment.
Just after that, without stopping the docker compose running profile, we should run irb API gateway
in our local computer.
Don't stop the docker compose.
Instead, set a irb API gateway as a startup project and run https mode.
Otherwise, Docker containers are not responding and we cannot redirect internal microservices.
For that purpose.
I am going to right click irb API gateway when running the Docker compose and set a startup project.
And now I'm going to run https mode irb api gateway in our local computer.
After running https mode, we can verify from the project console log and loading proxy data from the
configuration, which is the application settings Json file.
And now these microservices listening on the https localhost 5054.
After that, we can send the request to our API gateway in order to redirect to internal Docker microservices
for that purpose.
Please open the Postman in Postman collection.
I have created irb API gateway collection, including the three subfolders which are the catalog, basket
and ordering, and these will be redirecting the request to each microservices according to incoming
requests endpoint.
But before that, if you look at the localhost environment, I have set the environment variables and
adding the URL which is the https localhost 5050 port.
And these are the our port numbers according to our port mapping into our slide.
So we will send Http get requests into our local irb API gateway.
And this will be redirect to us internal microservices.
After defining this endpoint, you can open the catalog folder under the IRB API gateway and open the
Http get method for the Getproducts from the catalog microservices.
Here you can see the endpoint.
I have changed the endpoint with a URL which is 5054 port, and adding the slash catalog services to
indicate that this API gateway will be redirect to internal catalog microservices.
And the rest of the endpoint is exactly same with the catalog microservices.
I have just copied from this endpoint from the catalog and Getproducts and duplicate this endpoint and
paste into our irb API gateway Getproduct request.
So now I am going to send http get request to the irb API gateway with a given endpoint.
So I'm going to hit the http send button.
Here you can see that we can successfully get the products from the catalog microservices.
And if you look at the R project console log from the API gateway, you can see that we have successfully
proxying the incoming requests to the http localhost 6000 slash products and page number and page size.
So this is the successful request to our API gateway to internal Docker network.
And I'm going to following the same steps for the get product by ID.
And here you can see that we can get a specific ID information.
Again if you look at the R project console log you can see the redirection in here.
So also we can get products by category in here.
And this will be the similar for our catalog microservices.
We can create a new catalog and new product into our catalog microservices with a given payload.
I'm going to send a http post request and creating a new product.
You can get this product from the get products.
You can see that our newly created products comes to do our adding product list.
And these are the similar Http get and post operations with the catalog microservices over the ARP API
gateway.
So I'm going to follow the same steps for the basket microservices.
Here you can see that we can create a new basket with a given username as the boolean.
And I have created basket services over the irb API gateway.
Here you can see that this will be redirecting basket services with a given endpoint slash basket and
slash service.
We can verify that from the project console log.
We have forwarded to our basket microservices and created a new username.
And now I am going to send these username to basket Checkout operation in order to start asynchronous
communication.
If you open the post checkout basket, you can see the URL and slash basket service and slash basket
and checkout with the body of the our payload.
And if I send the http post request, this will be start asynchronous communication that we can confirm
from the RabbitMQ dashboard.
If you log in the RabbitMQ dashboard, you can see that this will be hit or RabbitMQ basket checkout
event queue and consume from the ordering microservices.
So in order to verify the consumer operations, we can open the ordering folder under the ARP API gateway
and get orders with pagination and send Http get request to the ARP API gateway with slash ordering
dash service endpoint.
Here you can see that we have three orders that we have created with newly created order in the last
order onto our item.
Of course, we use pagination for that purpose.
I need to go to second page because we will select two items in paging.
And here you can see newly created order item.
This is the order name as a boolean.
We can also send the ARP API gateway.
Get orders by name.
I'm going to change the order name as a boolean and send the http get request.
And here you can see the newly created order with asynchronous communication.
So as you can see that we have successfully tested API gateway operations and observed that the ARP
API gateway effectively routes the request to the respective downstream microservices.