In this video, we are going to add rate limiting into our reverse proxy as an API gateway.
So we are focusing on adding rate limiting into our reverse proxy within the API gateway.
Microservices and rate limiting is a crucial feature for maintaining the stability and security of our
services by controlling the rate of the traffic.
And here you can see the official documentation of the Yarp reverse proxy and rate limiting and rate
limiting.
Its a technique to limit the number of requests to our API in order to improve security and reduce the
load on the servers.
An Yarp natively support the rate limiting mechanism introduced from the.
Net seven and here you can see how we can apply rate limiting into our ASP.Net project.
We basically use add rate limiter extension method and specify the options.
And as a configuration.
You can see that in the route definition, we can specify the rate limiter policy and give the policy
name.
When we are registering into ASP.Net dependency injection.
So if you scroll down, you can see that how we can add this into.
Dependency injection with services dot add rate limiter and giving the options.
Options including the fixed window limiter and give the permit limit.
Windows.
Queue element and queue processing order.
And just after that we need to add.
Rate limiter middleware with using the app dot use rate limiter.
And it is important to use this method before using the app dot map reverse proxy.
So now let's apply the rate limiting into our API gateway.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to your API gateway project and open the Program.cs.
In the Program.cs, we need to add the rate limiter into Dependency Injection and configure the rate
limiter options.
Just after adding the reverse proxy, I'm going to come here and adding the builder services add rate
limiter extension method and save this file.
Here you can see that we will use add Rate limiter and giving the rate limiter options and into options
We have add fixed window limiter and give the name as a fixed.
As an option.
We can define Option Window as a timespan from second, ten second and give.
The permit limit is five.
So that means in the ten second we can send maximum five requests to our microservices.
So after that we can configure the HTTP request pipeline.
If you come to this point before calling the map reverse proxy, I'm going to come here and call the
app dot Use rate limiter.
It is important to call use rate limiter functions before calling the map reverse proxy method.
So that means we will use use rate limiter extension method in order to add rate limiter middleware
to the request pipeline before map reverse proxy.
So please add these two lines of code.
The first one is in here and the second one is in here.
So after defining these configurations in the program.cs.
It is time to apply rate limiting to a specific route.
So for that purpose we should go to the application settings JSON file and in this file we can specify
which route should have rate limiting applied.
For example, we can apply it to ordering route.
If you go to the ordering route in here we can define a rate limiting in the ordering route.
I'm going to come here.
And after defining the cluster ID I'm going to define the rate limiter policy as a fixed into ordering
route.
By this way we can apply rate limiting in the ordering route, which is the fixed window.
And the name comes from the program.cs of the.
When we are giving the At fixed window options here you can see the name of the are fixed as a rate
limiter.
For that purpose, I'm giving the fixed namespace into our application settings rate Limiter policy
as a fixed, and this is the defining ordering route rate limiter into our Yarp API gateway.
Actually, you can apply rate limiting to the desired route using the rate limiter policy section in
the reverse proxy configuration.
But this time I'm going to use only ordinary cloth and radiometer policy as a fixed.
So now we will test the rate limiting on the order service route.
But before that I am going to right click the Docker compose and set a startup project and activate
the baking services and downstream microservices on Docker environment.
And just after that we will start the API gateway.
Our microservices is up and running on the environment.
And right click the API gateway set as startup project and run with https mode A3.
Okay, our API gateway also started successfully.
Now I am going to send ordering route as several requests and understand how we can apply the rate limiting
policy for that purpose.
Please open the postman and go to the Yarp API gateway folder and go to the ordering subfolder.
For example, go to the get orders with pagination.
So now we are going to make multiple requests within the specified window.
For example, I am going to send five requests in 10s.
And when we exiting the limit, we should see and get the 503 service on any unavailable response,
and we will wait for the window to reset and try again to verify that the rate limiting is working as
expected.
So I'm going to send HTTP get button.
This is the first time we can get the result.
This is the second time, third time fourth and five time.
If I click again in ten second, you can see that we got 503 service unavailable exception.
And after waiting a certain time I'm going to send again.
And this time the new ten second is started successfully and we can get again the success response by
sending the Get request to ordering microservices.
As you can see that we have testing and verifying the rate limiting behavior on the API gateway using
the reverse proxy and ERPs integration with the.
Net native rate limiting capabilities make it straightforward to implement rate limiting into our microservices.