In this video, we are going to move local test configuration to the local application settings Json
file.
That means we will focus on organizing our configuration settings for the Yarp reverse proxy API gateway,
particularly separating local testing configurations into a dedicated application settings local Json
file.
This separation is crucial for managing different environments such as the local development and Docker
deployment.
So here you can see the R sharp microservices deployment strategy.
We will perform successfully testing deployment one.
And we are going to test deployment two which is the Docker compose all microservices and API gateway
and backing services.
But we will go to second step.
But before that we should arrange our configurations according to environments.
So now let's start the understanding configuration retrieve operation from the R Visual Studio.
If you open the Visual Studio go to ERP, API gateway.
And if you open the Program.cs in Program.cs, you can see the Yarp reverse proxy settings and configuration
in here, and the R service retrieves its configuration from the application settings Json file and
reverse proxy configuration.
So this line of code will be retrieved.
The reverse proxy configuration from the application settings Json file and reverse proxy settings.
But if you look at this configuration, if you scroll down the destination address are including the
localhost as a server.
But when we deploy these Yarp API gateway microservices into Docker environment, these localhost address
cannot be reachable in the network.
In Docker network, we should use correct container names in order to communicate with each other.
So that's why we need to separate configuration files for the local development and Docker environment.
The current configuration in application settings are suitable for local testing, but may not be appropriate
for Docker environment.
In Docker services communicate using container names rather than the localhost.
For that reason, the address specified in the local config won't work in Docker.
In order to solve this problem, we should create a new configuration file which name application settings
dot local dot Json in the ARP API gateway project, and this file will contain configurations specific
to local testing.
For that purpose comes to irb API gateway project.
Right click Add New Item and give the name of the new item as a application settings dot local dot Json
and click the add button.
Here you can see that this file comes and located under the Application Settings Json file.
Because it is derived from the our application Json file and specified the environment name as a local
Json.
So now I'm going to copy configurations from the application Json, and we will copy all existing configuration
settings from the application settings Json file.
I'm going to copy and go back to Application settings Json, local Json and paste in here.
By this way we can put all localhost related destination address under the application settings local
Json file.
By separating the local testing configuration into application settings local Json file.
We can maintain different settings for different environments without changing the core application
logic.
In the next video, we are going to develop actual configurations for Docker network environment and
ensuring that our API gateway correctly routes requests in the containerized setup, which will be changing
the Solo Cloud server name as a container.
Names in the environment.