In this video we are going to develop IRB application settings Json file configurations for Docker host
network.
So that means we will arrange our irb API gateway configurations according to the code.
Compose all setup for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and we will set our configurations into Docker Network and Docker Network.
Start our API gateway in the program says that will check the application settings reverse proxy section.
So now we will change this destination address according to our Docker network.
And in Docker compose environment, each container runs within its own network and can be accessed using
the container names rather than the localhost, and we should adjust the IRB configurations to use Docker
container names as the host for the downstream services.
So how can we identify these container names?
Of course we can check the docker compose Yaml files.
If you open docker compose and go to docker compose Yaml file, we can identify the container names
for our microservices.
If you scroll down, you can see the container names as a basket API, catalog API and the ordering
API, which are the container names for the Docker name of the microservices.
These container names will be used as a host name in the IRB configuration.
So let's configure for example in the catalog microservice configuration.
In the application settings Json file, please open the irb API gateway and go to Application Settings
Json file and go to the destination of the catalog cluster.
In address, we will change the http localhost to our catalog API container name, which is the catalog
dot API.
And as a port number I need to put 8080.
So why I have put two eight, 80 in the catalog microservices.
If you look at the slide here, you can see the port numbers that we have defined during the course.
So these are the Docker inside port numbers for Http and https.
When we are using the container name in Docker network, we need to set http or https port number.
Since I have selected the http, we need to 880 port number for the http port number inside of the docker.
After defining the our catalog API container name, we have give the 880 port number for accessing the
Http address as a destination of the catalog cluster, and we can follow the same configurations for
the basket and ordering microservices.
And for the basket cluster, we can set the destination as a Http and the basket container name, which
is the basket API, and the column is 880.
After defining the basket destination, we can define our ordering API container name and the destination
address.
If you come to this point, ordering cluster address will be.
Start with the Http and the container name will be ordering API, and the column name will be 8080.
So we can remove in the last backslash into our destination address and save this configuration.
So this is the latest configuration arranging by the Docker desktop and Docker compose environment.
And these configurations ensures that Earp forward the requests to the right container within the Docker
network.
If you consider that why we are not using the https ports, and instead of we will use http port if
the https is required for the internal communication, additional configuration is required to accept
any server certificate.
That means we need to SSL certificate configuration required to use Https when communicating inside
of the Docker.
However, in many internal microservice architectures, Http is sufficient and secure within the isolated
Docker network because the API gateway can handle the Https and authentication at the edge before forwarding
the requests internally.
So within these configurations.
Now we are ready to deploy and tested our API gateway in Docker environment.