In this video, we are going to containerize an orchestrate irb API gateway microservices for reverse
proxy as an API gateway into Docker Compose.
So we will focus on Containerizing and orchestrating these API gateway microservices into Docker Compose.
Here you can see our e-commerce microservice deployment strategy.
We are at this point and performing the deployment tool.
That means in Docker compose environment, each container operates within its own network and identified
by the container names instead of the localhost.
And our goal is to configure irb API gateway to communicate with other microservices using these container
names.
So now let me start with Containerizing irb API gateway microservices.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the irb API gateway project.
You can right click and click the add button.
And you can click the Docker support.
So you can click the target operating system as a Linux and click the okay button.
And here you can see the our Docker file which is basically building the Docker image for the irb API
gateway.
That means Docker file includes the steps for creating a Docker image for the irb API gateway.
It will start with using the dotnet base image for building and running the application, and after
that it is.
Continue with the copying the project files and restoring the dependencies, and after that it is building
and publishing the application.
And lastly, it is setting the entry point in order to run the IRB API gateway.
After creating Docker file and containerizing our irb API gateway, we can go to next step, which is
the orchestrate irb API gateway microservices.
So when we are talking about orchestration, we should talk about the docker compose Yaml files.
Docker compose and docker compose overwrite HTML files in order to include irb api gateway into docker
compose Yaml files, we should add the container orchestration support.
For that purpose, I am going to right click the irb API gateway project add container orchestrator
support.
After that you can select the or container orchestrator as a docker compose and click the okay button
and select the target operating system as a Linux and click the okay button.
So this will be create two items in Docker Compose and docker compose or write Yaml file.
If you open the docker compose file and go to.
At the end of this file, you can see that irb api gateway added successfully.
So that means this process.
Adding the entries for the irb API gateway in both docker compose and docker compose overwriting file.
So you can go to the compose file.
And if you scroll down and go to at the end of this file, you can see that we have also irb API gateway
configurations listing in the docker compose of HTML file.
But we need to configure additional configuration and adjustments in the irb API gateway, because we
should change these configurations and need to exposing the port numbers, adding the environment variables,
and so on.
So now let's configure it for our microservice endpoints.
If you look at the port numbers for the ARP API gateway, we can say that we will expose the ARP API
gateway in the 5004 and 5054, in the local environment, but this time we will exposing Docker environment.
For that purpose, we will expose the port numbers 6004 for Http and 6064 for Https.
So now we will go back to our docker compose, overwrite HTML file and arrange the port numbers and
adding the depends on section into our configurations.
In here you can see that I have added the Dependson and the port numbers according to Http, which is
the 6004 Https for the 6064.
So please make these configurations in your computer and let me explain these configuration and adjustments.
Basically we have only adjustments for the port and dependencies.
But let me explain from the scratch.
Here you can see the irb api gateway overridable configurations in the docker compose overwrite yaml
file, and we set the environment variables for ASP.Net core.
I don't have any additional environment variables from the irb API gateway, and just after that we
have basically defined the port numbers and port mapping in order to expose these irb API gateway externally.
And after that you can see that we have a volume definitions.
And we can use volume to map the user secrets and Https settings for development purposes.
And also we have depends on section.
We can specify the dependencies in order to ensure irb API gateway starts after other microservices,
which is the downstream microservices including catalog basket and ordering API started.
As you can see that we have containerized and orchestrate irb API gateway into our application.
And by this way irb API gateway route to request to the downstream microservices within the Docker network.