In this video we are going to test the ARP API gateway microservices in a Docker compose environment.
So that means we will test the ARP API gateway in a full Docker environment.
And we will perform the deployment tool, which is the Docker compose, all microservices API gateway
and the backing services.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio.
And before we start, make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running.
In here you can see that we have configured our Docker Compose Yaml files.
And here you can see the application settings Json file for the reverse proxy settings in order to route
incoming requests to the downstream microservices.
And we have used Http ports and the container names for the downstream microservices, including Catholic
API, basket API, and ordering API.
We can also use these APIs when we are depends on to the ARP API gateway when we are starting the Docker
compose environment.
So for that purpose I am going to right click the docker compose and set a startup project.
And this time I'm going to use running Docker compose without debugging because we will test reverse
proxy on the postman.
I'm going to click this button and start without debugging to hold docker compose environment.
And we will expect to running the all microservices in the docker compose, and make sure that all microservices
are running on Docker compose.
And we can check the Catholic API on the 6000 port basket API in 6001, and ordering API will be exposed
6003.
And lastly Erb API gateway will be exposed 6004.
So here you can see the our Docker compose and Docker desktop.
And in Docker desktop we can see that our microservices come in here.
And now we will also expect Erb API gateway and Erb API gateway also created and running successfully
under our Docker compose.
You can check the Erb API gateway logs by clicking this container.
And here you can see that this will be configured with the adding configurations from the application
settings Json file and ready to academic the incoming request.
And here you can see that we have exposed the Erb API gateway in the 6004 and 6064 for Https, and I
am going to use this https url.
When we are sending requests to our erb API gateway that will redirect to us downstream microservices
in a Http port numbers.
So now we can start to test our API gateway.
Please open the postman and I am going to open the our Icap Microservices Postman collection and go
to Erb API gateway and open the catalog API and open the first gate endpoint which is the Getproduct.
Here you can see the our URL and catalog service, which is the our incoming request to identify the
incoming requests to downstream microservices.
And the rest of the endpoint is belong to our catalog microservices and trained in order to get the
products with pagination.
But this is the important.
If you check the URL, you can see the ARP URL is arranging according to localhost environment 5054
port in Https format.
So I'm going to change the environment here.
You can see that we can change the environment localhost to docker to get the URL in a 6064 port number
in a Https endpoint.
So this is important to change environment.
And this is important to adding the environment variable in a Docker network as a URL.
Here you can see that we have adding variable for URL.
And we are using the localhost https 6064 port number.
In order to send http request to our erb API gateway microservices in docker compose network.
So now I am going to hit the send button in order to retrieve products from the catalog.
Microservices.
As you can see that we have successfully get the products from the catalog microservices over the Erb
API gateway.
If I continue to send other Http get methods, you can see that we can get the specific product into
the URL catalog microservices over the http api gateway even we can create a new product onto the catalog
microservices over the Erb API gateway.
Using these endpoints with adding the slash catalog, slash service and slash products.
So catalog microservices successfully redirecting to internal downstream microservices over the Erb
API gateway.
Now I am going to perform end to end test which is the basket checkout use case.
For that purpose, we will open the basket subfolder under the http api gateway.
And I'm going to create a new basket with username as a civilian.
And this is the URL.
Here you can see the endpoint which is including the slash basket dash service and slash basket.
And hit the send button to sending http post request to our API gateway.
This will be create a new basket into our microservices.
This is created successfully here you can see the response.
Now just after that I'm going to check out this basket from the basket microservices with Kubernetes
payload.
And I'm going to send http post request to this endpoint URL which is the basket service basket check.
God.
And with this payload, sending 83 postdocs and starting our asynchronous, event driven communication
that will publish basket checkout event to the RabbitMQ that is consuming from the organic microservices
that we can confirm from the RabbitMQ management dashboard.
If you go to our management dashboard, you can see that basket checkout queue is created successfully
and consumed by the ordering microservices.
You can also check queues and streams and see that basket checkout event handler triggering from the
RabbitMQ and consuming from the ordering microservices.
And if you look at the ordering microservice and means if you open the ordering subfolder, we can get
orders with pagination.
And here you can see that I'm going to get the orders with pagination.
This is first two orders.
That is seeding one application startup.
I'm going to change the page index from 0 to 1 in order to retrieve the second page of the orders.
That is newly created order for the asynchronous communication and consuming from the RabbitMQ events
into our ordering.
Microservices and all these operations are retrieving from the Erb API gateway and over the Erb API
gateway.
So as you can see that we have successfully performed and dined use case over the Erb API gateway in
fully docker compose environment.
At this point I would like to test rate limiting into our ordering microservices.
As you remember that we have adding the rate limiting into our configurations into our ordering route.
Here you can see that we have rate limiter policy as a fixed.
So for that purpose please open the postman.
And I am going to several requests to the same endpoint with Http, get requests to the ordering microservices
and see what's happened.
This is the first request second, third, fourth and fifth request.
If I send again this time you can see that we will get 503 service unavailable exception which is returning
from the rate limiting.
And we have sending maximum five requests in 10s.
If I refresh again and wait several times, this 10s start again and we can get successful response
from the ordering microservices.
So we have also successful test rate limiting.
And we have also successful testing and trend process over the ARP API gateway in fully docker compose
environment.