In this video we are going to learn what are microservices?
Microservices are small, independent and loosely coupled services.
So microservices are small business services that can work together and can be deployed independently
and autonomously.
Each service has a separate code base, which can be managed by a small development team.
A single small team of developers can write and maintain a particular microservices.
Microservices communicates with each other over the network.
Protocols.
Services communicate with each other by using well defined APIs.
Internal implementation details of each service are hidden from the other services.
One of the biggest advantages is that they can be deployed independently.
Microservices can be deployed independently.
A team can update an existing microservice without rebuilding and redeploying the entire application.
Microservices do not need to share the same technology stack libraries or frameworks.
Microservice can work with many different technology stacks, which is technology agnostic.
Microservices has its own database or persistence layer that is not shared with other services.
This is different from the traditional model where a separate data layer handles data persistence.