In this video, we are going to learn the challenges and disadvantages of microservice architectures.
Microservices has significant benefits, but also has significant challenges.
Moving from monolithic to microservices means a lot of more management complexity.
Here you can see the some of the challenges we need to consider before applying the microservice architecture.
The first challenge is complexity.
Microservices application has lots of services need to work together and should create a volume.
Since there are lots of services, that means there is more moving parts than the monolithic application.
Each service is simpler, but the entire system is more complex.
Even deployments can be complicated for hundreds of services.
Deployed different times.
Hard to manage versions.
Think about the communication.
It is really easy to communicate components in monolithic application because it is inter-process communication.
It can be same machine and same process.
But in microservices, microservice communication is hard topic and need to have a strategy to manage
interservice communications between server, even different geo locations.
And the second challenges is network problems and latency.
Since microservices are small and communicate with inter service communication, we should manage network
problems.
If we call chain of services for particular request, this will increase latency problems and need the
correct design to APIs for proper communication.
In order to avoid chatty API calls, you need to consider asynchronous communication patterns like message
broker systems using publish subscribe patterns.
Another challenges is development and testing.
Think about the end to end process, one of the long business requirement.
If the requirement touch on several microservice that need to act as a one application, it is hard
to develop and testing these end to end processes in microservice architectures.
If you compare to monolithic ones, existing tools are not always designed to work with service dependencies.
Refactoring across service boundaries can be difficult.
So that means integration testing as well as the end to end testing can become more difficult and more
important than ever in microservices.
Another challenges is data integrity.
Microservices has its own data persistence, so data consistency can be a challenge.
Mostly we should follow eventual consistency where it is possible, but transactional operations are
always will be challenging.