In this video, we are going to learn one of two fundamental design patterns of microservice architecture,
which is the database per service pattern.
One of the core characteristic of the microservice architecture is the loosely coupling services.
For that reason, every service should have its own database.
It can be a polyglot persistence among the microservices.
Let's think about our e-commerce application.
We will have product shopping cart and ordering microservices that each services data in their own database.
And any changes to one database don't impact the other.
Microservices.
The services database can't be accessed directly by other microservices.
Each services persistent data can only be accessed via Rest APIs.
So database per service.
Microservice provides many benefits, especially for evolve rapidly and support massive scale systems.
Let's talk about the benefits of database per service pattern.
The first benefit is data schema changes made easy without impacting other microservices, and each
database can scale independently.
Microservices domain data is encapsulated within the microservices itself.
If one of the database server is down, this will not affect the other services.
Also, polyglot data persistence gives ability to select the best optimized storage needs as per the
microservices.
So if you see the image on the slide, that is the example of microservice architecture of e-commerce
application.
We will have product shopping cart and ordering microservices that each services data in their own database.
The first microservice is product microservices, the product microservice using NoSQL document database
for storing catalog related data, which is storing Json objects to accommodate high volume of read
operations.
And the second microservice is shopping cart.
The shopping cart microservice using a distributed cache that supports it is simple key value data store.
And the last microservice is ordering microservices.
The ordering microservice using a relational database to accommodate to reach relational structure of
its underlying data.