In this video we are going to learn our project domain.
Our project domain will be the e-commerce application.
So we will understand e-commerce domain with all use cases and focus on the functional requirements.
This project will be the e-commerce web application.
So we should define our basic use case analysis.
It is really important to understand what you will develop, and it is crucial that defining your use
cases.
There are several ways to analyze the e-commerce domain.
We can follow several steps like requirement and modeling, analysis, identifying user stories, identify
nouns in the user stories, and identify verbs in the user stories.
Now let's elaborate the functional requirement of our e-commerce application.
Functional requirements are listing products, filter products as per brand and categories, put products
into shopping cart, apply coupon for discounts and see total cost items in the shopping cart.
Check out the shopping cart and create an order list.
Old orders and order item history.
Now let's identify use cases of our e-commerce application.
Another way to define these function requirement is converting them to the use case items.
We can see the user stories.
As a user, I want to list product as a user.
I want to filter products as per brand and categories.
As a user, I want to put products into shopping cart that we can check out later.
As a user, I want to apply coupon for discount and check the total cost.
And as a user, I want to check out the shopping cart and create an ordering process.
As a user, I want to list my old orders and order item history and so on.
So I have expanded the user stories of our application that you can see on the slide.
So basically this is the user story list only.
I have highlighted the verbs and nouns.
So you can see that we have marked as a red color, which is the verbs and marked as a black for the
nouns.
So for example, as a user I want to list products, filter products, see products, put products,
purchase shopping cart.
By this way you can see very clearly what we have interactions and what we have domains.
These black boxes are domains and these red boxes are the interactions between domains.
Listing products, filter products, see products, put products, purchase shopping cart, see items
in the shopping cart, see items, shopping cart.
And also we can be calculate and specify the address and delivery address.
Specify credit card.
Checkout the basket shopping cart and arrange the stock.
Receive order confirmation, email and order number, list order and order, item history, login system
and so on.
Now I am going to extract the nouns and verbs from the user stories.
Now I am looking for the nouns that will become the main objects and not attributes.
So here you can see that we have extracted the nouns from the user stories and our nouns.
That means domains are customer order, order details, product, shopping cart, shopping cart, item,
supplier, user address, brand and category.
These nouns will help us to find subdomains and bonded contexts, and we have also.
Verbs also can be extracted from the verb for understanding the communication between domains.
Our verbs are in here listing products, applying paging filter products by brand, category and supplier.
See product all information.
Put products into shopping cart.
See total cost.
See total cost for each item.
Checkout order purchase step specify delivery address and pay for the items.
See how many stocks in our application receive order, confirmation list, order and history, and so
on.
By using the nouns and verbs we can put together in a diagram.
For example, you can see in here an example diagram for our e-commerce application.
Once we have object interaction diagram, we can start thinking about object responsibilities.
One of the most common mistake is to push responsibilities on the actor object.
For example customer.
We need to remember that objects must take care of themselves, and objects need to be closed for direct
communication, and that you need to go through the functions to communicate with them.
So let's follow the approach and assign the responsibilities.
For example, we have a customer and customer has a shopping cart.
And now we can add items into shopping cart and get total price and so on.
Same way customer has an order that we can place an order and get order summary that and we can specify
credit card and so on.
Now we have object interactions and responsibility diagrams that we can start thinking about microservice
decomposition.
Here you can see the example offering the microservices.
If you follow the same steps that we applied in the previous video, that means following the nouns
and verbs and creating the domain and bounded context and identifying the sub domains, we can see that
we will have reached out this kind of microservices.
First of all, I grouped them as a main microservices that include the customers or users, product,
shopping cart, discount and orders.
These are the main microservices for our e-commerce application.
And I have also separate for the order fulfillment or transactional microservices that we can define
order, payment, inventory, shipment, billing, notify, and so on.
These can be used for the order fulfillment process when we are applying Saga pattern and distributed
transactions.
This is the order fulfillment asynchronous use case.
And these are the main microservices.
And we have additional microservices like identity marketing and location.
And as the same way we have intelligence microservices for example, rating reviews, search products,
recommendation engine or finance and so on.
So these are the potential microservices that we can apply our design afterwards.
As you can see that we have understand how to identify and decompose microservices for our e-commerce
domain and create our final microservices.