In this video we are going to learn mediator pipeline behavior and fluent validation library.
Mediator is a popular library in dotnet used for implementing the mediator pattern.
One of its powerful feature is pipeline behaviors, which allows us to introduce additional logic into
the request handling process such as validation, logging, exception handling, and performance tracking.
Pipeline behaviors act as a middleware in the mediator library.
They wrap around the request handling process, enabling us to implement cross-cutting concerns without
cluttering the handlers themselves.
A pipeline behavior is essentially a class that implements I pipeline behavior interface with t request
and t response.
It provides the handle method where you can execute the code before and after the next delegate is invoked.
Here you can see that how mediator pipeline behaviors works.
You can see that mediator will be trigger the handle method.
But before that we can invoke the preprocessor behavior.
And after that you can invoke the post-processor behavior.
So you can see an example of that.
The request comes into the first middleware and perform the first logic.
And after that invoke the next method in order to pass the middleware to and middleware two.
Also implement the actual logic and invoke the next middleware with next method, and after that, and
middleware three is the last middleware that performs the actual logic and response back to the middleware
two and one.
That means this will be invoke post-process behaviors and return back to the response.
So here you can see another example which is the tracing behavior.
So in the pipeline behavior this is tracing the logic.
And after that invoking await.
Next method.
And this will be handled actual handler method.
And after that this will goes to post pipeline behavior.
And this will be traced after operation under the post processor behavior.
And here you can see basic code example.
That is a pipeline behavior that locks the execution time of the request.
This is the logging behavior.
And in the handle method this will be basically logging the execution time.
And after that handle the actual handle logic.
So this was the mediator pipeline behaviors.
And now we will focus on the fluent validation library and how mediator pipelines work with the fluent
validation libraries.
What is fluent validation?
Fluent validation is a dotnet library for building strongly typed validation rules.
It is known for its clean syntax and ease of use, making validation logics more readable and maintainable,
so we can integrate fluent validation and with mediator to validate requests before they reach the actual
handler.
This integration happens within a pipeline behavior, especially the pipeline behaviors.
So fluent validation allows you to define validation rules in a separate classes, using a fluent interface
to specify conditions that each property of your models must satisfy.
You can see the image on the slide.
This is an example of validation class for a request model specifying various validation rules.
So combining mediator with fluent validation.
Centralized or cross-cutting concerns like validation making our code cleaner and more maintainable.
It is also ensures that our business logic only process valid data.
So this will be an example.
This is working Pre-processor that is validating the create product command and checking the members
name, category, image file price.
And these should not be empty and the price should be greater than zero.