In this video, we are going to add cross-cutting concerns into Building Blocks class library in order
to use in all microservices.
Cross-cutting concerns such as validation, logging and exception handling are integral parts of any
application.
To manage these efficiently, we often encapsulate them in a separate class library like building blocks,
which is our main microservices can utilize.
So you can see in here we will use fluent validation to performing validation, cross-cutting concerns.
And we will put the validation into our building Blocks class library to make it common for each microservices.
Here you can see the Building Blocks class library using our common NuGet packages.
In this case, we will use Fluent Validation NuGet package into building blocks and these will be getting
reference from the microservices and microservices.
Apply cross-cutting concerns with using Building Blocks class library into their code without changing
any business logic inside of the microservices.
So Building Blocks class library is our common class library for each of microservices development.
For that reason, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Building Blocks project that you can locate
to under the Building Blocks folder.
And under this folder we have Building Blocks class library.
So you should go to this location and we will start with validation cross-cutting concerns.
That means we will start with installing Fluent Validation NuGet package.
In order to implement Fluent Validation library, we can right click the Building Blocks C class and
manage NuGet packages.
So you can search for the wavelength variation.
And especially we will install fluent Validation dependency injection extension to make it available
for our ASP.Net web API microservice projects.
So please select this NuGet package, which is a validation that dependency injection extensions, which
including extension methods for dependency injection of ASP.Net Bulletin die.
And I'm going to install this package.
And if you double click these building blocks class library, you can verify that you have installed
successfully.
And this package includes all the necessary ASP.Net dependency injection tools for fluent validation.
And this will affect our catalog microservices under the services.
Because catalog microservices getting reference from the their application, you can open the dependencies
and if you open the project dependencies, you can see that we have already added building block class
library project reference into catalog API.
That means if we installed fluent validation into building blocks, this will be available for the Catholic
API, and we can add fluent validation into the program and use the Fluent Validation library and packages
into our catalog.
Microservices.