In this video we are going to do cross-cutting concerns.
So we will apply validation with using abstract validator class using the Fluent Validation library.
So please open the Visual Studio and let's define validation rules for our commands under the catalog
microservices.
Here you can see the Our products feature folder.
And here you can see that our use cases.
So I'm going to choose Create Product Use Case in order to define validation rules for our create product
command.
So we do this by creating a validator class for each command using different validations.
Abstract validator class.
So please go to the create product handler class.
And in here we are going to put the validation for our create product command that is requiring all
these information name category description and so on.
This will be product model properties.
So we need to validate these properties before passing the command handler.
That is we should check that this should not be null.
So we will create create product command validator.
And this will be doing by creating a new class which name is create product command validator under
the this command and result definition.
And before the handle definition I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is public class create product command validator class.
And I'm going to inherit this class from the abstract validator.
And as you can see that it is coming from the validation library.
This is coming from the building blocks library that we can access from the front validation and after
inherit from the abstract validator it is requiring for the validation object which is the or create
product command.
I am pasting the create product command and now we can specify our actual logic inside of this class.
So basically in this class the first thing we should do that I'm going to create a constructor.
And inside of the constructor we can define the rules with using the rule for method.
So this method define the rules and we will give the expression functions in order to define validations.
So for example I'm going to write a rule for and if you open bracket you can specify the rule definition.
And we are going to put a rule on the name.
And this name should not be empty.
And we can also use with message method.
And we can give the error message.
If name is null, we can say that name is required.
And this is the our name validation that we can use before proceeding the handler method.
And at the same way I am going to add different rules.
In here you can see that I have put the category not empty rule and image file not empty rule with these
messages.
And lastly, we can put the price rule greater than zero and with the message is price must be greater
than zero.
So in the constructor of the validator that inherits from the abstract validator, we can specify the
rules that will be automatically validate from the validation.
So we have completed our command validator class.
If you go on top of the class you can see that there is a using statement.
I'm going to cut this statement and go to the global using and adding these global using statement that
we can access from any class to implement validations.
Yes, the command class is completed.
So how we can proceed these validations.
Of course we need to inject a validator in our command handler class in order to validate incoming command
object.
So for that purpose scroll down and go to the Create Product Command handler class.
And in this class I am going to add a naive injection, which is.
The I validator comes from the fluent validation.
And in here I'm going to passing the create product command as a generic in here okay.
This will be our validator object.
And you can see that now our primary constructor including two objects one for the session to perform
actual logic, one for the validator.
And we will use validator at the beginning of the handle method that will perform the validations with
using the validator dot validate method.
So let me write first and explain.
After that I'm going to get a result from await validator that you can see that we have validate async
method.
And we can pass command object that we are going to validate.
And after that we can pass the cancellation token.
So after validating, we can get the errors from the result.
And if you filter the result by errors and select for the error message.
We can access the errors from the result if there is an error.
So if an error we can throw an exception which is the validation exception.
And this validation exception also comes from the fluent validation.
And we are passing the.
Errors and first default for now.
Okay.
As you can see that we basically put a validation block in here, the handle.
Now check the commands against our validation rules.
And if there is any errors in the validations we can throw a validation exception.
If not it is going to actual business logic.
So you can see that we have created a command validator.
And after that we have inject a validator into our command handler.
And after that we have to register these validators into ASP.Net dependency injection container.
To do so I'm going to open the Program.cs.
And after the mediator I can add a new service in here Builder Services.
And in here add validators from the assembly.
And this method comes from the Fluent Validation dependency injection extension that will facilitate
to inject fluent validation for our ASP.Net applications.
So I'm going to paste the assembly as the same way with the our mediator.
And I'm passing the Program.cs assembly.
So this will be make it available in validator that we can inject into the create product command handler.
And this will be validate these command validator with scanning the project with abstract validators.
So that means when we are registering in the program says this code block basically scans the assembly
for any validators and register them into this ASP.Net project.
So now we have defined the validators, and now it is time to test our validation by sending a request
with missing required fields.
So we will use create product endpoint in order to trigger this handle method.
For that purpose, let's run this application in https mode.
And this time we will send a http post request without giving the name information.
And this will be trigger our command handler.
So please put a breakpoint inside of your validations.
You can put a breakpoint inside of the command validator constructor.
And now if you open the your postman and go to the http post method and we are going to send http post
request in the local environment slash products, and I'm going to make it empty for the name attribute
and hit the http send method.
This will be trigger or create product endpoint and after that mediator will be triggered our handle
operation.
But this time you can see that when we send the mediator this will be before triggering the handle method.
This will be trigger the command validator.
So that means before running the actual logic this will be validate the incoming command object and
in here you can see that the name is empty.
And this will be collected all the messages from these validations.
And once we go to the handle method we are basically run the validator dot validate async method that
will be collect all the messages from these command validators.
And you can see the error messages collecting from in here.
And if any error message.
In our case we have one error message which is the name is required.
We can throw an validation exception that will not be continue or actual business logic, which is the
creating new order.
And you can see that we are throwing full length validation validation exception and name is required.
So we have successfully validate our incoming command object.
And we see that we can throw an exception if the name is required.
But this is not a good way to check every command with the validators manually.
If you go back to our code, you can see that in every command handler method in the handle method,
we can use these code blocks in order to validate these abstract validator.
But this is not efficient and we should not duplicate this code for each handle method.
This is not a good way.
So in the next video we will validate using the validate pipeline behavior in mediator without adding
any if command and any validation block in the handle method.