In this video, we are going to develop validation pipeline behavior with using mediator and validation
library.
So the idea is that directly injecting a validator in the command handler classes is not the most efficient
approach.
It requires manually adding validation logic to each handle method, which can be repetitive and error
prone.
So we should remove these repetitive code into our flow.
For that purpose, we will use mediator pipeline behavior that we can already see in the previous videos.
Mediation pipeline behavior allows us to introduce additional processing steps such as the validation
into the handling of the request.
So combining with the mediator with the full length validation, centralized or cross-cutting concerns
like validations and making our code more cleaner and more maintainable.
So now we will add these fluent validation mediator pipeline into our building blocks, because we will
put the building blocks as a common object.
So if you open the Visual Studio and go to the building blocks, we basically create a new folder which
name is behaviors.
And in here we will add our validation behavior class which will handle the validation of commands.
Using the full length validation, I'm going to right click and create a new folder.
Under the building blocks.
You can add folder and give the folder name behaviors and under the behaviors folder I'm going to start
by adding validation behavior.
In the upcoming videos we can add different behaviors like logging behavior, tracing behavior, and
so on.
So now we will develop our validation behavior.
We should remove the unnecessary using statements.
And after that I'm going to make it public.
And after that I make it generic types in validation behavior which will be the request and returning
the response.
So after that the important thing is we should inherit these validation class from the I pipeline behavior.
So this will make it pipeline behavior from the mediator.
And we can also paste these tracks and t response.
So once we are implementing from the interface members we can see that this will be the handle method.
If you look at the handle method parameters the first parameter is t request and the second parameter
is the next request handle delegate.
So the first parameter is representing the incoming request from the client, and the second parameter
is representing the next request handle delegate which means the next pipeline behavior or actual handle
method.
So this is very good illustration into our slide.
You can see that we are at this point.
So we have creating a middleware.
That means the pipeline behavior which is a preprocessor behavior.
And the request comes in here we have a request parameter.
And we can also paste the next method that will be defined and redirecting to our request in the handle
method.
So this is a very good illustration in here.
So we are going to put our validation logic at this point.
So please open the Visual Studio and continue the implementation.
Before proceeding the handle method I am going to put a var statement.
That means we are going to put a filter for the validation behavior.
I'm going to apply this validation behavior only for the Icommand object.
So you can see that t request could be I request.
Is it normal for the mediator.
But this time I'm going to change this I command.
That means I would like to apply all these validation behavior.
Only request comes from the commands.
That means Crud operations for example create product, update product and delete product.
And with this var keyword, this validation behavior would not be work for the I query request that
means get product and get product by ID and so on.
So now we can handle this method.
And before proceeding this method, the only thing that I need I validator objects to inject these objects
I'm going to use primary constructor in here.
So we basically inject I enumerable and I validator request which are the representing I validators.
So that means when we are implementing the I validator request in the command handler method, this
is only applying for the particular handle method.
In order to collect all handle methods, we are using the IEnumerable and validators that we can validate
all these validators in one place, which is the validator behavior.
So now we can implement these validation using the validators.
So the first thing I am going to do is creating a context object which is the validation context.
Comes from the or fluent validation.
So we are passing the incoming request and reaching the context object.
And after that we can run these all the validators using the validators object and return back the validation
results.
Here you can see that I'm going to run all validators.
And of course we should make it asynchronous function to run available functions.
Okay.
So in this method you can see that we use Task1.
All that means complete all validation operations where this comes from validators that we have injected
from the primary constructor.
And we are going to select these validate asynchronous method.
And we will call these validate method for each handle method.
And this will be accumulates all validation results into the validation result object.
And after that we will check that if there is any failures in any validation result, we can get the
failures object from the validation results and we are filtered by errors and select these errors into
the failure object.
And lastly, if there is any errors, we can throw an validation exception with a given failure message.
And at the last time of the handle method we have to return await and next request delegate handler.
This will be run the next pipeline behavior, which will be the our actual command handle method.
This is very crucial to calling this next method in order to continue this pipeline request lifecycle.
Okay.
As you can see that we have completed the validation behavior in here.
In this class, we basically implement AI pipeline behavior interface, and it checks for the all validation
errors in the incoming request in here.
And if there is any error which including the validation errors in the request, we will throw a validation
exception.
If any errors are found.
So that means the behavior iterates over all provided validators for the request type.
And it also accumulates any validation failures and throws an exception if there is any exception,
and ensuring that the only valid request reached our handle methods.
After developed validation behavior, it is crucial to register these behavior into ASP.Net within dependency
injection for that purpose.
Please go to the catalog API and open the program CSS.
When we are registering the mediator, we can add the pipeline behaviors into this place.
That means when we are adding the mediator related packages into dependency injection, we can also
add the pipeline behaviors in the configuration of the mediator block.
So after registering services from assembly we can use config dot add open behavior.
This will be provide pipeline behaviors into our application.
So I'm going to use this method and passing the type of the validation.
So that means we can use type of method and passing our validation behavior.
From the building blocks.
And in here I'm going to use generic one and complete this add open behavior method.
So save this file.
So in here we basically add our validation behavior as a pipeline behavior into mediator.
We also register all validators from our assembly with this way.
By using this pipeline behavior we achieve the cleaner handler methods focused on the business logic.