In this video, we will demonstrate how to remove manual validators from our command handler class,
and we will utilize the mediator validation pipeline behavior for more efficient validations in our
microservices.
So please go to the Create Product Handler class and locate this command handler class.
As you can see that previously we have injected a validator instance directly into our command handler.
And this approach is not effective.
And it leads to redundant code and deviates to hundreds from their core purpose.
So in order to streamline our code, we will remove the manual validation logic from our create product
command handler method and rely on our newly implemented mediator pipeline behavior.
For that purpose, let's remove these validator from the primary constructor.
And here you can see that we have only one object into the primary constructor, which is the session
for actual business logic.
And if you scroll down you can see that we can remove all these validation code block into our handle
method because this will be performed by the validation behavior anymore.
So now make it clean for handle method.
By the way, we can inject the Ilogger object into our command handler and perform the logging operation
at the beginning of the or handle method.
This will be common for each handle method for Crud operations.
So I have injected logger instead of the our validators and we have removed all validations related
injection and also validation code block into the handle method.
If you look at the handle method now, this handle method is focused and only includes its core functionality,
delegating the validation responsibility to the mediator pipeline behavior.
So now let's test the validation pipeline behavior by sending an invalid command through the http post
request.
For that purpose, I'm going to put a breakpoint in our handle method.
And this time also I am going to add a breakpoint under the behaviors validation behavior under building
blocks and put breakpoint in here.
At this stage, I would like to show you a mistake done by us when developing this validation behavior.
And this could be become a bug when testing our application.
So this is the important part.
And as you remember that we put var keyword in order to apply only validation cross-cutting concerns
in the command related requests.
So our command interface is only accepting t response not t requests.
If you go to I command, you can see that it is accepting t response.
For this reason, please change this t request to the t response in order to apply validation correctly.
And I'm going to change this.
I command t response and save this file.
And after that you can go to the Program.cs.
And in the program.cs you can see that we will register our required mediator and validation related
services into this line of codes in here.
Also, I would like to refactor my code since we are using assembly in two places.
I'm going to create a new variable, which name is assembly and comes from the type of program CSS.
And if you copy this assembly variable and paste this places, this could be more easy to read and understand
our codes.
Also, I would like to move this Carter after this mediator and fluent validation registration okay.
Save this program.
Yes.
And now it is more clear and readable.
Now we can start to test validation pipeline behavior by sending an invalid command through the http
post request.
For that purpose, right click and set a startup project Catholic API and start https mode.
After starting the application, you can open the postman and create an http post request.
And here you can see that we will send invalid name attribute and you can send the http post request
in order to create new product.
And this will be triggered to our create product endpoint.
If you go further in mediator step, mediator will be sent this command to the handle method.
But before that we have applied the validation pipeline behavior.
For that reason, it is directly jump into the command validator class and before proceeding to handle
method it is proceeding to validators.
Here you can see that collecting and calculating all rules for our validations.
And after that you can see that this is going to trigger validation behavior.
And in the validation behavior handle method this is the crosscutting concern.
And this is a common place for each validations.
And it is calculating the validations for each validation rules.
And after that this will be proceed to failures in the rules if any failures in the rules.
In our case we have one failure which is the name is required.
This will be throw validation exception and not proceeding to actual business logic.
As you can see that we didn't trigger the actual handle method.
We only run for the validations and validation failed with the name is required keyword.
By following this approach, we can ensure that our command handler class are more cleaner and more
focused on their intended purpose, while the validation is handled in the uniformly and effectively
by the pipeline behavior.