In this video, we are going to develop other command validators with using full length validation.
So we have already implemented validation for creating products.
Here you can see the create product command validator.
Now we will replicate this approach for update and delete operations in order to ensure our commands
are validated consistently.
So let's review this create product validator as our template.
So this validator enforce the rules like the name is required.
And the price must be greater than zero.
So each rule is a condition that the commands properties must satisfy.
And full validation makes these rules readable and easy to maintain.
So now we can continue to our update product handle and command validator.
Please open the update product and go to the Update Product Handler class.
And in this class, after the result definition and before the command handler class, we can put our
command validators, which is the update product command validator.
And this validator should be inherit from the abstract validator and including our update product command.
That means we will validate incoming update product command in this validator class.
And as you remember that we put our validators into our constructor.
So in here we can define our rules with using the rule for method.
So I'm going to add one by one and explain.
After that the first rule I have added is id.
So in here we ensure that the product ID is provided for the update operation.
And after that we can provide another rule which is the name.
In here we firstly check the name field is not empty and after that we will ensure the length of the
name within the specified range, which is the minimum and maximum length.
After that we can specify the rule about the price information.
So in here we basically specify and validate that the price is greater than zero.
So this is the update product command validator.
And you can save the file.
And after that we will go to the delete product.
And if you open the delete product handler in here we will also put a validator between the result and
command handler class.
So I'm going to create a delete product command validator class in order to validate incoming delete
product command.
For that purpose, please develop public class delete product command and abstract validator which will
be validate delete product command.
And in this class we create a constructor.
And in the constructor we will define the rules in here, since our delete product command has one property
which is the id, we will add one rule in here, which is ensure the product ID is provided for delete
operation.
So with our validators defined mediators pipeline behavior will automatically invoke them.
And this setup ensures that our command handles only process valid data.
So now we can go to the testing Crud operations with postman.
So we will now test our validators using postman and simulating various scenarios, including the invalid
request.
For that purpose, I am going to put a breakpoint for delete product command validator, and also put
a breakpoint under the update product handle class and update product command validator.
So we will perform update and delete operation and see how validation works.
You can set a startup project for Catholic API and run the application in Https mode.
And after that we can open the postman.
So we will locate the http put request.
And this time I'm going to remove the name information.
This is mandatory for our rule definition.
And after that I'm going to send this Http put operation.
And we will see that this will be trigger or update product end point.
And once we send the mediator this will be triggered our command validator using the validation behavior.
And in here the first rule is about product ID but the second room is command name.
And if you proceed these codes will be came to the handle method.
In the handle method this will be run the validate async method and accumulate the validate results
and if any failures.
In our case we have one failure which is the name.
Information is required and you can see that the fluent validation is failed and the name is required.
So we have successfully test our update validate operation.
And if you go to the Http delete operation and in here we should specify the ID information.
But this time we can remove this ID information and send the Http delete and see that this is even not
allowed to invoke our APIs.
As you can see that we have defined our rules in the command validators and when.
Recent invalid requests that will trigger our validators and resulting in error response to the client.