In this video, we are going to learn global exception handling in ASP.Net core with using the App.use
exception handling method.
As you can see that when we are sending invalid requests to our Http put operations without including
the name information, this is the response.
And as seen in the response, this is the raw exception message from our application.
And it can be very hard to read and very hard to maintainable and understandable.
So we should format these errors in a more user friendly way.
In order to make this message more accurate way, we will use ASP.Net global Exception Handling mechanism
in ASP.Net core.
Handling exceptions globally is crucial for a consistent error response format.
It helps to debugging and provides clear feedback to the consumer of our API.
So we should refer to Microsoft official documentation so you can go to the Microsoft ASP.Net core documentation
and handle errors.
In here you can see that we can handle the errors in ASP.Net core in different ways.
So we can you can see that we can handle with developing exception page and using the exception handle
page.
And we can use exception handle Lambda.
And we can use AI exception handler to perform global exception handling.
So we will follow these steps.
And I am going to explain to how we can handle the exception in a handle lambda function.
If you go to the exception handler lambda part of this article, you can see that this is an alternative
way to custom exception handle page and provide a lambda function to handle the exceptions globally.
So we can use the use exception handle method.
And we can provide the lambda function.
And this lambda allows to access error before returning the response.
So you can see an example implementation that we will follow the same steps.
So we will implement a custom exception handler in our Program.cs with the similar approach.
In order to catch the exceptions and return a standardized error message.
So please go to the Visual Studio and open the program.cs of the Catholic API.
Microservices.
In Program.cs, you can scroll down and locate the or configure Http request pipeline part, and after
the map cutter operation, we can configure our application according to our global exception handling.
So we will use the same step which is the app dot use exception handler function.
So in this function we can configure our exceptions in globally.
So we can use this function and configure this function.
You can see the method parameters in here we will use an action configuration.
And as you can see that we can use action configuration to configure these middleware as exception handling.
So now let me copy paste.
And after that I will explain one by one.
Here you can see the whole use exception handler method.
So basically we configure the application to use a custom exception handler that captures all unhandled
exceptions.
Our main goal is to return a structured Json response containing the error details, which is more readable
and informative.
So you can see that in the exception handler application we basically run this code and inside of this
code, first of all we will get the exception.
So once the we get the exception we can prepare the problem details.
The problem details object is used to format the error response.
It includes the exception message and the stacktrace.
And after that, besides returning the error response, it is important to log the exception for further
analysis and debugging.
That's why we will put a logging operations the exception.
So after that we will write all details into our response object as a Json format.
So this is the our use exception handle method in order to handle the ASP.Net exceptions globally.
So now we can test our application save this file.
Last time you can see that we have Get response as a raw message.
Now I am going to run this again without debugging and see that how these exception will be handled
with this method.
So application is started.
If I send again this http put request, you can see that we get the response as a Json format and it
is also structured.
You can come to Raw and go back to purity.
You can see that this is the title, information, status and details which including the Stacktrace.
This is more structural and more easy to read as a formatted Json error response.