In this video, we are going to explore how to centralize exception handling in microservices using
building blocks.
Approach building blocks is a concept used to encapsulate all common functionalities across microservices,
such as exception handling.
It helps in maintaining a consistent approach and reducing the code duplication.
So we will start by creating generic exception classes within our building Blocks project, and this
class will be represented our common types of the exceptions like not found exception, internal server
error and bad request exceptions.
So please open the Visual Studio and locate the building blocks.
So we will develop our common exceptions in here.
And we will create generic exception classes that we use inside of the each microservices.
For that purpose I'm going to right click and create exception folder under the building blocks add
new folder which name is exceptions.
Under the exceptions folder I have created three common exception classes.
The first one is not found exception, and in the not found exception, I'm going to make it public
and inherit from the system exception class.
And in here we will define two different constructors in order to handle not found exception.
The first one is passing the exception message and the second one we can name, and getting the key
information as a parameter that we can write the custom exception message, which is the entity name,
and the key was not found.
This is the customized exception.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
And here you can see the not found generic exception.
And after that I'm going to create another exception which is the invalid server exception.
So we will follow the same steps.
Make it public, inherit from the exceptions and inside of the exception class we can this time get
some details.
Here you can see that I am putting a details property that we can define.
And this is the typical message based implementation.
And in here we can passing the details about the internal server error details.
So we can remove the unnecessary using statement.
And after that we can create our last exception which is the bad request exception, and making the
same things as similar and remove unnecessary using statement.
And in here we will follow the same codes with the internal server error.
I'm putting the details, information and able to paste details information in a constructor of the
bad request exception.
So each of these classes extended from the system exception and adds specific context informations.
Next we will apply these generic exceptions in our microservices.
For example, we have defined the not found exception and in our catalog microservices we use Notfoundexception
to handle the product not found cases.
If you go to the catalog API microservice and see that there is an exception folder, and if you open
the product not found exception.
This is using in two places.
So we will also inherit from the standard exception.
But we can inherit from the not found exception because this time we have more generic exception that
we can use in here, not found exception.
And when we are inherited from the not found expression, we can also convert this as a with information
we can paste the with ID information.
And I'm going to convert this base constructor which will be using the our second constructor I'm going
to passing the are object name which is the product.
And after that passing the key information which is the ID.
In this class we basically extends from the not found exception comes from the building blocks exceptions
which including our generic exceptions and providing a more specific context for product related errors.
For that purpose, we will refactor our existing usage of the product Notfoundexception, so we will
refactor our handles to use these new exception constructor.
If you open the these two references, you can see that we have two references get product by id handler
and also update product handler.
So let me go to the first one and see that we are throwing product not found exception when we can't
find a product.
So in this case we will passing the ID information that we can't find this ID.
So copy this query.id and paste in here.
And after that if you go to the product not found exception and go to the second reference which is
including the update product.
Another class and this is also retrieving the product information.
If product is null, we will throw product not found exception.
So we will paste the ID information in the constructor of the product, not found exception and we will
make it correct for now.
So after implementing these changes, we will with the solution to ensure everything integrates seamlessly.
Right click and build the solution and see that there is no any exception and get the success response
in the build operation.
So this approach basically simplifies the exception management across microservices.
We put all common exceptions under the building blocks, and we will specify some customized exception
for each microservices and inherit from the actual and generic exceptions from the building blocks.