In this video we are going to do global exception handling with I exception handler interface in ASP.Net
core.
As you remember that when we are examining this article, which is the handle errors in ASP.Net core,
we saw exception handle with Lambda functions in the program case.
But one of the best practice is to handle the global exceptions using the I exception handler interface.
So I exception handler interface is provided by ASP.Net core and allows developers to handle exceptions
globally.
It offers a callback method for managing known exceptions, and it can be registered as a service.
So I exception handler instance are singleton and can be registered using the add exception handler
method.
This is one of the powerful feature that we can register using these add exception handler extension
method from the service collection and multiple implementations also can be added and are executed in
order of registrations.
So if the exception isn't handled by any registered under the control, falls back to default behavior
configured in the middleware.
So if you scroll down, you can see that how we can setting up the custom exception handler using the
I exception handler interface.
And we will also create this kind of custom exception handler.
And we will give the name as a custom exception handler.
And we will put this class into our bullying class in order to make it available for each microservices.
So we will develop global exception handler into the building blocks.
We will create custom exception handler that can be used for each microservices for handling exceptions
globally.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the building blocks.
And under the exceptions I am going to create a subfolder.
Which name is handler, add new folder, which name is handler.
And in the handler class I am going to create a new class.
Which name is custom exception handler.
So you can come here and see that we have created a new folder under exceptions which name is handler
and create new class which is the custom exception handler.
This class will implement AI exception handler interface and define our custom logic for handling exceptions.
So you can see that we have implemented this interface.
But if you try to using and adding these exception handler into our class, we cannot find the AI exception
handler.
So where is this class and interface defined in ASP.Net core.
If you open the documentation and click the I exception handler, you can see that AI exception handler
is located under the Microsoft ASP.Net core diagnostics.
Namespaces.
In order to use ASP.Net core specific interfaces like I exception handler.
In this case we need to reference ASP.Net core packages.
So if you open the Visual Studio, you can see that we cannot find I exception handler in the building
blocks because the building blocks is not ASP.Net web API project.
So this class comes from the ASP.Net core libraries.
Since we are in the class library, we cannot access this interface, but we should use ASP.Net core
APIs in a class library in order to avoid duplication of these cross-cutting concerns like exception
handling, validation, and so on.
So how we can solve this problem?
There is a very good solution that we can use.
We can install fluent validation packages that include ASP.Net libraries.
We will also use fluent validation for all microservices.
So for that purpose, it is a good way to reaching ASP.Net libraries over the full length validation
NuGet package.
So please come to Building Blocks and right click and manage NuGet packages.
And I am going to install Fluent Validation packages in here to access ASP.Net libraries.
Here you can see that fluent package has three packages.
We have already installed the dependency Injection extension.
Now I am going to install Fluent Validation and Fluent Validation dot ASP.Net core.
So please install the first one.
And after that please install the third one, which is related with the ASP.Net core.
And after that, you can double click the building blocks and verify that you have installed these three
Funand validation library.
These packages will allow us to access ASP.Net core specific APIs in our class library.
Now please save this file and go to the Custom Exception handler class.
And this time if you try to implement this interface, you can see that we will add the using statement
which is the ASP.Net core diagnostics namespace.
Please remove unnecessary using and we are ready to implement AI exception handler.
So now we can implement the interface members into our custom exception logic, which is the try handle
async method.
In this method, our custom handler class will lock the exceptions and determine the response based
on the exception type and the format response as a problem details object.
Let's start the implementation.
Our method is try handle async and it has different parameters including Httpcontext, exception and
cancellation token.
So we will use these parameters when implementing exceptions globally.
I'm going to change the Httpcontext to context to make it simple for parameter name, and after that
make this function as a async to implement available functions inside of these functions.
So now the first step is we are going to log the incoming error from the exception object.
Here you can see that I'm going to use logger.
So that means I have to inject a logger interface into my class.
For that purpose I'm going to add a primary constructor and passing the logger object in here.
So we have injected a logger object.
And make sure that your class should be public not internal.
And I'm going to change the access modifier as a public.
So now we will continue to implementation our try handle async method.
After logging the incoming exception with message, I'm going to use C sharp pattern matching to identify
exception type.
And after that I will populate the details of the these exception values.
So let me copy paste.
And after that I'm going to explain the code.
So here you can see that we are going to use pattern matching which is a C sharp feature.
And we will identify incoming exception type.
And according to this type we will perform some actions.
That means I'm going to create an anonymous object that we will populate these details title and status
code values for each switch statement.
So first of all let me implement this validation exception from the fluent validation.
And after that we can see that in every exception type we will specify these parameters including the
details.
As an exception message and title will be exception type and status code will be identified according
to incoming exception type.
If the exception is internal server error, we set the status code as a 500 and if the exception is
bad request.
For example, we status code 400 bad request.
So if you scroll down, you can see that there is a discard character.
That means if the exception is not including these types, the rest of the exception types will be available.
With these codes, we will give a detail and title and suffix could be 500 internal server error.
So after defining these values as a details, we can specify our problem details to identify the whole
exception as a problem detail.
You can see that I have created problem detail and give the title detail status from the detail object
that we have created in the previous code and instance comes from the context object, which comes from
the Http context object.
And after identifying and creating problem details, we can add more custom problem details.
As an extension.
You can see that I'm going to add a extensions dot add method and adding some additional detail into
problem details class with adding Tetris DX.
And also if the exception is validation exception, we can also add validation errors that will populate
from the validation exception that errors property.
So after defining all these details, we can use the context response object in order to write these
details as a Json format.
So here you can see that we perform await context response.
Write as Json async method.
In order to write this response as a problem.
Details and Json format in a more readable and manageable way to the client application and return the
true.
So this is the implementation of custom exception handler, and in this code we handle different type
of the exceptions such as the validation exceptions, bad requests and others, and setting up the appropriate
Http status code and response to problem details to the client application as a Json format.