In this video, we are going to register Custom Exception handling class into the ASP.Net with using
add exception handler method and remove the old codes.
So here you can see that we have developed custom exception handler.
In order to register this class we should go to the Catholic API Program.cs.
But in here, as you can see that we previously used inline code in Program.cs for handling the exceptions.
So while this works, it is not the most useful approach, especially for larger microservice applications.
For that purpose, I am going to remove this part so you can select the all code block and remove these
use exception handler.
So now we will inject actual custom exception handler class which is a more modular approach using a
custom exception handler.
So for that purpose you can go on top of these programs JS and remove these using statements.
And in here we can also move these as a global handling.
Please go to the global using and make this as a global using block.
Now we are ready to register our custom exception handler.
In order to utilize our custom exception handler, we need to register it in our application services
and configure it in the request pipelines.
So we should add two places.
The first one is in the container side.
So let me go to the container side.
And at the end of this line of code before building the application we can add a exception handler with
using builder services and add exception handler extension method.
And we can configure with the custom exception which name is custom exception handler class, which
comes from the our building blocks, which is the using building blocks custom exception handler.
So in here we basically add required services into ASP.Net routine dependency injection.
And here you can see the using statement.
I'm going to also move these using statement to the global using and make this clear our program case.
And if you go back to Program.cs we have completed the registration side.
But this time we need also add a required pipeline in order to configure our Http pipeline for that
purpose.
After the mapping Carter you can use app dot, use exception handler method and you can pass empty option
value.
So as you can see that in this line of code, we basically add our custom exception handler as a service
into built in dependency injection.
And after that, in this line of code we configure the application to use our custom exception handler.
So the empty option parameter indicates that we are relying on custom configured handler.
Now we can test our new setup by triggering different type of exceptions.
But before that I'm going to go to the custom exception handler and put a breakpoint in the try handle
async method and run this application in an https mode.
So this will be running our catalog microservices.
And after that.
We will open the postman.
And in here again I am going to send an http put request and will expected to this kind of structured
response.
Please send http put request without giving the name information and click the send.
Here you can see that this is triggering our update product endpoint.
And once we are validating this request, we don't send a name information.
And after these rule definitions you can see that our global exceptions will be triggering.
So if I hit the F5 this will be go to the validation exception.
When we throw the validation exception it is go to the these custom exception handler class.
So in here you can see that we are trying handle async method and start with logging the error in the
exception message.
So after that we are switching the incoming exception type.
And accordingly these exception we are defining the detail title and status code.
And here you can see that this is the validation exception.
And after that with these detail information we have prepared our problem details.
And in the problem details we add some extensions which is the trace ID.
And also since this is the validation exception we will add validation errors from the these exception
class in the errors message.
So after that we can return as a Json message as expected.
And this is more readable and manageable from our response to the client.
Here you can see the title as a validation exception.
And following that you can see the status 400 and details comes from the validation failed name is required
which is the inline exception message.
And here you can see the instance and trace ID.
And lastly we solve the validation errors which we can add the extension for the problem details.
In the validation errors, you can see the whole information about the validation rule into the full
length validation.