In this video, we are going to learn how to centralize logging within your application using the mediators
pipeline.
Behavior.
Consistent logging is crucial in microservices for debugging and monitoring, and usually logging is
done within each handler method and it is leading to repeated code and duplicated code.
So we will see how to optimize this using the mediators pipeline behavior.
But before that, let me show you the our handler classes.
If you open the Visual Studio and go to the create product handler method, you can see that in this
class we have injected a logger.
And after that we will put a log in the beginning of the handle method.
So this is the log information.
And this is typically log the incoming handle method and passing the command object.
And if you look at the other command object for example delete product handle.
And this is exactly the same what we are going to do.
Inject the logger and logging the incoming handle method.
And if we look at the update product handle method, this is exactly same.
We have injected logger and logging the information at the beginning of the handle method.
So this is not efficient and leading to repetitive code.
So how to avoid these log information for each handle method.
So the solution is mediator pipeline behavior.
As you can see the image mediator pipeline behavior allows us to inject logic into the handling of the
request and making them ideal for cross-cutting concerns like logging.
So we can put our cross-cutting concerns in the preprocessor or post-processor before handle the request
with using the mediator pipeline behavior.
For this video, our approach is creating logging behavior class, and this class will log every request
and its response.
And it will be applied to all mediator requests.
So for that purpose we are going to create logging behavior.
And please open the Visual Studio and go to the building blocks.
Under the building blocks we have behaviors folder that we are going to add new behavior which is the
logging behavior C-sharp class.
So in this class we basically perform logging operations.
So as you can see that I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
And the important thing that we should inherit this class from the eye pipeline behavior.
So this behavior comes from the mediator.
And this will be including T rex and t response generics.
For that purpose we will also make us logging behavior as a generics.
And after that I'm going to implement these AI pipeline behavior.
And this will be create handle method.
So before that we should configure our logging behavior.
First of all make it public.
And after that I'm going to inject logger information.
So here you can see that we have injected logger.
And after that we have inherit from implement from the AI pipeline behavior.
And I'm going to put some of the filters about the T rex and t response here.
You can see that T rex should not be null and also inherited from I rex t response object and t response
should not be null.
So please make sure that the signature of the class should be same.
And after that we can develop handle method.
In the handle method, you can see that this is accepting the t request as a request parameter.
And here you can see the next parameter which is the request handle delegate in order to call the next
pipeline or actual handle operation.
So now I'm going to make this class as a async.
And in the first line of the code we should always logging the incoming requests for that purpose.
I'm going to put logging information, and we are putting a start prefix and give some detail about
the request and response with the incoming object.
You can see the request data also including.
So we will paste these information.
This is the name of the T request and this is the name of the response.
And I'm going to paste the whole request object.
After logging the incoming request we can calculate the duration of the request and process time.
You can see that we basically add a timer.
And in the timer we will get a start and stop and duration of the actual handle operation.
And if the time taken more than 32nd, we are putting warning log and this will be the performance indication
and performance concern for our application.
So this is a very good illustration and logging operation for understanding the long running operations
in your handle method.
And lastly we will logging the end of the handle method.
And we indicate that this handle operation is finished with this request and response.
And we are returning the response object to the next operation.
So we have completed the logging behavior.
And in this logging behavior we basically implement AI pipeline behavior interface.
And it is logging at the start.
And at the end of the each request and measures execution time.
In order to apply this behavior globally, we need to register it in the dependency injection container.
For that purpose, please go to the Catholic API program case.
And as you remember that we are adding all the behaviors about the mediator in the configuration of
the mediator block.
In this block, add mediator block, we can configure add open behavior for the validation behavior.
Before now I am going to add a new open behavior which is the logging behavior.
So you can copy paste the logging behavior in here.
And you can add a second behavior into our each mediator pipelines.
This configuration provides that our logging behavior is applied to every mediator request.
So why we are using logging behavior for the mediator because we have lots of benefits.
For example now it is a centralized logging for every request and response.
And it is a consistent format for log entries.
And it increases the performance monitoring for each request.