In this video we are going to test seeding initial data with Martin on PostgreSQL database for our catalog
microservices.
First of all, please open the Visual Studio.
And now the first thing, we should ensure that our PostgreSQL database container is up and running.
So for that purpose I have started our Docker desktop.
But as you can see that PostgreSQL is not running.
In order to run our PostgreSQL we will use Docker compose.
I'm going to right click the docker compose and set a startup project and run without debugging.
Because my aim was is up and running to backing services for Catholic microservices or backing services
is PostgreSQL database.
So this will run the docker compose up command on behalf behind of the scene.
And if you open the Docker desktop, you can see that Docker Compose is running our PostgreSQL database
in this port numbers.
So now we are ready to run our catalog API.
I'm going to right click the catalog API and set a startup project.
And also I'm going to put a breakpoint into the data folder, catalog initial data and put a breakpoint
in the populate method which is actual seeding operation handle in this method.
So now we are ready to seeding database.
But before that let's check our existing PostgreSQL database has not any table or seeding product data
inside of it for that purpose.
This time I'm going to use Pgadmin.
If you open the Pgadmin, you can see that we can add new service in here in order to connect existing
catalog DB.
But I have created before and here you can see my catalog DB.
If I try to connect catalog DB, the server is connected successfully.
We can add a new server with providing information in the Program.cs appsettings.json file.
You can add new server with adding the server name localhost port name is this port name.
Default port name and connect the catalog db, providing these user id and password information into
your Pgadmin.
So after edit this information and server, we can connect the PostgreSQL database and browse the database.
Here you can see that we have created the catalog database if we explore the catalog database, if you
go to schemas and see is there any table or not under the schemas you can go to tables and see that
we have already created our product table before.
And if you right click and script as a select secret and run this script, you can see that we have
only one record that we have creating this record when sending the http post request.
But for now, I'm going to remove this table in order to see how we can see the operation without any
table and how Martin will be.
Create an auto, create this schema for us, and insert new records into newly created database for
performing seeding operation.
So I'm going to right click and delete this table.
And now you can see that we don't have any table under this database.
Now I am going to run this catalog microservices with Https running profile.
But before that I'm going to put additional breakpoint in the Program.cs and see that we are in development
environment.
And we can initialize Martin with using the catalog initial data.
And if I hit F5 you can see that this will be coming our breakpoint under the populate method for catalog
initial data.
This is the first thing in the catalog microservices.
That's why we should up and running this PostgreSQL database.
So now it is creating a lightweight session and it is checking that if is there any product under the
our database.
If not this will be continuing to our store operation, which will be the absurd operation that will
be create a new database table which is the product, and also insert these product records into the
database.
Here you can see that we have facing the get pre-configured products under this object array.
And this will be insert our product table.
And here you can see that in this line of code we will save change async and hit F5.
And this is performing the seed operation.
And also you can confirm from the project console logs, if you open the project console logs, you
can see that Martin is executing some SQL commands which is including the create table commands.
So it is running these scripts when the application start up.
When performing the seed operation, this is creating a new table which name is empty doc product and
after that this will be insert new records.
Under this table.
We can confirm from the Pgadmin if you open the Pgadmin and if you go to the tables under the catalog
DB, right click Refresh Tables.
See that our new table is coming in here.
Again right click script as select.
And if I run this script this time we will see that.
The whole data is listing into our database and different products are listed into our database.