In this video we are going to develop pagination for Getproducts query with using to page list async
extension method.
So pagination is a crucial feature for managing large data sets in microservices.
And Martin provides a bulletin to page list async method that simplifies the pagination implementation
and eliminates the need for the custom pagination logic.
So here you can see that Martin provides to page list and to page list async method, and this will
be facilitate and simplifies pagination implementation without writing any custom pagination logic,
and it only required by page number and page size.
And we can use to run this extension method which pacing this page number and page size.
So let's get start to implementation.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and locate the Getproducts and Getproducts endpoint.
So we will put the pagination into Getproducts.
And this will be returning the products with pagination.
So at this point we are going to create a request object that will accept page number and page size.
For that purpose I'm going to remove these commented get product request object.
And after that I'm going to put a parameters which is the page number and page size.
So this is our current Getproduct request object that will will get these information from the request.
So how we can get this page number and page size.
Of course we will get this request object as a request parameter into the our application endpoint.
So in here you can see that we have a delegate handler for these products and put it in the first parameter.
I am going to get these request parameters as a parameter.
And I would like to specify with these as a parameter notation.
And I'm going to give the parameter name as a get products request.
And this will be get this request object into our method.
And after that we can reach the request page number and page size in the request delegate handler.
So the first step is we are going to change the query object from the our incoming request object.
And I am adapting this request object with the Getproducts query that will be accepting from the our
mediator.
So in here as you can see that this is converting from the incoming request to the get products query.
And after that we can paste this query to the mediator send method.
And this will be trigger our query handler method.
So at this stage we can update Getproducts handler and handle the pagination logic inside of the these
handle method.
With passing this query information, we will move these page number and page size.
That means we will make it exactly same to our query object with adding page number and page size.
So please copy these parameters and go to the Getproducts handle method.
And in here I'm going to adding new parameters which is the page number and page size.
So this is the latest implementation of our Getproducts query with parameters.
By this way we can convert our incoming requests to query object.
And in the handle method we should implement the pagination actual logic in here.
Here you can see that the implementation performing with session query and to list async method.
But this time we will perform the pagination.
For that purpose.
I'm going to choose another extension method which is the to to page list async method.
So this will be provided to pagination using the Martin library.
And in this method this will be accepting the page number and page size.
So I'm going to pasting the page number and page size from the our incoming query parameters.
So let's me implement these parameters.
And after that explain.
So here you can see that we will use to page list async method to make it pagination available and passing
the query that page number.
If not provided we will give the one and passing the page size.
If not provided, we will give a ten and the cancellation token also providing in this method.
So this is magical operation from the Martin and this will be handled all pagination operations with
only one extension method.
If you want to learn how Martin handle these pagination, at this point we can take a closer look to
the to page list async method.
If you right click and go to definition, you can see that this method handle in the Martin Library
and return back to page list.
And if you right click and go to definition of this interface, you can see the basic information about
the pagination.
Asians like page count, total item count and methods to check for the next and previous pages and so
on.
This is the Martin implementation of pagination result and it can run on the session Equatable object.
So if you go back to our actual method, you can see that we will implement the two page list async.
And this will be adding using statement.
I'm going to moving this pagination using todo or global using statement.
And perform the pagination in our Getproducts query scenario.