In this video we are going to test pagination for Getproducts query use cases.
For that purpose, make sure that your Docker environment is running and our catalog db PostgreSQL is
up and running on Docker environment.
And after that you can see in the pgadmin we have seven items under the our product table.
And I am going to test by the pagination with sending only five in a first page.
And the second page we will see two items.
For that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and put breakpoints in the Getproducts endpoint and Getproducts under
method.
And after that run this catalog API microservice application in here.
And after running this application.
I'm going to remove this breakpoint and remove the breakpoint from the seed operation.
And yes, the application has started and after that please open the postman.
And in this time we will start by testing scenario where we send the first page with the five products.
And this is common use case in real world applications.
But before that let me send only products and to see all products listed and responded into our.
Product list.
Here you can see that these are the all products that including seven products from the database.
And we don't have any pagination yet.
So before proceeding to pagination, make sure that you have removed the unnecessary breakpoints into
your application in order to debug properly.
So after that, if you open the postman this time, we are going to request maximum five items in one
page and I would like to request the page one for that purpose.
I'm going to put request parameters in here.
The first one is page number, the second one is page size.
Here you can see the query parameters comes listed on here.
So if you save this Http get method this will be paging anymore.
And if you send http get request this will be come to the our Getproducts endpoint.
And if you check the request parameter as a parameter type, you can see the page number and page size
comes into our Getproduct request object.
And the first thing we are converting as a query.
And in query we will send query handler.
And of course before that we will see some logging operation.
Now here you can see the actual handle operation.
And in the query object we have page number and page size.
And this time Martin will be run to page list async extension method with pacing this page number and
page size and return back to product list according to this page number and page size.
Here you can see the product list comes with the five, which is the our page size.
And if you go back to response to the client, you can see that only five products comes for the first
page.
So in order to perform the pagination and retrieving the second page, we will send the page number
is two.
And if we send the page number is two, you can see that this time we will retrieve the next five items
if available on database.
If we continue these codes and go to the our actual logic.
This time you can see the product count comes with two.
That means we are retrieved the second two products into our database that is listing in here, which
is the LG, G7 and Panasonic Lumix.
And you can confirm from the these Pgadmin dashboard, we are retrieving the second page size items
from the database.