In this video we are going to orchestrate catalog API microservices with Docker Compose.
Docker compose is a tool for defining and running multi-container applications in Docker environment.
So you can see that in the last video we have containerized a single catalog microservices with adding
Docker support into our application.
And here you can see the illustration of the steps for containerization and orchestration.
We develop our code locally and adding Docker support to containerize our catalog API microservices.
And now we will orchestrate these microservices with using Docker Compose including the database and
microservice itself.
So with Docker Compose we use a Yaml file to configure our applications, services, networks and volume
definition.
And this allows us to run entire application with a single command which is the docker compose up.
So please open the Visual Studio.
We have already created docker compose before and docker compose overwrite file is generated when we
are activating our backing services PostgreSQL that you can check the docker compose for, including
only catalog db PostgreSQL and including in the overwrite file.
This only includes PostgreSQL configurations in here.
So far we have only used the compose for activating backing services, but now we will use the compose
to orchestrate all microservices and databases communicating each other in the network.
So for that purpose, we will follow the same steps to orchestrate the Catholic API.
We should select the Catholic API, right click Add Container Orchestrator Support and we should select
Docker Compose and click the okay button.
And target operating system should be Linux.
Click the okay and see that Docker-compose.yml and overwrite file editing from the Visual Studio.
And this time we can see two services, one for the Catholic DB and another for the Catholic API representing
our microservices.
And this is indicating our image and Docker file location that we will wield as a Docker container in
the Docker compose.
And if you go to the docker compose or write file, you can see that this is the catalog API.
Microservice configurations.
These configurations are generated from the Visual Studio, but these are not sufficient to activate
our Catholic API, because we should override these Yaml file to configure the port numbers accordingly,
and any new environment variables for database connections.
And also we will add some depends on containers.
So now we can start the editing these configurations one by one.
I'm going to explain and change the ports.
So ports are mapped to enable communication between our host machine and the containers.
We are developing the catalog API microservices and deploy the local environment.
But this time we will use these microservices in the Docker environment.
So that means we will perform the port mapping about 6066 port numbers.
So according to our slide we are going to edit these port numbers and exposing these port numbers with
starting to 6000.
So these are the Http and https port numbers that we redirect from the Docker environment.
And the next configuration is environment variables.
We need to set the correct connection string and environment variables for our services.
For that purpose I'm going to add a connection string under the these port definitions in the environment
variables.
Here you can see that.
We have put a connection string as an environment variable.
And these are the encoding servername as a catalog DB port number, which is the default PostgreSQL
port number.
Database name catalog db user id Postgres password is Postgres and include error detail is true.
So this is the environment variable.
That means this will be injected to the our catalog API.
Microservices.
When the application start up in Docker environment as a Docker container.
And the last configuration is dependency management.
We use depends on keyword in here.
In order to control the startup order of our services in Docker environment.
So catalog API service depends on the catalog DB because we are relying on the database in our catalog
microservices.
And that means this will be the or depends on keyword and under the depends on.
I'm going to put catalog DB which name is our PostgreSQL container name and catalog db.
So notice that we have configured the connection string to the point to the catalog db that also we
can depend on the catalog DB which is the our database server name.
So in Docker compose services on the same network can communicate with each other using the service
names or catalog API service can reach the database using the service name which is the catalog DB.
That's why we put the server name as a catalog DB to communicate with our PostgreSQL database in Docker
environment, and also we are overriding the existing configuration with double underscore.
This is also very important.
That means this will be overwrite the current configuration in the application setting.
If you go to the application settings for Catholic API, you can see that we have a connection string
and database.
In order to override this configuration, that means overriding this server name.
We put the double underscore in here and setting the whole connection string from the beginning.
As you can see that we have successfully orchestrated catalog API and PostgreSQL in Docker compose.