In this video we are going to test our catalog API microservices orchestrated with Docker compose,
including integration with PostgreSQL database.
Docker compose provides an efficient way to run Multi-container applications.
Our focus will be to ensure that our Catholic API microservices interact seamlessly with PostgreSQL
database in a dockerized setup.
How we can run these Docker compose.
In our application we have two ways.
The first way is we can run docker compose up command manually.
If you don't want to use Visual Studio tooling, you can right click the Docker compose and open in
terminal and start the PowerShell.
And you can run that docker compose up command with providing docker compose yaml and overwrite yaml
file.
This is the way one.
What is the way two?
Way two is using the Docker tooling on Visual Studio.
Visual studio has a great support for Docker and docker Compose that we can right click Docker Compose
and set a startup project, and we can run this application in Docker Compose running profile.
And we can debug all the applications and containers in the Docker compose with using Visual Studio
tooling.
This is one of the powerful feature that we can debug inside of the Docker containers.
So I'm going to following this step and click this button.
That means this will be run the docker compose up command in behind of the scenes.
And after that this will be activate all microservices and containers inside of the Docker compose that
you can see the Catalog and container window in Visual Studio tooling.
This is starting our catalog API at 66 support, which is a Docker network.
And you can see the catalog DB also running on our application.
Let's open the Docker desktop.
That means we will verify the containers from the Docker desktop that you can see that Docker compose.
Now two containers, one for the catalog API and another for the catalog DB.
If you click the Catholic API, you can see the logs listed on the Docker desktop.
And here you can see that Martin applies the migration.
You can see the applying the initial data catalog API and using the catalog initial data.
So this is the logs that we can verify the migration.
And we have seen all the containers are running successfully.
Now we can perform the health check for Catholic API.
For that purpose.
Please open the postman and go to the health checks.
And this time catalog URL should be changed.
The environment is changed.
For that purpose I'm going to change the environment localhost to Docker, and you can see that our
catalog URL has changed to 6060.
And I'm going to send a http get request to health endpoint and see that the status is healthy.
That means these microservices connected to PostgreSQL successfully.
So now we will use postman for testing various API endpoints.
Let's start by fetching a list of the products for that purpose.
Open the http get method for Getproducts endpoint and this is the providing the page number and page
size.
Click the Http send method.
See that this is also put to breakpoint, and we can debug docker compose inside of the container.
And this very powerful feature that we can debug this container and get a response.
You can see the five products retrieved from the database and return back to our API result.
So we can continue and confirm that the second page should be come with two product item we have confirmed
in the last videos.
Yes, you can see that we have also see two products listed in the second page.
So the next thing we can do is post operation.
We can use http post products in order to create a new product.
So I am going to add a new product which will be the test prod docker product.
And click the send button and this will be hit to or create product endpoint.
And if I put to F5 this will be trigger validator.
And after that actual handle class.
Of course before that we have validation behavior.
And now you can see that this is going to create a new product into our database and fully Docker environment.
And the new product ID is in here.
So Visual Studio allows us to debug our services running in Docker.
Let me open the Docker desktop and see how blocks are configured in the catalog API.
When performing Http, get and post operation.
Here you can see that we are adding log information when starting and adding these Http get products
query.
And here you can see the create product command which including the new Json object for the new product.
So we can confirm that our operation are logged successfully.
And you can also verify newly created product from the Pgadmin.
If you connect to catalog DB and run this select script, you can see that this time we have eight product
into our database.
As you can see that we have successfully performed Docker compose operation and we have run several
Http get and post requests.
Let me quickly test these Http put and delete operations, copy these newly created id and open the
http put request and change the ID information.
And I'm going to update it for Docker, change the name and hit the send button.
This will be also put our breakpoints and I hit the F5 to run the validators and run the actual handle
method, and after that this will be updated the existing product.
And here you can see the response is success.
We can verify these operations from the database.
And in here if you run again this script you can see that the value is updated which is the updated
for Docker.
So if you continue to delete operation or before that, you can also verify with the get products by
ID.
This API also working fine.
If you change the ID information and send request, this will be hit the get product by ID endpoint
and query handler and respond back to the newly updated product for us.
So now I'm going to delete this product.
And if you change the product ID on the http delete operation and send the Http delete, this will be
delete this product into our database.
You can hit F5 to perform delete operation and delete also is success.
You can open the Pgadmin.
And now if you refresh this secret, you can see that now we will have only seven item in PostgreSQL
database.
So that means we have completed the deployment to Docker, compose all catalog microservices with database
and next section we will focus on the basket microservices.