In this section, we will learn how to integrate Redis as a distributed caching solution in our basket
microservices, and we will also cover the implementation of key patterns and tools to efficiently manage
caching on basket microservices.
Here you can see the big picture of our application basket.
Microservices will be communicate with the Redis to increase the performance of the shopping cart operations.
So how integrating Redis into basket microservices.
Here you can see the implementation strategy.
We basically integrate Redis into our basket microservices to cache user data, shopping cart data into
Redis.
And this will be enhanced the performance by reducing the load our database operations and speeding
up the data retrieve operations from the basket microservices.
And here you can see that we can use different NuGet packages to connect and communicate with radius
from basket microservices.
And here you can see the architecture that we are going to implement during this section.
Why we choose Redis for distributed caching.
Redis is an advanced key value store known for its high performance, and it is often used for caching,
session store and pub sub systems.
Redis offers in-memory data storage resulting in fast data access, and it also supports various data
structures, make it versatile for different use cases, and also Radius is an excellent choice for
microservice architectures, primarily due to its inherent distributed characteristics and performance
efficiency.
Microservices often need to share state or data in a distributed environment, and Redis as a distributed
cache, enabling services to access shared data quickly and reducing the load on databases.
And as a result, we can say that we will implement proxy pattern, decorator pattern and security library,
and we will implement cache aside pattern and cache invalidation with using Redis.
And we will implement the decorator pattern with developing cased basket repository class using the
security library.
And we will set up Redis as a distributed cache using the docker compose file for multi-container docker
environment.
And we will end up integrated Redis into our basket microservices to cache our user shopping cart data,
and that will boost performance by reducing the load on our database and speeding up the data retrieval
operations.