In this video we are going to learn cache aside pattern in distributed caching for microservices.
A cache aside pattern is the most common caching strategy used in microservices.
You can see the picture on the slide.
We have three steps.
Now I am going to explain these following steps.
The first step is when a client needs to access data.
It first checks to see if the data is in the cache.
The second step is if the data is in the case, the client retrieves it from the cache and returns it
to the caller system.
And the third step is if the data is not in the cache, the client retrieves it from the database and
stores it in the cache, and then returns it to the caller system.
Some of the caching systems provide read through and write through or write behind operations.
In these systems, client applications retrieves data over by the cache.
For caches that don't provide this functionality, it is the responsibility of the applications that
use the cache and update the cache if there is a cache miss.
So a cache aside pattern comes to the picture and implements for these kind of cases.
Microservices.
Also a good example to implement cache aside pattern.
In a microservice architecture, it is common to use a distributed cache that is shared across multiple
services.
This can be useful for storing data that is commonly accessed by the multiple services, or storing
data that is expensive to compete or retrieve from a databases.
Using the cache aside pattern can improve the performance of a microservice architecture by reducing
the number of expensive database calls or data store lookups.
It can also help to reduce the load on the database or data store, as many requests for data can be
served from the cache.
In order to use the cache aside pattern in microservices, you would need to implement a cache layer
in your service that is responsible for managing the cache.
This may involve using a cache library or framework such as Redis or Memcached, or implementing a custom
cache solution.
Here you can see the process of the cache aside pattern.
When a service needs to access data, it first checks to see if the data is in the cache.
If the data is in the cache, the service retrieves from the cache and returns it to the caller system.
If the data is not in the cache, the service retrieves it from the database or other data store.
And after that stores it into the cache, and after that then returns it to the caller system.
So there are some drawbacks of using cache aside pattern for microservices.
Cache can introduce additional complexity into our architecture or may not be suitable for all situations.
For example, the cache may need to be invalidated or refreshed when the data is updated in the database,
and this can require additional coordination between the microservices.
And additionally the cache may introduce additional latency if it is located remotely from the microservices
that are using it.
So additional latency is also one of the drawbacks of using the distributed cache.