In this video we are going to learn proxy pattern, decorator pattern and security library.
Let me start with the what is proxy pattern?
The proxy pattern provides a placeholder for another object in order to control access to it.
This pattern creates a proxy object that serves as an intermediary for requests intended for the original
object.
A common use case is like lazy loading, controlling access, logging, and so on.
It is like having a gatekeeper who can add extra behavior or checks before accessing the actual object.
The next pattern is decorator pattern.
The decorator pattern dynamically adds behavior to an object without altering its structure.
It involves a set of decorator classes that are used to extend the functionality of the original class
without changing its code, and decorator pattern is useful for adding functionalities to objects at
runtime, for example, enhancing a window object with additional features like borders scrollbars dynamically.
So how can we use decorator pattern and how we can implement it?
The first step is we can create abstract decorators that implement the same interface as the object.
They will extend and then concrete decorator classes add additional behavior.
For example, if you have a basket repository class for database operation, you can create a cased
basket repository that extends the basket repository with caching capabilities.
So what is security library and why we use it?
Security library is a.
Net library that extends the built in IOC container of ASP.Net core.
It provides additional capabilities to scan and register services in more flexible ways.
Security library also particularly useful for implementing patterns like decorator in a clean and manageable
way.
It simplifies the process of service registration and decoration in ASP.Net core applications.
So how can we implement these decorator pattern using the security library?
I'm going to explain step by step.
The first step is define interface and base implementation.
We can start with an interface.
For example I basket repository and a base implementation which is the basket repository that communicate
with the database.
And after that we can create decorator class.
So in the second step we can create a decorator class like cased basket repository that also implements
a basket repository.
But adding the caching logic and business inside of this class.
And the last step is register services with Secretor.
We can use Secretor library in Program.cs to first register the Base Services basket repository, and
then they apply the decorator one, which is the cache basket repository.
You can see the code on the slide.
The first line of code.
We can register a basket repository with the actual basket repository.
But after that we can decorate these basket repository with using the Secretor library.
In the decorate method, we can decorate the basket repository with the case basket repository, including
the cache capabilities.
That means we can say that the decorator pattern and Secretor library offers a robust approach to extending
the functionality of services in ASP.Net core applications.
So now we will develop cased basket repository with proxy decorator patterns and security library.