In this video, we are going to start to developing Cash Basket repository class in the basket microservices.
And this class act as a decorator over the basket repository and adding caching functionality to optimize
data retrieval and manipulation.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the basket microservices.
And if you go to the data folder, you can see that we have already created basket and a basket repository.
Now I am going to create a new class which is the Cache basket repository.
Please add a new class which name is Cache Basket repository under data folder.
And here you can see that our data folder including three classes.
In this class, we basically inherit from the I basket repository and encapsulate an instance of the
basket repository, which is the base repository, and we will overwrite the methods to add caching
logic.
Let me start with the inherit from the I basket repository.
Come here and inherit from.
I basket repository and implement this interface and make sure that you have a correct order.
This will be get basket, store basket and the delete basket.
So how can we implement these methods.
Comes from the I basket repository.
Again we are going to inject a basket repository into our class.
So here you can see that we have injected a basket repository in the cache basket repository.
And we will implement these get basket store and delete basket operation using these injected repository
object.
For that purpose I'm going to inject it with return await repository dot get basket and passing the
username and cancellation token.
So this is the first implementation.
And the second implementation I'm going to follow the same steps.
I'm going to return await repository store basket and passing the basket.
And cancellation token.
You can see that when we are making available function, the method body could be adding the async,
so you can make it the same things in the delete basket.
I'm going to use return await repository dot delete basket and passing the username and cancellationtoken.
So let me explain this class and what we are going to do in here.
Basically we have implemented two patterns proxy pattern and decorator pattern.
For proxy pattern.
Cased basket repository acts as a proxy and forwarding the calls to underlying basket repository.
We can see that we will forwarding the get basket, store basket and delete basket operation using the
underlying repository object that we have injected.
And also we will implement decorator pattern.
That means we will extend the functionality of basket repository by adding caching logic.
So it is time to use Redis distributed cache into our cache decorated class.
That means we will integrate Redis for caching when performing get stored and delete basket operations.