In this video, we are going to focus on enhancing the cash basket repository by integrating the Radius
distributed cash.
This approach will significantly improve the performance of the basket microservices.
By reducing the frequency of database access.
You can think every repository call will be access to database, and we will reduce these database access
calls by implementing the Radius distributed cache.
So how can we integrate Radius in the caching layer.
Basically we will adding k radius related dependencies into our basket API project.
And we will implementing caching logic within each method and reduce the database calls.
So we will leverage the radius connection through the distributed cache interface provided by.
Net.
If you open the documentation, you can see that dotnet provided distributed cache interface that can
be using get async set async refresh async and remove async methods to perform distributed cache into
ASP.Net applications.
So if you go to the distributed cache interface, you can see that these distributed cache is under
the Microsoft Extensions caching library.
In order to use distributed cache and inject into our application, we should install this package that
I am going to install to Visual Studio.
Please open the Visual Studio and right click the basket API manage NuGet packages.
So now we are going to install Microsoft Extensions caching, dot stack exchange, Redis.
So please download this package into your basket API.
And if you double click the project file, you can verify that we have installed successfully.
Save this basket API and go back to our Quest Basket repository.
Now we can inject distributed cache into our class for that purpose.
After the repository injection I'm going to use I distributed cache from the extensions.
Dot caching and parameter name can be cache.
And if you put in here you can see that we have injected two services repository and case service.
So let's implement the get basket.
So running with distributed cache.
So basically before calling the database operation I'm going to create a cache basket variable and retrieve
this basket information.
Try to get from the distributed cache.
If you come to cache and put dot notation you can see that we can use get getString and asynchronous
functions in order to get and set value from the Redis distributed cache.
And I'm going to use get string async method.
And we will retrieve these cache value from the username and passing the cancellation token.
Within this code, we basically call getString async method with passing the username as a key information
of the cache.
So here you can see that this is the cache key, and we expect to return back our cache basket string
Json value that we can convert before sending the database operation.
That's why we should check this cache basket value as a string is null or empty condition.
If not null, we can perform the Json deserialize operation.
I'm going to use Json serializer from the system.text dot json namespace, and then serialize to shopping
cart object and passing our cache basket to this function.
So this will be deserialize the incoming text object from the distributed cache.
So if null that means there is no item in the cache.
Now we can perform the actual operation from the database.
For that purpose I'm going to get a basket definition and this time we can use await repository dot
get basket I'm going to cut in here.
And in this line of code we basically perform the database call.
And after performing the database call it is good to feed the cache with using the cache dot set string
async method.
And we will pass cache key as a username.
And the cache value is again Json serializer and serialize.
And this time we will serialize the basket object.
And also I'm going to paste the cancellation token.
And now we can return the basket object to this function.
So this is the implementation of the get basket.
And after that we can implement the store basket operation.
Following the same approach.
So first of all I'm going to store this basket from the database.
I'm removing the return object.
After storing the basket operation.
We can also store these information into our cache.
For that purpose I'm going to use case dot set string async method.
And the key is a basket dot username.
And now we will follow the Json serializer that serialize.
And I'm going to pass basket object and paste the cancellation token.
And we can return the basket in the stored basket operation.
And lastly, we will perform the delete basket operation for that purpose.
First of all, we will delete the basket from the database with using the repository object.
And after that we should delete this object into the cache cache dot.
Remove async function.
And we can give the username as a key and cancellationtoken and we can return true as a response of
the delete basket.
If you go on top of this page, you can see that we have two using statement.
I'm not moving these using statement to global using because these are only using in the case basket
repository that would not be using the other classes.
This will be encapsulate the cache operations in the cache basket repository.
So in this code you can see that we have performed get basket store basket and delete basket operations
in the get basket method.
Before calling the database, we basically check the value from the cache with a given username username
in here cache key, and we will use getString async method in order to access cache basket value.
And if this value if not null, we can deserialize object to the shopping cart and return this object.
So in here we forgot the returning this deserialize object.
Please fix this code as me.
Return this deserialize object and I'm going to use null for given operator at the end of this line.
So make sure that if cached basket is not null, we are going to deserialize object to the shopping
cart and we should return back to the get basket method.
So if the cache key and cache value is null, we basically perform the database operation using the
repository dot get basket.
And after getting the basket information before returning this basket, we will use cache dot set string
async method.
In order to set this basket object into the distributed cache with a given username.
So we will pass username as a cache key.
And after that we will serialize the incoming basket object and we will reach the Json serialized string
in order to cache these username into distributed cache.
And after that we will return back to basket object.
This is what the get basket operation.
And make sure that you have returning these if statement.
And after that we will perform the store basket operation.
So after storing and updating these basket to the database we will update the cache information within
the new data.
So when we are updating and storing new basket information we should also update the distributed cache.
For that purpose we will call distributed cache in here and in the delete basket we will basically remove
the basket information both database and the cache operations.
So in here this is the implementation of the cache basket repository.
And make sure that you have also developed at the same way.
In the Cache Basket repository class we have integrated Redis cache using the proxy and decorator patterns
and cache basket repository.
Now provide efficient data handling for the basket.
Microservices.