In this video we are going to register Decorated Cash Basket Repository class using the security library.
And also we will register.
I distributed Cash and stack exchange radius to activate register operations into our application.
Please open the Program.cs and go to the location of this line of code.
In here you can see that we have already registered basket repository from the I basket repository.
So directly registering multiple implementation of I basket repository is not feasible.
And it makes problem with direct dependency injection.
What I am talking about in here.
If you come here and register for the cash basket repository, you can see that we have injected two
repository types from the I basket repository and this is not working.
This will be taking the last registration and avoiding from the first registration.
So how we can handle this kind of operations.
The first solution could be we can decorate cash basket repository manually.
So normally we can inject decorated class with manually.
Instead of using this statement we can perform that and register basket repository.
With this line of code you can see that I am adding scope as a I basket repository, and in the provider
configuration we can get required services, but case repository which is the actual implementation.
After that we can paste these based basket repository to the our decorated cash basket repository in
the constructor.
And we can manually create cash basket repository providing these basket repository.
And I distributed cash.
But as you suggested this line of code is.
And manually decorating these cash basket repository can be cumbersome and not scalable and it is not
manageable.
Instead of that we should use security library.
So creator library simplifies the process of registering decorators in the dependency injection container.
So if you go to the GitHub project you can see that security library is very popular in.
Net ecosystem.
And we can install these package with using the install package command.
Or we can use security library from the package manager console.
And here you can see the usage this library adding two extension method into the I service collection.
These are the second and decorate.
So we will use decorate extension method for using the decorate already registered services.
That means we will decorate cash basket repository using this method.
And here you can see the example of the scanning and decoration in this line of code.
Now we can go back to our Visual Studio, right click the basket API, manage NuGet packages and search
for the security library and install Security Library into basket API project.
So if you double click the basket API, you can verify that security library installed successfully.
Save this file and go back to Program.cs.
Instead of the manually decorating our cash basket repository, we can comment these codes.
And now I'm going to decorate by using the security library.
Here you can see that this time we will decorate our basket repository using the decorate extension
method.
If I write decorate in here you can see that these decorate extension method comes from the security
library.
And by this way, we can easily decorate our cash basket repository using the I basket repository.
And we am going to removing these unnecessary code.
And here you can see our registration operation complete for the cash basket repository.
By this way, Secretus decorate method elegantly changes the repository object and its decorated version
in the Cash Basket Repository class.
So if you go to the cash basket repository, we have also injected I distributed cash, which comes
from the Stack Exchange and we should also register this stack exchange radius into our Program.cs.
For that purpose, please open the Program.cs.
In here we can register by writing builder services, add stack exchange register cash and we can provide
options inside of the parameter.
And as you can see that I have provided options when we are registering a radius cash.
And in the configuration we can provide the connection strings from the application Settings.json.
And if you want, you can also give the instance name and populate the other properties from the options.
Now I am going to leave as it is and I am focusing on the register operations.
As you can see that we have configured Radius as a distributed cache.
With providing this connection string.
For that purpose, we should define connection string for radius and please go to application Settings.json
file and under the connection string.
And database string.
I'm going to add a new string, which is the radius.
And here you can see the radius connection string, including the server name as a localhost.
And the port number is a default port number.
By this way radius is configured to connect to the local instance on default port, which is the six,
three, seven nine, and this configuration aligned with the standard radius setup and ensure seamless
integration with the application by providing registration in the Program.cs and indicating this connection
string.