In this video, we are going to remember our e-commerce microservice deployment strategy, and we will
start to set up Redis as a distributed cache using the Docker compose.
So here you can see that our basket microservices using the Redis distributed cache as a backing services.
So we should download Redis Docker image and run this image into our Docker compose environment.
By this way we can connect to radius from our local basket microservices.
But before that, let's remember our e-commerce microservice deployment strategy.
You can see that we have two options so far.
We have build and develop our microservices in local environment.
But now we need to connect to our Redis cache.
And we need IP and port number that we can connect from our local computer.
That means we will activate backing services on Docker environment with using Docker compose and expose
endpoints to our local microservices.
And the second step, we will orchestrate all microservices and backing services into Docker compose
and test inside of the full Docker environment.
But now we will do the first part of the deployment.
So we will set up the Redis as a distributed cache using Docker compose.
For that purpose.
Let's see how we can download and run Redis image into docker environment.
Here you can see the Redis image into Docker Hub.
This is the official image on the crop.
And if you scroll down we can get more detail about the configurations.
And if you scroll down you can see that how we can start Redis instance on Docker environment with run
the docker run command.
And if you scroll down you can see additional details about the Redis image.
And if you go to the Redis CLI documentation, you can see that Redis is connecting the localhost and
the port number is 6379.
This is the default port number for the radius.
And now we are going to download this Redis image and run this image.
There are two ways that we can do that.
The first one is running the docker run command.
And the second one is using the docker compose command.
So we will follow the docker compose command and add the image into our docker-compose.yml file.