In this video, we are going to integrate radius into our Docker compose setup and making it part of
our multi-container Docker environment.
So we have two files for this operation.
The docker compose yaml file and docker compose overwrite yaml file.
So in here the docker compose yaml file.
We will define Redis service along with other backing services and microservices.
And in the docker compose overwrite file we will override and specify configuration details for local
development, for example container name, environment variables, port numbers and volume definitions,
and so on.
So please open the Docker-compose.yaml main file and we will set up the art baking services in our case
Redis distributed cache for that purpose.
After the basket database, we are listing the baking services on top of these docker-compose.yml file.
And after that we will list microservices.
That's why after the basket db I'm going to write distributed cache.
Please type distributed cache in here.
And as an image we should give Redis.
Make sure that your indentation is correct and see that we defined Redis as a distributed cache into
our docker compose Yaml file.
Save this file and we can go to the overwrite Yaml file.
In order to configure this Redis distributed cache, again, we should go to the after basket db configurations
and before microservice definitions, we should put in here our distributed cache configurations as
a backing services.
Here you can see that the name should be the same as the docker-compose.yml file.
And as a container name we give distributed cache because it could be generic name that we can change
the radius to the memcache in the upcoming and future developments.
For that purpose, please give a container name and restart it always.
If there is any problem in the cache, this will be restart always.
And here you can see the port definitions.
This is the default port that exposing the same port number to the our local environment.
Here you can see the internal port number to access the redis in Docker environment.
And here you can see that we have exposed the same port number to our local microservices.
So please save this overwrite Yaml file and make sure that you have be careful about the indentations
and you have developed a the same way.
As you can see that we have added the redis to our docker compose configuration for the multi-container
environments.