In this video, we are going to run Docker Compose in Visual Studio in order to set up Redis as a distributed
cache in Docker environment.
For that purpose, make sure that your Docker desktop is started, and after that come to our Visual
Studio.
Right click the Docker compose and set a startup project.
And after that you can see Docker Compose running profile.
Come here.
And I am going to run without debugging in order to only activate the backing services.
These are the PostgreSQL databases and the Redis distributed cache.
Here you can see the output window.
This is going to run docker compose up command.
And the first thing it is downloading the redis image from the Docker hub and activating the Redis image
in our docker compose environment for the first time.
And you can see that our microservices also has started.
If you go back to Visual Studio, you can see the output window.
It is started our catalog and basket microservices and if you open the containers you can see that this
time we have four containers under Docker Compose including the distributed cache.
And if you click the distributed cache you can see all details, environments, ports, volumes and
so on.
And it's the same way we can open the Docker desktop.
And here you can see that our Docker compose environment, including the distributed cache.
And if you come here you can see the port number is exposing default port number.
So that means we have successfully activated Redis as a distributed cache.
In our Docker compose environment.
We can click the radius docker container and you can see the logs in here.
So now it is time to connect this Redis cache.
And we can run Redis CLI commands into Docker environment for that purpose.
First of all we should connect to interactive terminal of these redis docker image.
How we can open interactive terminal.
We have several options.
We can run docker exec command and dash it command to open the interactive terminal for this Docker
container.
But I am following the easy way to connect the container.
If you click this Docker image, and if you go to the exec section, you can see that this is going
to open interactive terminal for the radius container.
And we can directly run the Redis CLI command in order to interact with the radius container in Docker
environment.
For that purpose, I'm going to run Redis cli command to start our redis into our docker environment
and test the connection with sending the ping request.
So first of all, I'm going to run redis cli and hit the enter.
As you can see that we have started the Redis CLI.
And I'm going to try basic commands like get and set key value and ensure that Redis is functioning
correctly.
For that purpose we can write the ping command and this will be returned as the prompt.
That means redis is working successfully.
And also I'm going to set key value.
And after that we can get the key information.
In the previous line we have set the key as a value.
If we get the key from the redis, you can see the value comes as a value.
And you can also understand by setting the name as a met.
And you can also get the name key information, the value of the met.
So as you can see that we have run several commands into Redis container terminal.
So now we are ready to connect radius from our basket API.
Microservices.