In this video I am going to show you a quick tip.
We will configure docker compose, launch settings and not open the browser for microservices.
As you can see the docker compose Yaml file we have one microservices, which is the Catholic API.
And whenever I run the Docker compose profile on Visual Studio, this will be open a blank web page
on the browser.
And this is try to hit localhost and 6060.
This is the base endpoint for the Catholic microservices.
But we never use this browser.
We always using our postman collection when we are sending Http methods to our microservices.
So that means we don't want to open browser for each running in Visual Studio.
How we can do that?
Of course we should do that.
This setting by launch settings Json file for microservices.
If you open the Visual Studio, we can come to Docker Compose and right click the Docker compose and
open the properties.
You can see the general we have launch action for the Catholic API.
Since we have one microservices into our Docker compose, we can one Catholic API, and that we can
change the launch settings and launch action in here.
This is launching the browser.
And if you expand the dropdown you can see that we don't want to do nothing.
We will just want to start these API microservices.
And we will send the Http request using the Our postman collection.
Please set the launch action as a do nothing and apply this change and click the okay button.
You can also see that under Docker Compose, we have additional launch settings to configure our launch
options under the Core Compose.
Okay, now let's come to Docker Compose Yaml file.
And now I'm going to restart our Docker compose running profile.
If you stop this docker compose operation and restart this docker compose without debugging, this time
I would not expect to open browser.
We will see only containers up and running from the output and container window.
We can see that catalog has started successfully and containers are activated for Catholic API.
And this time we don't see any opening browser for catalog microservices.
So this was the quick tip for the launch settings.
And we will follow the launch settings under the each microservices.
For example, under basket API, if you go to properties and open the launch settings, you can come
here and change the launch browsers.
False for each running profile.
For example, let's change the Http launch browser as a false and also https launch browser as a false.
Because we have used http and https profiles when running our microservices, and I'm opening the catalog
API and go to the properties, launch settings and change the Http running profile.
Launch browser property as a false and Https launch browser property as a false.
As you can see that we have successfully changed the launch browser and we will provide to not opening
browser for microservices due to interaction with our postman collection.