In this video we are going to connect Redis cache from local basket maker services and we will send
http, get and Post request in order to connect basket case data from Redis container.
For that purpose, please open the Basket maker services and go to the Cache Basket repository.
And in here I'm going to put breakpoints into the get basket store basket and delete basket.
So now we are going to test and debug our basket maker services.
Make sure that your Docker desktop is up and running.
And you have started the Docker compose.
And your distributed cache container should be exposed.
The default port number for Redis distributed cache.
So after that, if you go back to our Visual Studio, you can confirm that application settings.
And we will connect Redis with localhost as a server name and default port number.
So now come to the basket API.
Right click the basket API project and set a startup project.
And I am going to run https mode.
And here you can see that this time application has started.
And listening on the localhost 5051 from local computer.
And it didn't open any browser that we have changed the settings from the launch settings.
You can see that launch browser is false.
That's why we didn't see any browser and our application ready to accept requests from the postman for
that purpose.
Please open the postman and this time I'm going to send a http get request to this endpoint.
The basket URL should be 5051 and the endpoint is basket slash s r username of the shopping cart.
Click the send button to send http get request and start debugging.
It becomes to get basket endpoint and after continue this debugging.
This will be trigger our query handler operation.
And at this time the repository get basket will be trigger or catch basket repository.
In here you can see that our newly developed catch basket repository hit the breakpoint for get basket
and the username is boolean.
First of all it is going to check this username from the Redis distributed cache.
If there is any key information as this username, the cache basket should be populated.
But now this is the null.
That means there is no cache with the username key information.
That's why it is going to check the database with using the actual repository object.
This time you can see that this is going to hit the basket repository and using the session that load
async method in order to get username and shopping cart from the PostgreSQL database, and it is going
to get the basket information.
But if you look at the basket basket also null from the database, because last time when we are hitting
the http delete method, we have deleting the.
Or is the boolean username.
So that's why we got the response which is the basket not found exception.
And this is the boolean username basket is not exist on our database.
So we can send http post requests in order to create a new basket for username.
For that purpose please open the http post Reqs.
And here you can see the URL payload that we are going to hit our store basket and point.
So you can see the URL is in here.
And we will use the slash basket and send http post request with this payload.
And I'm going to click the send button and trigger the Our Store Basket endpoint class.
In this class we basically accommodate the incoming requests and convert to command object and trigger
the our store basket command handle handle method.
And in this method we basically store basket into the database using the Martin.
And as you can see that it is hitting the our cache basket repository store basket.
And first of all this will be trigger the actual operation to storing basket into database using the
session dot store method.
And here you can see the basket as a whole Json object will be storing the database, the database store
operation complete.
And the second thing we are going to do, we will use set string async method.
In order to add these username and adding these basket object as a serializable object into the already
cache.
That means we are writing the username and shopping cart information on the distributed Redis cache,
and after continue our debugging or set string operation completed on Redis and we will continue to
return back the result, and this will be returned back to the client application as a username.
So that means we will save this shopping cart into database and the cache.
How we can confirm on the cache operation.
If you open the Docker desktop and open the distributed cache container, if you go to the exec for
interactive terminal.
So I'm going to right keys and start character and this will be checked all the keys under the Redis
cache.
Here you can see that there is newly added cache which is the.
Our username is the boolean added into our redis.
That means we have confirmed that we have successfully created this new shopping cart, and also adding
this shopping cart information into our distributed cache as a Json format.
So after that we can run Http, get operation again.
And this time we have expected that basket will be found and this will be retrieved from the Redis distributed
cache.
And avoid calling the database operations and provide performant response to the client application.
So click Http send button and this will be triggered get basket endpoint.
And if you continue our debug you can see that this will be comes to query 100 class.
And we will use repository get basket.
And this will be comes to our cache basket repository.
Get basket method.
And in the first line of code this will be try to get username as Subbulu and shopping cart from the
Redis distributed cache.
So if you continue that you can see that this time we will access the cache basket response.
This is the Json response, the whole shopping cart object.
And this comes from the Redis cache.
And if we look at the string or is empty or not, this will be not empty and null.
That's why we will deserialize shopping cart and return back to the client application without doing
any database call operations.
So here you can see that the method is returning.
And this comes from the our cache.
And if you come here you can see that the whole shopping cart information comes from the Redis cache
avoiding database calls.
And it is very performant.
If you send again you can see that this will be always go to the cache and checking all information
from case without sending requests to the database.
Okay, now the last thing we can test http delete operation.
If you come here and send http delete request for boolean username, you can come to the our delete
basket end point and continue with the delete basket command handler.
And this will be performed the delete basket from the database.
And after that remove async method will provide to delete these username key information from the Redis
cache.
So first of all let's delete from the database using the id distributed session operation.
So after that we will remove the cache with using the cache object from the distributed cache and returning
the tour information so it is returned back.
The is success.
That means delete operation.
Perform both database and redis cache.
We can confirm from the our interactive terminal.
If you come here and run again the keys command and hit the enter.
This time you can see that we don't have any boolean key under the.
This distributed cache.
So as you can see that we have successfully connected and test our basket microservices with Redis and
demonstrate the effective implementation of distributed cache.