In this video, we are going to implement health checks for basket microservices, ensuring that both
PostgreSQL database and Redis distributed cache are operational.
As you remember that ASP.Net health checks allows us to expose Http endpoints for checking the health
of the application infrastructure components, and we will add health checks to our basket.
Microservices with checking the health of our PostgreSQL database and Redis distributed cache.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio.
And now I am going to implement health checks in very basic format.
If you go to program.cs of basket API, we have two things that we are going to implement health checks.
The first one is we will register health checks before building the application.
And after that we will configure the middleware.
So let me start with the registering the health checks builder services dot add health check.
And this is a very basic implementation of the health check registration.
After that we can configure the endpoint.
If you come to after building the application and come after the use exception handler.
Basically we can perform the use health checks extension method and exposing the health endpoint with
slash health.
So by these two lines of code we have exposing health endpoint.
So let's try with running the https mode.
And.
Expose the health end point.
After running the application, you can open the postman.
And here you can see that I have created health endpoint for basket microservices.
This is the basket URL and this is the health end point.
If you send http get method, you can see that there is a healthy response returning for basket API
microservices.
But basket microservices relying on two backing services.
And we should also check the health status of the PostgreSQL database and Redis cache.
For that purpose, we will use different NuGet packages under this GitHub repository.
As you remember that, we can see ASP.Net core Diagnostics, health checks GitHub repository including
different health checks for different backing services.
If you scroll down and go to Readme file, you can see the backing services under the health checks.
These are the packages.
Different packages checks, different backing services for microservices.
So in our case I'm going to check for the PostgreSQL.
So in this line of code you can go to the NuGet package.
And also we need to check Redis.
Here you can see the Redis NuGet package in here.
So according to this NuGet package we can see that for the PostgreSQL we need to install these NuGet
packages.
And for the radius we need to install these NuGet packages.
So let me install one by one.
So let me copy this one and go to the our project and right click the basket API.
Manage NuGet packages.
Of course we should stop this project and right click manage NuGet packages.
And I'm going to browse ASP.Net Core Health Checks and Pgsql and install this package.
Okay.
And after that, come here and copy for the release health check library and browse for the release
and install release health check library from the ASP.Net core health checks.
If you double click the basket API, you can confirm that we have two health checks for PostgreSQL and
Redis.
Save this file and go to program.cs.
Now we are going to extend our health checks with including PostgreSQL and also Redis.
Here you can see that I have added two lines of extension method.
The first one is add an Pgsql and providing the connection string for database and add redis extension
method providing the connection string for Redis.
So please write these codes and after that you can verify the connection strings from the application
settings Json file under the connection strings.
This is the PostgreSQL database string.
And this is the Redis string that we can connect from our health checks.
So after completing our health checks including our database and cache, now it is time to add UI client
packages.
And for that purpose we can install ASP.Net Core Health Checks UI client.
So right click the basket API, manage NuGet packages.
And also I need to install UI client in order to make response more readable.
So install this package and double click API and confirm this UI package installed successfully.
Save this basket API project file and go back to Program.cs.
So under these building and configuring our Http request pipeline, we basically configure for custom
health check response.
In here I am going to modify this endpoint and the health check options.
As you can see that we have defined endpoint health slash health.
But this time we specify health check options.
And according to these options we are basically use UI response writer.
And this will be make our health endpoint response as a Json response including all entries.
So please save this file and run this basket API microservices.
And after running the application successfully you can open the postman.
And I'm going to send additional Http get requests to slash health endpoint.
And if you send get request you can see that a Json response comes and status is healthy.
This Json response indicating the health status of PostgreSQL and Redis under the entities.
If both services are operational working correctly, we should see the status as a healthy.
If any service is down, the status can be changed unhealthy with additional error details.
For example, if we stop the Redis or PostgreSQL we will see unhealthy situation.
We can simulate this case if you open the Docker desktop and select the distributed cache and stop this
container, you can see that now cache is not working.
If we send http get request for our health and meet this time, we should see status as an unhealthy
and redis should not be work in under the our entries.
As you can see that status comes unhealthy and redis comes with the exception with the timeout exception.
Let me fix this problem.
Open Docker desktop, select distributed cache and start again.
And after started we can send http get request and get the status as a healthy.
The idea is that monitoring backing services are required for ready to basket microservices.
Accepting requests and the health check endpoint provide real time monitoring of crucial services like
databases and caches.