In this video we are going to containerize basket API microservices with Docker.
If we look at our deployment strategy, you can see that we have finished the deployment one, which
is the deploying local and communicated with backing services on Docker.
And we will shifting to the deployment two.
That means we will Containerize and Docker compose all microservice and backing services together.
The first step for this operation is containerizing your microservices with docker file.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and right click the basket API.
You can come here and add Docker support.
So if you click the Docker support you can see the target operating system should be Linux.
Click the okay button.
This is asking that you have already Docker file.
Do you want to overwrite this file?
Yes.
And here you can see the newly generated docker file for Visual Studio.
Docker file contains a set of instructions to build the docker image.
So let's break down its component.
The first one is base image.
This is using.
Net eight as a base image and set the working directory slash app and exposing 8080 and 8081 for http
and Https ports.
And the second stage is build stage.
This is using dotnet SDK image for building the application and restored NuGet packages and builds the
project.
And the third image is publish.
And at this stage this will be publishes the application to the slash app slash publish directory.
You can see this directory in here.
And the last step is final stage is prepares the final image by copying the published application into
the base image, and it sets the Entrypoint in order to start the basket API application.
This is the.
Net and DLL application.
Also, you can see that how basket API integration with the building blocks the docker file.
Also handle dependencies with the building blocks project and ensuring all necessary components are
included in the build stage.