In this video we are going to orchestrating basket API microservices with Docker Compose and involving
setting up a Multi-container environment where each microservices and its dependencies, for example,
databases and cache run in a separate container, but they can communicate with each other in the network.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and open the Docker-compose.yml file.
This file defines services, network, and volume definitions that make up your application, but as
you can see that these are the backing services and these are the microservices.
We have only one microservices which is a Catholic microservices.
But this time we will put basket API microservices inside of the Docker network which using the Docker
compose.
And in here I'm going to add basket API manually.
Or we can generate from the Visual Studio.
I would like to follow with generating using the Visual Studio.
If you right click the basket API and click the add button.
And this time you can see that we have container orchestrator support.
If you click the Container Orchestrator, you can select the orchestrator as a docker compose and click
the okay button.
And operating system will be Linux and click the okay button.
You can see that basket API comes after the Catholic API, and this is indicating the image file from
the basket API project.
And in the build context, docker file is following the docker file inside of the basket API project.
So that means we have added the basket API microservices into docker compose environment.
After defining basket API in the docker-compose.yml file, it is time to define and give configurations
in the docker compose overwrite yaml file.
And as you can see that in.
Here we have configured the backing services on top of this page, and after the backing services it
is listing the microservice configurations.
This is the catalog microservice configurations, including environment variables, depends on ports
and volumes.
And in here now we will configure basket API microservices with exposing correct endpoints port numbers
and volume definitions.
So that means we need to modify these configurations according to our project port numbers and environment
variables.
So we will configure basket API like Catholic API.
And the first configuration is environment variables.
Here you can see the environment variables including connection string.
So for basket API we will also populate the environment variables.
And for the environment variables we should check the application settings of the basket API.
And here you can see that we have two connection strings that we have to override in the docker compose
overwrite Yaml file.
In order to overwrite these configurations, please open the docker compose overwriting file and locate
the environment.
So now I'm going to define two environment variables in here.
So the first one is this one which is the connection string database.
Here you can see that we use two underscore character in order to overwrite these application settings.
And as a server we can give basket db which is the container name of the backing services in Docker
network.
In Docker network we can give container names.
You can scroll up and see that basket database is container name basket db in Docker network.
That's why we can give as a server name basket db inside of the basket.
Microservices and port number is 5432, which is the default port number for PostgreSQL database.
Since we can give the basket db as a container name, we can use internal port name in docker network.
We don't need to change port number inside of the docker, because the server names are differentiated
in the docker compose network.
The first one is catalog db for catalog microservices, and the second one is basket db for basket microservices
and database name, and the rest of the connection strings are same.
And the next overriding thing is connection string and Redis.
Again, we use double underscore to overwrite application settings.
And in here instead of using localhost we use distributed cache which is the container name Docker container
name inside of the docker compose.
That's why we can give that name.
And we use the default port number of the distributed cache which is the radius.
So we have completed the environment variables.
And now after that we can configure the dependson.
Here you can see that I am going to copy from the Catholic API and comes in here.
So according to Dependson.
And make sure that you have indentation correctly as it depends on we can say that basket API microservices
depending on two backing services.
The first one is basket db and the second one is distributed cache.
And please make sure that.
You have put correct indentation and it depends on part also finished.
And the last part is port definitions.
At this stage we can check our port definitions for basket API microservices.
Here you can see the basket microservices exposing 5001 and 5051 for local environment Http and Https.
But in docker environment we will expose these services 6001 and 6061 for http and https endpoint in
Docker environment for that purpose.
If you go back to our Visual Studio, we are going to replace these port numbers according to our port
number mapping table.
And here you can see that this is the internal Docker network Http endpoint that is exposing to 6001.
And here you can see the internal Https endpoint exposing to 6061.
And we have completed the configurations for basket API.
Please save this override HTML file by using docker compose and docker compose overwrite HTML files.
We can efficiently manage and orchestrate all components for the basket API.
Microservices.