In this video we are going to test docker compose all with basket microservices and the backing services
including the PostgreSQL database and Redis for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to Docker Compose.
We are going to run Docker Compose profile, but before that we can configure Launch settings, right
click properties and go to launch.
Action is do nothing for Catholic API.
If you change the basket API and basket API should be also do nothing for launch action.
Apply and okay and right click the Docker compose set as startup project.
Now I'm going to run the compose profile from the Visual Studio in order to debug full Docker environment
basket microservices, and it is backing services.
Click this button and start docker compose on behind of the scenes.
This will be run docker compose up command and building newly added basket API container into docker
compose network.
And here you can see that our microservices and backing services listed under Docker Compose Network.
You can check the logs for newly added microservices, which is the basket API.
And here you can see the environments, labels, ports and logs, which is the incoming from the Docker
network.
Let me open the Docker desktop and you can also see basket API is listing our newly added Docker compose.
And here you can see the basket API logs.
So now we are ready for the sending Http request basket API which is integrating basket db and distributed
cache on fully docker environment.
For that purpose, please open the postman and we will start with sending Http get requests to health
endpoint to understand our health is ready or not.
Before sending Http get request to health and we should check the our basket URL.
Here you can see the basket URL is localhost 5051.
This is indicating our local environment, but this time we have deployed the basket to the Docker environment.
For that purpose.
I'm going to come here and change the environment as a docker.
And after that you can see the basket URL change 6061.
So now we can ready to send http get request.
And if you send a http get request you can see that status is healthy and entities including NPG, SQL,
PostgreSQL is healthy and Redis is also healthy.
So that means basket microservices ready to accommodate incoming Http requests with integrating PostgreSQL
and Redis.
And we will start with sending Http post requests in order to store the basket with including these
cart payload.
This is the username is boolean.
And we have added two items in this shopping cart.
So you can check the basket URL endpoint slash basket.
And we will send http post request with sending to our application.
So this is the fully Docker environment.
And Visual Studio allow us to debug inside of the Docker container.
Here you can see that this breakpoint hit under the store basket endpoint class.
And we will continue the debugging.
And this will be trigger handler class.
In the handler class we will perform repository store basket and this will be trigger our cache basket
repository store basket method.
And in this method we will perform storing basket into database.
And after that we will set string async method.
That means put this basket into the Redis distributed cache.
And now first of all store the shopping cart into PostgreSQL database using the document session object
from the Martin library and we will save change async and after that we will set setting async method.
This will be write to shopping cart into our Redis distributed cache with the key name as a username.
And after that we will return back to the client application with username.
So that means this respond 201 created and username is stolen.
This is confirmed that the database is including this shopping cart and also cache including this shopping
cart.
In order to verify this, we can open the Docker desktop and also open the distributed cache, and you
can open the interactive terminal with the exact statement of this distributed container in the Docker
desktop.
And now I'm going to write Redis CLI.
To run this Redis commands in here I'm going to run that keystore.
And as you can see that newly added shopping cart is located under distributed cache, which name is
serving as a shopping cart.
So now we can send the http get request in order to retrieve these shopping cart from the Redis distributed
cache.
And if you open the get endpoint, which is the basket URL slash basket, and serve as a shopping cart
username, and we will send http get request to this endpoint.
And this time this will be triggered get basket endpoint inside of the Docker container.
And this will be trigger our get basket query handler.
And this will be used repository dot get basket.
And it comes from the cached basket repository get basket method.
And in this method we will check the username is exist or not into the distributed cache.
If username key is existing as a cache basket, we can see the response of the cache.
This is the whole shopping cart Json.
Object.
We can basically check the if null or empty.
If not null, we will deserialize these incoming string to the shopping cart object and return back
to the method, and this method will be respond back to the client application which including all information
about the cart, username, items, and so on.
So that means we have successfully retrieved these shopping cart from the distributed cache without
calling the database into our application.
At this point, you can open the Docker desktop and go to the logs of the basket API and understand
what we are going to do and which use cases we have performing in the basket API.
First of all, we will store basket and after that we will get basket from the Redis distributed cache.
So now the last use case is delete basket by username.
If you open this delete basket Http endpoint and send the request, this will be trigger or delete basket
endpoint.
And if I hit F5 and go to the our delete basket method, this will be delete basket from the database.
And after that remove basket cache information to the Redis distributed cache.
And if we hit F5 it success response comes.
That means we have successfully removed the cache from the database and distributed cache that we can
confirm again from the distributed cache interactive terminal.
If you open the distributed cache and go to exec and run the same command, you can see that this time
as the boolean key information removed from the cache.
As you can see that we have completed the docker compose test for basket API microservices integrated
with PostgreSQL and Redis distributed cache.