In this section we are going to learn ASP.Net eight for microservices development.
So we will explore the capabilities of ASP.Net eight in building robust and scalable microservices.
It will provide to build web APIs and web UI using the ASP.Net core.
And we will see ASP.Net eight minimal APIs built in dependency Injection, create ASP.Net core web API
for single microservices.
And lastly, we will containerize and orchestrate services with Docker and Docker Compose.
So let's start with what is ASP.Net?
ASP.Net core is a cross-platform, high performance open source framework for building modern, cloud
enabled, internet connected applications.
With ASP.Net core, we can build web applications and services, Internet of things and mobile backends,
and we can also deploy to the cloud or on premises and we can run on.
Net core and net eight.
So why choose ASP.Net core?
Millions of developers use or have used ASP.Net to create web applications and building microservices.
ASP.Net core provides some of the benefits, including a unified story for building web UI and web APIs,
and architected for testability.
Razor page makes coding page focus scenarios easier and more productive.
Blazor lets you use the C sharp in the browser alongside with the JavaScript, and it provides ability
to develop and run on windows, macOS, and Linux, and it is also open source and community focused.
We can also add that integration of the modern client side frameworks and development workflows it supports
for hosting remote procedure calls, which is the gRPC, and it is also cloud ready environment based
configuration system included.
It also included built in dependency injection, and it is a lightweight, high performance and modular
Http request pipeline included, so it is ability to host on the kestrel IIs, nginx, Apache and Docker.
These two link that simplifies the modern web development and microservice development.
So now let's see the ASP.Net eight for microservice development, ASP.Net eight introduced enhanced
features that align perfectly with the cloud native microservice architecture and developments.
It supports building high performance web APIs and services, which are key components in a microservice
ecosystem.
We will also creating web APIs using ASP.Net core, leveraging its power to build both service endpoints
and user interfaces.
It offers best performance, scalability, and flexibility.
ASP.Net core is lightweight, supports cross-platform development, and provides a vast ecosystem of
libraries and tools.
It is optimized for cloud deployment and supports modern architecture patterns like SQS and event driven
design, making it ideal for building sophisticated microservices.
So ASP.Net eight is a great choice to building modern, efficient, and scalable microservices on the
cloud.