In this video we are going to learn minimal APIs in ASP.Net core.
We will use minimal APIs for every microservices into our application.
That's why it is important to learn them in here.
So what is minimal APIs?
Minimal APIs provide a simplified approach for building fast and efficient Http APIs in ASP.Net core.
They enable you to create fully functional Rest endpoints with minimal coding and configuration, reducing
the need for the traditional scaffolding and unnecessary controllers.
We can skip the traditional scaffolding and avoid the unnecessary controllers by fluent decorating API
routes and actions.
Here you can see the basic example.
Basically, we will use top level statement and in the first row we will creating a web application
and mapping the Http get request to the root path.
And it is basically simplified.
Return the hello world for every request.
So this shows the easy of setting up a basic http api endpoint with minimal APIs.
Minimal APIs also supporting dynamic routing.
You can see example code in here.
This time we will have a route parameters for using the user ID and book ID.
In this example we will also exposing Http get request.
But this route has some dynamic routing parameters which are the user ID and book ID and the API business
internal code basically respond with these IDs and basic text with including the user ID and book ID
is in here.
So in this demonstration, we can show that how easily you can handle more complex routing scenarios
using the dynamic routing feature on minimal APIs.
So throughout the course, we will leverage the minimal APIs for developing for each microservices in
our application.