In this video we are going to create ASP.Net web API for single microservices.
You can see the image on the slide.
There is a client server architecture.
So we are going to create ASP.Net web API project for a single microservices.
So here you can see the steps.
We will setting up our project and exploring the Program.cs and running the application.
So now let's start by opening Visual Studio 2022.
During the course we will use Visual Studio 2022 and come here click the create a new project.
So I'm going to create ASP.Net Core Web API project.
If you search from the templates or come here, we will follow the ASP.Net Core Web API for exposing
and creating RESTful APIs.
Click the next button.
And now we are going to give the project name.
This will be the example minimal project name.
And if you click the next button here you can see the configuration.
The configuration is started with the framework which is the dotnet eight.
During the whole course we will follow the dotnet eight framework and authentication type is none and
we have configured for Https and enable.
Docker is checked and Docker operating system is Linux and we are leaving as it is for default configuration.
But notice that there is three checkbox is not checked during the the default configuration.
So because of the minimal APIs, the default configuration is arranged by the minimal API and C-sharp
12 features, which is the top level statement if you would like to go a previous version, the style,
which is the controller and the top level statement removing.
You can check these checkbox to make it the previous versions, but in default we will follow with the
minimal API's for that purpose.
Leave as it is for the current configuration and click the create button.
So this is going to create an ASP.Net Core Web API default project.
And here you can see the default template for the ASP.Net web API.
It is including the app settings file, Docker file Program.cs, which is the top level statement for
setting up and configuring our web API.
So if you open the program says now, we will explain the codes in the program says that has generated
from the default ASP.Net web API template.
Here you can see that the Program.cs is developed with the top level statement.
So that means it is directly starting from the codes, not using statement and brackets.
In Program.cs, we basically create a web application and building the web application, and after that
we will run the web application and between them we will exposing the Http methods according to our
business logic.
And here you can see the some helper class for the weather forecast.
So now let me explain these codes one by one.
The first line of code is basically create a web application builder.
Initialize our application with the default settings and the configurations.
And after that you can see a commented part in here which is the add services to the container.
That means in here we can add ASP.Net built in services and any custom services using the dependency
injection.
And after that we are building these Web Application builder.
In this step, basically we will compile the application with all provided services and configurations.
And after that you can see another commented part which is the configure the Http request pipeline.
That means in this step, we basically define how our application handle the incoming Http requests,
and we can customize our custom Http request pipeline in this commented section.
So if you scroll down and skip this section, you can see that in this line of code in the App.run we
finally run the application.
So this command is start the application and begins the listening for incoming requests for these web
API project.
I'll explain all these steps in more detail in the next videos.
Let's continue with the Http endpoints for now.
So in this step you can see that here we are configuring the services, setting up the Http request
pipeline, and defining the Http get endpoint for the slash weather forecast exposing services.
So basically the weather forecast endpoint is a simple example of the minimal API.
It generates a weather forecast using an array of summaries and random temperatures.
You can see in here this is the summaries and the random temperatures are generated.
So basically the logic is returning the weather forecast with handling the Http get method in the slash
weather forecast http endpoint URL.
So this is the an example of the minimal API's.
And it is defined an API endpoint in ASP.Net core.
So now let's run the application.
If you come here you can see the running.
While I'm going to select the Https and click this button in order to run this web API.
So the application is started successfully, you can verify from the project console logs.
Here you can see that the application is started and listening on these http and https ports.
And this is automatically started a Chrome window in a browser.
And you can see that it is hitting the localhost and the https port.
And here you can see the slash weather forecast in order to retrieve the weather information from our
API, API is returning this Json response.
That means we have successfully creating an API with ASP.Net core Web API and getting the weather forecast
response which data generated from our API.