In this video, we are going to clear our project for the single microservices, and we will setting
up a minimal ASP.Net core web API for minimal code.
So that means we will streamline our project by removing the boilerplate code, which provided from
the ASP.Net core Web API and focusing on the essential elements.
Here you can see the items on our program.
Since we are divided by five steps and especially we will divide by two the before building the application
and after building the application.
So now let me explain these codes and these items from our program says please open the our minimal
API project and open the programs.
Yes.
So now I am going to remove the unnecessary and boilerplate code and which is regarding the weather
forecast.
So I'm going to removing these application use https direction and summaries and map get function.
Remove these line of codes and after that removing these helper class.
And here we can see the our minimal code under the program CSS that we can spin up our single microservices.
And these steps is reflected five main steps on our slide.
If you open the slide you can see that we have divided five main step in order to run this web API application.
And these steps are reflected on our program CSS.
And let's start with explaining the first step which is to create Web Application Builder.
If you open the Visual Studio and go to the first line of code, this is basically initialize the application
with default setting and configuration.
That means this line create a builder object for a web application.
So the create builder method initialize any instance of the Web application builder class and using
the provided command line arguments.
And this is where the configuration, logging and service dependencies are set up.
And the second step is adding services into container.
In here we can add the ASP.Net built in services and any custom services using the dependency injection.
So basically this command indicates that you can add services to the applications dependency injection
container services like database context Configuration services or any custom services required by our
application should be registered in here.
And the third step is building the application.
This line builder web application based on the configurations and services defined in the builder,
and it prepares the application to start accepting the Http request.
After building the application, we can go to the next step, which is the configure the Http request
pipeline.
In here we can configure the middleware for the applications Http request pipeline and middleware components
handle the requests and responses.
The common examples including the configuring, routing, authentication, authorization, and serving
the static files.
And so on.
And the last step is App.run which is to run the application.
This line basically starts the web application.
It is listening for the incoming Http requests and routes them to the appropriate endpoints or handlers
as configured in the application in the previous step.
So we can basically divide by two main step in.
Generally we use two main step.
That means we will setting up ASP.Net core web API involving the main two step.
These are the before building the application and after the building the application.
So before building the application you can see these two lines of code.
Here we use various add service method for setting up the dependency injection.
And after building the web application, we generally utilize the use function methods for configuring
the Http request lifecycles and pipelines.
So as you can see that this is the minimum boilerplate code for the ASP.Net web API project.
So in the next time we will use ASP.Net empty project, because this time we will use web API template
and have to remove some weather forecast operations in our code.
For that reason, next time we will use ASP.Net empty project that we can directly configure our microservices.
Also, these minimal setup gives us flexible base and ready to be customized for our specific microservice
requirements.
So that means during the whole course we are going to developing our microservices with using the minimal
APIs and ASP.Net core Empty project template.