In this video, we are going to create a simple Todo application using the ASP.Net core minimal APIs.
So this will be step by step process.
Here you can see the image on the slide for the todo web API.
This will be the typical web application architecture including the client server and database.
Basically, client send Http requests to the server, which will be our todo web API, and this will
be accodomate from the web API project and perform Crud operations using the in-memory database.
And here you can see the Crud endpoints that we will expose for Todo model.
These are including the get todo items, get todo items by ID, post, put and delete operations.
And finally we will use Entity Framework Core in-memory database to perform these Crud operations and
accodomate these Http requests.
So now let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio 2022 and create new project.
This time we will use ASP.Net Core Empty Project template as you remember that in the last video, we
have used ASP.Net Core Web API project template that including some of the boilerplate code about the
weather forecast, and we have to remove that code.
In order to avoid this kind of remove operation, we can use ASP.Net Core Empty project template that
you can search for the empty and go to the ASP.Net Core Empty Project template and click the next button.
And we will give the name as a todo API for our application and click the next button.
And here you can see the configuration we are leaving as it is for the default configuration for using
the minimal APIs and click the create button.
This will create ASP.Net empty project template.
If you zoom into the this solution window, you can see that there is very clear and only Program.cs.
Docker file and app settings are listed on our todo API project.
So if you expand the program says and you can see that this is very limited code and arranged by the
empty project template, that we can very fast removing the unnecessary code and locating for our microservice
requirements.
If you look at the Program.cs for the empty project template, this is typical.
Start with creating a web application builder and a web application with preconfigured default configurations.
And after that you can see in here it is creates an Http get endpoint and that returns hello world message.
So this is typical empty project that we can arrange for microservices.
Basically we will have a one command in here.
Add dependency injection.
In here we can put the add methods into dependency injection for example.
Mostly we will use add service method names when we are registering our services into ASP.Net within
dependency injection.
So as the same way, after building the web application, we are going to configure ASP.Net request
pipeline.
So in here we can configure pipeline and we can regularly and mainly use methods.
For example use method and use authentication use authorization and so on.
So this is typical best practice when registering to die.
We are using the add methods.
And then configuring the request pipeline.
We can use the use methods in order to configure our request lifecycle.
So now I am going to remove these app dot map get method.
And here you can see the our main boilerplate code we have already seen in the previous video.
So now I'm going to continue the our project which is the todo API that we are going to expose these
Crud endpoints.
But before that we need a model which is the Todo model in order to retrieve and perform these Crud
operation.
So if you go back to our project, I'm going to create a new class under the Our today API.
Right click the to the API and add new item.
We are going to add todo item dot cs and click the add button.
So this will be our model class.
And in this model class we will have properties which is the id name and boolean is completed.
So here you can see the our property members under the todo item.
So this will be our model class for todo web API project.
So after that we can configure the Entity Framework core in-memory database.
For that purpose I'm going to right click the todo API project template and manage NuGet packages and
open the NuGet package window and if you click the browse and we are going to basically adding new package
into our application, which name is Microsoft Entity Framework core Dot in-memory.
So this will be in-memory database for our Todo web API project.
Please click this button and install the in-memory NuGet package and click the I accept button.
And you can verify from this icon.
Or if you double click the project file, you can verify the packages from in the item group that included
the package reference for Microsoft Entity Framework Core In-memory.
So now we can save this project file and continue to our implementation.
So in order to using these Entity Framework package we need a Dbcontext class.
So for that purpose I'm going to create a new class under our project window.
If you right click Add New Item in here I'm going to add a todo Dbcs file.
This will be the data context object.
So that's why I'm going to inherit from the DB context.
This come from the R Entity Framework core.
And now we will implement these Dbcontext into the todo db class.
In this class we should create constructor that.
Accepting the db context option in order to make it Entity framework core db context.
Here you can see that we have created a constructor and accepting the DB context options and referencing
the base class, which is the DB context.
And after that we can define our DB set classes which including the todo item that representing our
model class.
So here you can see that we are adding the db set property under the todo db context object.
And if you save this class now we are ready to interact entity framework, core, NuGet package and
in-memory databases.
But of course before that we have to register dependency injection if you open the program.
Says.
Here you can see the R program says we are going to adding service registry into this command section.
We can register Dbcontext object in this place by writing the builder services dot add Dbcontext method
and passing the r to the db db context object.
And in here we are basically configuring use in-memory database and giving the database name as a to
do list.
So these provide the dependency injection container, access to database context and other services.
And we can use these in-memory database by registering Dbcontext which is the to do db.
And after that we basically add the Crud endpoints that we seen in the slide.
Here you can see that we will exposing these get post put and delete Crud operations into our Program.cs.
And we can configure these kind of requests.
Pipeline operations in the after building the web application in the this command section.
So now I am going to copy paste one by one.
By the way only for this video I am copy paste the codes.
Because of reaching the microservice development.
When we are developing our microservices, we will be develop and write step by step together.
But for this video, let me copy paste these operations and after that we will see how it is affecting
our to the application.
So here you can see that I'm going to copy paste for the map, get post put and delete operation to
perform Crud application and Crud operation into our to do web API project.
So basically you can see in this code in here we are retrieving all Todo items from the database with
using the map get method.
And inside of this method we are defining the endpoint definition with slash todo items.
And in here we are retrieving all todo items using the todo db data context object, which provided
by the Entity Framework core as the same way we are fetching a single todo item based on the id, and
also we are going to post a new item, which means create a new todo item in the database and we have
put method.
We basically update an existing todo item based on the id.
And lastly we have map delete operation.
Delete a todo item based on its id.
So each of these operation is defined using the application dot map method.
And after that we are http verb which means map, get, post, put and delete and these verb operation
corresponding to Http methods.
The methods are mapped to specific endpoints and include the logic and interact with the database using
the Entity Framework core inside of these code blocks.
So basically we have completed development of this picture and exposing the Crud operations for Todo
web API.