In this video, we are going to test our Todo web API project with incoming Http requests for accommodating
Crud endpoints.
So let's get started.
For that purpose, open our Visual Studio for todo API project.
And now I'm going to run this project with changing to run profile as a Https and click the run button.
So this will start our application.
We can confirm from the project window we can see that it is exposing and listening to these port numbers.
And you can see in here there is no response coming from the r localhost and port number because we
are exposing all the services with the endpoint name, you can come to our endpoints and see that we
should add slash todo items.
If you go back to our browser and hit the enter with adding the todo items, you can see that we don't
have any todo item into our application yet.
How we can add new todo item according to our architecture.
You can see that we have already exposed post http api that we can create new item into our to do list.
For that purpose, I'm going to use postman to sending the post request to our todo web API project.
Please open the postman and create a new Http request.
And now we can verify from the Get request.
If you copy from the URL into the browser and paste into your postman and send the http get request,
you can see that we don't have any todo item.
I'm going to create new http post request.
This time I'm going to change the Http method as a post and paste to do our http url localhost and the
port number, and adding the todo items.
So that means we are arranging our http post endpoint according to our development of this app dot map
post method.
So after that we are going to provide some Json input.
You can see that it is expecting todo item model.
So we should provide todo item model with the properties of the name and is complete.
So if you can go to the todo item you can see the todo item properties in here.
If you go back now, we will send http post request.
Open the postman and this time we can set the body parameters as a row and Json and paste in here.
Basically I'm going to adding the name and is complete attributes into Json format.
And now I'm going to send the http post request and it is created successfully.
We understood that the id is newly generated item into our in-memory database.
We can verify from the http get method, sending the get all todo items and see our one todo item into
the in-memory database.
We can also create new todo item into our list.
I'm going to change the name and send additional http post request and see there is new ID created,
and if you go back to get all todo items and send request, we can see two todo items into our list.
In order to get by id method, we can add slash and give the id in here.
When the query parameters.
If I send this get method, this will be get only specific todo item with providing the ID information
into the query list.
So now we can create the update method for that purpose.
I'm going to duplicate this get method with the right click and duplicate the top.
So the end point should be the same, but Http method should be the put.
And I'm going to create a body and raw json file.
So we will get this Json from the response of the get method and put in here.
So basically I'm going to name of the todo item is changed.
And after that I'm going to send the http put request and see that the response is not coming.
And the status is 204.
That means it is successfully updated.
We can confirm from in the Get method.
If you remove the this query parameter and get all Todo items, you can see the first item is updated
so now the only thing left is http get method.
Again, I am going to duplicate this http get method, and now I am going to remove the second item
and change the Http method as a delete and send this http delete method, and the status is 204.
That means successfully deleted.
If you go back to our Get method, we can successfully see that only one item left on our to do list.
So as you can see that we have created and implemented Todo web API project.
That means we will create minimal API using the ASP.Net core for a single microservices.