In this video, we are going to learn how containerize and orchestrate microservices using the Docker
and Docker compose.
Let's start with what is Docker?
Docker is an open source platform for developing, shipping and running the applications.
We can separate your application from your infrastructure so you can deliver software quickly.
The advantage of Docker for shipping, testing and deploying code quickly.
It is significantly reduced the delay between writing code and running it on production.
Automating the deployment of applications as portable, self-sufficient containers that can run on the
cloud or on premises.
Docker containers can run anywhere in your local computer to the cloud systems.
Docker image containers can run natively on Linux and Windows machines.
Docker is de facto standard for containerization of microservices.
So what are the Docker components and how it can use the Docker components are Docker containers, images
and registries.
Developers, developers and packages application with its dependencies into a container image that is
a static representation of the application with its configuration and dependencies.
In order to run the application, the application's image is instantiated to create a container which
will be running on the Docker host.
We should always store the images into Docker registries, so that means we should store the image in
registry, which is a library of images, and it is needed when deploying application to the production
orchestrators.
Docker image stores a public registry like Docker Hub or Azure Container Registry.
Developer create container in local and push the image to the Docker registry.
Developer download existing image from the registry and create container from the image in local environment.
So here you can see the application containerization with Docker and orchestration with Docker compose.
The first step is we should always write docker file for our application.
It is a configuration file is representing a Docker configurations.
And the second step is build the application with this docker file and create the Docker image.
And after that, we can run this image on any machine and create running container, which is the Docker
containers from the Docker image.
So lastly, we can orchestrate the whole microservice application with using Docker and Kubernetes.
This kind of orchestration, the idea is that the orchestrating the container environment and container
images.
Here you can see the steps on the slide.
The first step is creating a Docker file which including configuration about the application.
And after that we can build the application and create the Docker image from the Docker files.
And after that, we can run this image on any machine and create running Docker containers from the
Docker image.
So this is the containerization step.
And after that we can orchestration step using the Docker compose.
Docker compose is a tool for defining and running multi-container Docker applications.
With using Docker Compose, we can use a YAML file in order to configure our application services for
multi-container environments.
After that, with a single docker command which is the docker compose up command, we can create and
start all the microservices from our configurations.