In this section we are going to develop basket microservices with vertical slice architecture and the
securities design pattern.
Let's check our big picture and see what we are going to build one by one.
As you can see that we are in here and start to developing basket API with PostgreSQL database and Redis
cache.
So that means basket microservices has two backing services, one for the PostgreSQL database and one
for the Redis distributed cache.
And here you can see the internal basket microservice architecture.
This is following the similar architecture style with the catalog microservices and using the similar
NuGet packages.
But in the upcoming sections, basket microservices will use Redis as a distributed cache, gRPC communication
and RabbitMQ asynchronous communication and using different NuGet packages when the upcoming sections.
But for this section, we will focus on implementing vertical slice architecture as similar with the
catalog microservices.
So we can say that in this section we will perform ASP.Net core minimal APIs for building fast Http
APIs, fully functioning Rest endpoints, and top level program statements.
And after that we will implement vertical slice architecture with feature folders and single C-sharp
file, including different classes in one file.
And we will implement synchronous design pattern using the mediator library.
And we will also implement Martin Library for dotnet transactional DocumentDB when communicating with
the PostgreSQL database.
And also this time we will implement repository pattern over the Martin and Redis cache, because we
will use AI repository and shifting the communication between database or Redis cache.
And we will also implement Carter for minimal API endpoint definition.
We will implement fluent validation to validate input and outputs one mediator pipeline behaviors.
And lastly we will follow the Docker file and docker compose file for running basket microservices and
PostgreSQL database in the environment.