In this video we are going to create ASP.Net web API for basket API.
Microservices.
This microservices is crucial for managing shopping cart operations in our application.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the services folder.
So as you can see that we have already created Catalog Microservices under the catalog folder.
For that purpose, we will start by organizing our solution.
Under the services we will create a subfolder which name is basket and we will include basket API project
under this folder.
So please right click the services and add new subfolder which name is basket.
And under the basket we will create a new ASP.Net web API project which name is basket API.
But we should put correct location in this web API project.
And this project will be dotnet eight and include both Http and https support.
So for that purpose please right click the basket and add new project.
So we will follow the ASP.Net Core Empty Project template.
If you click the next button we can configure our ASP.Net web API project.
The project name should be basket dot API.
And the important thing is we should give the correct location for our API project.
For that purpose, you can click this browse button and go to the our main repository which is the microservices,
and go to source folder.
Under the source folder we have services folder including our microservices.
Here you can see that we have only catalog microservices yet.
But now I'm going to select this folder.
And after that I'm going to create a basket folder with monolith.
With writing in here you can see that this will be create a new basket folder under the services.
And my API project will be located in this path.
So let me zoom into this configurations.
And you can see that project name is basket API and location is following the microservices source services
and basket will be created newly folder.
And this will be the our main location for basket API web API project.
So after configure this project we can click the next button and we will leave as it is for these configurations.
These are the dotnet eight framework.
And we can configure for Https enabled for Docker.
And this Docker operating system will be Linux.
And we will follow the top level using statement.
That's why this checkbox is not checked.
And please click the create button.
And this will be Create Basket API microservices under our Services Basket folder.
Here you can see the our basket microservices.
The first thing we should do that go to the program stage.
And we will refactor Program.cs according to our requirements.
So as you remember that we are separating by two before building the application and after building
the application.
So before building the application we will add services to the built in dependency injection container.
That's why I'm putting a command in here.
And after building the web application I'm going to remove these Mapkit operation.
And we basically configure the Http request pipeline before running the application and after building
the application so you can save these programs.
Yes, we will follow this structure when configuring our basket API microservices.
As you can see that we have finished the initial setup of our basket API microservices.