In this video we are going to configure port numbers for basket API microservices.
Here you can see the R port mapping strategy for different microservices in our architecture.
As you can see that we have completed the catalog microservices.
And now we are developing basket microservices.
And in local environment basket microservices will expose Http port in 5001 and Https for 50 over 51.
So we are going to follow these steps and configure our launch settings.
If you open the URL Visual Studio, you can see that we will configure our port numbers in the launch
settings Json file.
Launch settings Json file in our project is crucial for defining how our application runs during the
development, and we will set the Http and Https ports according to our architecture plan.
So let's modify the launch settings in order to set the port numbers correctly.
So if you open the line settings Json, you can see different running profiles.
I'm going to change for the Https 5001.
And if you go to the Https running profile, you can see that we have http URL should be 5001.
And we will change the https port number as a 5051.
Okay, we have configured our basket API according to port mapping strategy.
Now we can run the application.
Please set a startup project for basket API.
Come here.
Right click set a startup project.
After setting a startup project you can see that our running profiles comes in here.
So this profiles is matching our launch setting Json.
And this time I'm going to select Https running profile and click this button.
In order to run this application.
This will be exposed our basket API to the 5051 port.
And we have configured from the this URL and also in the project console.
Here you can see that our application is listening these https port and these Http port.
So we have configured our port numbers according to local environment for basket API microservices.
And if you look at the our deployment strategy we can start with the deployment one which is the developing
our basket API microservices in our local environment that connect to backing services from Docker environment.
And after that we will go to the deployment tool.
But for now let's focus on developing basket API microservices.