In this video we are going to do technical analysis of basket microservices.
This technical analysis includes application architecture analysis.
And we will see patterns and principles.
And we will learn libraries and NuGet packages that we are going to use.
And lastly we will see project folder structure of our current basket microservices.
And we always say that each microservices can be follow different application architecture styles for
internal architectures.
If you look at the application architecture style for basket microservices, we can see that we will
follow vertical slice architecture that organize our code into feature folders.
And each feature folder is encapsulated in a single C sharp file.
So we will follow the same architecture style with Catholic microservices.
But in the upcoming microservices we will follow different application architecture styles.
If you look at the pattern and principles that we are going to follow in basket microservices, we will
implement different patterns like circles, mediator and principles like dependency injection, minimal
APIs and so on.
These are the same as the Catholic API microservices.
But additionally we will learn and implement repository pattern.
So repository pattern is a domain driven design pattern intended to keep persistence concerns outside
of the systems domain model.
It provides an abstraction of data.
That application can work with a simple abstraction interfaces.
So we will use this pattern that achieved the loosely coupling and we can keep domain objects persistence
ignorant.
Also, we can follow other patterns including the securities pattern, mediator pattern, dependency
injection in ASP.Net core, and minimal APIs and routing patterns that we have already learned in the
catalog.
Microservices.
If you look at the libraries and NuGet packages of basket microservices, we can say that we will use
mediator for securities, Carter for API endpoints, Martin for interacting with the PostgreSQL as a
document database, Napster for object mapping, and fluent validation for input validation.
Most of these packages will already comes from the building Blocks class library.
That basket will getting reference building blocks into the basket API project in order to implement
common operations into basket microservices, similar to catalog microservices.
After developing the this section, we will continue to develop basket microservices with new pattern
and principles and libraries that you can see that we will use security library to implement decorator
pattern gRPC for inter service communication, Redis for developing distributed case and Masstransit
library for RabbitMQ operations.
So now let's see the project folder structure of the basket microservices.
You can see the folder structure in here we will follow the these vertical slice architecture.
And this project is organized into model features data and abstractions.
Folder feature folders like Get Basket and Store Basket have dedicated handler and endpoint definitions.
Feature folder will be basket in our case.
And we will have also data folder and repository objects.
Manage the database and cache interaction in the repository objects.
So you can see that we have a feature folder which name is basket.
And under this feature folder we have use cases including get basket, delete basket checkout basket
and store basket.
And also we have a data folder in order to implement the repository pattern and to connect with the
Martin PostgreSQL database and also Redis cache.
That's why we have implemented the repository pattern to connect to different resources.
So lastly we will implement deployment of the basket microservices.
We will containerize our services with Docker ensuring seamless deployment and integration with PostgreSQL
and Redis cache.
And after that we will implement docker file and docker compose file for running the basket microservices
on PostgreSQL database and Redis cache in the environment.