In this video we are going to create our domain models.
So that means we will create shopping cart, shopping cart item and basket checkout under the basket.
Microservices.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the basket API project.
Our first step is Create Models folder.
So if you right click and add new folder, which name is models.
This will be store our domain entities so we can create by entities one by one.
I'm going to start with shopping cart item domain entity.
Let's add a new class under the models which name is shopping cart item.
So this will be represent each item in the shopping cart.
So the shopping cart item can be different properties which including quantity, color, price, product
ID and product name.
Please develop these properties under the shopping cart item domain entity.
The shopping Cart item class encapsulate the details of each item in the shopping cart, including the
quantity, color, price, and product information.
After that, we will define the shopping cart domain entity.
So I'm going to create a new entity under the models which name is Shopping Cart.
And this will be include a collection of the shopping cart item object.
For that purpose I'm going to develop members in here.
So we will start with the username.
And after that we can develop list shopping cart item items property which represent one to end relationships.
And after that we will calculate the total price with iterating our shopping cart item and multiplying
price and quantity information.
And we have one constructor including the username, and we have also one empty constructor.
This is required for mapping.
Shopping cart class will be aggregate throughout our domain analyzing and these will be indexed by the
username.
And this will be unique identifier.
So that means these two classes shopping cart and shopping cart item will be our document table on document
database with using Martin.
And the username will be our primary key object into the document table.
And this will be managed by the NoSQL database which will be the Martin and PostgreSQL.
And the whole shopping cart and shopping cart item data will be stored Martin document database and
also distributed cache with Redis.
So we will store shopping cart and shopping cart item in a Json format.
And these entities stored both PostgreSQL database and also Redis distributed cache.