In this video, we are going to setting up our feature folder structure using the vertical slice architecture
combined with the access and mediator patterns.
Let's start with the folder and class structure.
Here you can see the our folder structure in here.
And our main feature folder name is basket.
And under the basket we will create a sub folders representing our use cases including get basket,
delete basket and store basket.
And for each folder we will create two classes, one for the endpoints and one for the handle class.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio.
Right click the catalog API, add new folder.
Which name is basket?
This will be the our main feature folder.
And under this folder I'm going to create sub folders representing our use cases.
The first one is Get basket and the second one is right click Add new sub folder store basket.
And another one is right click add subfolder.
Which name is delete basket.
Now I'm going to add new classes under these each folder.
And for example if you go to the get basket I'm going to create two new classes.
This means the first class is get basket and points representing our API definitions.
And the second one is get basket handle class.
This will be representing our actual business logics.
So why we are creating two classes inside of the each feature folder.
Even we are following the vertical slice architecture.
Because separating the handler and endpoint clusters makes our code more readable and easier to maintain.
And also these structure align well with the principle of the clean architecture.
We can mapping the handle class to the application layer and mapping the endpoint class to the presentation
layer in clean architecture.
So now we will follow the same steps for other Crud operations.
Let me continue with the store basket.
I am going to add store basket endpoints.
And after that I'm going to add new class which name is store basket handler.
So the last folder is delete basket.
If you go to delete basket add new class which name is delete basket endpoints.
After that we will create delete basket handler.
Okay, let me zoom into and see that we have created basket feature folder.
And under basket we have use case folders.
And each sub folder has two classes.
Please make sure that you have created this kind of folder structure into your computer.
So now we can start to development of our feature sub folders.
And we will start with the Get Basket feature.
And every time when we are implementing any use case we will start with developing handle classes.
So our first step is to develop handle class in the application layer.
So these handles will encapsulate the business logic for our microservice use cases.