In this video we are going to develop Get Basket feature handler class with using SQS and mediator patterns
in basket microservices.
And we will start with creating our query and result record objects into the Get Basket feature class.
For that purpose, please open Visual Studio and go to the Get Basket Handler class under the Get Basket
folder.
So now I am going to write Public Record and defining Get Basket Query object.
And this time we will get string username as a parameter.
And this will be implements I query interface.
After that we can define our result object public record and get basket result as a parameter of including
the whole shopping cart object.
These records represent our query and it is expected result to get basket query.
Include the username as a parameter and get basket result will return the user's shopping cart object.
That's why it is a property of get basket result.
So as you can see that we need I query object in here.
So if you come here and try to implement this interface there is no package comes in here.
So that is not included.
Our basket API microservices yet how we can include these query object.
Basically we will implement SQS and mediator pattern using the mediator library.
So we should install mediator library into the basket API microservices.
But instead of that in the last section when we are developing our catalog microservices, we have developed
the Building Blocks class library that includes all common classes for our application layer.
So if you double click the class library, you can see that these are the common NuGet packages that
we can use for each microservices.
For that purpose, instead of the manually installing all these packages into basket API microservices,
we should only add project reference building blocks to the basket API microservices in order to get
all securities and mediator related capabilities.
So now I am going to right click the basket API and click the add button.
And we are going to add Project reference.
In here, I'm going to add a building blocks as a project reference and click the okay button.
If you double click the basket API, you can see that our project reference comes into the R project
file.
So that means we can use building blocks for introducing securities and mediator related packages into
our basket microservices for that purpose.
If you go to the get basket handler this time, if I try to implement this query, you can see that
I'm going to add using statement for boolean blocks and six.
After implementing securities and mediator packages, we can ready for the developing actual Get Basket
100 class.
The first thing I'm going to change the name of the this class, which is the get basket query handler
to specify query or command handler.
And after that we are implement I query handler interface and we will paste the query and result object
in here.
So we are query object get basket query and result object is get basket result.
If I implement this interface into class it is generated handle method.
And in this handle method, as you can see that it is getting the first parameter.
Get basket query and change the name of the first parameter name and the second parameter is Cancellationtoken.
So now I'm going to make this method as an async.
And after that we will start the implementation.
So what is the main logic of this handle class.
This will be get basket from the database.
Since we don't have any database related injection in here I'm going to I'm going to put a command documentation
in here which is the to do statement.
So that means we will get basket from database and we will use repository object that we didn't develop
yet.
So that's why I'm going to this to do statement.
And we will come back here and implement actual logic later when we are developing the repository classes.
But now I'm going to return naive get basket result object with mocked information, which means that
I'm going to create manually new shopping cart and give the username as a swan.
So we have completed the handle method.
So if you look at the R class you can see that we have using statements.
One of the best practice is creating a global using class.
For that purpose I'm going to create a new class which name is global using under the basket API, and
moving all these using statements in this class.
For that purpose, I'm going to copy, paste and put the global keyword in the beginning of this using
statement and save this file.
If you go back to our actual class, you can see that.
Now we can remove these using statement.
And this is more clear now.
So after developing the handler class we will focus on the endpoint class.