In this video we are going to develop gate basket endpoint with minimal APIs.
And Carter, we will start with developing request and response record type.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the Get Basket endpoint.
And now I am going to create Request and Response object.
As a request.
We will get username from the request parameter.
For that purpose I am putting in here commented request object to follow the best practices.
And after that I am going to create a get basket response object as a record type public record get
basket response, and as a response we will expect the whole shopping cart object.
After that, we can define the get basket endpoints.
In order to implement minimal API we will implement these I Carter module interface and I Carter module
should be comes from the Carter.
But we didn't install Carter yet.
So as you remember that when we are developing our catalog microservices, we realized that in the catalog
Program.cs the Carter only scanning the operation and I Carter module interfaces for the current assembly.
And we cannot give the assembly like mediator for that purpose.
We have to install Carter for each microservices where we are implementing minimal APIs.
And I am going to go to the basket API and right click manage NuGet packages and search for the Carter
and install Carter for basket microservices into the web API project.
And if you double click, you can see that we have installed Carter successfully.
And save this file.
Go to the Get basket endpoint.
And this time you can see that we can implement Carter module with using Carter statement.
And also I'm going to move this using statement into the global using class.
If you come here and put the global keyword in the using statement of the Carter.
And if you go back to get basket endpoint, you can see that our Carter module now is available.
And I'm going to implement the interface members which is the add routes method.
At this point we can check the basket microservice RESTful APIs.
You can see that we are going to expose http get method with this endpoint URL and we will get basket
with username.
So please open the Visual Studio.
And now I am going to implement this add route method with add dot map get method to expose http get
operation.
And we will specify the endpoint URL which is the basket slash username.
And after that we will perform delegate handle operation.
And in this delegate handler I am going to take the username from the request parameters.
And after that I am going to inject Isander object which is our mediator.
So in delegate handler method the first parameter is populated from the request parameters.
And the second parameter will be injected by the ASP.Net built in dependency injection.
So I'm going to click the Isander and using mediator.
And also I am going to move this mediator to the global namespace.
If you go to the global using and put in here, you can copy and paste global.
And if you go back to our Get Basket endpoint classes, you can see that Lysander comes in here.
And now we will implement to accommodating incoming HTTP requests.
In here the first line we will get the result object with async await sender that send object.
That means mediator will send a new get basket query object.
And inside of this get basket query, we will passing the username and expecting the result object from
the mediator that will be handled the query handle method and respond back to the result object.
And after that we can convert this result object as a response.
For that purpose I am going to use result dot adopt method and passing the get basket response object.
So how we can run this adopt method?
We didn't install master in the basket API because master has installed in the building blocks, and
since we are getting reference from the building blocks, we can access the Master and Mediator library
from the building blocks.
So if you go back to the get basket endpoint, we can return back to the client application, this response
object.
For that purpose I'm going to write return results dot okay response and passing the response object.
We can also configure these HTTP get endpoint with using the width methods.
These are the extension method that we can configure our HTTP get method.
If you go on top of this class, you can see that we can move these master to the our global using statement.
By this way, the other operations will not be using statement into their operation.
So if you go back to get basket endpoints here you can see that we define get basket endpoint class
that implements the I Carter module.
And our Get request takes the username as a route parameter and returns to the user basket, which means
that shopping cart object from running the query handler class.