In this video, we are going to develop store, basket and print with using minimal API's and Carter
for exposing HTTP post operation to perform store basket use cases.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the store basket and open the store basket endpoint.
So as always, we should start with defining Request and response object as a request.
We will have store basket request record type.
And this will be getting shopping cart information at the same way with the handler class.
Here you can see the command object getting the shopping cart as a parameter.
After that we can define our response object, which is also following the same record type from the
command class.
And here you can see that store basket response.
And this will be getting username as a parameter.
Same as the handler class which is the store basket result and string username.
Make sure that these parameter names are also same.
In order to mapping easily using the master, and these are the request and response object.
So now we can define our http post request into store basket endpoint.
So how we can do that.
Of course we should inherit from the I Carter module and implement this I Carter module interfaces.
And inside of the add route method we will expose http post request with running the app dot map post
method.
Here you can see the method definition in here.
And after that we will define actual delegate handler class.
So basically we will expose post operation in this endpoint.
And we will expecting store basket request object to incoming JSON body operation in the request parameter.
And also we have inject the Isander which is a mediator.
So the first line of code in the delegate handler we basically adapting the incoming request to our
command object.
And after that we can send this command object to the mediator.
For that purpose we can use await dot Sandsend method and passing the command object.
This will be run the command handler method and return back to us result.
And after that we can again adopting this result object to our response object.
And the last line of code we will basically return to the client.
As a result, state created response, which is returning 201 HTTP status code, returning the created
response.
After that, we can configure as usual configurations including name, produce, summary and description.
So this is the Our Store basket endpoint class for defining HTTP post endpoint in order to store shopping
cart.