In this video, we are going to develop the rate Basket feature hundred class with using circles and
mediator.
So we are at this point and implement delete basket with username.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the delete basket.
Use case folder and go to the Delete basket handle class.
As always, we will start with the defining command and result object.
Here you can see the delete basket command object.
Taking the username as a parameter and implement I command interface which is the including delete basket
result generics.
And here you can see the result object, including the Issuccess boolean flag in the parameters of the
result.
And after that we will define our command validators for the delete operation.
For that purpose, I am going to define a new class which name is delete basket command validator and
implement abstract class, which is the abstract validator with validating delete basket command.
In the constructor of this class, we basically define only one rule, which is the username is required,
and this validation will be run by the validation pipeline behavior.
And after that we will develop handler class which include our business logic.
The first thing we should do that renaming the class name as a delete basket command handler.
And after that we will implement this interface from the I command under interface and implement the
members.
So after that I'm going to change the first parameter name as a command and make this handle function
as an async.
And in here we will perform actual business logic.
What is the business logic for delete basket command under.
So we will basically delete the basket from database and cache for that purpose.
I'm going to put a commented todo statement in here that we will perform this operation after this section
when injecting related database and cache operations into our command handler.
But for now, I am going to see keeping actual implementation and mocking the return operation which
is returning to delete basket result.
And I am passing the true as a success.
And that's all.
So if you go on top of this page, we don't have any using statement.
So basically we will define command and result object including the username and issuccess parameters.
And after that we will define command validator class with one rule which is the username is required.
And in the command handler class we perform actual logic.
But for now we will put commands and return mocking response, and we will revisit this handler with
interacting with our database and cache operations to delete this basket.