In this video we are going to develop delete basket endpoint with using minimal API and Carter.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to Delete basket.
Use case folder and open the delete basket and print.
The first thing we should do that define request and response object.
So as a request object I put command to delete basket request because we will get username from the
request parameters and as a response object we will develop the delete basket response object, including
the Issuccess same as the r handler class delete basket command operation.
After that, we can expose http delete operation into our delete basket endpoint with inheriting from
the I Carter module, which comes from the Carter library and implement the members and this will be
create add routes method that we can expose HTTP delete operations inside of this method.
So basically I'm going to exposing delete operation using the app dot map delete method.
And these are the endpoint of our delete operation.
This username specifying in the request parameters.
That's why we will get the username in the asynchronous delegate handler.
And injecting the I sender.
The first line of code.
We basically sending the mediator send operation.
And we will passing the command object with incoming username.
And this will be run the our delete basket command handler and return back the result.
And we will convert the result object to the response with using the master and the last line of code,
we basically return to the client okay.
Response.
And these are the configurations of the HTTP delete operation.
Please develop these codes into your computer.
And we don't have any using statement.
And this is the our delete basket endpoint definition.