In this video, we are going to register Mediator and Carter libraries into ASP.Net core Dependency
Injection and Request Pipeline tool.
So as you remember that we have implemented these use cases.
And in every use cases, if you open the endpoint classes, you can see that we basically injecting
is handler object which is the mediator.
And we also using the I Carter module which is comes from the Carter.
And we also using the adapt method which comes from the mapper.
And we didn't configure these libraries into Program.cs.
And without configuring and adding these packages into ASP.Net within dependency injection these use
cases cannot be run for that purpose.
Please open the program case.
Remember that our program case is divided by two, which is before building the application and after
building the application.
So in the before building application we will add services into dependency injection container.
And I'm going to start with registering Carter Library Carter simplifies the creation of our minimal
API endpoints.
So for that purpose I'm going to run builder services add Carter.
By this way we can add Carter related classes into our container.
And after that we should go to the configure Http request pipeline step.
And I'm going to use app dot Map Carter method.
And this will be mapped Carter endpoints into our ASP.Net web API project.
So we have successfully inject Carter related classes with using these two line of code.
By this way Carter will be second eye Carter modal interface implementation and expose minimal APIs.
For example, if you open the delete basket endpoint, Carter will be scanning this interface for the
current assembly and this will be exposing map operation, including Http, delete, get and post operations.
So now it is time to register our next library, which is the mediator.
So we will integrate mediator for implementing access pattern and redirecting to our command and queries
into handler class.
So for that purpose I'm going to add a mediator into built in dependency injection.
So we can use again builder services add mediator.
And in here we can configure our mediator injection with specifying additional details.
So for example I'm going to write config dot register services from assembly.
And I'm going to paste this assembly as you remember that we can get the assembly from the type of program
case.
And this will be get current assembly.
I'm going to copy this assembly variable and paste in here.
By this way we can register our mediator into current assembly.
For that purpose we can use Mediator library from the Building Blocks class library.
And after that I'm going to add open behavior into configuration of the mediator add open behavior method.
Provide to adding validation behavior into our request pipeline into the mediator.
So we can also add additional open behavior which is the logging behavior.
So by this configuration we have completed the mediator configurations.
So the first line of code we will activate mediator in the current assembly.
And these two lines of code we will add open behaviors and validation and logging behavior in the mediator
request lifecycle.
If you go on top of these programs you can see that we have using statement.
I'm going to move these using statement into global Usings.
If you go back to our program says, you can see that our configurations is done.
We have registered these mediator and Carter services, and our micro services is ready to handle incoming
requests efficiently.