In this video we are going to test our basket APIs, get post and delete requests using the postman,
and debug our application because we will follow and understand the secrets and mediator request lifecycle,
we will send Http request from the client and we will perform that.
The request comes from the mediator and mediator trigger.
The handler and handle will be perform actual operation and return response.
So we will validate this flow into our application.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio Set startup project of basket API and run https mode.
After running the application, we are going to place debug points into our endpoint and handler class.
Our application is running successfully, so now I am going to open the get basket endpoint and put
a breakpoint inside of the delegate handler and go to handler class.
Put a breakpoint in the beginning of the handler method and following the same steps for different Http
delete operations, and after that http post operation, which is the store basket use cases.
Okay, our breakpoints are ready and we have already run our application and our basket API.
Microservices is listening on https localhost 5051 port.
So if you open the postman you can see that we have separate folder for basket microservices.
And I have created http, get post and delete endpoints inside of this folder.
So if you open the get basket by username you can see that basket URL variable comes from the localhost
environment and the value is 5051.
We can change the environment in here.
And now we are on the localhost deployment strategy.
So you can see the endpoint continue with the basket.
And we can specify the username as a request parameters.
So now if I click the Http send method this will be triggered our application and comes from the get
basket endpoint.
And if we continue with the step over we will send mediator to the get basket query information with
incoming username.
And this will be triggered our Get Basket query handler class.
And this is the handle operation which is the actual business operation.
For now we will mocking these operation and returning an empty shopping cart with the username as a
boolean.
Here you can see that if we hit F5, this will be returning to us.
A random and empty cart object.
The username is S1 and there is no items for this cart.
So we have confirmed that the http get operation is successfully triggered the Carter endpoint and successfully
triggered the mediator handler class.
And at the same way, we can send http post requests in order to store new basket into our database.
So here you can see that I have created http post operation and our endpoint is basket URL.
This is the 5051 port and slash basket.
And this is the http post operation.
That's why you can see that body row of Json format is in here.
This is starting and empty Json body.
And here you can see the cart object.
The cart name is very critical in here if you open the Visual Studio, if you go to the store basket
and print, you can see that our store basket request includes the parameter of the shopping cart and
the shopping cart variable name as a cart.
So that's why we should give the exact same name of this parameter name into our postman.
And that's why this is the cart.
And opening a new object inside of the new object, you can see the members of the shopping cart, and
this is the items that we have added two items into our shopping cart.
So let's send http post request and see the request pipeline life cycle.
So send button and this will be triggered store basket endpoint.
And the first step is we are converting to command object and inside of the command object.
If you expand this one you can see that cart object is populating and comes from the our incoming http
post operation.
And if you continue to debug, you can see that mediator will be sent this command to the command handler.
And this will be triggered our actual operation.
I'm going to remove these breakpoint from the validation behavior that you can see that our validations
also trigger.
And here you can see the store basket command handle method to perform the actual operation store basket
in database and update the cache.
For now we are going to return mocking response and we can continue our debug that.
You can see that this will be continue and converting our result object to the response, and return
back to the created response to the client.
So we have confirmed that also our post store basket operation is working perfectly.
But the important thing is in here, when we are sending http post request, we should create Json structure
same as the request class.
So request class is inside of the our store basket endpoint.
And you can see the request class.
So it is accepting shopping cart.
And this cart variable name is crucial when sending the request to the http post operation.
If you change this variable name, your Json will not be accepted.
If you, for example, change the name as a cart two or shopping cart.
And if you go back to http post operation, your Json would not be work and.
Jason is expecting the exact same name parameter into in here.
So the Json is very important and the naming is also very important.
And finally we can go to the Http delete operation.
In here I have created http delete basket url.
This is the endpoint and this username comes from the URL request parameter.
I'm going to hit the send button and this will be triggered our get basket endpoint.
If I continue I can see that this will be trigger get basket delete basket command handler class successfully
and return a mock response.
And if I hit five, I can verify that delete operation performs successfully.
As you can see that we have confirmed securities and mediator request lifecycle by sending Http, get,
post and delete request to our basket.
Microservices.