In this video, we are going to explain infrastructure and data concerns for basket API.
Let's start by remembering banking services.
Banking services are the external resources or the components that microservices depends on for their
operations.
They provide support for various functionalities and in the cloud native architectures, banking services
like databases, messaging systems and caching services are treated as attached resources.
So these services are the external to the microservices and can be swapped or replaced without changing
the microservice core logic.
In a cloud native microservice architecture, backing services are decoupled from the microservice themselves
and promoting the flexibility, scalability, and easier to maintenance.
Here you can see the illustration showing the various backing services in the cloud native setup that
you can see the databases, distributed caches, message brokers, and so on.
In our scenario basket, microservices interacts with the PostgreSQL database and the Redis distributed
cache.
So that means for this section we will focus on PostgreSQL database operations similar to catalog microservices.
But in the next section we will focus on the adding cache capabilities into basket microservices.
In order to implement these two different external resources for our basket microservices, we will
use repository pattern.
Let's examine the class diagram for our repository implementation that you can see in the picture.
So according to this picture you can see that we will create an interface which name is AI basket repository.
And this interface should be inherited from the basket repository and cached basket repository.
So we will follow the repository pattern which is provide an abstraction layer over the database.
And we will use decorator pattern using the secretary library in order to decorate the basket repository
for caching operations.
And we will follow the cache aside pattern fetching data from the radius when available, otherwise
from the PostgreSQL and updating the cache information.
So now let's get started.