In this video, we are going to implement a basket repository interface using the Martin Library AI
documentation interface.
Here you can see the opening sessions in Martin as a document database.
We will use Primary Constructor to inject Martin classes into our repository object.
Here you can see that we will inject a document session.
And especially we will use lightweight document sessions for that purpose.
Please open the Visual Studio and we should install Martin NuGet packages into basket API.
I'm going to right click the basket API project and manage NuGet packages and search for the Martin.
Install Martin Library into basket API project.
And if you double click the basket API, you can confirm that our Martin library comes into basket API.
Now we can use this library into our basket repository to inject AI documentation.
So I'm going to inject AI documentation.
Is the station name.
So if you come here and using Martin's statement, you can see that we have injected successfully.
And now we can use Session object to perform, get, store and delete operation.
Let me start with the get basket operation.
I'm going to remove this throw exception statement.
And now I'm going to create a basket variable.
And we will use session dot load async method.
And I'm going to retrieve shopping cart with a given username and cancellation token.
Here you can see that we will get basket information from the PostgreSQL database using the I document
session from the Martin library.
And we will passing the username because we will get shopping cart by username.
And after that I'm going to return this basket.
But this basket can be null.
So for that purpose I'm going to check that if basket is null we can throw an exception.
So what kind of exception that we can throw.
We can throw any basket Notfoundexception.
We will create this exception a few minutes later.
So let me create.
And after that I will explain.
If basket is not null we can return the basket object to do our method operation.
Okay.
Get basket is completed successfully.
Now I'm going to implement Store basket as.
You remember that when we are storing the basket information, we will perform Upsert operation because
Martin provides an absurd functionality that simplifies our operations.
That means if this shopping cart doesn't exist into database, Martin will insert it.
If the shopping cart is already existing, Martin will be updated.
The existing shopping cart object.
Since we are storing the shopping cart as a Json body into document database, we can update the whole
Json into our database.
So this behavior aligns with the dynamic nature of the shopping cart and shopping cart items in our
e-commerce application.
So we will use store method for that purpose.
I'm going to write session dot store and pacing the whole basket object.
And after that we have to write session dot save change async operation to perform all these operation
on database.
And I'm going to return this basket.
And lastly we can implement delete basket method.
For that purpose we have using the session dot delete method, passing the shopping cart as a generic
and we have to give username because we will also delete shopping cart by username.
And after this operation, of course we will again using the save changes async method.
And I'm going to return true as a successful complete operation.
So now it is time to develop our custom exception which is the basket not found exception.
For that purpose I'm going to create a new folder under the basket API project.
Right click Add new folder, which name is exceptions.
And under this folder I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is basket Notfoundexception.
So in here we basically inherit from the not found exception which comes from the or actual building
blocks operation, which including all common related objects into building blocks.
And we will follow the same step and creating our custom notfoundexception inherited from the not one
exceptions comes from the building blocks.
And in this class we basically create a new constructor exception constructor and this constructor gets
a username information.
And we will paste these username in the base of the notfoundexception.
If you look at the parameters of the base constructor, you can see that we have two parameters that
we can use name and object k.
So I'm giving as a name basket and key username.
So this will be provide a clear and meaningful exception when a basket is not found in the database.
So we can move these using statement into global Usings I'm going to go to global Usings and add exceptions
to make it available for each classes.
And if you go back to our actual Basket repository class, you can see that basket Notfoundexception
is requiring using statement.
And I am adding these using statement.
And if you go on top of this page you can see that we have two using statement.
I'm going to move to the global using CSS and come here copy paste and make it global using statements
for Martin and the basket.
Exceptions.
And if you go back to our basket repository, as you can see that we have successfully implemented the
basket repository class using the Martin AI documentation.