In this video we are going to register and configure Martin DocumentDB library into Program.cs.
As you can see that we use Martin documentation in here, but we need to register and connect PostgreSQL
database in order to use I document session for that purpose.
Please open the Program.cs.
In here we can add Martin related packages into ASP.Net built in dependency injection.
Before building the application you can come here and write builder dot services dot add monitor and
we will configure with two options.
The first option is connection string.
So we will provide connection string as we have already did before in the catalog microservices.
We will use connection string to connect to PostgreSQL database.
And Martin will be used as a ORM system.
After registering to Martin we have some considerations.
The first consideration is lightweight session.
Most of the use cases Martin should use default lightweight sessions for better performance.
For that purpose I am going to add additional configuration.
After making Ed Martin we can use lightweight session.
Here you can see the different session types, but we will use Martin lightweight session to getting
batting performance and make sure that you have also configured these lightweight sessions.
And the second consideration is Martin schema auto creation Martin has auto create schema object property
that we can set in the configurations.
If you come here and set the options that auto create schema object and right click go to definition.
You can see the default value is auto created.
Create or update.
So Martin can automatically create database schema objects.
And this feature is extremely useful during the development phase.
So we will follow these configuration and leaving as it is for this configuration.
And this was the second consideration.
And the third consideration is document identity.
So as you remember that if we open the models for basket API or main entity is shopping cart and shopping
cart item in the shopping cart, we don't have any ID property in here.
Instead of that, we use username to identify for shopping cart object.
In order to use username as a identifier in the document database, we need to mark these username as
identity of shopping cart document table.
For that purpose.
Martin has great feature that we can use if you go to this article document identity from the Martin.
If you scroll down, you can see that we can basically overriding the choice of the ID property field
with providing the identity attribute in the beginning of the Or class entity class.
Or we can configure by giving the schema and data table name and providing the identity function with
a inline function that we can use identity property in here.
So we will choose the second option.
When we are configuring the Martin into Program.cs, please open the Program.cs and go to the Program.cs.
In here I'm going to configure my Martin options again using the options.
And this time we will configure schema and we will configure for the shopping cart model.
And in the shopping cart model we basically change the identity.
And in here we can use function expression to identify and set our identity field should be username.
So within this code, we basically configure Martin with our PostgreSQL connection string.
And we specify the shopping cart entity will use the username property as its identity field.
And lastly, we will use lightweight sessions to optimize performance by utilizing Martin's lightweight
session mode.
So now we should provide the connection string in the application settings Json file to connect with
Martin.
For that purpose, please open the Application settings Json file and in the beginning of this file
create a connection string and under the connection strings, create a database string and this will
be indicating our PostgreSQL database for basket API.
We can see that the server is localhost, port number is default port number, database is basket db
username and password is Postgres and we should include error details as true.