In this video, we are going to run Docker Compose on Visual Studio in order to set up PostgreSQL database
on the environment.
So first of all, please open the Visual Studio and also open the Docker desktop and make sure that
your Docker desktop is running.
And after that you can come to Visual Studio and right click the Docker Compose as a startup project.
And run the Docker compose profile from the Visual Studio.
This action will bring up our PostgreSQL database as defined in the Docker compose files.
Okay if you open the.
Docker desktop.
You can see that this time we have two PostgreSQL database on Docker desktop.
So after running the Docker compose, we have verified that we have two PostgreSQL instance running
one for the catalog db.
And if you look at the catalog db port numbers, you can see that this is exposing the default port
number and another for the basket db.
Exposing the PostgreSQL database 5433 that we have exposed to our local computer, and the internal
port numbers are the same.
These are the five, four, three, two.
These are the internal port numbers, that is the actual PostgreSQL default port number.
So now we have successfully run two database into our computer and docker compose environment.
Now it is time to browse the databases and see the database and tables into the basket database.
I recommended to using Pgadmin for more user friendly interface and managing our databases for that
purpose, please open the Pgadmin.
You can download Pgadmin from their official website.
After opening the PGA admin, you can register servers for Catalog and basket DB.
You can come here and right click and register a new server and give the server name as a local server
name as a catalog or basket DB.
For example, you can give basket db and after that in the connection tab, you can give the server
name as a localhost, and this time basket db will be hosting as a five, four, three and three in
order to access basket db in different port.
So you can create this kind of server registration.
And after that you can come here and listing your servers for catalog and basket DB.
Here you can see that I have created basket DB.
And you can see the empty doc products table is created successfully.
And if you open the basket DB you can see that basket DB also connected in different port from our local
computer.
And if you go to the tables, we can right click and refresh this page.
There is no table is created yet because we are looking for the basket DB database now.
And we didn't start our basket DB application or we didn't send any request.
That's why Martin is only create database for us.
So as you can see that we have connected two different database into our local computer and we are ready
to implement actual business operations which are the basket get, delete and store basket operations.