In this video, we are going to integrate the Basket repository class with our six handler classes to
perform Crud operations on the basket microservices.
So we have developed the basket repository under data folders.
Now it is time to integrate these repository objects to our 600 classes.
These are the get basket handler, store basket handler and delete basket handler.
So let's open the get basket handler.
In get basket handler class, we basically inject a basket repository to retrieve the basket data from
the database with a given username.
For that purpose, I am going to inject the I basket repository into our query handler classes I basket
repository and I'm going to give as a name repository.
So with injecting these I basket repository in the handle method we use this repository object and perform
the get basket operation in order to fetch the basket for provided username from the database.
For that purpose I'm going to remove the these two do statement.
And in here I'm going to write the basket variable.
And this time we will get this basket using the repository that get basket method.
And we will passing the username from incoming query object.
And here you can see that we got the basket information.
And I'm going to remove the mocking shopping cart object inside of the result.
And passed the basket object in here.
So here we handle the get basket query and return basket data.
And if you right click and go to implementation of this repository class you can see the Basket repository
class.
And in this class we basically load async method and get the basket information with a given username
from database.
If basket is null, we will throw an exception.
If not, we will return back to the basket object to the our handle method and this will be.
Go to the result object and result object will be redirect to the endpoint class, and endpoint class
will be convert to the response object and return back to the client application using the result dot
okay method.
So after that we can continue to the next Crud operation, which is the store basket.
For that purpose, please open the store basket and go to Store Basket Handle class.
Here you can see the our actual handle class.
In this class we again use I basket repository and inject a basket repository into our handle class.
We will use these basket repository to store basket data.
And this will be an observed operation.
Creating a new basket or updating an existing basket with a given username.
For that purpose I'm going to use await repository dot store basket method and I will passing to shopping
cart information with incoming command object command dot cart.
And we will passing the cancellation token which is the incoming cancellation token.
And here you can see that we basically store the basket information.
And after that we are going to return back to the store basket result object with a given username.
For that purpose I'm going to remove this hardcoded username and passing the command dot cart dot username.
Okay.
We have completed the implementation of store basket command handler.
If you go on top of this page you can see that we have using statement.
And I am going to move these using statement to the global using CSS.
By this way each class can be used these data related operations.
And if you open the gate basket handler now we can remove these unnecessary using statement in here.
Now if you go to the delete basket and delete basket handler we will follow the same steps.
In class definition we basically inject the I basket repository.
And we will use basket repository inside of the handle method.
So basically this is very straightforward.
We will just use the repository dot delete basket operation.
And I am going to paste the username with the incoming command command dot username and paste the cancellation
token.
Now we can delete this session line.
And of course we should make this method call as an available method call.
So basically this handle method processed the delete command and ensure the basket is removed from the
database.
After integrating repository object with the handle methods, it is time to register our basket repository
into ASP.Net Core Dependency Injection container, because we will inject these repository into every
100 class with using the primary constructor, it is need to register into Program.cs.
Please open the Program.cs and go to the add services into container part.
Before building the application.
In here we can add a Services Builder Services add scoped.
I'm going to add a scoped services and this will be the I basket repository.
And we are going to resolve this.
I basket repository to basket repository.
With this setup.
Our handler class now fully integrated with the basket repository and capable of performing the necessary
Crud operations on basket microservices.