In this video we will test Http, get and delete endpoints of our basket microservices which are connected
to PostgreSQL database using the Martin.
And we will also address how to handle exceptions to ensure our servers respond with user friendly message.
So please open the postman as you remember that in the last video we have created new basket with using
http post request.
Now I am going to open http get request, which is the get basket by username.
And if you look at the endpoint you can see the basket URL is located our localhost 5051 and the endpoint
continue with the basket slash means that our username we will pass the username from the request parameters.
Please click the send button and trigger our Http get endpoint.
And this will be hit our breakpoint which is the get basket endpoint.
And if you continue and debugging this will be sent to our Get Basket query object into the Get Basket
query handle.
And this handle method.
This will be using repository Get basket object with passing the username.
And in this method we basically use Martin session load async method in order to get shopping cart by
username.
So if you continue debug operation, you can see that we will retrieve basket information from the database.
And if you come here and expand the basket, you can see that we have two items and calculated total
price.
And the username is boolean.
Now I am going to return back to the our handle method.
This will be returned a result object and this result object will be.
Continue a response object and return back the result okay.
To the client application that we can confirm from the this response we have 200 okay response.
And we have whole Json body of the shopping cart object including the username and two items.
So we have confirmed that our Http get operation working successfully.
Now I am going to test http delete operation.
This is delete by username.
Again the end point is exactly same.
We passing the username from the request parameters.
But this time we will send http delete method.
So click the send button.
This will be triggered delete basket and point class.
And this will be sending to mediator to delete basket command handler class.
This time we will use repository dot delete basket method.
If you go to implementation and put breakpoint and continue our debug operation in here, you can see
that we will use Martin's session dot delete method in order to delete shopping cart by username with
passing the username as a parameter, and this will be delete or record from database and we will save
change async and return true object and this result object returning true, and we will return back
to the client as a response.
And in the response we will include a message of the is success that you can confirm from the 200 okay
delete operation is succeed.
So now we can verify the deleted shopping cart from the database using Pgadmin.
Or we can send http get method again with the same username.
Last time we can get the whole cart object, but this time we will expect that this boolean has deleted
and with no response to our http get method.
Click send method and see what's going happen.
And this comes to our Get basket endpoint.
I'm going to hit F5.
And in here in the handle method we will use repository dot get basket and the repository get basket
method.
As you remember that we use load async method.
But this time basket is null.
When basket is null we have throwing basket not found exception with a given username.
So that's why this will be throwing an exception.
And if we hit F5 we can see.
The exception is entity basket with the username as was not found.
But as you can see that this is unreadable real message.
And this is not acceptable for the client response.
So we should fix this response and make this more readable and manageable.
Now let's improve this exception message for the client applications.