In this section, we are going to develop ordering application layer with actors and mediator and implement
the command and command handler patterns.
Here you can find the big picture that we are going to develop during the course.
We are still at the ordering microservices, but this time we will develop ordering application layer.
And here you can find the ordering microservices internal architecture that we are going to implement
clean architecture, domain driven design and security design pattern.
So that means we are at the application stage.
We complete the domain and infrastructure layer and we are going to develop application layer.
And application layer is storing our core layers according to Clean architecture.
So in this application layer we will apply the domain driven design skills and clean architecture patterns.
We will develop Crud order command and handle methods.
And we will implement the command process pipeline with a mediator pattern using the mediator library.
And we will develop AI application DB context object for injection Entity Framework core DB context
object.
And we will develop mediator pipeline behaviors for validation and logging to perform cross-cutting
concerns.
And we will develop domain event handlers with mediator AI notification handler interface.
And we will develop order queries with queries and mediator.
And we can say that the main objective is implementing the application logic and use cases with securities
and mediator pattern in these application layer.
So before that we should understand the fundamental patterns of application layer.
We will learn what is securities pattern event sourcing pattern, securities with event sourcing pattern
and eventual consistency principle.
And after that we will design ordering, microservices, application layer and the web layer to implement
the command and command handler patterns with using mediator.