In this video we are going to learn skills.
Design pattern skills is one of the important pattern when querying between microservices.
We can use skills design pattern in order to avoid complex queries to get rid of the inefficient joins.
Queries stands for the command and query Responsibility segregation.
And basically this pattern separates read and write operations with separating the databases.
The main idea is that we can divide application operations into two separate categories.
The first one is commands.
These commands are changing the state of data into application, and the second one is queries.
And these queries are handling the complex.
Join operations and returning a result and don't change the state of data into the application.
In a large scale, microservice architectures need to manage high volume data requirements for this
kind of use cases.
Monolithic approach, like single databases for services, can cause the bottlenecks for complex and
large scale microservice architectures.
We can use both skills and event sourcing pattern in order to improve application performance.
Skills offers to separate the read and write data that provide to maximize query performance and scalability.
Let's think about the monolithic applications.
Most of the time we have one database, and this database should respond to both query and update operations.
That means a single database is both working for the complex joint queries and also perform Crud operations.
But if the application goes more complex, this query and Crud operations will be also is going to be
unmanageable situation.
In example of reading database, if your application required some queries that needs to join more than
one table that will lock the database due to latency of query computation.
Also, if we give example of writing database when performing Crud operations, we would need to make
complex validations and process long business logics.
So this will cause to lock the database operations also.
So reading and writing database has different approaches that we can define different strategies in
order to handle that operations.
In order to do that, Sickles offer to use separation of concerns principles and separate reading database
and writing database with two databases.
By this way, we can even use different database for reading and writing database types, like using
NoSQL databases for reading operations and using relational databases for Crud operations.
Mostly read database uses NoSQL database with denormalized data which is generated from the right database,
and right database uses relational databases with fully normalized and support strong data consistency.
But during this section we are going to use logical sequence pattern implementation, which separates
the read and write operations logically in ordering microservices.