In this video we are going to learn event sourcing pattern.
What is the event sourcing pattern?
As you know that most of the applications saves data into databases with the current state of the entity.
For example, if the user change email address into our application, the user email field updated with
the latest updated one.
So email information overwrite the existing field of email in the user table.
By this way, we always know the latest status of the data.
This is the traditional model that works fine to overwrite existing field when something changed.
But in large scale architectures frequently update database operations can negatively impact the database
performance, responsiveness, and limits of scalability.
In order to solve this problem, event sourcing pattern offers to persist each action that affects the
data into the event store database and call all these actions as an event.
So we can say that instead of saving the latest status of data into databases.
Event Sourcing pattern offers to save all events into database with sequential order of data events.
These events database called event store.
That means instead of overriding the data into table, it creates a new record for each change to data
and it becomes sequential.
List of the past events.
By this way, events store database become the source of truth for the data and these sequential list
using for generating materialized views that represent the final state of the data in order to perform
queries.
So that means these events store convert to read database with following the materialized view pattern.
This convert operation can handle by publish subscribe pattern with publish events with using the message
broker systems.
Also, these event list gives ability to reply events at given certain timestamp, and by this way it
is able to breathe latest status of data with replying to events.