In this video we are going to learn skills design pattern with event sourcing pattern.
In the last video, we have learned the sequence pattern and the sequence pattern is mostly using with
the event sourcing pattern.
When using sequence with event sourcing pattern, the main idea is store events into right database
and these will be the source of truth of that events database.
After that, the right database of skills design pattern provides materialized views of the data with
denormalized tables.
Of course, these materialized views read databases, consume events from the right database and convert
them into denormalized views.
The writing database is never saved.
Status of data.
Only events actions are stored.
By this way, saving only events actions into right database.
We can store history of data and able to reply any point of time in order to regenerate the status of
the data.
So with following the event sourcing pattern, the system can increase the query performance and scale
the databases independently.
Here you can see the image on the slide.
An example use case for applying queries and event sourcing pattern.
Event sourcing pattern offers to save all events into database with sequential order of data events.
This event database called Event Store.
Here you can see the event store in here.
In this architecture we are not updating the status of data record.
It appends each change in a sequential list of the events.
So that means these events store is become a source of truth for the data.
After that these events store convert the data to the read database with following the materialized
view patterns.
This convert operations can handle by such publish subscribe pattern with publish event to the message
broker system, and this will consume from the read database.