In this video we are going to learn eventual consistency principle.
In the last video, we have learned the sequence pattern and how to use sequence pattern with event
sourcing pattern.
Now we will talk about the concepts of eventual consistency principle, which has happened that when
we use sequence with event sourcing pattern.
So what is eventual consistency principle?
Eventual consistency is especially used for the systems that prefer high availability to strong consistency.
The system will become consistent after a certain time, but it doesn't guarantee strong consistency.
We call this latency is eventual consistency principle and offers to be consistent after a certain time.
And as you remember that when we are learning the Cap theorem, we also learned the consistency levels.
According to Cap theorem, we need to consider the consistency level that we need.
So that means in our application we should ask ourselves what is the consistency level requirement of
our microservice databases.
So there are two types of consistency level.
The first one is strong or strict consistency, which is aimed at when we save data, the data should
affect unseen immediately for every client we can give.
Example of strict consistency is debit or withdrawal on bank account.
And the other type is eventual consistency.
Basically, when we write any data, it will take some time for clients reading the data we can give
example of eventual consistency is YouTube video counters we see in different video numbers and in different
sessions.
So with implementing six design pattern and event sourcing pattern.
When user perform any action in the application, this will save actions as an event into event store
and this data will convert to reading database with following the publish subscribe pattern using the
message brokers and this data will be denormalized into materialized view database for querying from
the application.
So during the process of converting the event store to Denormalized data, this system will be eventual
consistency.
And that means we call this process is a eventual consistency principle.