In this video we are going to analyze application layer in ordering microservices.
Let's remember application use cases of ordering microservices.
The first one is Crud ordering operations that including get order with items, create, update, delete,
order and add and remove order item from the order.
Following that, we will see asynchronous ordering operations that including basket checkout and order
fulfillment.
And after that we can remember the technical analysis of ordering microservices, which is pattern and
principles that we are going to use when developing application layer.
Here you can see that we will implement six and six design patterns.
We will develop command and command handler patterns.
And we will use mediator pattern with mediator library to perform mediator pipeline behaviors.
And we will also use fluent validation and logging cross-cutting concerns.
And here you can see the folder structure of the application layer that we are going to develop in this
section.
As you can see that we will start with the data folder which is including I application db context.
This is the abstraction interface for application db context that we use in infrastructure layer.
And after that you can see that the important folder is feature folder which is the orders.
Orders has commands event handlers and queries sub folders that we are going to follow.
Sequence design pattern.
We will develop the commands under these commands folder and under commands.
You can see that we have Crud operations including the create, delete and update order.
And for each folder structure we have command and handler class.
And if you look at the our queries you can see similar use cases in here.
Get orders.
Get orders by name.
Get orders by customer queries located in this place.
And if you look at the event handlers, you can see that we can handle domain and integration events
into this place.
And we will also have dependency injection and global using to performing ordering application.
After that, we can explore the NuGet packages that we are going to use in ordering application layer.
Here you can see that we will be using the libraries from the building blocks, including the mediator
and validation and so on.
According to clean architecture, in the application layer, we are getting reference from the building
blocks in order to get common operations for each microservices.
For that purpose, the building blocks libraries can be referencing in application layer that we can
use mediator extensions, dependency injection, fluent validation, fluent validation, dependency
injection extensions, Mapserver and logging abstractions.
All these libraries that we are going to use from the building blocks in the application layer in order
to perform application use cases of the ordering application.