In this video we are going to implement six command and command handler patterns with mediator.
So six can be implemented in two main ways.
These are the logical and physical.
So now let's remember these logical and physical implementation of the six.
In the logical implementation of six we basically splitting the operations not databases.
Separate the read query operations from the write command operations at the code level, but not necessarily
at the database level.
Even though the same database is used, the path for reading and writing data are distinct, and if
you look at the physical implementation of six, this is basically perform separate databases, splitting
the read and write operations, not just at the code level, but also physically using the separated
databases.
It introduces data consistency and synchronization problems in ordering microservices.
We will use logical six implementation when applying the separation of concerns between read and write
operations.
So now let's understand the command and command handles in queries when developing ordering application
layer in the command in six, a command is directive to change the state of the system.
It encapsulates the data which required for a specific action.
As an example, you can see create order command under the orders commands and create order.
And here you can see the create order command CS that might be contain order details for a command class.
After that we can see command handlers.
Those are the responsible for handling the command.
Each command has a corresponding handler that containing the logic.
In order to execute the command, the handler interacts within the domain model and persist the changes.
That means it executes the business logic and updates the state through the repositories.
Here you can see the command handler class under the create order folder.
This is the command, and this is the command handler class that perform the business logic.
And also you can see the image of the command and command handlers.
When a request comes from the client, you can see that these will be trigger the command and query
operations that comes to interact with the command handler.
In order to perform use cases with interacting repository object and connecting the database, and after
handling the command that will be returned, the result and response to the client application.
So how we can trigger these commands to do their command handler classes.
Of course implementing the mediator pattern and using the mediator library.
So for that purpose let's understand six design pattern with mediator library we will be using the mediator
for six implementation.
And mediator is a popular dotnet library used to implement the mediator pattern which is a great fit
for the six implementation.
And we will use I request interface.
It is used to define a request which can be either a command or a query.
The return type of the request can be specified as a generic parameter.
And after that we can learn handlers.
For each command and query, you can define a handler that inherits from the request handler interface,
which is accepting tracks and t response generics, where the t request is the type of the command or
query, and t response is the return type.
And we can also make our custom I command and I query abstractions.
So we will distinct I command and I query.
To make this distinction between command and queries, we can define two custom interface which are
the I command and I query.
Both interface can inherit from the mediators I request interface.
So we will use mediator and securities design pattern into our ordinary microservices.
ASP.Net core application with controllers or minimal APIs act as an entry point for handling the Http
request, instead of the implementing the business logic directly within the API.
Actions.
These actions delegate the responsibility to the mediator, and we can call this process as a wrapper
pattern, which is the request response pattern that we will see in the upcoming sections.
So that means when a minimal API receives a request, it creates a command or query object and send
to the mediator.
And mediator dispatch this object to the appropriate handler, and this handler class interact with
the repository object in order to perform use case and return back the result to the client application.