In this video we are going to create folder structure for our auditing application layer.
As you can see that we are going to create these folder structure when developing our ordering application.
And these ordering application layer in Essex architecture is structured to separate commands, queries
and event handlers.
These separations align with the six principles which is segregating read and write operations.
That means separating query and command operations.
Here you can see that we are using orders which is the features folders.
And under these folders we will create a commands folder which contains classes for commands and their
respective handlers.
And after that we will create queries folder that include query models and their handlers.
And we will also create event handler folder for handling the events responding to the domain events.
So now we will apply these folders into our application architecture.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering application layer.
So in this layer I'm going to create our main folder which is the orders.
If you right click here and add new folder which name is orders.
This will be representing our main sequence folder that include command queries and event handlers.
So I'm going to create a sub folder.
Right click the orders add new sub folder which name is commands.
And after that I'm going to follow the same steps for the queries folder.
And lastly we will have event handlers folder under the orders.
Here you can see that we have created three main folders for KCRW's implementation.
So after that I'm going to follow the R slide to creating Data and Details folders.
For that purpose I'm going to create a data folder in the beginning of the ordering application.
If you go back to Visual Studio and create a new folder with right clicking the ordering application,
add new folder, which name is data, and also we will follow the same step.
For the Dto's folder, right click application and add new folder which is the details and these details
representing and containing our data transfer objects like order DTO and Order Item, DTO and data folder
include interfaces like IE application db context which is the abstraction of the DB context, Entity
Framework, Core Operations.
And lastly, we will create a common classes for each layer, which are the Dependency Injection case
and global using case.
So for that purpose open the Visual Studio.
As you can see that we have already created Dependency Injection case.
This is responsible for setting up the dependencies specific to the application layer.
And this is where we are configuring the mediator and other related services for application layer.
After that, I'm going to create a new class under the ordering application right click Add New Item
which is the global using CSS.
And this is the convenient place to put all global using statements, reducing the need for the repetitive
code across the application layer.
So here you can see that we have created the skeleton of the ordering application that we are going
to develop each layer and each folder one by one.