In this video, we are going to develop DTO classes for orders in ordering application layer.
Here you can see that we will develop DTO folder and it is good to use data transfer objects when accepting
the commands from the presentation layer.
And after that we will map these details into our application logic with creating domain order and raising
domain events.
So now let's setting up the folder structure and create DTO classes.
Please open the Visual Studio and locate the ordering application and go to details folder.
And after that we will include all DTO classes inside of this folder.
For that purpose I'm going to start with creating order DTO.
Add a new class under this folder, which name is Order Dukes.
So we will develop order DTO class in order to represent the order data structure.
So let's get started.
Remove unnecessary using statement and remove the order DTO class definitions.
Because I'm going to create a record type for the order DTO record types is very well suited for the
DTO classes, because DTO classes provide for the mapping from one type to another type, and record
type is best practice to using this kind of operations.
And here you can see that we have created public record order DTO.
And inside of the record type we have ID, customer ID, order, name, shipping and billing address,
payment status and the order item list.
So these DTO represent a complete order including customer details, shipping, billing address, payment
information and items within the order.
So we will follow the same steps for the rest of the details.
Here you can see that we use address DTO, payment DTO and order item DTO.
So now let's create a order item DTO inside of the the same folder which is the details folder.
Add new class which is the order item detox.
In here.
We also create a record type for Orderitem DTO in order to represent individual items in an order.
For that purpose, I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and delete the this class definition
and create a record type for Orderitem DTO.
Here you can see that we will use public record Orderitem DTO, and these are the members that we are
going to use for particular Orderitem, including the order ID, product, ID, quantity and decimal.
This DTO represents the essential information of each item in an order such as the product ID, quantity
and the price.
So I'm going to continue the next DTO.
If you go to the order DTO, you can see that we will also create address DTO.
I'm going to create address DTO inside of this DTO folder, create a new class under this folder which
name is Address Detox and follow the same steps.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and delete the address DTO and this will be represent
an address value object from the domain layer and we will make this record types for the address DTO.
Here you can see that I have created Public Record Address Studio and the members comes from the address
value object which including the first name, last name, email address, address, line, country state
and zip code.
So this is the address DTO definition is the same way.
I'm going to create payment DTO.
If you go back to order DTO, the only payment DTO is required under the details folder.
Create new class which name is payment DTO and follow the same steps and payment DTO also represent
payment value object from our domain layer for that purpose.
Again, I'm going to remove this definition and create a new record type, which is the public record
payment.
DTO and the members are card name, card number, expiration, CVV, and payment method and make sure
that you are setting the CVV as a C, as a uppercase, V as a lowercase.
Because maps cannot map for the uppercase properties inside of the record types.
So these are the DTO definitions that encapsulate the details from the domain layers, including the
address payment order and order.
DTO.
You can go to order DTO and see that now we don't have any exception and all order details representing
a specific order, including default value, object DTO and the list of the order item details.
So why we have developed these Dtos under the application layer?
Because we will map these D2 objects when moving to presentation layer.
So that means when a request comes to the ordering API, we will map these objects to the DTO in order
to perform our business logic.
So for that purpose we need a map store.
So if you double click the ordering application you can see that we don't have maps library, but it
comes from the building blocks because ordering application is getting reference from the building blocks.
And if you go to the building blocks that include the common libraries, that is including the master.
So we will use DTO objects when mapping with maps in ordering application layer.