In this video we are going to develop orders, create order command and create order command handler
in the application layer.
So that means we will develop application features into our orders folder.
And we will specifically implement the use case of the create order feature.
So under the create order we will develop create order command and create order command handler.
So let's get started.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering application and Orders folder and go to the commands
folder.
I'm going to right click this command folder and add new subfolder.
Which name is Create Order.
This will be represent our application use case and feature folder.
And inside of this folder we will create create order command and handler classes.
So under this Create Order folder I'm going to add a new class.
Which name is Create Order command Dax.
So this will be represent our command operation.
And we will define a record type for the create order command that takes an order DTO as a parameter.
So let's start the implementation.
Remove unnecessary using statement.
And I'm going to remove this internal class definition and start with defining our record type with
taking the order DTO.
And this will be inherited from the I command interface which comes from the R abstractions.
So here you can see that we will create public record create order command as a parameter.
It is getting order DTO and order.
And this will be inherited from the I command.
In order to identify this is the I command operation to performing our create order operations.
So this command object basically encapsulates the data needed to create a new order, which is the order
DTO.
And here you can see that we also need to create order result for the response of this command object.
That's why I'm going to create a create order result record that will define a record type to encapsulate
the result of the command execution, which is basically return a ID of the newly created order.
For that purpose, I'm going to create a basic record type for the result object, which is the public
record create order result, and as a parameter it is response, the gid id, which is the newly created
order id which comes from the command object.
And after that we can define the command validations with full and validation.
So as you remember that when we are developing our catalog and basket microservices in the command classes,
we will develop command result and validator object.
And these are representing our mediator lifecycle.
Here you can see that when the request comes we will create a command and query object.
And this will be also including the result object that we can return the client application.
And when we are developing these command and query we can also develop the validations.
So for that purpose I'm going to go back to Visual Studio and implement the Create Order command validator
using the full length validation in order to ensure that the incoming order data is valid or not.
And in here you can develop these codes which is the public class create order command validator.
And this will be inherit from the abstract validator with including the create order command type.
Abstract validator comes from the full length validation library to performing the validations in the
constructor of this class.
And here you can see that we have created the constructor, and inside of the constructor we can use
rule for methods comes from the full length validation library.
And we will specify the order attributes with including the order name, customer ID and order items
not empty and not null with the messages that we define in here.
So this is the rule definition for the create order command.
And we basically validate the crucial fields like order, name, customer ID and ensure the order items
are not empty.
Validators are vital to prevent invalid data from propagating through the system.
In our case, we will validate the create order, command and order data in order to perform create
operations without getting any error with these validators.
So after that we can start the developing create order command handler.
If we look at the order mediator pipeline, you can see that after converting the command we will trigger
the command handler with using the mediator.
So we should develop the command handler class.
In our case this will be the create order handler class.
For that purpose I'm going to create a new file.
Which name is create order handler in the same directory of the create order folder.
So please create this class.
And after that we will implement I command handler for the create order command and returning the result
object.
So I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And we will implement the I command handler for the create order command.
And the handlers responsibility is to process the command and interact with the domain model and databases.
So I'm going to start with the.
Implementation of the interface, which is the IE command handler interface, and in this interface
we will passing the types which is the create order command and create order result.
And after that I am going to implement these interface members which is the handle method.
So this handle method will be triggered from the mediator handle method.
Also act as a mediator between the incoming command and the domain model.
So if you look at the method body you can see that the handle method taking parameter from the create
order command as a request and cancellation token, and this will be respond back to the task create
order result object.
That means in the handle method, we basically encapsulate the business logic in order to create an
order entity from the command and persist it to the database for that purpose.
Let's implement this handle method with a piece of code in a commented items.
Here you can see that I'm going to add a commented items for implementing this handle method.
These are the create order entity from the command object that comes from the parameter, and after
that we will perform the save to database and return the result, which is the create order result.
So implementing these 100 logic will involve the interacting with the application db context and database.
So how can we save order entity in this handle method?
Of course we should use application db context object that we developed in the ordering infrastructure
layer.
But according to clean architecture we should not getting reference application layer from the infrastructure
If you look at the clean architecture layer and dependencies, you can see that application layer should
not get dependency from the infrastructure instead of that application layer is using in the infrastructure
layer.
So how we can save these operations inside of the application?
The best practice is using the interface abstractions in the application layer for the Entity Framework
core DB context object.
That means we will create AI application db context interface to implementing and representing the DB
context operations, and these will be resolved when the application start up in the dependency injection
classes.