In this video we are going to develop AI application DB context interface for injecting the Entity Framework
core DB context object in our application layer.
So this approach provides an abstraction over the Entity Framework core DB context object, which is
vital for the decoupling of the application layer from the specific database provider implementation
from the infrastructure layer.
So normally for abstraction we are going to use repository objects and we will create IO parser object.
But when using the Entity Framework core we don't need extra abstractions like implementing repository
pattern, entity framework core db context object is already an abstraction of any database provider
that we can use for the application layer.
For that purpose, we will define an interface which name is AI application db context that uses Entity
Framework core NuGet package reference, and this interface will expose Dbset properties for each entity
and including a method for saving changes asynchronously.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the Create Order folder.
And in here we can use Save to Database operation.
For that purpose we will create AI application db context object.
In order to do that, you can navigate to Ordering Application and go to the data folder.
And in this data folder I'm going to create a new interface.
Which name is AI application db context dot CSS.
So this interface will include dbset properties for entities like customer, product, order and order
item.
And we will add a method for saving changes asynchronously.
So let's get started.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this interface as a public.
And here you can see that I'm going to define the members of this interface with using the Dbset properties.
And in here I'm going to create a customers entity.
And following that I'm going to use product order and order item.
These will be represent our entities from these interface.
And lastly I'm going to create a new method which is the task integer save change async method and accepting
the cancellation token as a parameter.
So this is the interface definition.
I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
And these interface provide a contract for database operations, ensuring that the application layer
remains independent of specific database implementation and also not including any infrastructure implementation
like SQL server, database provider and so on.
This will be the main abstractions, but as you can see that even we are using the abstractions.
We need a Dbset object.
So where these Dbset object comes from, of course this comes from the Entity Framework core package.
In order to use Dbset in our application Dbcontext interface, we should add the Microsoft Entity Framework
Core NuGet package into our ordering application.
So I'm going to right click dependencies and manage NuGet packages.
And in here I'm going to search for the browse for the Microsoft Entity Framework core.
As you can see that there's lots of Entity Framework core packages, like including the SQL server and
other data providers.
And in here we are using the plain Entity Framework core that will represent an abstraction of other
database providers.
So for application layer, we can install this package safely in order to perform abstractions into
our interface.
So please select this Microsoft Entity Framework core and install this package into the application
layer after installation.
You can confirm this from the Ordering application project file and save this file.
And here you can see that we have adding the package Microsoft Entity Framework Core.
And this package will act as an abstraction for Entity Framework core SQL server data related operations
and data provider which we implement into Infrastructure Layer.
And this will be an abstraction.
You can think this is an AI repository layer into ordering application.
So after installing an abstraction of the Entity Framework core NuGet packages, we can go back to our
interface and add the using statement for these Dbset objects using Microsoft Entity Framework core
and save these interface.
And after that we should register Dependency Injection in order to use these interface.
For that purpose, I am going to go to the Dependency injection class on the ordering infrastructure
where we have installing these application DB context.
For that purpose, open the ordering infrastructure and go to the dependency injection case that we
have already registered DB context object in this line of code.
So these are the registration and configuration for the Entity Framework core and SQL server data provider.
And in here I'm going to also adding an if scoped services which is the AI application db context and
application db context.
So please open these commented code and add a scoped services.
I application db context.
If you come here you can using the ordering application data because infrastructure layer can easily
use the application layer according to Clean architecture.
That's why I am adding these using statement.
After that you can see that there is still an exception and you can come here and read the exception.
According to the exception, you can see that there is no implicit reference conversion from the application
DB context to our interface.
For that purpose, we should implement this interface inside of the application db context.
Right click the application db context, go to definition.
And here you can see that we will inherit from the DB context.
And also we will implement the AI application db context inside of the our actual implementation of
the application DB context under the infrastructure layer.
So please make sure that you have also adding these interface.
Because without adding these interface we cannot resolve these interface to our actual application DB
context into the application layer.
So if you go back to our dependency injection and save this file and go back to dependency injection,
you can see that we have added the code for this interface to our actual DB context object.
This registration enables the injection of AI application db context interface throughout the application
layer, where we implement actual business logic, which is the create order handler, and you can see
that we can save the database with using this interface.
But before that, let me right click the ordering API and build the ordering microservices.
And let's recap what we have done in this video.
As you can see that we succeeded in this video.
We basically start with creating a data folder and AI application db context interface under the ordering
application.
And after that we have installed the Entity Framework core based NuGet packages into our ordering application.
After that, we have registered our interface under the ordering infrastructure and Dependency injection
with adding scope services to our application DB context.
And lastly, we adding these interface into our application DB context with implementing these interface
with using the application DB context in order to resolve application db context one dependency injection.
So now we can ready for the inject these AI application db context into our command handler class to
performing Crud operations and performing use cases in the handle method.