In this video we are going to develop create order command underclass using the AI application DB context
interface.
For that purpose, please navigate to Ordering Application Orders commands.
Create order and create order handler class.
This class implements I command handler interface for handling the create order command.
And this handle method using I application db context interface in order to interact with the database.
For that reason.
First of all, we should start with injecting AI application db context into our create order handler
class.
I'm going to use primary constructor for that purpose.
I'm going to open a bracket and injecting application db context object, which name is db context parameter
name.
So you can see that we have injecting primary constructor of the AI application db context.
And now we can use db context to performing an interacting database in the handle method.
Let's start to implement our handle method.
First of all I'm going to make this function as an async.
And after that I'm going to change the name of the create order command parameter request to command.
After that we will iterate our to do list, which is the create order entity from command save to database
and return result.
So I'm going to do the first step, which is the create order entity from the command object.
For that purpose I'm going to create a new function which name is create new Order.
And I'm passing this command dot order object, which is the order DTO to do our method.
And in here I'm going to convert this DTO to the order entity.
So we will implement Create new order method in a few minutes later.
But before that let's continue the our task.
And you can think that this line of code create a new order entity from the commands DTO object.
And after that we can perform the save to database operation.
In order to do that we are going to use db context object.
Here you can see that after creating order entity, I'm going to use db context object and adding new
order into the orders collection into db context and the new order is added to orders db set and after
that saved using the save change async method with available function.
So this will be perform interaction with database operation, and after this operation we can finally
return the create order result with a newly created ID information.
So I am come here and returning a new order result which including the order ID and volume information
which is newly created order ID.
So now we can safely remove this throw new Notimplementedexception.
So this is the implementation of the handle method.
And now we can start to development of the create new order method.
For that purpose I'm going to come here and create a method body which is basically getting order detail
information and returning to order entity.
So this is the body of the our create new order method.
So in this method we will basically construct a new order entity from provided the order DTO object.
And it will include the conversion of DTO properties to the domain objects like the address, payment
and order items.
For that purpose, I'm going to start with the creating, shipping and billing address with incoming
order DTO object.
So I'm going to create shipping and billing address value objects from the DTO object.
Here you can see that this is the shipping and billing address definition using the Addressof method.
In order to create our value objects, and we are passing the value object parameters from the order
DTO shipping and billing address, first name, last name, and the rest of the properties that we are
going to populate when creating value objects into our method here you can see that we will populate
the state zipcode and the rest of the properties inside of these value objects.
And after defining these value objects, we can start to create new order using the order dot create
method.
So with this line of code, we will creating a new order and passing the attributes like in here.
So ID is generating with new width and customer id using the customer id off method and passing the
order detail your customer ID order name and passing the shipping and billing address.
And we will also create payment value object with using the payment off method with passing the incoming
order, DTO payment and the details of the properties.
So this will be create a new order entity from the incoming order DTO.
And after that, lastly, we should for each the order items and create new order items for our newly
created order entity.
Here you can see that we have a for each statement and we will iterate the order items from the order
DTO.
And after that we will add a order item for newly created order entity into our method.
And lastly, we can return a new order from our method.
This is the.
Definition of the create new order method in order to creating order from the incoming DTO object,
and after that we use this order for saving the database using the DB context object and returning the
create order result with passing the newly created order ID.
And basically when we are developing this create new order.
You can also using the custom mapping profile in order to do these operations from mapping order DTO
to order entity.
But I would like to develop explicitly to see how we can create our address and different value objects
and how we can populating the order items when creating any order.
So this is the implementation of the Create Order handler class.
You can also move these using statement to the global using class.
If you copy this using statement and go to the global using Under order application, I'm going to remove
these statement and putting these global keywords in the beginning of the using statement in the global
using CSS, I'm going to go back to our create order handler and remove unnecessary using statement.
So now we can right click and build the ordering API and verify that we have no exceptions.
Yes we completed successfully.
So now we have finished the development of the create order handler.
And we will continue the other Crud operations.