In this video we are going to develop update order command and handler class using the AI application
db context interface.
So we are at this point and we have developed a create order.
Now we are going to create Update Order feature folder and implement the update order use case.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering API Orders and Commands.
And under this command I'm going to create a new subfolder.
Right click Add New subfolder, which name is update Order and this will be represented update order
use case that need to include update order, command and handler class as well as the create order.
For that purpose I'm going to create a new class which name is Update Order command.
The update order command will include an order detail to carry the updated order data, and we will
also develop validator to ensure the necessary fields are present and valid.
So let me start with developing this class.
And I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
And we will make this class as a record type.
In here you can see that I'm going to create public Record update order command.
And this will be taking order DTO as a parameter.
And this record type implement a command interface and this will be returned update or the result.
For that purpose we will also need to create update order result as a record type.
Here you can see that public record update order result taking is success Boolean value as a response
of this update operation.
And after that we should also create a validator class which name is update order command validator
and this will be inherit from the abstract validator from the full length validation.
And in the constructor of this validator, we will validate the update order command, including the
ID or the name and customer ID columns.
So this is the update order command class that including update order command and result record types
and validator class.
So now we are going to start creating Update Order handle class.
I'm going to come to the update order folder and add a new class.
Which name is Update Order handler.
So in this handler class we will implement a command handler interface for updating the order.
For that purpose, I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make the class as a public.
And now I'm going to implement I command handler.
Of course we should remove duplicate column in here.
Okay.
We will inherit and implement a command handler which comes from the using building blocks.
And when we are implementing these interface members this will be creating a handle method that we are
going to perform update order operation.
But before that we should inject inside application DB context into our class.
So in here you can inject I application context object as a db context parameter in the beginning of
the class definition.
So now we can implement the handle method.
I'm going to make this method as an async method and also change the first parameter name request to
command.
So let's plan our handle method.
I am going to update the existing order.
So here you can see the steps that we are going to do.
Update order entity from the command object that we are accessed to DTO object.
And we will update the order entity from this DTO object and save the database and return the result.
So let's follow these steps.
First of all we will check the existing order in place or not.
In here you can see that with this line of code, we will basically perform the order ID and creating
order ID with using the order ID of method with incoming command object, I'm going to go to command
order d2 and ID information and getting the order id, which is the order ID strongly type ID because
we require this strongly type IDs in order to use find async method in the Entity Framework core.
So after that we will use await db context dot orders and find async method and passing this strongly
type order id in order to get existing order, including in database or not.
If the order is null, we are going to throwing order not found exception and we are passing this command
order ID into this exception.
So these are the fetching operation and check if the order exists or not.
If not we will throw order not found exception.
After that we can go to the second step which is to save the database.
So first of all we will update the orders with the new values from the incoming order from the command
dot order DTO.
And we will update order values with the new values incoming from the DTO object.
And after that we will perform the DB context orders, update and save change async in order to reflect
these update operation into database.
And finally we can go to the last step which is the returned result.
So I'm going to write return new update order result with passing the true, which means this update
operation is performed successfully.
So now we can remove this throw statement safely.
And here you can see the implementation of the handle method for the update order handle.
As you can see that we should develop update orders with new values method, which is basically mapping
DTO object to order entity.
So we will map these object properties in order to update new order.
So I'm going to create these method.
So this is the method body which is the public void update order with item new values.
And this will be taking order entity and order DTO object that we are going to map the values from DTO
to order entity.
So I am doing these mapping operation manually.
First of all I'm going to create our value object.
Which are the or shipping and billing address and also payment.
So here you can see the variables updated shipping address, billing address and updated payment that
we are going to create these value objects using the off methods and passing the DTO object related
parameters inside of these off function.
And after that, after getting these updated value objects, we can basically use order dot update method.
So this method is located in domain layer.
And according to domain driven design, we will perform update operation inside of the order entity.
So you can go to the update method and see the details inside of the order entity.
We will accept order name, shipping and billing address, payment and order status information when
updating an existing order into rich domain model order aggregate.
So after that we will sending domain event and raising domain event which is the order updated event.
So if you go back to our code I'm going to using order update method and passing the order name, shipping
and billing address and payment and status information.
This will be update an existing order and this will be implementation of these update orders with new
values method.
You can also use custom mapping profile for this action, but I would like to see explicitly when updating
an existing order.
If you go on top of this page and see the handle method, the only thing we left is creating order Notfound
exception.
To implement these exception, I'm going to create a new folder under the ordering application, right
click Add new folder, which name is exceptions folder.
And inside of this folder we are going to create order Notfoundexception.
And we will implement these custom exception.
I'm going to make it public and I'm going to inherit from the not found exception that we have already
developed in our Common Building Blocks class library.
You can go to Notfoundexception definition, which is located under the Building Blocks Exceptions folder.
And we can use these common exception class into our ordering application layer, which is inherited,
and getting reference from these building blocks into our ordering application layer.
So if you go back to our exceptions and order not found exception, we can implement the constructor
of these exception with inheriting from the base, not found exception with passing order and ID information.
If you go to base constructor, you can see that this will be is arranging some custom exception message.
So now we can go back to our update order handler class.
And now we can using these exception folder.
And if you go on top of these folder you can see that we will have using statements.
I'm going to move these using statement to the global using for that purpose.
Copy these using statements and go to the global using for application layer and passed in here.
So put the global keyword in the beginning of these using statements and save this file.
If you go back to update order handler you can safely remove unnecessary using statement and save this
file.
So I'm going to right click and build ordering microservices to verify everything is working fine.
As you can see that we have successfully develop update order use cases and we will continue to do other
Crud operations.