In this video we are going to develop delete, order, command and handle using the AI application db
context.
Here you can see that we are at the stage of the delete order use case.
And we are going to create this folder and implement Command and handle class.
For that purpose, please open the Visual Studio and go to the Ordering application orders commands.
And under the commands I'm going to create a new folder.
Which name is delete order.
Right click Add new sub folder, which name is delete order and in the delete order folder I'm going
to create a new class.
Which name is Delete Order command.
So we will follow the same steps with the Create and update order.
I'm going to add a new class, which name is Delete order command and this delete order command will
be very straightforward.
It will be carry the ID of the order to be deleted.
And we will also validate ensure the presence of the order ID for that purpose.
Please remove the unnecessary using statement and I am going to delete the internal class definition
because we will create a record type for the delete order command.
And here you can see the delete order command which is the public record delete order command.
And it is taking order ID get value as a parameter and implementing a command interface with a returning
the delete order result.
That means we should also create delete order result as a record type.
In.
Here I have created public record delete order result and taking its success Boolean value as a parameter
that representing the delete operation is success or not.
And after that we can also validate the incoming command object.
For that purpose, we always creating a delete command validator with inherits from the abstract validator
for the delete order command.
And in this validator class, we basically create a constructor and put a rule for method.
In order to rule for the order id not empty with the message is order id is required.
So this is the implementation of the delete order command class.
And we will also implement delete order command handler.
For that purpose, please go to the delete order folder and add a new class.
Which name is delete order handler.
So in this handler class we basically implements a command handler interface with getting type of the
delete order command and delete order result.
So let's get started.
Please remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And after that I am going to implement I command handler interface for this class.
Here you can see that we have implementing I command handler and getting the type of the delete order
command and returning type of the delete order result.
And after that we can implement the interface members which is the handle method.
So now we can start to implement these actual handle method.
I'm going to make this method as an async method.
And after that as you can see that the first parameter is delete order command.
I'm going to change the parameter name request to command.
And now we are going to implement this handle method which is the our actual operation.
For that purpose I'm going to start with the our to do list command items.
Here you can see that we will delete order entity from the command object.
And we will say to database and return the result before start the implementation of this method.
When we are implementing the database, we need AI application db context.
For that purpose, I am going to go to the the class definition and inject the AI application db context
with using primary constructor.
Please add this line of code in order to inject our db context when the application start up, and we
will use these db context object when we are interacting and deleting order into our database using
the Entity Framework core.
So now we can start implementation.
And the first step is I'm going to fetch the order using the find async method, which I have provided
the order ID information to the find async method.
So here you can see that the first line of code I'm going to create an order ID for strongly type IDs.
I'm going to passing the command dot order id to creating this strongly type order id because find async
method in the Entity Framework, core is requiring the strongly type id in order to get the order id
and order record from the database.
So after getting the order ID, we are using the await db context orders and find async method and passing
the these order id as a parameter of the find async method and cancellation token, and this will be
returned an order from the database with a given order id.
If the order is null, we can throwing any order not found exception as we have created in the last
video, and we can pass the order ID from incoming command to order ID and after that, after validating
order is exist, we can remove the order from the context and save the changes that.
Means we will perform the remove operation in the database level using the DB context, and this line
of code provides.
DB context orders removed, and we are passing the order that we get from the database.
And after that we will running the await db context save changes async method with passing Cancellationtoken
in order to delete this record from the database.
And lastly, we can return a result indicating the success of this operation.
Here you can see that return new delete order result with passing to true.
So now I'm going to safely delete this throw operation.
And this is the implementation of the delete order handler method.
We can remove unnecessary using statement.
And here you can see the delete order handler command and handle method.
At this point I would like to explain why we are using find async method in order to retrieve a one
order record from the database.
If you open the documentation, you can see that we can several ways to read one entity with using entity
Framework code, including first order default, single order default, and find async.
So when we are using the find async, the retrieve operation performing over the primary key.
And this is the best performance way in order to retrieve a single record from the database.
So that's why I have used the find and async method into our code.
And also when we are passing the order ID, order id is a primary key and the type is order id strongly
type ID.
That's why Entity Framework code expecting this strongly type IDs.
When seeking the table, it has conversion definition into configurations that is getting the great
value and seek table with the great value.