In this video, we are going to develop mediator pipeline behaviors for validation and logging in our
ordering application layer.
Mediator with its mediator pattern enables a clean, decoupled architecture for handling requests and
responses on pipeline behaviors.
Are extension in the request processing pipeline, allowing us to inject cross-cutting concerns like
validation and logging.
And here you can see the request handling process for the mediator that we can put pre and post-processor
before handling the request.
So we can follow the key behaviors for implementing logging and validation.
That means we will be adding log behavior and validation behavior into our application.
Log behavior is log details about the handling a request validation behavior.
Provide the validate incoming requests before they reach the handler.
So we will add these two behavior into our pipeline behaviors when using the mediator and when we are
implementing pipeline behaviors, we will check the ordering application layer.
And here you can see that we have several use cases including create delete update order into the commands
folder.
So in this folder we will implement command and command handler class.
And we use fluent validation for performing validate operation.
But direct validation triggering is absent.
And similarly there is no logging mechanism into these classes.
And logging mechanism aren't explicitly implemented in the handler class.
So if you open the Visual Studio, you can go to the commands folder and create command.
If you open the create order command, you can see that we have a validator class that comes from the
abstract validator from the fluent validation.
And this validation is performing manually.
In order to do in a pipeline behavior, we should use pipeline behavior for the validations.
We can see the command class using abstract validator from the full length validation, but we didn't
register or call any validate method yet.
Also, you can see handler class we didn't register in Ilogger interface.
If you open the handler class, you can see that we don't have any logger operation and we didn't register
any Ilogger interface, not injecting and not logging incoming and outgoing handler message.
In order to do that, we can use mediator pipeline behaviors, and we already did it before when developing
catalog and basket microservices.
If you look at the architecture, you can see that we were leveraging the building blocks in order to
use pipeline behaviors, because we have developed common logic for behaviors in the building blocks
library, which is including sequences and behaviors.
Since ordering application, getting reference from the building blocks, we can readily use these behaviors
with from the building blocks.
If you open the Visual Studio and go to building blocks, you can see that we have a sequence class
abstractions, and we have also behaviors folders.
And here you can see the logging behavior.
And also validation behavior is developed in this place for common operations.
That is already used from the catalog and basket microservices.
And we will also use these common behaviors into our ordering microservices.
So how we can use these behaviors into ordering microservices.
Of course we need to register these behavior into our dependency injection.
So in order to activate these behaviors we need to register these behaviors with the mediators configuration
in the dependency injection class of the ordering application layer.
If you go to ordering application and go to Ordering Application Dependency Injection, you can see
that we have registered mediator in this place.
So in this place we should also register the validation and logging behavior when we are configuring
these mediator in this place.
Here you can see that I'm going to make this more clearly as a config.
And this is the mediator configurations.
And after configuring the assembly information we can also adding open behavior for the validation and
logging behavior.
You can see that I have added two lines of code in here.
In order to register validation and logging behavior with mediator.
This setup ensures that every request passing through the mediator is automatically validated and logged.
You can right click ordering API and build the ordering microservices that you can verify the build
operation and verify the validations are added successfully.