In this video we are going to develop domain event handlers with using mediator I notification handler
interface in the ordering application layer.
And this mechanism is key for handling events triggered from the domain layer and potentially publishing
integration events to other microservices.
Now let me show you a folder structure that we are going to develop in the ordering application layer.
Here you can see that in the orders feature folder we have a commands, queries and event handlers as
you remember that in application layer we implement queries and mediator and separated the command and
queries in the feature folders in orders feature folder and implement the application use cases.
So before implementing and developing the queries, we should also implement event handlers which are
triggering from the domain layer when creating and updating order.
So now let's understand the domain events and event handlers.
Here you can see the picture of the dispatching domain events with using Entity Framework core save
change interceptor.
So when we are implementing securities design pattern using the mediator library, domain events represent
a significant business moments.
Here you can see that order aggregate is raising a domain event.
As an example.
This is order created domain event.
And we can also raising order updated domain event which are triggered upon creating or updating orders
in the domain layer.
So how can we dispatch these domain events when we are developing domain and infrastructure layer?
We have already implemented these topics.
That means when we are in the domain layer we have aggregates and aggregates have domain event list.
And when we are raising an domain event we will add these domain event into aggregate domain event list.
And after that we will dispatch these domain event using the Entity Framework core save changes interceptor
into the ordering infrastructure layer.
So this is the best practice to dispatching domain events using the Entity Framework core save change
interceptor in the ordering infrastructure layer.
And now in this video we will develop the event consumer part which is the handling this domain event
in the ordering application layer.
Now let me explain these topics into the R code.
Please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering domain layer.
If you go to the ordering domain layer and go to the models and go to the Order aggregate, you can
scroll down and see that order.
Aggregate has a rich domain model, including the create and update method.
In the create method we are creating an order and after that we will add an domain event into the Our
Domain event list, which is the order created event.
If you go to this method, you can see that there is a domain event list under the aggregates that we
can add when a significant change into order aggregate.
And if you scroll down we have update method and following the same steps.
Adding domain event when updating an order which is the order updated event.
So we will paste the order entity in the parameters of this domain event in order to carry the order
information.
Also, if we go to details of the domain events, you can see that domain events are implementing I
domain event interface.
If you go to this interface, this is located the abstractions on domain layer.
And these domain event interface also implements I notification which comes from the mediator.
By this way we can use mediator publish method in order to dispatch these domain events into infrastructure
layer.
So if you go to the ordering infrastructure layer and go to the interceptors, you can open the dispatch
domain Event interceptor.
And in this class we basically dispatch domain event before saving the changes.
If you go to this method and scroll down, you can see that this will be retrieved the aggregates and
retrieved the domain events into the aggregates, and after that iterate the domain events and using
the mediator publish method in order to dispatching these domain events.
So where these domain events handle when publishing on the save changes operation.
So whenever we publish a domain event, we should also handle this domain event in the ordering application
layer.
So that means we should handle these domain events in the ordering application layer.
For that purpose we have created orders, commands, queries and event handlers.
So these event handler folder is representing the handling these domain events in the ordering application
layer.
That means we organize our application layer into feature folders and in orders feature folder we have
a commands queries and event handlers.
And in this event handler class I'm going to create two new classes for handling the order created and
order updated event handler.
So I'm going to add a new class which name is order created event handler.
And also I'm going to add a new class which is the order updated event handler.
This class is representing the handling order created and order updated domain events from the order.
Domain layer.
So what we will do when handling domain events into our ordering application layer.
And these order created event handler class.
At this point it is good to see our architecture.
Here you can see that we are raising domain events from the are ordered aggregate which is the order
created domain event and dispatching this event from the ordering infrastructure layer and handle these
event handler in the ordering application layer.
That means we are at this point and handling and catching these event into ordering application layer.
So what we can do in this handle method, basically we will handle the domain events in this handlers.
And after that domain events leads to integration event.
So that means we will handle business logic or intra microservice communication in this handle method.
And after that this will be communicate significant change across different microservices or different
bounded contexts.
And we will use integration events.
That means domain events become and leading and integration event in the handle method.
So in the upcoming sections we will develop domain event handlers to publishing the integration events
to the message broker like the RabbitMQ for cross microservice communications.
But now we will handle the domain events which fires from the domain layer.
And we are going to logging incoming domain event into our handler class.