In this video, we are going to develop domain event handlers with using mediator in notification handler
interface.
So the implementation of the domain handlers in the ordinary application layer is crucial for handling
internal business events.
So in here you can see that we will develop order created event handler which is triggered from the
order is successfully created from the ordering domain layer.
And here you can see the ordering domain layer is raising order created domain event.
And if you go to this domain event you can see that this will be implemented by domain event.
And I domain event is implement I notification which comes from the mediator.
That means we will handle these notification with using I notification handler interface from the mediator
into our handle class.
For that purpose, I am going to open the Or order created domain event and remove unnecessary using
statement and make this class as a public.
And now the first step is we will implement I notification handler in order to handle mediator I notification.
Here you can see that I'm going to implement I notification handler from the mediator and passing the
order created domain event.
And these interface implementing the members of the handle method.
So we will implement this handle method.
This will be trigger one mediator publishing the notification from the infrastructure layer.
If you open the Dispatch Domain Interceptor class, you can see that we will publish the domain events
when saving the changes and one mediator publish the domain event.
This will be triggered by notification and this will be comes to our I notification handler and which
will be the order created event handler.
And this will be trigger the handle method.
If you look at the handle method, you can see that as a parameter.
It is taking order created event and the parameter name is notification.
So we will be getting these notification and we will implement internal business cases in the handle
method.
But for now I am only doing the logging operation which is the logger that log information.
That means I need inject a logger into our primary constructor.
For that purpose, please go to the class definition and adding a logger.
Injecting the logger for the order created event handler class and we will use these logger object when
we are running the log information, which is a domain event handle is successfully hitting with these
event and the type of the name.
So this is the log operation.
We will log the incoming operation which indicating the order created event has been handled and the
logger captures the event type for monitoring and debugging purpose.
For now it is enough for the implementing internal business operations, which is the logging.
But in the upcoming sections we can publish integration event in this place.
So I'm going to moving these using statements into our global using for the ordering application layer.
If you come here and paste your using statements and put the keyword as a global, and you can see that
we have added these operation in the global listing.
And if I go back to our order created event handler, I'm going to remove these using statements after
adding the global using statement and save these changes.
And this is the order created event handler.
And at the same way I'm going to follow the same step for the order updated event handler.
If you open this class, remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And also we are going to implement from the I notification handler which is in this case order updated
event and implement the interface members, which is the handle method, and this will be getting notification
from the order updated event.
So as you remember that in the notification object, we are passing the our orders that we can access
to order and get the order members with using the notification order.
But for our case, in our business case, we can only logging the information with the incoming event,
which is the domain event and we are notifying this domain event is triggering and we will use logger
object.
That means I'm going to inject the I logger in the beginning of the class definition with the primary
constructor that we can use Logger.log information, and in this case we will log the order updated
event and giving the notification type in the handle method so you can safely remove unnecessary using
statement.
And this was the implementation of the order.
Updated event handler and order created event handler that we have.
Understanding the role of the domain event handlers with using mediator I.
Notification handler interface.