In this video, we are going to develop ordered queries with securities and mediator in the ordering
application layer.
So in our ordering application layer we have following folder structure to Accodomate securities pattern
these including the commands, queries and event handlers.
So now we will focus on the queries part in securities.
So we have three queries sub folder which including get orders by name get orders get orders by customer.
These are the representing our query use cases that we are going to implement in this video.
So let me start with the get orders by name.
So please open the Our Visual Studio.
And I am going to locate the ordering application orders.
And now we are locate the queries.
So now I'm going to right click and add a new subfolder which is get orders by name.
In this folder we will follow the same steps when we are developing any commands.
Here you can see that we have a create ordered use case and we will develop command and handle class.
But in the queries we will create query and handler class.
So we will follow the same steps.
When implementing get orders by name.
I'm going to create a new class under this folder.
Which name is get Orders by Name query.
And in this class we basically define our record types for the query and the result operation.
For that purpose, I'm going to create a record type, and I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement
and remove these internal class.
And we will use record type which is the public record.
Get orders by name query with including the string name as a parameter and this will be implement AI
query interface and returning the get orders by name result.
So I query interface also comes from the our abstractions that we define under the six folder from the
building blocks library that represent separating the query and command operations with using these
interfaces.
So this time we will use I query interface to implementing get orders by name use case.
And this will be returning get orders by name result.
And this is also again record type.
And we will define public record.
Get orders by name and including parameter of the order detail list which is the I enumerable order
DTO orders.
So this class represents the query in order to retrieve orders by a given name, and it contains a single
string name property.
So after defining get orders by name query, we should also develop the handle class.
So that means I'm going to create a new class under this use case folder.
Which name is get orders by name handler.
So this will be the our query handler and responsible for handling the get orders by name query object
and returning the corresponding result.
So I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
And the important thing is we are going to implement this class from the I query handler.
And as a type parameters, you can see that this will be accepting get orders by name query and returning
the get orders by name result.
So in order to implement this query handler members we can add the members which is the handle method.
And in this method we will get the request parameter which is the get orders by query.
And I'm going to change the name of this parameter as a query, and this will be respond back to the
task.
Get orders by name result object in the handle method.
So now we are going to implement this handle method.
I'm going to make this method as an async and also change the parameter name as a query.
And after that we can start by implementing and planning our todo items in a commented section.
Here you can see that the first step we will do get orders by name using the Dbcontext and return the
result.
So how we can use the Dbcontext?
Of course we need to inject I application db context into our query handler class.
Come to the class definition and adding and injecting I application db context as a db context parameter
that we can use for querying and retrieving data from the database.
And after that we can start the implementation.
So the first step is getting orders by name using the DB context object.
Here you can see that we will use await db context orders collection in order to get orders by username
and return back to the orders into our orders variable.
And we are using different extension method to performing these query operation.
So let me explain one by one.
The first step is we will include order with order items into our query in order to get the order items
from the order when we are reaching the order list, and the second configuration is as no tracking.
This is a good optimization when you are only reading data and don't plan to update these entities in
the same context, it tells Entity Framework Core not to track changes to.
These entities, which can improve the performance.
And after that we are performing the where keyword with using the var keyword, we basically filters
the orders based on the incoming query name information.
So in here we are using the order name dot value because order name is a strongly typed value object
that we need to contains with the value object, which is a string, and we will compare with the query
name with the string value of the order name.
So after performing these filter operation, we have also ordered by keyword.
This will be provide sorting the result by the order name.
And lastly we will use two list async method with passing the Cancellationtoken.
This provides to asynchronous.
Executing the query and respecting the Cancellationtoken is a good practice and return back to order
list.
So this is the performing filter and returning the orders to our object.
After performing these query operation, we should return the result.
But if you look at the result, result is including the I enumerable order DTO object.
So we should convert these orders to order DTO.
In order to do that, I am going to create a new method which name is project to order DTO with passing
the orders entities as a parameter of this method.
So basically this method provides to transform order entities into order DTO object because our result
object requiring enumerable order DTO for that purpose.
After preparing the order DTO object, we can basically return nil get orders by name result with passing
to order DTO collection.
So now I'm going to remove these throws statement.
And this is the implementation of the handle method.
So according to this method we should develop project to order DTO method.
For that purpose I'm going to create any private method under this handle method.
And in this method we basically accepting list order entities as a parameter of this method.
And we will return list order dto object.
That means we will transform order entities to order DTO.
For that purpose, I'm going to create a new list order DTO.
And after that I'm going to for each for the incoming order entities.
And I'm going to convert order DTO by Mon-El.
Here you can see that we will use order DTO and New Order DTO record type.
And in this record type I'm passing the ID, customer name, order name, shipping address, billing
address, payment status, and order items and these will be provided to convert order entity to order
DTO.
Here you can see that we will passing the value objects address and payment.
And after that we will passing the order items with select method.
And I'm going to pass order item with new order item DTO with passing the order item members, which
is the order ID, product ID quantity and price and respond back to the to list object in order to populate
order items for our application in here you can see that we need to fix these member which is the payment
CVV.
This should be CVV uppercase in order to make it correctly and save this file.
And after that we can safely return this result object.
After this, for each statement I am going to return the result and this will be basically return all
result DTO object.
And this result object is projected to list of the order DTO.
Here you can see that this will be returned list of the order DTO aligning with to our project to orders
method with expecting in this line of code.
In the handle method, if you go on top of this page, you can see that we will move these using statement
to our global using CSS.
Go to global using CSS and moving to our Entity Framework core reference into here.
And if you go back to our get orders by name handler, you can see that we have successfully developed
get orders by name and you can right click the ordering API and build the project.
This will be the first query object in our ordering application layer that align with the sex and mediator.