In this video, we are going to develop an extension method for the order entity.
Here you can see that we have developed project to order DTO and this method project to order entities
into order DTO object and facilitating the transformation process in various query handlers.
So in order to make it reusable, it is good to create an extension method to performing these operations.
For that purpose, let's creating an extension method in the ordering application layer and we will
create a new folder which name is extensions.
In here select the ordering application.
Right click add new folder.
Which name is extensions.
In this extension folder I'm going to create a new class.
Which name is order extensions dot CSS.
So when we are developing our get orders by name handler class, we have developing project to orders
DTO manually and it is good to move these methods as an extension method in order to make it reusable
for other get use cases, which is the get orders by name, get orders by customer, and so on.
So for that purpose please go to Extensions and Order Extension.
And I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
I'm going to make it public and static class because we will develop an extension method under the Order
extensions class.
So I'm going to create public static.
And here you can see that this is the extension method body.
And according to this body we will create and we will develop this method with extending the I enumerable
order entity to transform a collection of the order entities to the order DTO object, which is the
collection of the enumerable order DTO.
So now we will implement this static extension method.
In order to do that, I'm going to copy from this operation in the handler class here you can see that
we will move this operation into extension.
I'm going to write a different and manipulating with using the orders select method.
If you go back in here you can see that I'm going to directly return orders dot select method.
In order to manipulate order data to the new order DTO.
With select method, we can return back the IEnumerable order DTO object with iterating for orders object.
And here you can see that for each order, we are going to create a new order DTO and passing the ID,
customer ID, order name, shipping and billing address, payment status and order item values to the
order DTO object.
And again in here for order items, we are using select method in order to manipulating order item to
order item DTO object with passing the order id, product id quantity and price.
If you scroll right hand side, you can see that we have an exception that I am going to change payments
CVV.
And here you can see that we are basically creating our address value objects and payment value objects
with passing values from incoming order entity and creating order DTO object.
So with this implementation, we basically perform the two order DTO list extension method and this
method designed to encapsulate the logic for transforming domain entities, which is the order into
their corresponding DTO objects, which is the order DTO.
And this makes the code more maintainable and reusable across different parts of the application.
So now it is time to using this extension method into our get orders by name handler.
Please go to the get Orders by name handler, and we are going to using as an extension method.
Instead of the manually writing this method, please go to this location where we are using the project
to order DTO class.
If you come here and write the orders collection, which is our least ordered entity collection, and
if you type the dot and if you look at the methods, you can see that we have to order DTO list extension
method returning the IEnumerable order data object.
That means we don't need to convert this line of code anymore.
And I'm going to remove this line of code.
And when we are returning result object.
This result object expecting us a DTO object, which is the IEnumerable DTO object that we can convert
from the orders list.
Here you can see the orders entity list that I am going to use, newly created extension method, which
is to order DTO list and passing the I enumerable order DTO into our result object.
By this way, we can provide maintainability and reusability of our application code and make it simplify
for handler method by removing these manually.
Project operation which is the project to order DTO.
So I am going to remove the whole function, and you can see that our handler method is more clear and
more concise.