In this video, we are going to develop a naive query feature, which is the get orders by customer
for that purpose.
Please go to the Visual Studio and locate the orders queries.
And I'm going to right click in here and add new subfolder which is the get orders by customer.
So in this use case we will also need to add query and handle class.
So I'm going to add a new class which name is get Orders by Customer query and add a new class.
Which name is get orders by customer handler.
So create new class and you can see that we have query and handle class.
So now we are going to focus on the query class.
And this class will define our query request and result.
So for that purpose I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
And also I am going to remove these internal class definition because we will create a record type for
the query object.
And here you can see that we have created public record get orders by customer query with taking the
great customer ID as a parameter.
And this will be implemented by query interface and returning the get orders by customer result for
that purpose.
Also, I'm going to create a result object with a record type.
Here you can see that public record get orders by customer result.
And this will be getting a orders parameter which is the IEnumerable order data.
That means we will return this order detail list as a response of the get orders by customer request.
So now we can go to the handler class in order to implement this query handler.
So I'm going to remove unnecessary using statements and make this class as a public and implement the
I query handler interface, which is incoming.
Get orders by customer query and returning the get orders by customer result.
So when we implement these members here, we can see that the handle method comes in the picture.
And this is the our first parameter which is the get orders by customer query.
I am changing the name of the parameter request to query and also make this method as an async method.
So if you plan to implementation of handle method, we can say that we will get orders by customer using
the Dbcontext and return the result.
So that means we should inject the application db context object into our class.
So come to the class definition and use the primary constructor and inject the I application db context
as a db context parameter in order to interact with database.
So after that we can start the actual implementation.
And here you can see that we will use DB context that orders that include where as note taking order
by and to list async functions in order to perform get orders by customer.
So let me explain.
One by one we basically retrieve the orders using the DB context based on the given customer ID, and
here you can see the include keyword.
This statement ensures that the related order items are also fetched, and also we use as no tracking
because we will use for the read only scenarios in order to improve performance.
And also in here you can see that we have a where keyword, and in here the orders are filtered by the
customer ID and ordered by the order name, with the order by keyword and returning list of these orders,
which is the to list async method.
This will provide to run query asynchronously and return back to order list operation.
So that means we will perform the get orders by customer with this line of code.
And you can see that when we are filtering the customer ID, we are converting the customer ID that
off method with incoming query object and the customer ID, and this will be provided to convert strongly
typed customer ID when we are filtering the orders by customer ID.
So after getting orders by customer, we basically return a result.
So when we are returning a result, we will use return new, get orders by customer result and in this
result object is accepting IEnumerable order DTO.
For that purpose we will use orders dot to order DTO list, which is an extension method that we have
developed in the previous video.
So we will use extension method in a reusable manner into these get orders by customer handle method.
So after returning a response we can safely remove these throw off statement.
And this is the implementation of the get orders by customer.
And I'm going to use these statements into the global using.
So if you go to the global using and paste to our extensions folder, you can put the global keyword.
If you go back to our get customer by handler.
Here you can see the implementation of the get customer by handler class.