In this video we are going to develop get orders, query using techniques and mediator in the ordering
application layer.
But before that, let's understand pagination with using the Entity Framework core entity Framework
core supports pagination through the skip and take link methods.
These methods allow us to retrieve only a subset of the data corresponding to specific page, and in
the skip method, we basically skip the first and element of the sequence, and in the take method,
we basically returns a specified number of the contiguous elements from the start of a sequence.
So Entity Framework Core supports pagination through a combination of the skip and take methods, which
are the part of the link, and pagination is a common requirement in many applications, especially
when dealing with large data set.
It involves dividing data into pages and retrieving only a specific page at the time.
So let's start with developing pagination classes with using Entity Framework Core.
For that purpose, I am going to open the Visual Studio, but this time I'm going to add this pagination
functionality into building blocks because it is a common operation that can be used different microservices.
That's why I am going to add pagination folder under the building blocks.
Let's go to Building Blocks class library.
Right click add new folder which name is pagination.
So in this folder we basically add the pagination classes.
And this class will represent the result of the paginated query.
I am going to create a new class.
Which name is paginated result which is representing a result of the paginated query.
So in this class I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
After that we will develop the class definition.
This class will be a generic type and after that you can see that we will add a generic entity that
accepting any entity into arpeggiated result.
And here you can see the primary constructor including the page index, page size count and IEnumerable
entity data.
And these two entities should be class.
So inside of this class definition, we can define the properties and add the these primary constructor
members into the properties.
Here you can see that we have adding the property page index, page size count and data.
And we will assign these parameters inside of the constructor with adding these primary constructor.
So as you can see that we have developed page index which is the current page index starting from the
zero.
And we have also adding property of the page size which is the number of the items per page.
And here you can see the count property which is the total number of the items in the data set.
And here you can see the data which is the actual data for the current page.
So this is the paginated result class that we can use for each paginated operation.
When we are using Entity Framework core in the microservices.
And as the same way we can create a new class which name is pagination request.
Here you can see that this is the paginated result.
And I am going to add an additional class which name is pagination request.
And in this request we basically represent a request for a paginated query.
I am going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public and inside of the.
This class we can develop the record type.
Here you can see that we have developed public record pagination request.
And in this record type we can accept page index and page size as a parameter of this record type.
So basically the pagination request record holds the page index and page size with the default values
of the zero and ten respectively.
This setup allows for the flexible pagination request.
So by implementing the paginated result and paginated request classes under the pagination and building
blocks, we have laid the foundation for efficient pagination in our microservices.