In this video we are going to develop get orders query apply the pagination.
So that means we will develop the get orders query use case in our ordering application with applying
the pagination and using the Skip and take methods in here.
So please open the Visual Studio and go to the ordering application and go to orders and go to queries.
So we are ready to implement get orders.
Use case with using the paginated classes that we have developed in the last video.
So for that purpose I'm going to create a new folder under the queries which is the add new folder,
which name is get orders.
In this folder we will create query and handler class as the same way with the other folder use case
structure.
So that's why I'm going to add a new class.
Which name is get orders query.
And this class represents the query to retrieve paginated orders.
For that purpose I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement.
And I'm going to create a record type for the get orders query.
Remove this class and create a new record type which is the public record get orders query.
And as a parameter it is taking the pagination request and the name of the parameter is pagination request.
And as you remember that we have developing these pagination request in the last video.
And this will be include page index and page size.
And if you go back to our code you can see that we will also implement AI query interface and returning
the get order result from this query.
For that purpose I'm going to create these get order result record type.
After the query definition.
Here you can see that we will create public record get order result.
And as a parameter of the result you can see the paginated result including the order DTO.
And the name of the parameter is orders.
So that means we will wrap the result in a paginated result containing a collection of the order DTO.
You can see the detail for page ended result this including page index, page size count and actual
data.
So if you go back to our get orders query, this is the R query definition under the R get orders folder.
And now it is time to implement get orders under class.
I'm going to add a new class under the get orders.
Which name is Get orders handler.
So this will implement the handler for the get orders query.
For that purpose, I'm going to remove unnecessary using statement and make this class as a public.
After that we will implement these get order handler class from the I query handler interface.
And this interface will be getting the type of the get orders query and return type of the get order
result.
So I'm going to implement these interface members which is the handle method.
And here you can see that handle method getting the first parameter which is the get orders query.
I'm going to change these parameter name request to query and also make these method as a async method.
So now we are ready for the implement this handle method.
First of all we will start with the planning our handle method.
Here you can see that we will have two items.
The first one is get orders with pagination and return the result.
So in order to get orders I'm going to inject I application db context into our class.
Please go to class definition and inject I application db context using the primary constructor of the
get orders handler class and give the name of the DB context as a DB context.
And after that we can start the implementation of the handle method.
So we will get the orders with pagination.
And in order to apply pagination, we will use the skip and take method in a link operation.
But this method also required for the page size and page index.
For that purpose, I am going to get the page size and page index from the incoming query object.
If you call the get Orders query and go to the request of the pagination request, you can see that
this will be page index and page size should be sent with the query object.
That's why I am going to get the page index and page size in the beginning of the method, and after
that I am going to prepare the get order result.
If you go to the result, this is expecting paginated result of the order detail list.
And if you go to page and result, you can see that we need the return page index, page size and also
count and data.
So for that purpose, if you go back to our implementation after getting the page index and page size
from the query object, I'm going to calculate the count operation with using the DB context orders
long count async method.
This will be returned a total count of the our order records on database, and after that we can perform
the pagination retrieve operation using the skip and take method.
Here you can see that we will perform orders with using the DB setup orders and including the order
items into our query and order.
Thereby with the old name.
And after this point you can see that we have used skip and take method in order to perform pagination.
That means we will skip page size and page index multiplexing this value.
And also we will take the page size of the record types, which is the default value is ten.
And after that we will run the query in a synchronous way and return the orders entity list.
So after that we can returning get orders result with populating the values.
Here you can see that I'm going to return Neve get order result with passing the new page entity result
and including this object we need page index, page size, total count and orders and two order detail
list.
As you remember that we have developed an extension method in order to convert orders entity to order
detail list.
So we use this extension method in here when wrapping with the pageant result.
So now I am going to safely remove these throw off statement.
And here you can see the implementation of the get orders handler and handle method.
Basically in this handle method retrieves the total count of the orders and applies the pagination using
the skip and take methods.
Orders are fetched with the related order items and converted into order DTO objects, and the result
is a paginated result of order DTO encapsulating the paginated order data.