Thank you so much for being with me on this journey.
I am so glad you two followed me the course for all through with the end.
I hope this course will help you to understand how to design and implement microservices with pattern
and best practices.
And now I believe that you will use your skills on your next challenging project and jobs.
So I hope this course will grow your career for all aspects.
Before closing the course, I would like to request one last thing.
If you can provide reviews and feedbacks of this course, this will help me a lot for further courses,
reviews and feedbacks is really encouraged me to for pushing forward to create new courses like this.
And also your reviews and feedbacks help to choose the right course for other students all over the
world.
So if you can some time to put your review and rating of this course, I will be very appreciated.
You can follow my activities from the GitHub, Twitter and medium.
Thank you for everything and your support.
Really important for me.
See you next courses.